<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H279C4DB92105401C8F8A78766952EDA3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1072 IH: Directing the Committee on Ethics to preserve and publicly release records of the Committee’s review of violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment) and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1072</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260223">February 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Directing the Committee on Ethics to preserve and publicly release records of the Committee’s review of violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment) and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas there is no place for sexual harassment or unwelcome sexual advances in the House of Representatives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas clause 9 and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House prohibit sexual harassment and unwelcome sexual advances in the House of Representatives; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sexual harassment and unwelcome sexual advances by Members, Delegates, or Resident Commissioners, in violation of clause 9 and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House, affect the safety, dignity, and the integrity of the proceedings of the House of Representatives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5393995AEAF444FCB4AC2AB3A7CDFE08"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HAB616C3962F04E68BA78A5AE4D8B720C"><enum/><text>That the Committee on Ethics shall—</text><paragraph id="H694461B0BF114D3EB9E05381AB594D8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserve all documents and investigative materials related to any violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment) and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House by a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F9DDE23872A4AD1AD853EDF5131329B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 60 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, make public all reports, including any conclusions, draft reports, recommendations, attachments, exhibits, and accompanying materials, with the personally identifiable information of victims or alleged victims redacted, related to the Committee’s investigations into violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment) and clause 18 of rule XXIII by a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

