<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A58ABA53C4D4C0F843A3EB9322E7A93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7459 IH: Coastal Trust Fund Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7459</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund and authorize the use of amounts in such Fund for coastal storm risk management activities of the Corps of Engineers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB4BCFFD4A7E24D86B9F35E58D89517A3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9CA7FAF264484308961A5E163349BADE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coastal Trust Fund Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD76B207599074BEEB749837C216536D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund</header> <subsection id="H4C6363CAC720447886766856D303B87B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund</quote>, consisting of amounts credited to the Fund as provided in this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1826297E232F4767A4CEEA9F3247CB52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>There shall be credited to the Fund—</text> <paragraph id="H565544DDBBB149E6B12B45B331B62E52" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,000,000,000 for each fiscal year, derived from available revenues received by the United States from bonuses, rentals, royalties, fees, and other receipts due and payable to the United States for deposit in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6AD3192FEBE46D7B3517E38C4DBA6EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all amounts earned on investments of the Fund under subsection (d)(2).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H84F285E1A04E43FD941017B1D606D6EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts in the Fund shall be available for obligation and expenditure only as provided in section 3 of this Act and shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8009E2119DB347EDBE993A98907C685B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other rules</header> 
<paragraph id="H8F17FCC484E449E489678114471C9DF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fund shall be administered by the Secretary of the Treasury, who shall determine and certify quarterly the amounts required to be credited to the Fund under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D13218C32F14BB6B85D80C48683A43E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investment</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Secretary, required to meet current withdrawals. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States. The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any such obligations shall be credited to and form part of the Fund.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EFDD33DD0AE44A990F227FEC63B82F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certain amounts otherwise made available held harmless</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to reduce or otherwise affect—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FC519D211144902822F52C1FBD9A691"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the amounts deposited in the Land and Water Conservation Fund under section 200302 of title 54, United States Code; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA6932D2F2D242D099A6E6C7A0A91EB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts made available under section 105(a)(2) of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A81FD6D412C43299274B715E39EB1B2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon termination of the Fund, any unobligated balances remaining therein shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H533EFF9B393347DBB6654EA63CEF3653"><enum>3.</enum><header>Availability and use of funds</header> 
<subsection id="HE8EB913D54FB4FCDB2E67F1DB5FA0543"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent amounts are made available in advance in appropriations Acts, amounts in the Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund shall be available to the Secretary for obligation and expenditure for the Federal share of the costs of construction, operation, maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, and periodic nourishment of coastal storm risk management projects.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H411324FCC1F74EFF921AFAC7DC0140C0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual budget request</header><text>The Secretary’s budget submission to the Office of Management and Budget for any fiscal year shall be equal to the total amount projected to be in the Fund at the beginning of such fiscal year.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H28EAA214BF6747D4B6EEEF94C8EFC66A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report describing—</text> <paragraph id="HB42D131177B2442D84F4E550A0BF8999"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total amounts made available from the Fund under this section for that fiscal year;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H363BDBA0816345328B546AB1BBD0DC47"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the coastal storm risk management projects for which amounts were obligated or expended; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A3D2312A1264B6B9575FEFA27FC5AFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the unobligated balance of the Fund at the end of that fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE21A636A658A4266986F7A811C54FE35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H100126EF773B433D821D1BF01C84BE2D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Coastal storm risk management project</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>coastal storm risk management project</term> means a project for hurricane and storm damage reduction, coastal storm risk management, shoreline protection, or periodic nourishment that is specifically authorized by Congress and carried out by the Secretary under any provision of law, including any associated feasibility studies, engineering and design activities (including preconstruction engineering and design), operation and maintenance activities, and repair or restoration under section 5 of the Act of August 18, 1941 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/701n">33 U.S.C. 701n</external-xref>).</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7DC9068C503449ABDE3AEDD565571B9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund; Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund</term> and <term>Fund</term> each mean the Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund established under section 2.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0BACCD4320E44FEB5E97C955C0FEEC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5071E6DB539D4C7992B58F98CC5C7C6E" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Budgetary treatment expansion and adjustment for the Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 251(b)(2) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/901">2 U.S.C. 901(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H67329AA1A7254CBBB335567313A6CA1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H9E8D92BE1A8C4D1EB2EF3ACC771325A5" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Coastal storm risk management projects</header><text>If, for any fiscal year, appropriations for the Construction, Mississippi River and Tributaries, and Operation and Maintenance accounts of the Corps of Engineers are enacted that are derived from the Coastal Storm Risk Management Trust Fund established under section 2 of the <short-title>Coastal Trust Fund Act</short-title> and that the Congress designates in statute as being for coastal storm risk management projects (as defined in section 3 of such Act), then the adjustment for that fiscal year shall be the total of such appropriations that are derived from such Fund and so designated.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

