<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H01327878485141FA87DBBCCA066CAC16" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7215 IH: Stop Schemes, Cyberfraud, Abuse, Manipulation, and Swindles Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7215</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and the Federal Trade Commission to undertake a governmentwide effort to counter scams, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDA2DC75E88C144D2B3D1B09429567A63" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCE35EB73F334437BBBF2844563ACBD2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Schemes, Cyberfraud, Abuse, Manipulation, and Swindles Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Stop SCAMS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7A155C983E7E4D3188289DB8587F80EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Countering Scams and related activities</header> <subsection id="H345CC754309144C2897E787C73AAA729"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall, in coordination with the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Federal Trade Commission, and the head of any other agency that the Director determines appropriate—</text> 
<paragraph id="H279A3E77920946BEA0B8BD88CF908C38"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H27146888A54B4850A73A2647D182412A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and implement a government-wide strategy to counter scams and coordinate activities across the government relating to countering scams;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD02FAC12838F4215A8779A278C139DDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adopt a single definition of scam and various scam types; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8FBACB3F1654CE4A080F630EA9C32B9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>explore ways to harmonize data collection to better identify scams, including by consistently collecting data on scam type, dollar loss amount, payment method, and other data fields, as determined appropriate by the Director; and</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61FAF8B57D964621BEC90527D2684EF9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, develop and report a single, governmentwide estimate of—</text> <subparagraph id="HFAAB367F54E94D5AAE9ACF7795732F8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of consumers affected by scams each year, factoring in an estimate of incidents not reported; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE29B369D2994365899A60478E802F3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the dollar losses resulting from such scams.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1B9F7665FF0B4E2F8CC0423D73693BE7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency requirements</header> <paragraph id="H605E46FAA0A64F62AE2BF3069234C21F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal Bureau of Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0DF4CE4C884A43A78827571F10E70B10" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report an estimate of the number of complaints received by the Federal Bureau of Investigation relating to scams (as defined pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A)) each year and the estimated dollar losses associated with such scams; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAEF6FBC4D1C48E590DF396BEB00782E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish metrics and a plan to measure the effectiveness of anti-scam training offered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation through in-person events and webinars. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H044CEBF7A1C34141AAB226BA3D542D93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</header><text>The Bureau shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H1AADC73F46F94E9BB0EDD27A2073A83E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report an estimate of the number of complaints received by the Bureau relating to scams (as defined pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A)) each year and the estimated dollar losses associated with such scams; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E3BBEAA5ACB4466B201A439DE6C4E4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish metrics and a plan to measure the effectiveness of anti-scam training offered by the Bureau through in-person events and webinars.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H876E8BD2B30F4E3CB2372BDCA9722AFD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07184C9364284D13A03162CBBFCB191D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report an estimate of the number of complaints received by the Commission relating to scams (as defined pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A)) each year and the estimated dollar losses associated with such scams; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38E0B8D4F45A49D6B1CDE592D7D8109B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish metrics and a plan to measure the effectiveness of anti-scam training offered by the Commission through in-person events and webinars.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF613E549192F4457A1707C2B83424EDC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, Bureau, and Commission shall make publicly available in any annual report on scams the estimate of the number of complaints received by the Director, Bureau, and Commission, respectively. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD12B46B6DB3E448887D865B8AE8B4202"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB487276CC2FD427BBDAE25B6F99988F8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code. </text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FAA39E6A28447C98204735199DB2B74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H604ABDA651EB43E1BDFE7F2F5B5373C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38828BF0EB794AFF89D40762A107376A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

