<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E12ACC2209C4CE4B9A9ABDA8E29E2B7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6361 IH: Ban AI Denials in Medicare Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6361</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from testing the WISeR model, and to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to prohibit the implementation of payment models testing prior authorization under traditional Medicare.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H850FB5B886CB4D0C9CB1A220607A0477" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H63B67B30261F4851B452D8386FBEBB5D" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ban AI Denials in Medicare Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3578CE2B50B74067BD09178D882825FA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting implementation of Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation models testing prior authorization under traditional Medicare</header> <subsection id="HA7FB3F98E80C42B8A9313BFF7997D06A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibiting implementation of WISeR model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may not implement the innovative payment and service delivery model described in the notice titled <quote>Medicare Program; Implementation of Prior Authorization for Select Services for the Wasteful and Inappropriate Services Reduction (WISeR) Model</quote> (90 Fed. Reg. 28749 (July 1, 2025)), or any substantially similar model.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E7C7D8541384B33B768F78D7BBEAD2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibiting implementation of future CMI models testing prior authorization (including through the use of AI) under traditional Medicare</header><text>Section 1115A(b)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA36E5229F8A94B65A14976377C266121"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>The Secretary shall select</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the limitation under subparagraph (D), the Secretary shall select</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA53118E73E8C4FA5AABEAF746D3C9679"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7E6CF1C70B5D4C47921B41ABA8DCB80C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H968849AD256E44FE80180E06C39D377D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on models to be tested</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, the Secretary may not select a model to be tested under subparagraph (A) if such model would provide for the implementation of prior authorization (including through the use of artificial intelligence) with respect to items or services for which payment may be made under part A or part B of title XVIII.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

