<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H653B26D95B7E4B989F80780909A6D0C7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 847 IH: Supporting the recognition of November as “National Bread Month” and celebrating bread as a nutritious, affordable, and culturally significant staple food.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 847</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the recognition of November as <quote>National Bread Month</quote> and celebrating bread as a nutritious, affordable, and culturally significant staple food.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas bread has been a staple food enjoyed by cultures worldwide for centuries, with its versatility, nutrition, and affordability making it an essential part of diets across the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas enriched and whole grain breads provide essential nutrients, with grain foods like bread contributing to nearly 40 percent of dietary fiber in the American diet and delivering vitamins, including folate, thiamine, niacin, vitamin B<subscript>6</subscript>, riboflavin, and vitamin A;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas bread also provides minerals necessary for good health, such as iron, zinc, manganese, copper, magnesium, phosphorus, and selenium;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention credits enriched grains for reducing neural tube birth defects by nearly one-third in the United States;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas bread can be paired with a variety of foods, making it an adaptable, nutritious choice that complements proteins, vegetables, soups, and salads for balanced and satisfying meals;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas bread varieties such as loaves, boules, naan, roti, baguettes, pita, tortillas, and many more reflect the culinary diversity of cultures around the globe, underscoring the universal role of bread in bringing communities together; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas grain foods like bread are affordable, shelf-stable, and accessible, offering vital nutrition and helping to combat food insecurity by being a dependable food source for households of all incomes: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1C9A306E36E049928EB939A9E55B080E"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H203FD6A255E44A7191B1169A67C2E76C"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HB8B95544593E40D799682DCE0D41544E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes <quote>National Bread Month</quote> as an opportunity to celebrate bread’s role as a nutritious, versatile, and culturally significant food;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DF98EBD1BD947CC82C3FB23A8039C06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>highlights the contributions of grain foods like bread to public health and balanced diets;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H81CFE01B358C455EAC1BB8F99C59A691"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the American commercial baking industry for providing a wide variety of affordable and accessible grain foods; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF71F325E684441BB9E1FAF78195562A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages all Americans to celebrate the diversity and benefits of bread and grain foods during <quote>National Bread Month</quote>, exploring new varieties and pairing them with nutritious foods for a well-rounded diet.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

