<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24F459A92F0D4C75AF11D77DAD23FCF4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8517 IH: Clean Energy Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8517</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To develop career and technical education programs of study and facilities in the areas of renewable energy.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D7C8036CBAA4A58BD54842BF372533E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC6014761E8E741FB943C4DE760831994" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Energy Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H27A0204A14014BC5A243DB6034769A1B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clean energy curriculum development grants</header> <subsection id="HAF683EE83CAD47E89B3DE05731AAA537"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated under section 6 to carry out this section, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships to develop or expand programs of study that are focused on emerging careers and jobs in a covered field.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2337CED3DE4741B09300F38D6E4E78BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible Partnerships</header><text>For purposes of this section, an eligible partnership shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H48E17CE5023F4814985060443769F439"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at least 1 local educational agency, an area career and technical education school, or an educational service agency;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDF5CDEE244E042F1B35441D60B55DE87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 postsecondary institution; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5924018288048A0A5AC41D49DCF5579"><enum>(3)</enum><text>representatives of the community to be served by the eligible partnership, which shall include business owners, industry representatives that have experience in a covered field, and members of labor organizations as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8B3BA45956704A4A94571A2D46CEE003"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
<paragraph id="H34BB823D4C9A422F9E06908B0BAE43AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible partnership seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99312416424F44EEBB077619266A2FDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application submitted by an eligible partnership seeking such a grant shall include a description of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H56DE606AB3B5441A8931127B88263C2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligible partnership, including the partners and the roles and responsibilities of each partner, and a demonstration of the capacity of each partner to support the program of study to be funded by the grant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F6E72DA558E4956835ADBA968707B4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such program of study, which shall include a description of the secondary and postsecondary components;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC46D4AFC9427409BB13DAEF5A3E3FA23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how the program of study will—</text> <clause id="HC22B16C5535F42BDA71FD0639D9897F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be replicable and disseminated to postsecondary institutions or schools that are not part of or served by the eligible partnership, including postsecondary institutions or schools in urban or rural areas;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC564349985C844C4BC2DF5A00205503E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be delivered to students;</text></clause> <clause id="H82E02EF68C814D169A9F6A96EC4A6E9F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be accessible to students from a variety of backgrounds, including students who are economically disadvantaged, low-performing, and from urban or rural areas; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9871FC712A84416BAF9362A977A3E7BB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>address placement of students in non-traditional fields;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD8EC9955902411090BFCF20FC558375"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the industry and specific occupation or occupations within a covered field for which the program of study provides preparation for employment and the reason the eligible partnership intends to provide such preparation, including any evidence of a labor market need to prepare students for such industry or occupation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDAD28F1DACBE48F68B5349AD92D38128"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the students to be served by the program of study;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB64553BD6DD455888690349F1F09BF1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>applied learning that will be incorporated into the program of study and how such learning will incorporate or reinforce academic learning; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5558405885A3461793082D42C7C3E587"><enum>(G)</enum><text>how the eligible partnership proposes to consult or has consulted with a labor organization, labor management partnership, or a sponsor of an apprenticeship program or joint apprenticeship and training program that provides education and training to prepare students for employment in the industry or occupation in subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDEC47FEFD2254106BA0DFC0DBD9805A1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the peer review committee under section 4, shall give priority to an eligible partnership that demonstrates in an application submitted under subsection (c) that the program of study will—</text>
<paragraph id="H2ED3EB753DA74E1C83081652A2AE96D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deliver (such as through the use of online learning or other innovative means) the program of study to students, educators, and instructors at other postsecondary institutions or schools that are not part of or served by the eligible partnership; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35803574F6D24D63A7BDCE5915FF886E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">focus on low-performing students and special populations.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD486887C437A4886A6DBF8283E8D3B42"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uses of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded to an eligible partnership under this section shall be used for each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1D8CF42B6D664C208FDAFAAFDFBF5352"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The development and implementation of a new program of study in a covered field, or the expansion of an existing program of study in such field, by the eligible partnership that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAF3F9210808D4E238196A9E951C387AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is replicable and able to be disseminated to other postsecondary institutions or schools that are not part of or served by the eligible partnership; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9011B119B4D642919AF581217482DABA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepares students for a career in a covered field.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFA140312FFA143D885CF9352A5122454"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dissemination of a program of study under paragraph (1) to postsecondary institutions or schools that are not part of or served by the eligible partnership.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F974DA8823342819D01239CD9DC9F45" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Renewable energy facilities grants</header> <subsection id="H5055C3F678834D3CA378FEE6A570F104"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>From the amounts appropriated under section 6 to carry out this section, the Secretary of Energy shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to promote—</text>
<paragraph id="H390E651EF6244DB19FAAC8DFA49DA530"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development of career and technical education facilities that are energy efficient; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B957B08C8084CB681C53D7DA61F7297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the use of renewable energy practices at such facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H310AE4B009294A54B61065E283E83F23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE3EED4B7BC7148D2988518B5888D4B3E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity awarded a grant under this section shall use such grant to—</text>
<paragraph id="H9918F6A4CC7D4B4491F60C4CB01391A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">perform an evaluation of the sustainability aspects of the facilities of the eligible entity, which shall include measuring the energy effectiveness of the facilities of such entity and evaluating whether the facilities comply with existing renewable energy standards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97EAABC60ECB432CBBEEEDBFAE86423C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>convene stakeholders, including organizations devoted to the promotion and support of renewable energy activities, to develop a plan to address needs identified in such evaluation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F9527D6CA5F41FCA80CE75F826EFF69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carry out activities related to the construction, operation, and improvement of facilities that promote the use of renewable energy practices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD523E3A7149845E5BEFA7371EDA1C080"><enum>(4)</enum><text>purchase energy-efficient machinery, technology, or other physical equipment used as an educational tool to deliver career and technical education courses; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5C9EAA40056246D7A5D05DA8060C8B1C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>communicate to other eligible entities the lessons and practices learned from activities carried out under paragraphs (1) through (4).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC4644042E37C4E9492B4C6A03EC1F95A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>For purposes of this section, an eligible entity means—</text>
<paragraph id="HD66F7B610E6940F3801F0AEED5615DB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H825C5D7C43474D18A2665637E40C4950"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an area career and technical education school;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E404454D0C14704B68D8FAEC332FB45"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an educational service agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D6C1493B64B4940B56F5429F216A53B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a postsecondary institution; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA16CA1EC1D394B8BAFBF078B6991C502"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a consortium of any of the entities described in paragraphs (1) through (4).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5F77E02F4256428FB5496C7223B7DC4B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Peer review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In evaluating applications for the grant programs established under sections 2 and 3, the Secretary shall convene a committee to conduct a peer review process of grant applications and to make recommendations to the Secretary regarding the selection of grantees. Members of the peer review committee shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H84BA4A5BC85549118BD08C630A84A37C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>career and technical education educators and administrators who have experience with energy-efficient facilities and equipment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38B1799A3E9F46DDA7F7F668426C4182"><enum>(2)</enum><text>business and industry experts who build and work in renewable energy facilities.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HCE0E4171FC184A6C99EB5271D19BCE53"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H75CBCB2FEE2B4A2EA7F0CD4B525FA69B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>area career and technical education school</term>, <term>educational service agency</term>, <term>non-traditional field</term>, <term>program of study</term>, and <term>special population</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86DB33A4A86744A09BCEA296A265917F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered field</header><text>The term <term>covered field</term> means the fields of clean energy, renewable energy, energy efficiency, climate change mitigation, or climate change adaptation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DC53CCD98F24823962798E135871B6E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency eligible for funding under section 131 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2351">20 U.S.C. 2351</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD08FEE2A785F47488F891F6B99863EE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Postsecondary institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>postsecondary institution</term> means a postsecondary institution eligible for funding under section 132 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2352">20 U.S.C. 2352</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5205749214284C9ABA097CB12C6F586D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy $100,000,000 to carry out this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

