<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV26838-P7X-KJ-KW1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 697 ATS: Welcoming Their Majesties King Charles III and Queen Camilla of the United Kingdom to the United States on the occasion of His Majesty’s address to a joint meeting of Congress, and recognizing the historic global significance of the United States-United Kingdom relationship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 697</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Welcoming Their Majesties King Charles III and Queen Camilla of the United Kingdom to the United States on the occasion of His Majesty’s address to a joint meeting of Congress, and recognizing the historic global significance of the United States-United Kingdom relationship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United Kingdom and the United States share a special relationship based on common heritage, language, culture, and legal and democratic principles;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the unalienable rights and freedoms proclaimed in the Declaration of Independence and enshrined in the United States Constitution by the founding fathers of the United States are founded on the concepts and principles of the English Enlightenment movement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, following the American Revolution, the United States and the United Kingdom established formal diplomatic relations when John Adams presented his credentials in London to establish diplomatic ties on June 1, 1785, which have subsequently endured and deepened over centuries and generations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in September 2025, President Donald J. Trump led a second state visit to the United Kingdom and, in his remarks at Windsor Castle, declared that <quote>the bond of kinship and identity between America and the United Kingdom is priceless and eternal[,] irreplaceable and unbreakable</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States-United Kingdom cooperation and educational exchange have produced groundbreaking scientific innovations, including in industrial production and information technology, that have contributed to the benefit of mankind and will be further deepened by the U.S.-UK Technology Prosperity Deal established on September 18, 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States and the United Kingdom share a common interest in advancing cooperation with our partners in the European Union to protect Western values and transatlantic unity and advance our strategic competitiveness against rivals and adversaries like China, Russia, and Iran, who seek to undermine the transatlantic community around the globe;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United Kingdom is one of the United States’s closest security partners, hosts over 10,000 United States military personnel, and assists in the defense of United States national security through bilateral cooperation established by the U.S.-UK Mutual Defense Agreement of 1958 and within the North Atlantic Treaty Organization alliance, the United Nations Security Council, the Five Eyes intelligence alliance, and the Australia-United Kingdom-United States (AUKUS) partnership;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States and United Kingdom have stood together to defend freedom around the world, including in the First and Second World Wars, throughout the Cold War, including the Korean War, and in the Persian Gulf War, the Iraq War, and the War in Afghanistan; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United Kingdom has, among other United States security partners, supported efforts to increase the NATO defense spending obligation to 5 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) by 2035 and bolster European support for Ukraine;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the United Kingdom has played a critical role in delivering economic and military support to Ukraine amid Russia’s full-scale invasion, most recently by its leadership through the coalition of the willing to secure a lasting peace in Ukraine; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas King Charles III is recognized by the United States for his distinguished military service in the Royal Air Force and the Royal Navy, as well as for his strong commitment to environmental issues, and his tireless support of disadvantaged youth through the King’s Trust, which he founded in 1976; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, on April 28, 2026, His Majesty King Charles III will deliver an address to a joint meeting of Congress commemorating the United States-United Kingdom relationship and the 250th anniversary of the Independence of the United States, marking the first address from a British monarch since the visit of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II in 1991: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id8264fc52df6249f393fe1d9e7f05e4e1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>welcomes Their Majesties King Charles III and Queen Camilla on their first official state visit to the United States in preparation for His Majesty’s address before a joint meeting of Congress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22f7f07e9a314eb791d928a71f553a37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the historic significance of His Majesty’s state visit on the occasion of the 250th anniversary of United States independence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca19ffd29a9842eda875cf97afa88878"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the strong and enduring partnership between the United States and the United Kingdom to defend our common values and interests and advance the peace, security, and prosperity of our citizens and the broader international community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f6da39b838b4c588eeebb492d17125a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses its appreciation for the historic and continued friendship between the people of the United States and the United Kingdom; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3da5b19cfe0452b875d34b3fe098d9d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages deeper cooperation between the United States and the United Kingdom on strategic security cooperation, including in Europe and the Indo-Pacific.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

