<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25K44-0HH-7L-CL5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3276 IS: UNtaxed Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3276</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for limitations on the implementation and enforcement of a global carbon tax with respect to the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H64239B89D40147428E0D01476310A578"><section section-type="section-one" id="HAA4D005D638E45A2A4ADA4FBFECD1EE6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>UNtaxed Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1DDA71462443415088FF8FE355F9065A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on United Nations taxes, tariffs, fees, or other such penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No tax, tariff, fee, or other such penalty may be levied upon United States citizens or United States entities by the United Nations or any organ, specialized agency, commission, or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations, unless such tax, tariff, fee, or other such penalty is imposed under a treaty with respect to which the Senate has provided its advice and consent under clause 2 of section 2 of article II of the Constitution of the United States.</text></section><section id="H53CAFE075699485D9C79845C644CE0BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on funds relating to global carbon taxes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for—</text><paragraph id="H00B3137567E64FEA87085B660EF94D90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assessed or voluntary contributions of the United States to the United Nations or any United Nations-affiliated body that would be used to impose a global carbon tax; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B84FD7D90FB457EB2DF5FA01127AA62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementation or enforcement of such a global carbon tax.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB24794EC72FB45AAB0548F7EA8A4B3F9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf46d0238e0e45c4bc2c6e77e2d09604"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Global carbon tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>global carbon tax</term> means a tax imposed under a global fuel regime that—</text><subparagraph id="HEE308C39FCDD46FFA753406571D0A223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requires the owner or operator of a vessel to reduce the level of greenhouse gases emitted by the vessel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A06DDCD67004E99B855D3A33B7FCCE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>imposes such a tax at set costs with respect to such level of emission of greenhouse gases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbae142e592fe4d1183399397e60e1d57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States entity</header><text>The term <term>United States entity</term> means an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

