<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H57423FDD3FCC41A8A8FC3C7AF2BAB6A6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5895 IH: Protect Patients from Healthcare Abuse Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5895</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish certain standards and requirements with respect to obtaining informed consent and providing chaperones for providers of services participating in the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H281C0E71D89E4BF889E67E1597BFC5DB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H371A6E1B42D24FD194E87239C2A10370" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Patients from Healthcare Abuse Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8E5EC840B98E42CFA350B8FC2CEBE654"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishing standards and requirements with respect to obtaining informed consent and providing chaperones as a Medicare condition of participation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1866 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H004429FA2DA945ED904B8AD801E9C36C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEBF538FF3F5C4F60B516FA4C3231F3DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (X), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9927AF01B54A4F129191EC5A2146809B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD112E60BD46F456BBB32FB6B94C7BD15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H78A2C520E6A24DB98B042EE9B1D4EBBA" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="H658031D33A154567BDD58810841D77D8" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(Z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning January 1, 2026, in the case of a provider of services, to comply with the informed consent and chaperone requirements described in subsection (l).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF738CED84E1F4BA0842260B3775B813A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9A9A9F733368419383425D735B68EED0" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H90E0738A8B044CCFA047C43AEEA28331"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Informed consent and chaperone requirements</header>
<paragraph id="HCC5BE5F8488D4F83BF68FF8D763E666A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(Z), the informed consent and chaperone requirements are, with respect to a provider of services—</text> <subparagraph id="HB10630276B7A4AD5986F61BF489B3CD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the written notification requirement described in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB622FB4B9ABF4EA08F3E7E78DB724069" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the chaperone training and education requirement described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63E9856724DA4D1ABA7041829F64B350"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Written notification requirement</header><text>For purposes of <internal-xref idref="HCC5BE5F8488D4F83BF68FF8D763E666A" legis-path="(l)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the requirement described in this paragraph is, with respect to a provider of services, that the provider maintains written policies and procedures with respect to all adult individuals receiving medical care by or through such provider to provide written information to each such individual concerning the right of such individual or a surrogate of such individual (to the extent permitted under State law) to make informed decisions with respect to the care of such individual, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC87D0D32EB194420A0A657AEA6BC1715"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right to be informed of the individual’s health status;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64E4A8214CE14DC880122E66BB497B83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the right to be involved in planning for the individual’s care;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3E4D7B16780D4007A8AA3982A707D0C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the right to provide informed consent with respect to an item or service before such item or service is furnished to such individual; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D720EEF13174AAE9A5CEBEFAAA0D89F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the right to request the presence of a chaperone during a sensitive procedure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31F3127C3EC445D39657F5631ECD5087" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chaperone training and education requirement</header><text>For purposes of <internal-xref idref="HCC5BE5F8488D4F83BF68FF8D763E666A" legis-path="(l)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the requirement described in this paragraph is, with respect to a provider of services, that the provider provides for the education and training of appropriate staff (as determined by the provider) with respect to the rights of individuals receiving medical care by or through such provider described in paragraph (2). Such training and education shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H0DF0527A35D14B029D101760B867F9C7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training in how to perform the functions of a chaperone during a sensitive procedure;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9AB9643298B84A77A447EFD331CD502A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>education with respect to what constitutes a sensitive procedure; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1B427F672754C13B837C6F110D7C556" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>education with respect to an individual’s right to provide informed consent to items and services being furnished to such individual, as described in paragraph (2)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2261BE62460E44CFB4C08365A714DFC0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the following definitions apply: </text> <subparagraph id="H4606BADC829047FFBCB4C28D6734C8E2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Chaperone</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>chaperone</term> means, with respect to medical care furnished to an individual by or through a provider of services, an appropriate staff member (as determined by the provider)—</text>
<clause id="HE385819BD8A54F0492595FFA7FC49B71" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who is trained and educated in accordance with paragraph (3); and</text></clause> <clause id="HDBFA3FEBDC06495C89A9978B59DE4430" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who is present during a sensitive procedure furnished in connection with such care in order to—</text>
<subclause id="H3439F27876BE464F9684BC0CA20F1671" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>act as a witness to the procedure;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7CCDE6BF4AD64068985380C882B704E1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide a comfortable, safe environment consistent with the generally accepted standard of care for such procedure; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB450B2B290D0401DA47B7304B501F02E" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>report sexual abuse (as defined in section 2242 of title 18, United States Code) to an appropriate supervisor (as designated by the provider).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC9C79B61CC84929B422C2C29E567FC9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Informed consent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>informed consent</term> means, with respect to an item or service furnished to an individual by or through a provider of services, that the individual understands the risks, benefits, and alternatives of such item or service.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD901220AC0CE4F368DDA7309185D9D85"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Sensitive procedure</header><text>The term <term>sensitive procedure</term> means, with respect to medical care furnished to an individual by or through a provider of services, any of the following procedures furnished in connection with such care:</text> <clause id="H7EE06F9581A6436DB1DBC76EFD69D04E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any physical examination, surgery, or other procedure involving the individual’s genitalia, breasts, perianal region, or rectum.</text></clause>
<clause id="HAB7C5636F19A42A68ECED478DE79657E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any other physical examination, surgery, or other procedure that the individual considers to be sensitive.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

