<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H875177B996704F958FC08A06972627DC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8603 IH: Dismemberment Abortion Ban Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8603</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit dismemberment abortions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5B679813FFDA420C8B95A87D551AE5A1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC6DED207B0124217969DA4DA13C9FB6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dismemberment Abortion Ban Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC94F2AEF36F8434F84957528305ECB54"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dismemberment abortion ban</header> 
<subsection id="HF11C6D899BF44DE4A5FF2A129AE1F2CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">Chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1531">section 1531</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H4D42CDACFC554B5D98F9489DC7704700" style="USC"> <section id="HEA25D136A5904539800B82FEE1181D64"><enum>1532.</enum><header>Dismemberment abortion ban</header> <subsection id="HC6888B251E3E4CBE9EE84493718D0AD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Dismemberment abortion prohibited</header><text>Any physician who, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, knowingly performs a dismemberment abortion and thereby kills an unborn child shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 2 years, or both. This subsection does not apply to a dismemberment abortion that is necessary to save the life of a mother whose life is endangered by a physical disorder, physical illness, or physical injury, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H19654AAEA5CF4EDD852D4A1156E8C45E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit abortions performed for any reason, including when the pregnancy is a result of rape or incest, if performed by a method other than dismemberment abortion.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60B0760E9E324C80BABD4DE646A4DA96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil remedies</header> <paragraph id="H7E6B90D0289943D38DEB29141E3D071E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action by a woman on whom an abortion is performed</header><text>A woman upon whom an abortion has been performed in violation of any provision of this section may, in a civil action against any person who committed the violation, obtain appropriate relief.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5462104C4EE42D0973FFF4ECA14D90A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil action by a parent of a minor on whom an abortion is performed</header><text>A parent of a minor upon whom an abortion has been performed in violation of any provision of this section may, in a civil action against any person who committed the violation obtain appropriate relief, unless the pregnancy resulted from the plaintiff’s criminal conduct.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3887E20FC0364C3B922C4652310C5B8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate relief</header><text>Appropriate relief in a civil action under this subsection includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB13B305E2D524220BAC1039B9BC2A5B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>objectively verifiable money damages for all injuries, psychological and physical, occasioned by the violation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29DEAF07BC7546A1A87FABC27E3DA067"><enum>(B)</enum><text>statutory damages equal to three times the cost of the abortion; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA60D2C0ACFAC4926B0A3295904ED5FFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>punitive damages.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78488EECB9F94C9D86F2DF69ADD67793"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attorneys fees for plaintiff</header><text>The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs to a prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B1EF321A21046A6BB1E20650F9D9D63"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Attorneys fees for defendant</header><text>If a defendant in a civil action under this subsection prevails and the court finds that the plaintiff’s suit was frivolous, the court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee in favor of the defendant against the plaintiff.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53CE352471A74B5798870C28A16AEB4B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Awards against woman</header><text>Except under paragraph (5), in a civil action under this subsection, no damages, attorney’s fee or other monetary relief may be assessed against the woman upon whom the abortion was performed or attempted.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H22BD4FAE0D5A4C69937ED87497E36E32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Immunity from prosecution for woman upon whom a dismemberment abortion is performed</header><text>A woman upon whom a dismemberment abortion is performed may not be prosecuted under this section, for a conspiracy to violate this section, or for an offense under section 2, 3, or 4 of this title based on a violation of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9A72DC3D9D8E46CF91F574BFB5536552"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H77538F39DD874ECD932B84B1DED9AA7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text>The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CFD291E7C6E44FFBA4571245D6CB9E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD817A5EFFBC3454090F536B2AF397F6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text> <clause id="HB7B0365EEE1F4E0692DEC06EE3D201B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H113ABE5E98304C51BE8908F5B8DDA293"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB718413C34504B73862B2E6A3DF8540E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dismemberment abortion</header><text>The term <term>dismemberment abortion</term>—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H0AB3C1A222D247AB965B98B8147AAE63">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>means, with the purpose of causing the death of an unborn child, knowingly dismembering an unborn child and extracting such unborn child one piece at a time or intact but crushed from the uterus through the use of clamps, grasping forceps, tongs, scissors or similar instruments that, through the convergence of two rigid levers, slice, crush, or grasp a portion of the unborn child’s body in order to cut or rip it off or crush it; but</text>
                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E3AFD65A6B2411992BA64FBB1B2B2F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="H1ABB4EE3C7A64AECBD88347E0BB8268B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an abortion which uses suction to dismember the body of the unborn child by sucking fetal parts into a collection container unless the actions described in subparagraph (A) are used to cause the death of an unborn child but suction is subsequently used to extract fetal parts after the death of the unborn child; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H906D465E810743C8964C6040D9FD88F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a procedure to remove a deceased unborn child—</text> <subclause id="H09E0E02AF0124887B28C07A81DA95E93"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whose death was the result of a miscarriage or a medical emergency; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HBE48E3ECE8334E98912186010392D6DF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who otherwise died not as the result of intervening action by a physician to cause such death in preparation for performing the actions described in subparagraph (A).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A137AEB577148DFA7115EB693FBE165"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55AC30EDD4D1472EABD4D82EA067B21C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Physician</header><text>The term <term>physician</term> means a doctor of medicine or osteopathy legally authorized to practice medicine and surgery by the State in which the doctor performs such activity, or any other individual legally authorized by the State to perform abortions: <italic>Provided, however,</italic> That any individual who is not a physician or not otherwise legally authorized by the State to perform abortions, but who nevertheless directly performs an abortion prohibited in this section shall be subject to the provisions of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF4AA26F23A94C89954A9C10A3EFAA3C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unborn child</header><text>The term <term>unborn child</term> means an individual organism of the species homo sapiens, beginning at fertilization, until the point of being born alive as defined in section 8(b) of title 1.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H69A406E74F1F4A739A85B703C4BE56A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="HCB054BC3EA80417CA7D089668D8CCDAA" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">1532. Dismemberment abortion ban.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1C2B95AB91114E5AB201908AA9AB66A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chapter heading amendments</header> <paragraph id="H932565907AF6462FA9F56A16BFB7569E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chapter heading in chapter</header><text>The chapter heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="USC">Partial-birth abortions</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="USC">Abortions</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H439CB677322946B3B8777D3EB2141BA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of chapters for part i</header><text>The item relating to chapter 74 in the table of chapters at the beginning of part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC">Partial-birth abortions</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC">Abortions</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

