<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26059-1R4-7K-6W6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3707 IS: Nurse Faculty Shortage Reduction Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for a wage differential program to support new nursing school faculty members.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nurse Faculty Shortage Reduction Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id67E6DDC958F54471B5CEAC27658DC8D2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nurse faculty demonstration program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 846A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/297n-1">42 U.S.C. 297n–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82b39ba81fda49de9a935fba45c6bf7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC49D31C06B0A4C5187081D04206A452B"><subsection id="id6d62fb5a249b4d3caf60f87993f77849"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To increase the number of qualified nursing faculty, the Secretary may—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide68c14d8493e4bf5931f5a6359eccf95"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into an agreement with any accredited school of nursing for the establishment and operation of a student loan fund in accordance with subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7928d425034e49d7b5301cf549494383"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">award nurse faculty grants in accordance with subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98d6fb55a92946bdadeb0b234f23fe3a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id762c86d5a449474ba0fbf78a04ec35ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (2) as clauses (i) through (iv), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide64168e9140d46868a1c5df3ee5802fb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (5) as subparagraphs (A) through (E), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6e460a4b79e498eb6536f536e392aba"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47cad8767ae04bd08dab80c7cce31fcb"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(b) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Agreements—</header-in-text>Each agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall—</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE01EE284CFCD4771BB0817625152FD37"><subsection id="id045ec4d9755c43cbb2e1f66b77c79ba7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>School of nursing student loan fund</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb39296fb2f0641d790224fcb3a8c2729"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each agreement entered into under subsection (a)(1) shall—</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f2d329a2dd044c1ab2a17a65d3ad722"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8980f7a50d8140848d8040bfe8ffc155"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(1)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd114916e2b647adbccc1f78064cc22e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f1e8454739c4692abab03e426ac3806"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id233f34ffe2bc44abaa43c3ecba3ccf9c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (6) as subparagraphs (A) through (F), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a7ecb7cc69447e88af8724bf4302d93"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)(ii), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (4)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9914ac52f31d4daabd5ead6d88eaaf2a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>subsection (c)(6)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2)(F)(ii)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46db2a4986114ff7a1c99e2d6f50afb6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (e) as paragraphs (2) through (4), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddab5f0d63caf40b68039ba6b4f2dfcdd"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77E6C8A861D54FD08DC9B8B6385F45FA"><subsection id="idE555150FE516475BAC29F811D7763784"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nurse faculty demonstration program</header><paragraph id="idBA766F128793405DAF2C7B931833C5CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and carry out a demonstration program described in subsection (a)(2) under which eligible schools of nursing receive a grant for purposes of supplementing the salaries of eligible nursing faculty members to enhance recruitment and retention of nursing faculty members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC9F8C424F0084656A687E45D6FB73FA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an entity shall—</text><subparagraph id="id661E08CA89DB48189163A21F7F13F4BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a school of nursing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA99E4F9D53E64A5F87801444CD0A6040"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit an application to the Secretary, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><clause commented="no" id="idA92C564E1E77460CA0AD4DBEC31F8DCF"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1911e8c0fcd5454aa21d9eca79fd6d02"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to the extent such information is available to the school of nursing, the salary history of nursing faculty at such school who previously were nurses in clinical practice, for the most recent 3-year period ending on the date of application, adjusted for inflation as appropriate and broken down by credentials, experience, and levels of education of such nurses; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="ida39caed846bc4a21b66fcc1cf045fea8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the information described in subclause (I) is not available, information on the average local salary of nurses in clinical practice, adjusted for inflation as appropriate and broken down by credentials, experience, and levels of education of the individual nurses, in accordance with such requirements as the Secretary may specify;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idE0A7C87BB1454EFAB3B5D5C8DFD2FA07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an attestation of the average nursing faculty salary at the school of nursing during the most recent 3-year period prior to the date of application, adjusted for inflation, as appropriate, broken down by credentials, experience, and levels of education of such faculty members; </text></clause><clause id="id70846BDA0C1D4D588A0037D932A7E8E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of nursing faculty member vacancies at the entity at the time of application, and the entity’s projection of such vacancies over the ensuing 5-year period; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ac9dd130f8f40a18405f8764a291a75"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the entity's plans to identify funding sources to sustainably continue, after the 3-year grant period, the salary available to the eligible nursing faculty member pursuant to the program under this subsection during such grant program and to retain eligible nursing faculty members after the end of the grant period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC4992AC6C1BA4A7F83AC7419A15CD704"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Awards</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection, with respect to supporting eligible nursing faculty members, shall—</text><subparagraph id="idA068F23600FF4165A96ACBDF060CE05F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be awarded to the school of nursing to supplement the salaries of eligible faculty members at the school of nursing, annually, for up to a 3-year period, in an amount equal to, for each eligible nursing faculty member at the eligible entity during the grant period, the difference between—</text><clause id="idEE3C4CD59CDA47F2926E2C672975A464"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the average salary of nurses in clinical practice, as submitted under subclause (I) or (II) of paragraph (2)(B)(i); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idA8D8A693C1DE4A41A5AB828E1A63986B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the greater of—</text><subclause commented="no" id="idACCA79B2E9864484ADCC06A2BA15E8D7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the salary for the eligible nursing faculty member at the school of nursing; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id7A257443C8D2469D9A7F59AE83768CE1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the average nursing faculty salary, as submitted under paragraph (2)(B)(ii) for faculty members with the same or similar credentials and level of education; </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAC5C78800160423E816FF96ACB23F60E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notwithstanding section 803(a), be used in its entirety to supplement the eligible faculty member's salary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30F0425109FA4433A7DE03EAC3A03E94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be conditioned upon the school of nursing maintaining, for each year in which the award is made as described in subparagraph (A), a salary for such faculty member at a level that is not less than the greater of the amount under subclause (I) or (II) of subparagraph (A)(ii). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5949781d0364610afbacf4611c5eec5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall ensure the equitable geographic distribution of awards, and shall give priority to applications from schools of nursing that demonstrate—</text><subparagraph id="id6232fd38f17a429ea153482062ced3dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the greatest need for such grant, which may be based upon the financial circumstances of the school of nursing, the number of eligible nurse faculty members, the planned number of students to be trained or admitted off a wait list;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce66d963fa06470a97f47259b64b455f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training or partnerships to serve vulnerable patient populations, such as through the location or activity of a school in a health professional shortage area (as defined in section 332); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4784afca1fd8453482eaf5d70227d17c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recruitment and retention of faculty from underrepresented populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b7c5c71195e45969be6d38d20081a09"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection precludes a school of nursing or an eligible nursing faculty member receiving an award under this section from obtaining or receiving any other form of Federal support or funding. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0D10218088D842FF870514BF61B6A9AA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Nurse Faculty Shortage Reduction Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report that evaluates the program established under this subsection, including—</text><subparagraph id="id2f7aec5a0fbd4242ba93e2820a074f0f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the impact of such program on recruitment and retention rates of nursing faculty, as available, and specifically for each faculty member participating in the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8f30fd6e13c4a65bb3fd6bab2a66517"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations and considerations for Congress on continuing the program under this subsection. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAA95516D7F0D417A868B5609AE69F989"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id3CE2D1D39D9842C6ADF8FF6D01E533AD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible nursing faculty member</header><text>The term <term>eligible nursing faculty member</term> means a nursing faculty member who—</text><clause id="id431EE88E7BC44C599A861FA6F686DD16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was hired by a school of nursing within the 2-year period preceding the submission of an application under paragraph (2), or a prospective nursing faculty member; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d2c90ddb53d4818acf7a366eb25d2dd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is currently employed at the school of nursing and who demonstrates the need for such support; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c5b2a911195499784e307ba72ef850d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>previously worked as a nurse in clinical practice or as a nurse faculty member at another school of nursing; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide827555ab2ec4c82bf92b74a0504515a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may work on a part-time basis as a nursing faculty member, for whom such award amounts described in paragraph (3) shall be prorated relative to the amount of time participating in part-time teaching.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBFC448312E95475290FB2E5992DE8D4F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inflation</header><text>The term <term>inflation</term> means the Consumer Price Index for all urban consumers (all items; U.S. city average).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7D15F914326B4C158E02BDA517060F90"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this subsection, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal year 2027 through 2031.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

