<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6C7BC028446940A686E12A77EC4757BD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7759 IH: Afghanistan Vetting and Accountability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7759</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require verification of the personal and biometric information of all individuals evacuated from Afghanistan, to require in-person interviews of such individuals, and to prohibit Afghan evacuees who do not provide such information or submit to such interviews from receiving Federal assistance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H526E5817FE224FDF8130DC751C78AEED" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB46C82F3453F42219B0BBD0CC9716272"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Afghanistan Vetting and Accountability Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7E59408594004D0599456676907B1A53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Verification and vetting requirements with respect to individuals evacuated from Afghanistan</header><subsection id="H469C241D8A58435F9932A2C20495B73F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H70FFF69AFFC844BDA9436F08FC4DE89F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal means-tested public benefit</header><text>The term <term>Federal means-tested public benefit</term> means a Federal means-tested public benefit within the meaning of section 403 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1613">8 U.S.C. 1613</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7F3861DAB948E592B6529688680522"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual evacuated from Afghanistan</header><text>The term <term>individual evacuated from Afghanistan</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HFDE73984A5B64D79970B4AB819942FA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any individual, other than a United States citizen or a member of the United States Armed Forces, conveyed out of Afghanistan into the United States in coordination with the Government of the United States during the period beginning on January 20, 2021, and ending on January 20, 2022; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF730C715517C4C0AB59074429994F07E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes each individual, other than a United States citizen or a member of the United States Armed Forces, evacuated from Afghanistan as part of Operation Allies Welcome.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E8650D32EB46E7BD38D638B07E7612"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74F0F2F0D90E4EEBB60F8A04C2DB0727"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unemployment compensation</header><text>The term <term>unemployment compensation</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/85">section 85(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0245B9A0969741C5B6FB1AC16EAEC23C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Verification and vetting requirements</header><paragraph id="HCC3912A096554B6D9634D322839A033C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall verify the personal and biometric information and conduct in-person vetting of each individual evacuated from Afghanistan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7379A736CBCB4E6892A6437B9ED7934B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vetting database</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and maintain a database that contains, for each individual evacuated from Afghanistan, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H328220372D36452888E8B2AA56DBA7DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Personal information, including name and date of birth.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DF71D84B5B74C33A6DAB6A36FED8875"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Biometric information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF996B1EA86E1466A8FE2350225BED6AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any criminal record since the date on which the individual entered the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC57C2C1D75B4820B4F0D12A15356C96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any application for, or receipt of, unemployment compensation or a Federal means-tested public benefit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90E4FF3EE20F428F9F8F092AE8B65AD5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The vetting status of the individual, including whether the individual has undergone in-person vetting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFEB8ED5374E24CBF9B80035679D5B7F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quarterly report</header><paragraph id="HD2FFF4D25D24463C95F818A051368CBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than quarterly until the date on which the Secretary submits the certification under subsection (d), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing the compliance of the Secretary with subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99448AC4329B48D4B89E64FD3EEC77E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA63C77B6659745E98B5F8878E464138F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of all individuals evacuated from Afghanistan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28F28561CC174400A5D38031C5E356A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to each such individual—</text><clause id="H2857046B866B458AAB67F2A34762AEAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vetting status, including whether the individual has undergone in-person vetting;</text></clause><clause id="HA60F2621D6E14D7FAD493B306E14E0DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment as to whether the individual has received unemployment compensation or a Federal means-tested benefit;</text></clause><clause id="HF2ACDF95BA044D5EB934B74CB3E01DA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of any arrest or criminal record for conduct that occurred in Afghanistan, if available; and</text></clause><clause id="H43FCEA3E1C8C432FBB80A73F1FD6C8C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of any arrest or criminal record for conduct that occurred in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6A6E0419FBD49819710AB0FA27A87C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The estimated number of days remaining until the Secretary completes the verification and vetting of each individual evacuated from Afghanistan as required by subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3ECEFB0F5A3F49E8B7642B39EF7AD596"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary completes the verification and vetting required by subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a certification that such verification and vetting has been completed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1A31986ABDE249CF80E216C25B5CBC8A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO Audits and Reports</header><paragraph id="HAF4EFEC8C7904CE8AD49D6ED5F267D7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit and investigation with respect to the compliance of the Secretary with this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H0DA3E160C9314DE5A5CF3FD71F92F0AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1154109396E143FC8838AD0E9483FF6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary makes the certification under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD42E71AB4A354CC6A04506ACFA80692C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the completion of each audit and investigation required by paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the audit and investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H774C091C153A4AA9B80A5B897FC9C1FC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Restriction on Federal assistance</header><text>An individual evacuated from Afghanistan who has not provided personal information and biometric information to the Secretary, and undergone in-person vetting, shall not be eligible to receive unemployment compensation or any Federal means-tested public benefit.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

