<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F2821291E9B4D27AD24A2674716B902" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 818 IH: Impeaching Deborah Boardman, Judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 818</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Deborah Boardman, Judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5A33C17A685D44808AD5A95F4EA57B7D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H110D5634A713491FA392343879F4971B"><enum/><text>That Deborah Boardman, Judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors and for violating the constitutional standard for continuance in judicial office of <quote>good behavior</quote>, and that the following article of removal be exhibited to the United States Senate.</text><subsection id="H7BFB63F06B1F44B6990130CF453FB3B8"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Article of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Deborah Boardman, Judge of the United States District Court for the District of Maryland, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against her for high crimes and misdemeanors and for violating the constitutional standard for continuance in judicial office of <quote>good behavior</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H64B0C6481D654D1EAB112D741B7A8EE8" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article I: Willful and systemic refusal to comply with the law</header><subsection id="HBB8A33CE18A14A3F8B3DF4C8AE9BC81E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Boardman, in violation of her oath of office, did knowingly and willfully use her judicial position to knowingly interfere with the President’s constitutional prerogatives and enforcement of the rule of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE77B00C7FDD54F57A6FF41CD1CFD75EB"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Constitution grants Congress the authority to create, eliminate, and regulate all Federal courts inferior to the Supreme Court. Section 1 of Article III of the Constitution provides that <quote>[t]he Judges, both of the supreme and inferior Courts, shall hold their Offices during good Behavior</quote>, thereby granting Congress the authority to remove a judge who fails to remain in good behavior while in office.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFDA5E516FE9A462BBE2F389EC07133CA"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through her conduct, in which she violated her oath to the Constitution and duty of impartiality to the people of the United States, Judge Boardman has abused the powers of her judicial authority, having engaged in actions that deviate from the law and toward political ideology as follows:</text><paragraph id="H418B6C5A52D04A148292F95293CB34EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On October 3, 2025, Judge Boardman sentenced the defendant, Nicholas John Roske, found guilty of attempting to assassinate U.S. Supreme Court Justice Brett Michael Kavanaugh on June 7, 2022, to eight years and a lifetime of supervised release instead of the 30-year sentence recommended by the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA484A1BA378841F7AD217BD690CA59F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Roske traveled by aircraft from his home in Simi Valley, California, to Chevy Chase, Maryland, where Justice Kavanaugh resides with his family, resulting in his arrest outside of Justice Kavanaugh’s home with a firearm with a laser sight attachment, admitting to wanting to inflict harm. Roske was also equipped with zip ties, a tactical knife, pepper spray, a hammer, a screwdriver, a nail punch, a crowbar, duct tape, a pistol light, and was wearing padded boots to minimize noise.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4F8155BA8E545A4B8E12A9E5BCE7EF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Roske spoke to a Montgomery County emergency communication center operator to detail his thoughts while standing outside Justice Kavanaugh’s home. He said that he traveled from California to Maryland <quote>to kill a specific United States Supreme Court justice</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C31E2E4966A4AC4A4A74AD8500F8CED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In May and June of 2022, before the attempted assassination, Roske’s cell phone history showed repeated internet searches for <quote>quietest semi auto rifle,</quote><quote>how to quietly knock someone out,</quote><quote>most effective place to stab someone,</quote><quote>most effective way to silently kill someone,</quote><quote>how much force do you need to stab someone’s neck,</quote><quote>best way to break into a house,</quote><quote>how to make handcuffs with zip ties,</quote> and <quote>does the secret service protect supreme court justices</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD4A209B832F4500AD6DDB547A6D783B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Justice’s sentencing memorandum of Roske’s detailed how he <quote>researched, planned, and attempted to assassinate at least one—but had a stated target of three—sitting judges of the United States Supreme Court</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07E5DA63242D47AA9862742AE99F4D5C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Justice also noted Roske intended to <quote>… murder up to three justices in total, and try to evade prosecution by leaving no evidence, claiming an insanity defense, or fleeing to a non-extraditing country</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37456DB21B8945018881E285ED08CDF5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of Justice outlined Roske’s criminal conduct of attempting to assassination of a Supreme Court Justice required extensive premeditation, as he extensively researched the home addresses of Supreme Court justices and marked their homes on Google Maps, obtained weapons and other tools to eventually use them for killing and traveled across the country with those items, and researched how to infiltrate private residences without detection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99D0C62124B24319BA742EB1092FC98E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Roske attempted to delete any online evidence of motive and intent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A1E50C29669414A8C107E3DB8CAB62D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Judge Boardman accepted the delusional fiction that Roske—a biological male—has become a woman and then based her sentencing decision on that claim, saying, <quote>I take into consideration the conditions of pre-trial confinement and the fact that she is a transgender woman,</quote> apparently because the pre-trial detention facility in which Roske was confined does not, of course, indulge this fiction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H578E033A378D4A4D939CAB0463825EDF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Attorney General Bondi said of Judge Boardman’s decision, <quote>…the judge Boardman also would not refer to the defendant by his biological name</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F58A09C8EA04A1786200C9967B41DA1"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Judge Boardman’s indefensibly light sentence undermines the gravity of the offense committed by Roske and the assault it represented on our Constitution and the rule of law by targeting a Supreme Court Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA035C3BA7924E60B04B82FC39504728"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Judge Boardman’s sentencing decision is an egregious instance of a judge allowing her ideology to subvert the TRUTH—which is irreconcilable with the bedrock function of the judicial process and violates the constitutional standard for continuance in judicial office of <quote>good behavior.</quote></text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81FA9F39898D4EF08D37B5430FB8AA71"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This conduct undermines the orderly functioning of the judiciary by providing an exceptionally low sentence for a defendant who methodically planned to execute multiple assassinations of sitting Supreme Court justices by extensively researching what weapons and tools to procure, researching the home addresses of Supreme Court justices and saving them onto his smart phone, and inquiring how to infiltrate private residences without detection and how to incapacitate and kill individuals.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE7213EF08AAD4AB496AC22FC7F79F83C"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Allowing her personal feelings of Roske identifying as a transgender woman to influence her sentencing decision in her high office, Judge Boardman interfered with the will of the people and Congress that have codified statute to impose appropriate sentences for those who intend to kill Federal judges, ignoring the 30-year sentence recommendation by the Department of Justice.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1C6C7A0AEF6488E8879CFE4CC620FEF"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In so doing, Judge Boardman used the powers of her position to engage in actions that undermine judicial authority. By making a political decision outside the scope of her legal duties, she compromised the impartiality of our judicial system.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE58D1237AC314B46B821D14CE1C6D8AD"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Judge Deborah Boardman is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and of conduct that violates the constitute standard of good behavior, and she should be removed from office.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

