<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HADF695C744A0454184125974CF4F0A5D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9069 IH: Keeping Immigrants and Destinations Safe Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9069</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the Department of Homeland Security from detaining children and individuals with a cognitive disability and to prohibit immigration enforcement actions at sensitive locations without a court-issued criminal warrant.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H264C92E0376045A98B45A27EC5C9A8D4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE3E46518A8CB44B6BC69CE66685FAB7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keeping Immigrants and Destinations Safe Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>KIDS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8E441476B5B43DD9513576372F84239"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF9D42DD1F95488397058CE5FFB597BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>child</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H527A8066A3BF45578F9CF809B12EA39A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cognitive disability</header><text>The term <term>cognitive disability</term> means a mental impairment that substantially limits one or more major life activities of an individual involving learning, reading, concentrating, thinking, or communicating, or the operation of a neurological or brain function, consistent with the meaning of <term>disability</term> under section 3(1) of the Americans with Disabilities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC28A4C32B6D04E99BD542B4280522E06"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H184DC4D3EBEC4F8981D633B004F43D97"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Primary caregiver</header><text>The term <term>primary caregiver</term> means a noncitizen parent or legal guardian who is the primary caretaker of 1 or more minor children in the United States, including a noncitizen parent or legal guardian with a direct interest in family court, probate court, guardianship, or child welfare proceedings involving a minor child.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDF2DF0B98C84BE88C8DF06473E78B38"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88AE933EC3474EAF95E6254A7C57B2F2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sensitive location</header><text>The term <term>sensitive location</term> includes any physical space located within 1,000 feet of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1E7D4EBD754041FEB0581AA867B212CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any medical or mental health care facility, including any hospital, health care practitioner’s office, accredited health clinic, vaccination or testing site, emergent or urgent care facility, or community health center;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56B40D40871A49A9AC591887EE757719"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any public or private school (including preschools, primary schools, secondary schools, and postsecondary schools (including colleges and universities)), any site of an early childhood education program, any other institution of learning, such as vocational or trade schools, and any other site where individuals who are unemployed or underemployed may apply for or receive workforce training;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4E69C20DE2CE4309B306B20D0551494F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any scholastic or education-related activity or event, including field trips and interscholastic events;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36B8D03FFB17417FBD4DB82C26A95860"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any school bus or school bus stop during periods when school children are present on the bus or at the stop;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD4A251FEED4F478189B3DADD05C83CAB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any recreational facility for children, such as playgrounds and formal recreational facilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD18C7E5595BE46B1B151D08AE41DE786"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any child care focused facility, including child care centers, before or after school care centers, foster care facilities, and group homes for children;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1CB8ACFA3BA6449599B40ABCBF0282CF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any location where disaster or emergency response and relief is being provided by Federal, State, or local entities, such as—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5910FC6EBA0A49A8891A2A8585F8A491"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the distribution of emergency supplies, food, and water;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCC01881AF5841938AE41462461256D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any place of temporary shelter;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF852CA09CD0F4B10B0FF4E049DBBB94F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any place along an evacuation route; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H073C03B93BB44A8BA64CD16FDDA850E8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any site where registration for disaster-related assistance or family reunification is taking place;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40C73F77BE8A452C8B9F66F346D205A9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any location of any organization that—</text>
<clause id="H60AF699D90A541E8B314AB2FFD53E46C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assists children, pregnant women, victims of crime or abuse, or individuals with significant mental or physical disabilities, including domestic violence shelters, child advocacy centers, facilities that serve disabled persons, drug or alcohol counseling and treatment facilities, rape crisis centers, supervised visitation centers, family justice centers, victims’ services providers, and community-based organizations providing social services; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEB20E669FB76461E8B2D2B5D8DD40E3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides disaster or emergency social services and assistance, or services for individuals experiencing homelessness, including food banks, pantries, or other establishments distributing food, and shelters;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC850819F0E444DA088D975F342F768A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any church, synagogue, mosque, or other place of worship or religious study, such as buildings rented for the purpose of religious services or a temporary facility or location where such activities are taking place;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA4AF3B98CC041C78FB4AF9C32106429"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any site of a funeral, graveside ceremony, wedding, or any site where other religious or civil ceremonies or observances are occurring;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA4C5F80E71FB483190DCCE9559A90202"><enum>(K)</enum><text>any site during a public demonstration, such as a march, rally, or parade;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73924B0DC4264A829522085905888ABB"><enum>(L)</enum><text>any Federal, State, or local courthouse, including immigration courts operated by the Executive Office for Immigration Review, the office of an individual’s legal counsel or representative, probation offices, and any facility where programs or services are provided in relation to a court proceeding;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H969FD251B7C74FB1B14533E9D9DF8DB1"><enum>(M)</enum><text>any congressional district office;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67D11EEE5C4148748B305FC574430AC9"><enum>(N)</enum><text>any office of the Social Security Administration;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEBB57F406F9C4BF2B22BF76033676F59"><enum>(O)</enum><text>any public assistance office, including locations at which individuals may apply for or receive unemployment compensation or report violations of labor and employment laws;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA9AF99AEA344FAEB5BC31B94A57ECC4"><enum>(P)</enum><text>the indoor or outdoor premises of a department of motor vehicles;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8680CE424B2645C7A6B3569BA94B2F8B"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>a polling place, including any building or infrastructure at which voting takes place during an election;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H632D8AE719A04BBFA40908A31948275B"><enum>(R)</enum><text>a labor union hall or any other union-operated building or office at which registered applicants are referred in rotation to jobs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2A5342210F254E4C84939617EAFD5054"><enum>(S)</enum><text>any public library; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35FDA4EF5E4D4BE3BAC51747177D390C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(T)</enum><text>any other location specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7165DC4C38DA40ABB34EA242EF7C77F8"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Detention of children</header>
<subsection id="H91A881EB92EF4547905B8D2FC56B5CD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Except as provided in section 5, the Department may not detain a child, an individual with a cognitive disability, or a primary caregiver of a child or individual with a cognitive disability.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC24AB14948AA4718A8B58245E37B5CE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Parental notice and reporting</header><text>If a detention is permitted under section 5, the Department may not detain any child or individual with a cognitive disability without the confirmed notification of a parent or legal guardian of such child or individual. All such detentions shall be reported to Congress not later than 24 hours after the Department takes such a child or individual into custody.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE46A575C605940DDB76E3B0CC760CB7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on detention of primary caregivers</header><text>There shall be a presumption that a primary caregiver of a child or an individual with a cognitive disability may not be detained unless the Department Secretary documents, based on clear and convincing evidence that has been provided to the primary caregiver of such child or individual, that release of the primary caregiver is unreasonable or impracticable.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H96BB3DCD7EEE452A84B4F9EB879165CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Release to designated caregiver or child welfare authority</header> <paragraph id="HAFFBFAEE5CED42E9BF1CE736599FF91D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a child or an individual with a cognitive disability is detained by the Department in violation of subsection (a), the Department shall prioritize the prompt release of such child or individual to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDF64283200AB478EA0B4FFF32CF8D1D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a parent or legal guardian;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CEEE0A2A5394D2698BBC20454F58519"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a designated caregiver identified by a parent or legal guardian of such child or individual;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE122DB5FBDEE4709B5550050CB1B75AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the appropriate State or local child or adult protective services agency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9DD65FB7E6B437AB531426BE5CD3FE6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>appropriate officials of the Department of Health and Human Services Office of Refugee Resettlement, if appropriate and practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H083898B7129C4CBD82586AB64BEA9BB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recognition of delegated parental authority</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), the Department shall recognize and give effect to any written instrument executed by a parent or legal guardian that delegates temporary caregiving authority or parental authority to another individual, including a power of attorney or other document authorized under applicable State law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H058200D1C8334E54ADF4D25F0F4537E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>The Department may take reasonable steps to verify the identity of the designated caregiver or the authenticity of the written instrument described in paragraph (2), but such verification shall not unreasonably delay the release of the child or individual with a cognitive disability.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1870A2D1ABA04E508F23D429DE4692C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Best interests of the child</header><text>All determinations made under this subsection shall be guided by the best interests of the child or individual with a cognitive disability.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HBC19998016494CFFB5D022CBBA25108D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on enforcement actions at sensitive locations</header> <subsection id="H52E4F2524F0845138E5D7AEC8C4E1ECF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in section 5, the Department may not conduct, engage in, or execute any immigration enforcement action that takes place at, is focused on, or occurs within 1,000 feet of, a sensitive location.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC265D550FCC94A3E938574F9CA7F2A2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Travel to and from sensitive locations</header><text>For purposes of this section, an immigration enforcement action shall be considered to occur at a sensitive location if such action is taken while an individual is traveling to, attending, or returning from a sensitive location.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8B75797C14CD44D8A22CBB91AAF7A3F2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Exception for criminal warrants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The restrictions under sections 3 and 4 may not be construed to prohibit or restrict enforcement actions conducted pursuant to a criminal arrest warrant or a criminal search warrant issued by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text></section>
<section id="H2CDA18DF6B89438C8289E0BAE0BC08D7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Remedies for violations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the event of a violation of section 4—</text> <paragraph id="H5BD15A9039B7403695634CDF4361855F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any information obtained as a result of such enforcement action for purposes of establishing alienage or chargeability may not be—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A721B7B37E34D74AE6E48C6DD893BF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entered into the record or received into evidence in a removal proceeding; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H447A7234436E4CEF86F6632D0C1D432E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used by the Department to effectuate any type of removal;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5DB27DA94C724E309366C98B3F163E57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the noncitizen who was the subject of such removal proceedings may file a motion to enforce the prohibition under section 4, including through a motion to terminate such proceedings;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74D9BA2FF01F4C329CFCD5CAC0661D55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any individual who was detained in violation of such section shall be released from detention; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA7C387AA19F240CCB7695C856490FCB5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any person wrongfully detained shall be placed in section 240 proceedings, which require the Department to rebut the presumption of the individual's eligibility for release by clear and convincing evidence.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

