<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9F66F2FEEE964C3094CFCDDF42A474B9" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1351 IH: Impeaching Eleanor Louise Ross, Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1351</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Eleanor Louise Ross, Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFB1E48B857C641F0B03D5F39AD428B0E"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA7B617C0E1054BA093FE7FC156FECCA4"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Eleanor Louise Ross, a Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following articles of impeachment be exhibited to the Senate.</text></section> <section id="H0F9375B4C1374B1CA267E681B6A1E0F4" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Articles of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and all of the people of the United States of America, against Eleanor Louise Ross, a judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against her for high crimes and misdemeanors.</text></section> 
<section id="H96F40BACCC2046028E39E9A7E9C83B76" section-type="undesignated-section"><header>Article I</header></section> 
<section id="H9CD952220CC547B5B182D0C21EF4592B" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Incident to her position as a United States District Court Judge, Eleanor Louise Ross has engaged in conduct with respect to improper sexual activity in chambers with a law enforcement officer that is incompatible with the trust and confidence placed in her as a judge, as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HE05DE94B08A3499B8985BFBD87AE759A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a period of roughly 2 years, from around October 2023 through October 2025, Judge Ross participated in an extramarital affair with high-ranking Atlanta Police Department officer, Kelley Collier.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6954E31E480940879A29AE26B33AA96C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Collier was undoubtedly involved in numerous criminal and civil cases being litigated in the Northern District of Georgia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77684CEAEEE24C1F9FD85401C38B1F5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross did not disclose the affair to any other judge, court staff member, or litigating party.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAA97497336B41A0A4B4E157EF548019"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The undisclosed affair created the possibility that Judge Ross would be assigned to handle a case in which Mr. Collier or his employing police department had an interest, thus creating or appearing to create a conflict of interest.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24E2F877B63C4057AA3615BCF10A06A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Further, Judge Ross and Mr. Collier, while in Judge Ross’ chambers and during business hours, engaged in intimate contact, including, by admission of Judge Ross, sexual intercourse.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EAA887079FE4792A5E8C1CB90B729FB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 3 of Judge Ross’ former clerks heard sounds resulting from the intimate contact coming from Judge Ross’ chambers, thereby adversely affecting those staff members.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5590ECF414C45309E3472BFB80F8A91"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross’ conduct regarding the relationship demonstrated a gross lack of judgment and created an uncomfortable and troubling workplace for staff members.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H372637C0B3414570B7F160881AF3D0C1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Moreover, the undisclosed affair left Judge Ross vulnerable to extortion, as the Officer's spouse and Judge Ross' spouse were both unaware of the relationship, and the relationship could be used as leverage against a sitting Federal judge.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFC8F03511714C0FA48113A2B250BFA1"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross’ behavior violated multiple provisions of the Code of Conduct for United States Judges, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D291B593E5A434BA727442A50726A94"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canon 2, which provides that <quote>a judge should avoid impropriety and the appearance of impropriety in all activities</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC657729889704459B5FD7EEDF35ABE4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canon 2(A), which adds that <quote>A judge should respect and comply with the law and should act at all times in a manner that promotes public confidence in the integrity and impartiality of the judiciary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7DA19F05F43847C1BB0B8D73DC16A8B9">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the commentary to Canon 2(A), which further explains that <quote>public confidence in the judiciary is eroded by irresponsible or improper conduct by judges, including harassment and other inappropriate workplace behavior</quote>.</text>
                </subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB994EF539DC046CBA9D0EC2A14674C49" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Judge Eleanor Louise Ross is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office.</text></section> <section id="H325BF535E2C7480CB83954241C0DF3EF" section-type="undesignated-section"><header>Article II</header></section> <section id="H6C54E4A2BF9B4BC0928E4316F95543F9" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eleanor Louise Ross engaged in judicial misconduct by attending a partisan political event, as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDC5881F14C4A49C5BC0DC5E26624084F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross attended an event hosted by Fulton County District Attorney Fani Willis’ campaign, as conceded by Judge Ross during the investigation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C416172A7AB4520A66DC7C0C1D2A29A"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross attended the event the evening before she was scheduled to preside over a criminal revocation proceeding in her own courtroom.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BEECE5D02324048BAE52CB211B1227C">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following morning, Judge Ross stated to court interns and staff that she had consumed <quote>too many martinis</quote> the night before at an event hosted by the district attorney's campaign.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95F4311ED6244636931AC77AF87CCD2A">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross violated the Code of Conduct for United States Judges, including—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H414A934306AC445EB5011156179000CF">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canon 5, which states that <quote>a judge should refrain from political activity</quote>; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H8399744C14944D52A8B6C1D222AD1A0A">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canon 5(A)(1)(3), which explicitly prohibits a judge from attending <quote>a dinner or other event sponsored by a political organization or candidate</quote> and a <quote>political organization</quote> includes <quote>a group affiliated with a political party or candidate for public office</quote>.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE433C092CF7B4279985D37EB3B029DA4" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Judge Eleanor Louise Ross is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office.</text></section> <section id="H042FC6146D144A938582FB147DB321FB" section-type="undesignated-section"><header>Article III</header></section> <section id="HC909A31F5A3D4595B5D9DAA520BAE2BB" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eleanor Louise Ross corruptly obstructed, influenced, or impeded an official proceeding, as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA69D89327191459AB8845E3D2EF82BE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In September 2025, the Chief Circuit Judge of the Eleventh Circuit received a complaint against Judge Ross based on a memorandum received from the Chief District Judge of Judge Ross’ court that suggested possible misconduct by Judge Ross.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6B48074D99F43D0A3113BE1CF1E58F3"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 29, 2025, the Chief Circuit Judge notified Judge Ross of the report made by the Chief District Judge and requested that Judge Ross respond to the allegations in the Chief District Judge’s memo no later than October 20, 2025.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78C01130528446E3955E4D511BEBA3CB">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Later the same day, Judge Ross submitted a response that denied each allegation and characterized the allegations as <quote>outrageous</quote> and <quote>baseless</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BB4ECC748EF420DA0A131DA38D7808D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The same day, Judge Ross also sent an email to the Chief District Judge denying the allegations and denying that Judge Ross knew the identity of the alleged visitor to her chambers.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BDA855EF993465F82AF002DBB7CA6C1">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 30, 2025, after receiving Judge Ross’ response, the Chief Circuit Judge appointed a special committee to investigate the allegations in the complaint. The special committee subsequently retained experienced counsel to assist in conducting the investigation.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC798011DE8CE4CE0B4F90FC5CC3CFEB0">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The special committee found that Judge Ross made numerous, material false statements to the Chief Circuit Judge and the Chief District Judge when initially responding to the allegations.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BD23F60E16541F9AAA8C751840F47A1">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specifically, Judge Ross falsely stated <quote>I have never engaged in sexual intercourse in my office, nor anywhere else in the Courthouse</quote>. Judge Ross further falsely stated that she was <quote>not sure who this allegation concerns or whether it is alleged to have occurred with different individuals</quote> and that she was <quote>astounded and confused, and have no idea what this clerk is referring to</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAD4DDCB6AB4429CB3E8D3C5602458D1">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross did not recant these false statements until October 10, 2025, 11 days after making them, by which time the special committee had already gathered significant corroborating evidence. The special committee found that Judge Ross' recantation came only after she likely knew her false statements had been, or were about to be, exposed, and declined to treat the recantation as absolution.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D02A6B7BAFB4664AC612BDD36F31A8B">
                <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule 4(a)(5) of the Judicial-Conduct Rules states that cognizable misconduct includes <quote>refusing, without good cause shown, to cooperate in the investigation of a complaint</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F584C3C77924E1EA60ABF81CCB8EE07">
                <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Ross’ failure to truthfully respond to Chief Judge Pryor’s inquiry constituted a failure to cooperate in the investigation of the complaint and thus an instance of cognizable judicial misconduct.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14BB8D03B1084C64BD22B02961892415">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not only did Judge Ross fail to fulfill her duty to self-report under Rule 4(a)(6), but her false statements to Chief Judge Pryor and to the Chief District Judge constituted affirmative attempts to prevent the Chief Judges from learning of her misconduct, thereby obstructing the judicial conduct process established by Congress.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71E2215B7BED4EB784F40372E570BEA4">
                <enum>(12)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Further, under Section 1001 of Title 18, United States Code (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1001">18 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>), it is a felony to <quote>knowingly and willfully</quote> make <quote>any materially false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation</quote> on any <quote>matter within the jurisdiction of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch</quote> of the Federal Government.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD972DCC4B02C4DB7957F5A9D5AA32B4E">
                <enum>(13)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making numerous, material false statements to the Chief Circuit Judge and the Chief District Judge, Judge Ross' conduct would constitute a felony in violation of 18 U.S.C. 1001 in any other Federal context, reflecting the gravity of the misconduct and the degree to which it subverted the integrity of an official proceeding.</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB2330750EE93465EBAE8591027D2AC99" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Judge Eleanor Louise Ross is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

