<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H6ADA25A0D2E9457ABD5B4CA0DE453CED" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1068 IH: Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 143) enabling Congress to advance important policies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1068</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 143) enabling Congress to advance important policies.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5D2C0EA62B674EC3B3DDF75DCE5EBD1A">
<section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5ADA25A0D2E9457ABD5B4CA0DE453CED"><text>That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 143) enabling Congress to advance important policies. All points of order against consideration of the joint resolution are waived. An amendment in the nature of a substitute received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII dated at least one day before the day of consideration of the joint resolution, if submitted by the ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted. If more than one such amendment is submitted, then only the last amendment submitted shall be considered as adopted. The joint resolution, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the joint resolution, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the majority leader and minority leader or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section> <section id="H4ADA25A0D2E9457ABD5B4CA0DE453CED"><enum>2.</enum><text>Upon passage of H.J. Res. 143, an amendment to the title of such joint resolution received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII dated at least one day before the day of consideration of the joint resolution, if submitted by the ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted. If more than one such amendment to the title is submitted, then only the last amendment to the title submitted shall be considered as adopted.</text></section>
<section id="H3ADA25A0D2E9457ABD5B4CA0DE453CED"><enum>3.</enum><text>Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H.J. Res. 143.</text></section> <section id="H6ADA25A0D2E9457ABD5B4CA0DE463CED"><enum>4.</enum><text>The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.J. Res. 143 no later than three calendar days after passage.</text></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


