<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25990-VJL-DK-FCN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 505 IS: Recognizing the success of the Memphis Safe Task Force.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 505</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the success of the Memphis Safe Task Force.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Memphis, Tennessee, is a historic city that is full of iconic landmarks including Beale Street, Graceland, and the Memphis Pyramid;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, due to its central geographic location, Memphis serves as one of the transportation and logistics hubs of America, connecting much of the United States by rail, air, road, and water;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 1973, Memphis has served as the hub of the largest cargo airline in the world, Federal Express;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas crucial events of the civil rights movement and the fight for justice for all occurred in Memphis, including the 1968 strike by sanitation workers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 1962, Memphis has been home to St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital, which has provided treatment to children with cancer or other life-threatening diseases at no cost to families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the city of Memphis has experienced an unacceptable level of violent crime over the last few years and has been ranked nationally as one of the most dangerous cities in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to data from the Federal Bureau of Investigation, Memphis in 2024 had the highest rate of violent crime per capita, including some of the highest per capita rates of murder, robbery, aggravated assault, and carjacking;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump made a commitment to the American people to restore law and order in cities throughout the United States and to <quote>Make America Safe Again</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the summer of 2025, the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and component agencies launched <quote>Operation Viper</quote> in Memphis, an ongoing FBI mission in Memphis that resulted in nearly 500 arrests of the most violent offenders;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 15, 2025, President Trump signed a Presidential memorandum entitled <quote>Restoring Law and Order in Memphis,</quote> establishing the Memphis Safe Task Force;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Memphis Safe Task Force is a joint Federal task force that, in close coordination with State and local agencies, has the objective of combating and reducing violent crime, aggressively prosecuting criminal defendants, and making Memphis once again a safe place to live and raise a family;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in a little more than 50 days, the Memphis Safe Task Force has yielded tremendous results for the people of Memphis, including—</text><paragraph id="id31df8b596c744e8eb4e5cb3b45e7bb28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nearly 3,000 arrests, including the arrests of more than 300 known gang members;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0e761f031034b34b34dc14cba3bfb46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>over 450 illegal firearms seized; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66ee3026f0744417a7a6e74cd5c02f1f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>over 100 missing children found;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the Federal law enforcement surge in the summer of 2025, violent crime in Memphis has plummeted, with historically low levels of homicide, aggravated assault, and carjacking;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Memphis Safe Task Force will serve as a national model for President Trump’s broader mission to reduce violent crime in many of the Nation’s largest cities, including Chicago, Los Angeles, and Portland;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, thanks to President Trump’s bold leadership and the diligent and coordinated efforts of 13 Federal, State, and local agencies, the city of Memphis is on track to be one of the safest cities in America; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Memphis Safe Task Force will remain in operation for the foreseeable future, making clear that Memphis’s best days lie ahead: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id211c84c39db74200832c9244e5c1137f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the monumental success that has already been achieved because of the Memphis Safe Task Force and President Donald J. Trump’s decisive leadership; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida083af9bbe8741b39c3af2b6eba00996"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends President Trump, the most pro-law enforcement President in the history of the United States, for his work to make America safe again.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

