<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E2762C5FF854143864BF76BE843C18B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6187 IH: Wojnovich Pipeline Safety Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6187</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration to establish a grant program to facilitate the improved safety and modernization of hazardous liquid distribution infrastructure, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEB04FE5DDED1418DA82425F5247DDFDD" style="OLC"><section id="H21AD7C31AD0B4C47A974C05AE089A991" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wojnovich Pipeline Safety Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H40CA39F4EED04E1D9EC1EDD19CC2F35A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hazardous liquid distribution infrastructure safety and modernization grant program</header><subsection id="H848CBF10D3504923AC1936F7D83254B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration shall establish a grant program to facilitate the improved safety and modernization of hazardous liquid distribution infrastructure.</text></subsection><subsection id="H83CCE94F09CF4CA3A2D903856F4990B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><paragraph id="H506A1A8D9A444705B5C90BF7C8FA4566"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant to—</text><subparagraph id="H1F8C459D07594C28B2DE1105A9478988"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a municipality in a State that carries out the disclosures described in section 4; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F430056FB244407A11061C07981C307"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a community-owned utility that is not a for-profit entity in such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB39E5BD3A13C4B08B19B92A3E52854D6"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Public-Private partnerships</header> <text>An eligible recipient described in paragraph (1) may engage in public-private partnerships while carrying out a project using funds provided under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81F5D42FE1934BC39EF26FB66F009562"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of eligible projects</header><paragraph id="H8BC62EE0CCDF4C0891FA2A55E4B8E768"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of funding opportunity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which funds are made available to carry out the program, the Secretary shall publish a notice of funding opportunity for the funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98CEDA557C174033B4086844CEDF7CA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a procedure for awarding grants that takes into consideration—</text><subparagraph id="HF22BE103DF344600ABDD2D63BCDDC60B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the risk profile of the existing pipeline system operated by the applicant, including the presence of pipe prone to leakage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE64419B49CE4662AFCE068A75C25E84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the potential of the project for creating jobs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05C15AFE3152421FA5ED1D7A2F623CB3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>economic impact or growth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5276911C9F36474FA722AF9670825935" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Awards</header><paragraph id="H704C32967DFE42138F00B5BBA166D9AB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of funding opportunity</header><text>Not later than 180 days after each date on which the funds to carry out this section are made available, the Secretary shall issue a notice of funding opportunity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA560F499F3164D7CA2258AF95A1B7339" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Not later than 270 days after issuing a notices of funding opportunity under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall make awards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B1EBB9F2E304AE5A82F6DC2BB835E03" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall award not more than 12.5 percent of the funds available under this program to a single municipality or community-owned utility.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H413822341CCC430A9E987E320AB641E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H2D4E48218967433FA7F21E4C2C549F0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100 million for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7049730D57CD470BB9788FB436B10F02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 2 percent of the amounts made available each fiscal year to carry out this section may be used to pay the administrative costs of carrying out the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77C1B498A4CB4CA78EDEC68EF5D0BB39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inspector general oversight</header><text>The Secretary shall transfer one-half of one percent of the amounts provided to carry out this program in each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to the inspector general of the Department of Transportation for oversight of funding provided to the Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDB28231FE10E453BBAA12DB73A4A0DFE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Update website</header><subsection id="H65055F32F6144BBC9692832D490868C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall update the website of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration to increase the ease of use and public accessibility of the website.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFE3B2E18B0BD49B9A77B260A7793B6F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>In updating the website under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall require—</text><paragraph id="HB349613E410D4634AE00F93B980E6F63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>easily readable reporting of each accident and incident, including information on the details of such accident or incident; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEF9AFD67F34446DB2E9B4A176FF1D3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each accident or incident, a remediation status update to be provided by operators and posted on the website not less than every 90 days until the remediation is complete.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9D60F45396E0459F946995B6C0BA0802"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public notification and preparedness</header><subsection id="HF1C4EB87A73C4320BBF90A197B72D446"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Real estate disclosure</header><paragraph id="HE31B439A8DB8416B9D5A58630CACB163" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to participate in the grant program established under section 2, a State shall require each real estate contract to include the disclosure of any known hazardous liquid pipeline easements regulated by the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration that are within one-half mile of the boundary of the property subject to such contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7537662FF4754FD49409C2C442611B07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The notice shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H881581FC01CE4089965AB8472F353492"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and contact information of the operator;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69F7EFB47CCA450EBCB3D72B9CF207B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name of the pipeline and the substance in the pipeline;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5560C37B93946E19307B66116F8B994"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the pipeline has undergone repairs in the 10 years prior to the date of submission of the notice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0618564384E943BAAAF3726556E0154C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a list of any leaks, failures, accidents, or incidents the operator has had within the State in the last 10 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C43AA8771A54F178C3048B965FB2021"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration shall ensure the information required under paragraph (2) is collected and made publicly available on a website of the Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D5F840DD5DD4F498D931C2AF171BE4A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency response plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 60102(d)(5) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0CEDA7BB6CD042DE9EF015A0C26C7E23" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9271C60AF424B789504462F08436D62" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H09FD46EA392F45C6902CDE8C24194DA9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HB26ED30EFBF747D9B12B1D0AE1FCDF2A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community involvement strategy detailing how the operator will inform and liaise with landowners and homeowners impacted by a release; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2382732301149849211892BC71953C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Emergency alert system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule requiring each operator of a hazardous liquid pipeline facility to—</text><paragraph id="H023D423810904A1BB8C62DA083A6DBF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and maintain a localized emergency alert system to send an alert to communities within 1 mile of a pipeline of any leaks, failures, accidents, or incidents; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H553A20C1421C434E96BEEC202324D263"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish an agreement with each State in which the operator operates in which such State agrees to use an alert system of the State to send such alert.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EEB973645E2477487E53F274765980E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule that requires—</text><paragraph id="HD9ABCEC1CA5D47D6B6EEE7E46C9A3F83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a standard, timely process or procedure for pipeline operators to conduct in-person tests of water, soil, or air for potential pipeline leaks or failures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H356AC69165294476BE81D3328FC6CEE6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an in-person water test—</text><subparagraph id="H342873D9BE254037A3C1E52FDAC0D1EA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the test to be conducted on any well within one-half mile of a leak, accident, incident, or failure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDD58BC8DD894D638B550265E5B14A21" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>samples to be taken from both the top and the bottom of such well;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51DC65B92C4645909307EE678CCCEA58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>annual in-line inspection tool tests for pipelines older than 50 years or wherever a sleeve repair has been made; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H673A2054483A4922A128614615D4A695"><enum>(4)</enum><text>notifying impacted residents and landowners when a test comes back positive for contaminated water, soil, or air.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA546B6B30E0D41FE8F8FE11780FD3D38"><enum>5.</enum><header>Penalty for accident</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall levy a penalty in the amount of $2,500,000 against an operator of a hazardous liquid pipeline facility that declares a leak, accident, incident, or failure.</text><paragraph id="H25210796356740A9B15EE4BB86C6A231"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The penalty shall be levied on an annual basis until the Secretary certifies that such leak, accident, incident, or failure has been remediated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCF44D0F09BB4E9CB782963EDA426B78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Double penalty</header><text>In the case of any operator which does not declare a leak, accident, incident, or failure within 15 days of the operator knowing that such a leak, accident, incident, or failure has occurred, the penalty shall be in the amount of $5,000,000.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7C8C13DE57124BB38F5624B002CBD6CA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Emergency reimbursement</header><subsection id="HFC4550BD4DA94F388B9796219252E945"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration is provided a declaration by an operator of a hazardous liquid pipeline facility that an event has occurred, the Secretary shall make available funds to reimburse an eligible entity for the following:</text>
                                <paragraph id="H2944D2D43BFD4BAE94F42924B0564ED2">
                                        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The cost of replacing equipment that is damaged, contaminated, or otherwise rendered unusable as a result of the response of the eligible entity to an event.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H9088BAECE9DC42E18ACD73C6358BA13D">
                                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Overtime pay for firefighters, law enforcement officers, or other emergency responders who work at the scene of an event.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HD028CC5441314E9395D1CA5640F9B631">
                                        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Operational costs for actions taken to respond to an event.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H05F769B470F3472B81A54AEBA63C9010">
                                        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Any other purpose related to an event, as determined by the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H8EA511B4AEBB4528A3040A532B70DCB4">
                                        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>To retroactively cover a cost described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4) that is incurred after the date of an event or within 30 days of the receipt of amounts under this subsection.</text>
                                </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE0E0C5608B2D450FBD0A8518BFC3EB8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2708DAFD4B3F4E88B3240D9F5288663F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State or local emergency response group, including a law enforcement agency, a fire department, and an emergency response agency, located in an area affected by a hazardous train event.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34BF4DD06E894CA4BF8D9AADE4F698F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Event</header><text>The term <term>event</term> means a hazardous liquid pipeline leak, accident, incident, or failure.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDC639BBE3984771B16FCE76FD4BD278"><enum>7.</enum><header>Hazardous liquid pipeline community trust fund</header><subsection id="H41BA83348954433EAED176399CADE04F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Treasury of the United States a fund which shall be known as the <quote>Hazardous Liquid Pipeline Community Trust Fund</quote> and which shall be administered by the Secretary of Transportation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1990441698E475B8BF0C9CF537213F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>Penalties collected pursuant to section 5 of this Act shall be deposited into the Hazardous Liquid Pipeline Community Trust Fund established in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDC27AFD13F5D400BA87EFAE4357131E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disbursement</header><text>The Secretary shall make disbursements from the Trust Fund to carry out sections 2 and 6 of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H452750B4DE3A4C11A9A6633CF0E645C4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Quarterly report on industry knowledge</header><subsection id="H43FDA93601614C25B65CCA58BA557247"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration shall deliver to the appropriate congressional committees a report which details industry knowledge or developments regarding hazardous liquid pipeline safety and integrity.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB005F054557C44C69F97AC418718F08C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incorporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make every reasonable effort to incorporate relevant knowledge or developments regarding safety and integrity from each quarterly report into the regulations, guidance, recommendations, advisories, or notices of the Administration.</text></subsection></section><section id="H671DF6EE1BCE4F6FB12657BE4AAE5891"><enum>9.</enum><header>Office of Public Engagement</header><subsection id="H8720391CE4004F2EA853A683E1225395"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall rename the Community Liaison Services within the Office of Pipeline Safety of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration as the Office of Public Engagement (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9178B1F9F62A4952B68A25D10952FCAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Office are to—</text><paragraph id="H1112B166375240BEAE1B8410E3AD7D35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proactively engage with pipeline stakeholders, including the public, pipeline operators, public safety organizations, and State, local, and Tribal government officials, to raise awareness of pipeline safety practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D3A967ECFF24353A3938F7EF1C99D15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote the adoption and increased use of safety programs and activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14B14E0D57674F138376012A7BCDE446"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inform the public of pipeline safety regulations and best practices; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD887F3AA81394A648C47F520D0B14FC4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assist the public with inquiries regarding pipeline safety.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C50A8AB06B8456D8E5A856D110D5ABB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public accessibility</header><text>The Office shall ensure that activities carried out by the Office and information products developed by the Office are accessible to the public.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA9F0805C125A4F54B1AB4A60D4DBADB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Community liaisons</header><paragraph id="H01D923F8B5224DEE90F8ACC8CD8A9E3E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Office shall incorporate positions known as <quote>community liaisons</quote> under the Community Liaison Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD132068D01424D6CA413FA013A4FEF8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Meeting inclusion</header><text>For the purposes of formulating a proposed safety order case, the Administrator shall make every reasonable effort to include a community liaison in each meeting or separately provide the community liaison with a detailed update of each proposed safety order case meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3501D77E54B54F71AA3DEFEA5EFF1FCE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

