<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HE6FAACE8C46648CBA19A0B08C0762B07" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1156 EH: Expressing support for tax policies that support working families.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1156</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Expressing support for tax policies that support working families.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 4, 2025, the President signed <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>, commonly known as the <quote>Working Families Tax Cuts</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts prevented a $2,600,000,000,000 tax hike on taxpayers making less than $400,000 per year;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, for the 2025 tax year, the Working Families Tax Cuts helped deliver an estimated $222,000,000,000 in tax refunds, putting money directly back into Americans’ wallets;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, for the 2026 tax year, the Working Families Tax Cuts are anticipated to deliver an average tax cut of $3,750, helping make America affordable again;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts ensure that families of four making under $73,000 will generally face zero Federal income tax liability;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts will result in a 15 percent tax cut for Americans whose income is in the bottom 40 percent, with the largest percentage reduction going to the bottom 20 percent;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the share of total income taxes paid by Americans whose income is in the top 1 percent will increase to nearly 40 percent as a result of the Working Families Tax Cuts, while the share paid by Americans in the remaining 99 percent will decrease to 60 percent;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts enacted <quote>no tax on tips</quote>, which will provide millions of tipped workers with $32,000,000,000 of tax relief;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts enacted <quote>no tax on overtime</quote>, which will provide hard-working Americans with a $90,000,000,000 tax cut on their overtime pay;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts provide a new deduction for interest on auto loans for new American-made vehicles, lowering costs and helping more Americans get behind the wheel;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts honor a lifetime of hard work by American seniors by providing them with a deduction of up to $6,000 per year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, to date, nearly 45 percent of tax returns filed this tax season have claimed at least one of these four new tax cuts;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts help jump-start the American dream for millions of youth by making a down payment of over $15,000,000,000 in tax-advantaged investment accounts for American children;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts permanently increase the standard deduction, delivering $205,000,000,000 in new tax relief to the 90 percent of earners who claim it;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts permanently expand the child tax credit, increasing the maximum credit amount to $2,200 per child and ensuring that the credit will not lose value due to inflation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts expands the accessibility of the $17,280 adoption tax credit so that all families who adopt, regardless of income, can benefit;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts expands educational freedom and choice for working families by ensuring 529 accounts can now cover costs associated with trade schools or K–12 educational expenses; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Working Families Tax Cuts expands access to health savings accounts for more than 10 million Americans to help control health care costs and promotes preventive care by allowing patients to pair these accounts with innovative direct primary care and easier access to telehealth: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H30DD7014B51643B491884F554C446AAA">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H55E507D3EB034B79A85319F41860A1FB"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H7BB5E917EE354766826CD57F7E5FEA46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses its support for tax policies that support working families and let them keep more of their hard-earned money; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE60205EC39EC4B7A8D42E73016D1A293"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the significant tax relief provided by the Working Families Tax Cuts for hardworking Americans.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

