<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCBBD7D83374A4F7EB447C4450BFEC54E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7590 IH: Protecting Student Athletes from Concussions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7590</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260217">February 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote minimum State requirements for the prevention and treatment of concussions caused by participation in school sports, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F9FFB42488E4F15BA15CE3B85683959" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H405A3C5F30694D9BBBECC24539AB9E11"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Student Athletes from Concussions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5E3C0C5E801A4FEB888F97EB6D312061"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimum State requirements</header> <subsection id="H98E0D1DF77174C7DAD70CBF4BA92230D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State that receives funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) and does not meet the requirements described in this section, as of the date of enactment of this Act, shall, not later than the last day of the fifth full fiscal year after the date of enactment of this Act (referred to in this Act as the <quote>compliance deadline</quote>), enact legislation or issue regulations establishing the following minimum requirements:</text>
<paragraph id="H8225070A80284C42AA0A47638BCF9F2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agency concussion safety and management plan</header><text>Each local educational agency in the State, in consultation with members of the community in which such agency is located, shall develop and implement a standard plan for concussion safety and management that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2942067240346A7B5F26B80D6B459F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educates students, parents, and school personnel about concussions, through activities such as—</text>
<clause id="HB4424FBD61D04F7D82F387EC83E067BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>training school personnel, including coaches, teachers, athletic trainers, related services personnel, and school nurses, on concussion safety and management, including training on the prevention, recognition, and academic consequences of concussions and response to concussions; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0E9C2A1452674D658704FDF900E3F2DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using, maintaining, and disseminating to students and parents—</text>
<subclause id="H3E65E70C64B84116B93CD6698A7675B5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>release forms and other appropriate forms for reporting and record keeping;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3DBE50752AB044D49D5F72765A245E8C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>treatment plans; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HF0FD3394F1B645B9874A1599849BDEC6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>prevention and post-injury observation and monitoring fact sheets about concussion;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED3A17F93FBC4AABAC7A8696786FB1D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourages supports, where feasible, for a student recovering from a concussion (regardless of whether or not the concussion occurred during school-sponsored activities, during school hours, on school property, or during an athletic activity), such as—</text>
<clause id="H1A10C3A12D814B87BB228F2571AAD739"><enum>(i)</enum><text>guiding the student in resuming participation in athletic activity and academic activities with the help of a multi-disciplinary concussion management team, which may include—</text> <subclause id="H51B6E2DDAFAA49A292A1151EFE7EE624"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a health care professional, the parents of such student, a school nurse, relevant related services personnel, and other relevant school personnel; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H57A43C5688834D709FCD9820CA0D6F3A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an individual who is assigned by a public school to oversee and manage the recovery of such student;</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H2FC61D990FD141DA90D5A3E0D9AC0F0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing appropriate academic accommodations aimed at progressively reintroducing cognitive demands on the student; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21C9CAF9C17B48228F0C859181F8C58D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the student’s symptoms of concussion persist for a substantial period of time—</text> <subclause id="HAAD19DB8949349AAB9C4AA72422566E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>evaluating the student in accordance with section 614 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1414">20 U.S.C. 1414</external-xref>) to determine whether the student is eligible for services under part B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1411">20 U.S.C. 1411 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H2AFF33A7702A4112B231B0BD41877215"><enum>(II)</enum><text>evaluating whether the student is eligible for services under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>); and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3298200174214CC8984A1C1773836AD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encourages the use of best practices designed to ensure, with respect to concussions, the uniformity of safety standards, treatment, and management, such as—</text>
<clause id="H931D1894F6BA404C883761919F24582A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disseminating information on concussion safety and management to the public; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1ECDC069B5C44F498C34FC4D56D37D2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applying uniform best practice standards for concussion safety and management to all students enrolled in public schools.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4BF85CD3ABF04A1CBDBFD593A010BE4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Posting of information on concussions</header><text>Each public elementary school and each public secondary school shall post on school grounds, in a manner that is visible to students and school personnel, and make publicly available on the school website, information on concussions that—</text> <subparagraph id="H47A68145FD604340A5AA96930AD1B17B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is based on peer-reviewed scientific evidence (such as information made available by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDBF3D13FF00B46AF9A56091E4F079ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include information on—</text> <clause id="H9C579111CE574A0D92B97F0DE10D211F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the risks posed by sustaining a concussion;</text></clause>
<clause id="H32CE182C5F50452F9E1A36E5367465E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the actions a student should take in response to sustaining a concussion, including the notification of school personnel; and</text></clause> <clause id="H14CAC0F433E34440ADDC668EDBE8E087"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the signs and symptoms of a concussion; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5D5989185924F7DA5634DC967609C0C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may include information on—</text> <clause id="H2A58F5539FD54B4FAA36CE3EA4E7DDB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the definition of a concussion;</text></clause>
<clause id="H58A2022BA6DD4DC1846FFF566B0D7296"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the means available to the student to reduce the incidence or recurrence of a concussion; and</text></clause> <clause id="H019E141B05B04EB7BAAC5FF4EE42837A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effects of a concussion on academic learning and performance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1438E91378D44F0FBB10CA7D5A3D3ECF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Response to concussion</header><text>If an individual designated from among school personnel for purposes of this Act, one of whom must be in attendance at every school-sponsored activity, suspects that a student has sustained a concussion (regardless of whether or not the concussion occurred during school-sponsored activities, during school hours, on school property, or during an athletic activity)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3108C5601A6A4C47AC2751FCAA8F9F69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the student shall be—</text>
<clause id="HC073AFE971EA4B10874AA26C35614550"><enum>(i)</enum><text>immediately removed from participation in a school-sponsored athletic activity; and</text></clause> <clause id="H353D7E9C0EFB4000AA8797114AAF456A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prohibited from resuming participation in school-sponsored athletic activities—</text>
<subclause id="HDC732066D99D4934935612DABEA1155E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on the day the student sustained the concussion; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAF2EAC30C54344C2819E3D837E560040"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">until the day the student is capable of resuming such participation, according to the student’s written release, as described in paragraph (4); and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDC192D97920B47B78B93BFB1F252A8F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the designated individual shall report to the parent or guardian of such student—</text> <clause id="H94CF6300017444BAB93C55FBFBCD1A26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any information that the designated school employee is aware of regarding the date, time, and type of the injury suffered by such student (regardless of where, when, or how a concussion may have occurred); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HB28A68CCE74B47E1ABC7F58D5779C706"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any actions taken to treat such student.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2F90A3E9C8548E09FE6D037DAB0BFAC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Return to athletics</header><text>If a student has sustained a concussion (regardless of whether or not the concussion occurred during school-sponsored activities, during school hours, on school property, or during an athletic activity), before such student resumes participation in school-sponsored athletic activities, the school shall receive a written release from a health care professional, that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBC36CBEF44E346DB9F4E2D9C8F79EA24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>states that the student is capable of resuming participation in such activities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0D9FF0A642B4A29AF1193133C2773C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may require the student to follow a plan designed to aid the student in recovering and resuming participation in such activities in a manner that—</text>
<clause id="H9A4DB4FFB4534CEFB4DB087032AA5221"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is coordinated, as appropriate, with periods of cognitive and physical rest while symptoms of a concussion persist; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFA1BE722B8124AB5942488559AFC612E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reintroduces cognitive and physical demands on such student on a progressive basis only as such increases in exertion do not cause the reemergence or worsening of symptoms of a concussion.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1BAE1BC3DAC644DB822F7A3ED0420BEF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Return to academics</header><text>If a student enrolled in a public school in the State has sustained a concussion, the concussion management team (as described under paragraph (1)(B)(i)) of the school shall consult with and make recommendations to relevant school personnel and the student to ensure that the student is receiving the appropriate academic supports, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HC4CE6907A4224BC2B358016C6901E58C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing for periods of cognitive rest over the course of the school day;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6AD1CB8C16EF4365BBC1ABD819E1393B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing modified academic assignments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83A2C73DA6044272ADAA30CCD0F247EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allowing for gradual reintroduction to cognitive demands; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB386D65AD6DF4D3C9A2C2F7964C78AFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other appropriate academic accommodations or adjustments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H4DA71BE5A84C436DAF2FAF7D1C06DBA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA5B8A51623654E3EBE9BB40DBDE90BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First year</header><text>If a State described in subsection (a) fails to comply with subsection (a) by the compliance deadline, the Secretary of Education shall reduce by 5 percent the amount of funds the State receives under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) for the first fiscal year following the compliance deadline.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC0F9645AB84840ECA588C1CAB916701F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Succeeding years</header><text>If the State fails to so comply by the last day of any fiscal year following the compliance deadline, the Secretary of Education shall reduce by 10 percent the amount of funds the State receives under that Act for the following fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1E4A2D28903640859CB7418468F1357E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification of noncompliance</header><text>Prior to reducing any funds that a State receives under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) in accordance with this subsection, the Secretary of Education shall provide a written notification of the intended reduction of funds to the State and to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H11DB106F72D9481198CF972F13F91747"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect civil or criminal liability under Federal or State law.</text></section> <section id="HE35C51E8A394447185532224AB8870E4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H345B1CC392874F9284FA64851CCDFD2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Concussion</header><text>The term <term>concussion</term> means a type of mild traumatic brain injury that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEF5B105D343A4EB199669CC821B1E408"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is caused by a blow, jolt, or motion to the head or body that causes the brain to move rapidly in the skull;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H63DDBF7920E844D29BED3BA7BB772F1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disrupts normal brain functioning and alters the mental state of the individual, causing the individual to experience—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H4346C37708194C42BDAA25A044D35B7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any period of observed or self-reported—</text>
<subclause id="H677B2E934E8D4DA1A47BC33666FE6396"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transient confusion, disorientation, or impaired consciousness;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB9681BB2A01741D78985579125B5CD80"><enum>(II)</enum><text>dysfunction of memory around the time of injury; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H71B61E7D5AC54E49843486915FDAEA9A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>loss of consciousness lasting less than 30 minutes; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H94FB4EBC393D4980A00CA2B1CA0659DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any 1 of 4 types of symptoms, including—</text>
<subclause commented="no" id="H91E24A0CB5154718B76DB7A71D1E05E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>physical symptoms, such as headache, fatigue, or dizziness;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H015ED279DA7B484792A30D4BDA21C358"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cognitive symptoms, such as memory disturbance or slowed thinking;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H8DC28471F59E4AAB9DE25E28ECA762A5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>emotional symptoms, such as irritability or sadness; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H52E35EECDC4841448445DB069A6C0B0F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>difficulty sleeping; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H7BF0E4DB26F74FA79F38BBAD41C9B689"><enum>(C)</enum><text>can occur—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HF601CA2E762E4A74ACD58AD048C2952F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with or without the loss of consciousness; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HF5BCD3FE34534BC48123B5DDDE7D2E88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during participation in any organized sport or recreational activity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF59FE3A407C24DF1B1F4C0167729D9AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care professional</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health care professional</term> means an individual—</text>
<subparagraph id="H96A5C51936C4415F87AA0B2F51BF008D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has been trained in diagnosis and management of concussion in a pediatric population;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF6162D888A14BD2993B653403E087C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is registered, licensed, certified, or otherwise statutorily recognized by the State to provide such diagnosis and management; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5E2AF8D5026C40B081B3B432EA3ACAA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whose scope of practice and experience includes the diagnosis and management of traumatic brain injury among a pediatric population.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12D65BFF7EAD4AE6BB9EFA9BA440B5D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local educational agency; State</header><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>State</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H82501C089E7D4B4582497B4FFEC09864"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Related Services Personnel</header><text>The term <term>related services personnel</term> means individuals who provide related services, as defined under section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EDA2F1AF427492D82D6638A84928C09"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School-sponsored athletic activity</header><text>The term <term>school-sponsored athletic activity</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE1B9408CEB3447A8B091846BAA86700A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any physical education class or program of a school;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6242F4050B964DF087B4739E7FE3E09C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any athletic activity authorized during the school day on school grounds that is not an instructional activity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3597FA0B2161471EB775109C32032486"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any extra-curricular sports team, club, or league organized by a school on or off school grounds; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB127CAC9EFF43B88E74BDC8F96D7E6F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any recess activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

