<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEEF7BEF757044885A7A1065AC045D0EA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6701 IH: Heat Emergency Assistance for Transportation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6701</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for emergency relief for repair or reconstruction of infrastructure damaged by extreme heat, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBB11356DD43046DEAB3C594DFCC8599D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H84B22B9590DE4ED39E571ABC00DD9419" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heat Emergency Assistance for Transportation Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEAT Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBDFA8C51953949FA89DA575F9A40ECEC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8E59523C1386445C9CDC1AA936752182"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Extreme heat, particularly heat waves, are an emerging threat to critical transportation infrastructure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB2E67E778DF4601B7E22C8DFF133F5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Extreme heat is damaging critical transportation infrastructure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HACE8611EB248487697EE2EF6F7E0145F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research indicates that high temperatures cause bridge expansion joints to crack or fail, accelerate the degradation of concrete and steel, and weaken structural integrity over time.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11EDF2FDA0174332911349383495B35C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Aging infrastructure is at heightened risk.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F78CFA43F87420CA6A2B500D474F10A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Assessments show more than 85,000 girder or movable bridges are over 50 years old in the United States, carrying 860 million vehicle crossings each day.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3446CD7876774FA491E56C6371A5641A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Many such bridges designed for historical conditions and are now experiencing stress beyond their original design.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBFA6DA8F6EC411A8588D28F8F4306A1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Movable bridges may face operational challenges, including breakdowns during heat waves.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11FC9904131D426AB361A2AC210B535F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Steel expansion during extreme heat can cause drawbridges and similar structures to jam or fail to close properly.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EB82706364F4558BAF9ECFE3C0FA420"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Emergency cooling measures, such as spraying bridges with water, have already been required in cities such as New York, Chicago, Portland, and Seattle.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD6791FEFA78454CA14D941CC0FF50F0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Extreme heat threatens economic continuity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39109A05233840D4A6DF0C71422F874A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Unplanned bridge closures and roadway restrictions caused by thermal stress interrupt freight movement, supply chains, and daily commuting, imposing significant costs on local economies and national productivity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFD4B36A0C83427F9E2614AB0CB6BBA8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Federal disaster programs omit extreme heat.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60ABD0ECB67F4D2AB074018DE9FB9F64"><enum>(13)</enum><text>While section 125 of title 23, United States Code, recognizes disasters such as flooding, severe storms, and wildfires, extreme heat is not explicitly identified as a qualifying event for Emergency Relief funding, despite its clear infrastructure consequences.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF59594C632A24E8DB349979D8644D736"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Communities can face disproportionate risks.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71376CCB789D415998D6EADC5E3C6C2B"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Rural areas and regions with limited redundancy in transportation networks are particularly at high risk, as heat-related transportation disruptions can isolate entire communities, delay emergency response, and endanger public safety.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF2DCC6C35D0F42FCB3E483382CC2BD3A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Emergency relief</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 125 of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF6FE2A5E625428D96B639DC63B1A6AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by inserting <quote>extreme heat,</quote> after <quote>severe storm,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9F161884A1544D3A30245D6995E9BFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b) by inserting <quote>This subsection shall not apply to a bridge with respect to which physical deterioration was substantially caused by extreme heat exposure.</quote> after the period at the end; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82D6D0742A4B4DA1A4C3A6B296A8E85C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>extreme weather, flooding, and other natural disasters</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>extreme weather, heat waves, flooding, and other natural disasters</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H55D9E3BB27564EC59256C2B690F32E60"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study on extreme heat events</header> <subsection id="HF63F4B040BED4DA5AD2D8F3A6FB1EB6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall enter into an agreement with the Transportation Research Board of the National Academies, in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation, shall conduct a study to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF684B2520EB4445F9BD341E1AD31A42B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the measurable costs of an extreme heat event, particularly long-duration, high intensity heat waves;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48F514DFD626409FA00F46AF576BF5EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide recommendations on how to track damage from extreme heat events, separate from regular deterioration over time; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E75B87CF53F4FA683FBBF3C95DFCDB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to examine how the Secretary may better assist State departments of transportation, public transit systems, Amtrak, freight rail systems, and other interested parties with tracking damage from extreme heat events.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0546A0598672493CBE1F7018DA663019"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the study under this section, the Transportation Research Board shall consult with the Secretary, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, State departments of transportation, public transit systems, Amtrak, freight rail systems, stakeholders with expertise in engineering and natural disaster management, and educational and technical groups in extreme heat and infrastructure safety.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5BF0FF2FADB450B995B09E4BA7366B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>The Transportation Research Board shall submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report detailing the results of the study under this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H04F344D7E602470282C94309BECDE442"><enum>5.</enum><header>Best management practices report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue a best management practices report to reflect new information and advancements in highway and bridge safety as related to extreme heat.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

