<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" slc-id="S1-HEN25E03-3S6-72-R12">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 532 PCS: Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
<calendar>Executive Calendar No. 4</calendar>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. RES. 532</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was ordered to lie over, under the rule</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>EXECUTIVE RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" id="H6588ACF116D4487BB0EB832A8A483074">
<section commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5A8A37B616754C00BF9B72B9E5A6BF5B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it shall be in order to move to proceed to the en bloc consideration of the following nominations on the Executive Calendar:</text> <paragraph id="id3f06468763f24fb29284ec54f03b14ee"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Calendar Number 166: Henry Mack III, of Florida, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idfaca49088ff741ee90a83af2e6b87c05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Calendar Number 267: James Percival, of Florida, to be General Counsel, Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idb5dabf00c3b046b49658a544988cb202"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Calendar Number 354: Pedro Allende, of Florida, to be Under Secretary for Science and Technology, Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9621d00d1cc9452ba0b1ed040f4ca4b9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Calendar Number 429: Michael Powers, of Virginia, to be Deputy Under Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idd1b6e9daee5a41ae8bb680d514ae965d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Calendar Number 430: Benjamin Kohlmann, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Navy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id8bf9e62d3dbe41cdaa7b4aa7d7e6b747"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Calendar Number 431: Amy Henninger, of Virginia, to be Director of Operational Test and Evaluation, Department of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idb96ab41d41884c7b8f76e5d61194c272"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Calendar Number 432: David Denton, Jr., of Virginia, to be General Counsel of the Department of the Navy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id52acce71c937444d861e0fdf4f6d552f"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Calendar Number 452: Benjamin Hobbs, of Ohio, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5faafe611aca4d0588f961e40c12cac3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Calendar Number 453: Ronald Kurtz, of Georgia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id562bd5bed1e44a14bf7540cf5590545e"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Calendar Number 454: Jonathan Burke, of Georgia, to be Assistant Secretary for Terrorist Financing, Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ida93d60ce4f354648bed92ed2f281bb10"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Calendar Number 455: Chris Pilkerton, of Maryland, to be Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Investment Security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id86a169bffa0246d58991b036b34d50b5"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Calendar Number 456: David Courcelle, of Louisiana, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Louisiana for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id02583a35321d4ece8a2db2b266deb797"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Calendar Number 461: Jeremiah Workman, of Ohio, to be Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans' Employment and Training.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id5a16865c73ee40bf80ce18c3dd122947"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Calendar Number 462: Derek Theurer, of Virginia, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id0c70137745c249adaecd9dac3f3c3953"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Calendar Number 463: Jonathan Greenstein, of New York, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ida39e135b2e4f425ea8e6500086c94c53"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Calendar Number 465: Crystal Carey, of New Jersey, to be General Counsel of the National Labor Relations Board for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idde3f1d7836d84b759700eccc3871bb85"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Calendar Number 466: Rosario Palmieri, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id2b4c3c2ff2f74491808c784ed4710b6a"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Calendar Number 467: James Murphy, of Maryland, to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board for the term of 5 years expiring December 16, 2027.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idc0882d4e9e6e4e688b579630dc2885bb"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Calendar Number 468: Kirsten Davies, of Tennessee, to be Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id2e653ef7c0df4114b8182e5def3a50a2"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Calendar Number 469: Derrick Anderson, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id90c3e3217b224f2abc2160f2a6bdbd37"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Calendar Number 470: James Mazol, of Virginia, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9bbd925835f4489cb4f141f4daac3f84"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Calendar Number 477: Braden Boucek, of Tennessee, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of Tennessee for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ide205729d21304c448d4f2d850e2a6872"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Calendar Number 478: Dominick Gerace II, of Ohio, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of Ohio for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ida5b5b42a6e1b4c74a99f2a1fcb96a2c3"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Calendar Number 479: Jerome Francis Gorgon, Jr., of Michigan, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Michigan for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ide07386a13e4d4c469c3a535fbc7f3f94"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Calendar Number 480: Bryan Stirling, of South Carolina, to be United States Attorney for the District of South Carolina for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id81dcd33246e04a74b1af4329f9de966f"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Calendar Number 481: Thomas Wheeler II, of Indiana, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of Indiana for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id60674fa6364e488fbc15795069aec1f2"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Calendar Number 482: Thomas Albus, of Missouri, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Missouri for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id0154eb268bde4d9d95a39418144d0ba5"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Calendar Number 483: Adam Mildred, of Indiana, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Indiana for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id003a16662f8c48b0b5914415f741196e"><enum>(29)</enum><text>Calendar Number 484: Harry Kumar, of New York, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd1400dceaf8f49cbb9d6a99c0e2a19db"><enum>(30)</enum><text>Calendar Number 486: Joyce Meyer, of Virginia, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Economic Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id901611ce083a4372b8792d1cfdb3bdd5"><enum>(31)</enum><text>Calendar Number 488: Andrew Veprek, of Louisiana, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Population, Refugees, and Migration).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd0f4f0d6e1334ddfaf6c275153bae47c"><enum>(32)</enum><text>Calendar Number 489: John Bartrum, of Indiana, to be Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id188ee53c49d44a3692d8cd78f0b051cb"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Calendar Number 509: William Kirk, of Maryland, to be Inspector General, Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idb93555ffef8c4cda89a697c5b708008e"><enum>(34)</enum><text>Calendar Number 510: Jeffrey Hall, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id061977ae703a47de83d2af77ce1a3214"><enum>(35)</enum><text>Calendar Number 511: Mitch Graves, of Tennessee, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority for a term expiring May 18, 2029.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id544a139d834a438694fdf731fc1f4f76"><enum>(36)</enum><text>Calendar Number 512: Jeff Hagood, of Tennessee, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority for a term expiring May 18, 2029.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idd257fb7fbe094067a20c3ce578537626"><enum>(37)</enum><text>Calendar Number 513: Randall Jones, of Alabama, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority for a term expiring May 18, 2028.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id42075bc87bc24254b3b4a6f969eb03fa"><enum>(38)</enum><text>Calendar Number 514: Arthur Graham, of Florida, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority for the remainder of the term expiring May 18, 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idbc478a3f018b47f6bae39841650059e4"><enum>(39)</enum><text>Calendar Number 516: Douglas Troutman, of Maryland, to be Assistant Administrator for Toxic Substances of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id1c677ec0034b4101b6b47ee1f9816665"><enum>(40)</enum><text>Calendar Number 517: Anthony D'Esposito, of New York, to be Inspector General, Department of Labor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id805bfee4eba34c3a9e4ad43c5bece04b"><enum>(41)</enum><text>Calendar Number 518: Platte Moring, of South Carolina, to be Inspector General, Department of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idfec6a57995d84d74b9f8edbc7da401f1"><enum>(42)</enum><text>Calendar Number 520: Mindy Brashears, of Texas, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food Safety.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id051cc8d98efa476c9d45388c8e823b56"><enum>(43)</enum><text>Calendar Number 521: Stella Herrell, of New Mexico, to be an Assistant Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id3037b10a3da342b6b8b074a33ac0dbf1"><enum>(44)</enum><text>Calendar Number 522: Peter Metzger, of the District of Columbia, to be Assistant Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id7dcdeb796ed34771931d90d3ffe988bd"><enum>(45)</enum><text>Calendar Number 523: Charles Arrington, of Illinois, to be a Member of the Federal Labor Relations Authority for a term expiring July 1, 2030.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id7e64f6396120452db9eb349a976c795a"><enum>(46)</enum><text>Calendar Number 524: Edward Forst, of Florida, to be Administrator of General Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1a33e62ad9074ed2bb5360c3fb203314"><enum>(47)</enum><text>Calendar Number 525: Stephen F. Rickard, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the term of 15 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id11e61074474a42668f016497b3cea2ba"><enum>(48)</enum><text>Calendar Number 526: Elana S. Suttenberg, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the term of 15 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id2991f2de972545ef98151e14f34f00d5"><enum>(49)</enum><text>Calendar Number 527: John Cuong Truong, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for the term of 15 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id12cf71f7ec964fc6a16641582af044a3"><enum>(50)</enum><text>Calendar Number 528: Thomas Ferguson III, of North Carolina, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of North Carolina for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id05d05ebfbe23412ab7458bd82ee4def0"><enum>(51)</enum><text>Calendar Number 529: Robert Kadlec, of New York, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idfdd3d50c8bd54062b99d3ce7b979746f"><enum>(52)</enum><text>Calendar Number 530: Marc Berkowitz, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idb6f1e36208f444ccb0a8a51777378452"><enum>(53)</enum><text>Calendar Number 531: Joseph Jewell, of Indiana, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id2c41370edcad4a7c9964af014f31b8dd"><enum>(54)</enum><text>Calendar Number 532: Brendan Rogers, of Connecticut, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Navy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id194f87d4d2ef4568b96513578831e6c5"><enum>(55)</enum><text>Calendar Number 533: David Beck, of Tennessee, to be Deputy Administrator for Defense Programs, National Nuclear Security Administration.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id8d7f6829b2e44e16941dbfb606503c9f"><enum>(56)</enum><text>Calendar Number 534: Charles Young III, of West Virginia, to be General Counsel of the Department of the Army.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idcb715c1c212a43969e6c99976beabc58"><enum>(57)</enum><text>Calendar Number 535: Michael Borders, of Florida, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Air Force.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ida8d86028a7a549c7a59f6660b30793ad"><enum>(58)</enum><text>Calendar Number 536: William Lane III, of Virginia, to be General Counsel of the Department of the Air Force.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idb08df1ca52fb485895b49f925de5ea04"><enum>(59)</enum><text>Calendar Number 537: John Noh, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd703f8ceb255432eaa8fe25d808f9eb3"><enum>(60)</enum><text>Calendar Number 538: James Caggy, of New York, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense. (New Position)</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idf19b1ba9980d4cc898b8e0563ab8e3c2"><enum>(61)</enum><text>Calendar Number 539: Timothy Dill, of Ohio, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id3c964174d6fd488badb134a847ea681d"><enum>(62)</enum><text>Calendar Number 540: Michael Payne, of Virginia, to be Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, Department of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idbdba1c311aad4d4b9674971937823023"><enum>(63)</enum><text>Calendar Number 541: Maurice Todd, of Florida, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd8e6c519118f44f9886062752056f80d"><enum>(64)</enum><text>Calendar Number 550: Ethan Klein, of New Jersey, to be an Associate Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ideca1310ba2944291a5784fc199f3cfe6"><enum>(65)</enum><text>Calendar Number 551: Stephen Carmel, of Virginia, to be Administrator of the Maritime Administration.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9a97113233e249bb943be7f84667273c"><enum>(66)</enum><text>Calendar Number 552: Timothy Petty, of Indiana, to be Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idd39170a4e4f94f84a0d02939fff46526"><enum>(67)</enum><text>Calendar Number 553: Laura DiBella, of Florida, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2028.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id31e3d5ed8e8b450d8652282ef3e7c42f"><enum>(68)</enum><text>Calendar Number 554: Trent Morse, of Florida, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority for a term expiring May 30, 2030.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id033b978be898474da198e2c6d2fdb54b"><enum>(69)</enum><text>Calendar Number 555: Michelle A. Schultz, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Surface Transportation Board for a term expiring November 30, 2030. (Reappointment)</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd1214733880f4dda9edd52e1ca98a952"><enum>(70)</enum><text>Calendar Number 556: Paul Hollis, of Louisiana, to be Director of the Mint for a term of 5 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a0deca3985244d5b1fd379784570fc4"><enum>(71)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Calendar Number 557: Francis Cassidy, of Pennsylvania, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id23ba5fd04a51483c8a05a3174715aa0e"><enum>(72)</enum><text>Calendar Number 558: Joseph Gormley, of Maryland, to be President, Government National Mortgage Association.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id059f99e674f6481fa8a2cba55c4de74b"><enum>(73)</enum><text>Calendar Number 559: Travis Hill, of Maryland, to be Chairperson of the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation for a term of 5 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id0598f976211a4b24870660ae8fe9cdd3"><enum>(74)</enum><text>Calendar Number 561: Jeffrey Goettman, of Virginia, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Africa, Western Hemisphere, Europe, the Middle East, Environment, Labor, and Industrial Competitiveness), with the Rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idcfb076bb432146ffac2bc8cce6d32253"><enum>(75)</enum><text>Calendar Number 562: Arjun Mody, of New Jersey, to be Deputy Commissioner Social Security for the term expiring January 19, 2031.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id60d7b4ff39ed4f39b0421782f62e83b7"><enum>(76)</enum><text>Calendar Number 563: Julie Callahan, of the District of Columbia, to be Chief Agricultural Negotiator, Office of the United States Trade Representative, with the rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idfebab564859249a7a1c4c695eb1b332b"><enum>(77)</enum><text>Calendar Number 564: Leo Brent Bozell III, of Virginia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of South Africa.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ida701364bef5e4ff08b5bf9ef3d48718c"><enum>(78)</enum><text>Calendar Number 565: Benjamin Leon, Jr., of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Spain, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Principality of Andorra.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1caea049d824490cb4f8cfd98ec623ca"><enum>(79)</enum><text>Calendar Number 566: Brent Christensen, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the People's Republic of Bangladesh.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id3eca222a8cc74d4494c951851f30dda5"><enum>(80)</enum><text>Calendar Number 567: Morvared Namdarkhan, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Consular Affairs).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id87a2a82e56e241b3a57ea56b605a999b"><enum>(81)</enum><text>Calendar Number 568: Thomas Bell, of Virginia, to be Inspector General, Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id18ec92ec193b40dcb52eedaf6b897602"><enum>(82)</enum><text>Calendar Number 569: John Walk, of Virginia, to be Inspector General, Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idafe280621dbe468db9668572f51d6179"><enum>(83)</enum><text>Calendar Number 570: Andrew Duva, of Florida, to be an Assistant Attorney General.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idc3da7bea5d2f4b0899be6bf1c87490c3"><enum>(84)</enum><text>Calendar Number 575: Erin Creegan, of New Hampshire, to be United States Attorney for the District of New Hampshire for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id07494e8111a24adcb740b74c3a6469bc"><enum>(85)</enum><text>Calendar Number 576: Ryan Anthony Kriegshauser, of Kansas, to be United States Attorney for the District of Kansas for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id51f6e807504e41afb5541549510d62f6"><enum>(86)</enum><text>Calendar Number 577: James Kruger, of Mississippi, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of Mississippi for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1ddec5950bee49b693dc19da792f46cf"><enum>(87)</enum><text>Calendar Number 578: Scott Leary, of Mississippi, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Mississippi for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id4268782422f5496bb3b0af31f89bb9b6"><enum>(88)</enum><text>Calendar Number 579: Michael Selig, of Florida, to be Chairman of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1454e300d57b4ef48fe056798e842e09"><enum>(89)</enum><text>Calendar Number 580: Michael Selig, of Florida, to be a Commissioner of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission for a term expiring April 13, 2029.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id826f647e3a3849ff94c48bc0146d71f6"><enum>(90)</enum><text>Calendar Number 582: Melissa Argyros, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Latvia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id18680208171e4194996e8f5152aa0993"><enum>(91)</enum><text>Calendar Number 583: Yehuda Kaploun, of Florida, to be Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism, with the rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id561bf8b950534d0cbfe9f043371f2eb2"><enum>(92)</enum><text>Calendar Number 584: Bernardo Navarro, of Puerto Rico, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Peru.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idddcd3a6f33c844fc8433f845ec75617d"><enum>(93)</enum><text>Calendar Number 585: Darryl Nirenberg, of Virginia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Romania.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd8b8cdf4c5a64c739038b6816745d22b"><enum>(94)</enum><text>Calendar Number 586: Tammy Bruce, of California, to be the Deputy Representative of the United States of America to the United Nations, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary, the Deputy Representative of the United States of America in the Security Council of the United Nations, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Representative of the United States of America to the Sessions of the General Assembly of the United Nations, during her tenure of service as Deputy Representative of the United States of America to the United Nations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id555918e965db41bba874965d9465c499"><enum>(95)</enum><text>Calendar Number 587: Christopher Yeaw, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Arms Control, Nonproliferation, and Stability).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id026a7db19be047a4886ae6475c9f0b91"><enum>(96)</enum><text>Calendar Number 588: Mary Anne Carter, of Tennessee, to be Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Arts for a term of 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ida856678095c74ca1bad3256e41ff1f1c"><enum>(97)</enum><text>Calendar Number 589: Scott Mayer, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board for the term of 5 years expiring December 16, 2029.</text></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
<endorsement>
<action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc>Ordered to lie over, under the rule</action-desc></endorsement>
</resolution> 


