<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4FDA162A1F494E69BF0B352CB56FD72A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7896 IH: NOAA Global Ocean Monitoring and Observing Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7896</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration a research program comprising global ocean monitoring and observing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H987FE6730C594081AA73F5D35C1017CD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H526565B3F113446B81BB6A7256F5814C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NOAA Global Ocean Monitoring and Observing Research Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H59DA21F3EF854385944144DF45DBDEFC"><enum>2.</enum><header>NOAA global ocean monitoring and observing research program</header> 
<subsection id="HB9E17702DF574746A0B265D1999F2217" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), shall establish within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration a research program comprising global ocean monitoring and observing (in this section referred to as the <quote>program</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9DEC7B7FEF8341FF803EB70B860A0945" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program shall provide high quality global ocean environmental data and information to improve scientific understanding and knowledge to advance capabilities and services for climate, weather, and ocean needs that support the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s mission to monitor and observe the global environment in order to protect lives and property from extreme weather and other natural phenomena by carrying out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5C80AABB0DFE432F8A2A8CFECE0ADB53" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing and improving sustained global in-situ ocean monitoring and observing systems capable of systematically collecting ocean environmental data to support ocean research, weather research, and climate research, including by leading the development of the global One-Argo system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AFFDF25554B4BDB92DA31ABFEA88252" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Supporting basic and applied research, including the utilization of public and private partnerships to test and evaluate innovative and improved ocean observation technologies to address emerging research needs and support the scientific understanding of ocean health and ocean economy, and the weather and environment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H140D95D7A9184FD88A98AC8A298AF02E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improving the findability, accessibility, interoperability, quality, usability, and reusability of environmental and observational data and research products to carry out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H99CA3569E9354BE6AB83CF84556D33F1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Collecting critical baseline ocean measurements.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD458AE91B9842BDAD8D776A8775E823" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening public understanding of marine and ocean research.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE425EDE17FC64E1481623F004C77B563" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Meeting the national needs for the research community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD621304637424F92861BAD8E69526920" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Undertaking interdisciplinary earth-system research, and coordinated interagency activities to improve understanding of the physical, chemical, and marine ecological features of the ocean, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H68E513D806D347D2B2808E2EED216F9A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ocean heat content and temperature.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H054D9EE0C1EB4364AAA7E5AE445B26B2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Arctic ocean changes, including sea ice and marine ecosystem monitoring and prediction.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE28BD17C9774E0B9D2EDFB05B99BB78" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Ocean carbon and biogeochemistry.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C63EFDC62104CCF99F0F0A4ED802B36" commented="no">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other research the Administrator determines appropriate.</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H357494AB9FDD479A8F39456A3340F804" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In collaboration with the U.S. Integrated Ocean Observing System, the National Data Buoy Center, and the National Oceanographic Partnership Program, ensuring coordination of ocean observing research and relevant activities with other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, State and local governments, regional partners, academic institutions, nongovernmental organizations, private sector entities, and international ocean science and observing bodies, including the Global Ocean Observing System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C77AD5FB17C40989D5DF4639A9FD1CA" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accelerating development and enhancement of ocean observing technologies for forecasting improvements of hurricane intensity, atmospheric rivers, and other extreme weather events.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55EFF4921D344E2C8119AFEE301B1A91" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Building research capacity and increasing the use of autonomous observing systems to fill gaps in the coverage of observations in critical areas of the ocean.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE756633BF8664660AD95DEE8C1C43576" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Integrating artificial intelligence and cloud technologies to optimize data use, as practical.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0F192C3BF9A4238896C4D76A08202E4" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Developing best practices for interactions with the ocean-coastal monitoring and observing science community, including strategies to foster competition and avoid sole sources for critical components and data.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H75BAD07F48894E3D8F9C60A4ED1004B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Framework and review</header> <paragraph id="H468A3F4CBC44425088D481D7C7A0874D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Framework</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop a framework for prioritized monitoring and observational activities for research and metrics to measure progress in data quantity, quality, and management. In developing such framework, the Administrator shall identify and consult with users of the program’s environmental data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F7D260E4AAD420992D52F068EB20C0E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall implement a process for an annual review of activities carried out by the program. Such reviews shall include assessments of the quality and efficiency of the systems and data developed under the program.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC64A847CAC7C4CD1A0DDE792CCEB2E1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Financial assistance</header> <paragraph id="H13676EF7F28B464C9F284FB551BA9AEB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program may provide to academic institutions, cooperative institutions, private sector entities, and other entities the Administrator determines appropriate financial assistance in the form of contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements for research projects to carry out the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFBF47830E74449BBF34E2FA749A85BE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Financial assistance under paragraph (1) shall be awarded on a competitive, merit-based process.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5375772010CC480A8A8DF53FFB699237"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote>—</text> 
<paragraph id="H17CEF69EB8AF4B51B888CF79101F774A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6FC3FA8185E443EAAD0EBB2D83F52EF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes machine learning, neural networks, and natural language processing.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

