<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83AEB453FEC649E98216F1B7910134BC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8032 IH: Facilitating Access to Innovation in Cancer Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8032</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260320">March 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure equitable payment for, and preserve Medicare beneficiary access to, cancer treatments under the Medicare hospital outpatient prospective payment system.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1E27B242A0134859A2F8BAEADBF8CF02" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBCE0C54CDEC84324A7F472DC95D304C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Facilitating Access to Innovation in Cancer Care Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAIC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6A792EECE7AA432F904D8A10AB005977"><enum>2.</enum><header>Separate payment for certain cancer treatments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1833(t)(16) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395(t)(16)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HD8F741106A4F43B2A4C842C8A23A82BA" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC3ECA60E8C69479DBC945EC578052340"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Separate payment for certain cancer treatments</header> <clause id="H68996D9899944A76A8239E7C6AEAD894"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, with respect to a specified cancer treatment (as defined in clause (v)) furnished during a year (beginning with 2026), the Secretary shall not package payment for such treatment into a payment for a covered OPD service (or group of services), and shall make a separate payment as specified in clause (ii) for such treatment, if such treatment has an estimated mean per day product cost equal to or exceeding the threshold specified in clause (iii) for such year.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0408B847B4864872915CB94DF109AA43"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Separate payment</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the separate payment specified in this clause for a specified cancer treatment is a payment in an amount equal to—</text> <subclause id="H1D9D6F2400AA453397E22ECD0C3FF338"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average sales price for such treatment established under section 1847A, as calculated and adjusted by the Secretary to the extent such adjustment is adopted for other specified covered outpatient drugs under paragraph (14)(A)(iii)(II); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H41D59BE3047B40089C4E56958B4E041B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the data necessary to calculate such average sales price for such treatment is not available, the wholesale acquisition cost (as defined in subsection 1847A(c)(6)(B)) for such treatment, as calculated and adjusted by the Secretary to the extent such adjustment is adopted for other specified covered outpatient drugs under paragraph (14)(A), or, if such wholesale acquisition cost is not available, the mean unit cost for such treatment (as derived from hospital claims data).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6AAA06337FE24FEEB0427509C886530A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Threshold</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the threshold specified in this clause is—</text> 
<subclause id="HEF5E1C141B374B53854D4B3EA2D52BCD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for 2026, $350; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA0E4A9C124DB4B3FA24777FA6BFBE164"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for a subsequent year, the amount specified in this clause for the preceding year, increased by the OPD fee schedule increase factor under paragraph (3)(C)(iv) for the year.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H20A215C7B8374381AF16ED8EDC37DE97"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Budget neutrality</header><text>The Secretary shall make such adjustments as are necessary under this subsection to ensure that the amount of expenditures under this subsection for a year with application of this subparagraph is equal to the amount of expenditures that would be made under this subsection for such year without application of this subparagraph.</text></clause> <clause id="HC3B34CC07DED42A28AEFD2DA513CA460"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>specified cancer treatment</quote> means a drug or biological that—</text> 
<subclause id="HC04182CBC83F4637906ED183F5A1E813"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is approved by the Food and Drug Administration on or after January 1, 2008, for use in the detection or treatment of cancer;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE8FA2BDA67BC479AA21C8A2F360A73CC" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not receive transitional pass-through payments under paragraph (6); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H75AA773335844CB19A63908937DDFB25" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has payment that would, but for application of this subparagraph, be packaged into a payment for a covered OPD service (or group of services).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

