<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C14BBCB24F445E69975DE1F5439B392" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8695 IH: No Delays in Disaster Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8695</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to appoint an Acting Regional Administrator in any case in which a Regional Administrator position of the Agency has been vacant for at least 90 days, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6421F00D5FB2437EA31CACDD25E4E9B3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCE9C3AD058E84F25B92E23F81494D0CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Delays in Disaster Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H281E4959CC7546999E9786FA760ACE9E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Acting Regional Administrators of Federal Emergency Management Agency </header> <subsection id="HAB6ECF76172941B18F2643519BE3EE59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall establish a process by which the Administrator appoints an Acting Regional Administrator in any case in which a Regional Administrator position of the Agency has been vacant for at least 90 days.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5478662CB50B40B69B25F1E5D5D9F212"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority of Acting Regional Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that an Acting Regional Administrator shall have the authority to—</text> <paragraph id="H8A3AA5715C8D4D26995DEB22A72AB274"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make relevant grant and programmatic decisions necessary to support the timely obligation and disbursement of funds; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46EE53E3EFE84C04943474762B845B0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">process and disburse Federal grant assistance to States and local governments.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2D86C46545434C16A615D37CCDD35C8F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit a report to Congress that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H57B76D993BD84D7DA45B3ACAA4A5CB4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of actions taken to implement the delegation of approval authority, including any updates to policy, guidance, or internal controls.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9572B76E22524F77AEE0CFEC9C63A4B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identification of regions of the Agency with vacancies exceeding 180 days and the status of Acting Regional Administrator designations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H256A04C6B82D4FB5BF7409588B6A71F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The scope of authorities delegated to Acting Regional Administrators and any limitations placed on such authorities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB05F8475FD8401F90533202220A3932"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Data on grant processing and award timelines before and after implementation, including any measurable improvements in timeliness of obligations and disbursements.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74E044A825F449778A4E222AC195083B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact of delegated authority on program efficiency, internal controls, and risk management.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69D72434782F452FB9581984044CDEED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any challenges encountered in implementation, including legal, operational, or staffing constraints, and steps taken to address them.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0431D9D21BAC4A8BB1614292E181D9F5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any recommendations for legislative or administrative changes needed to further improve the timely delivery of Federal assistance of the Agency.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

