<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2AE2E26477FC4D4EA26A93E122EB07FE" public-private="private" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7194 IH: Kareem N. Dockery Medal of Honor Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">V</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7194</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to award the Medal of Honor to Kareem N. Dockery for acts of valor as a member of the Army while serving in Afghanistan.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H49A09DFD7FAA469CBAEE23F005759FA5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2948963BE8914B3B97DB054393A58626" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kareem N. Dockery Medal of Honor Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBC61B563BAC340439EAD99EA316923EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7D138B4BFAB94A5F9DE51DF54137A202"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On October 2, 2012, then 2nd Lieutenant Kareem N. Dockery was serving as an Infantry Rifle Platoon Leader with the 2nd Battalion, 12th Infantry Regiment, 4th Brigade Combat Team (Light), 4th Infantry Division, in support of Operation ENDURING FREEDOM.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF05A8F4E5C0848CF95E34768A20C40E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Dockery’s platoon and accompanying Afghan and ITS forces were conducting combat operations in Kapisa Province, Afghanistan when they were ambushed with rifle, machine gun, and rocket-propelled grenade (RPG) fire by a large group of Taliban fighters.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DA46B801724457589FAAD0188F2DD66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>During the ambush, Dockery moved between Afghan units with his own small element, attempting to rally and reinforce partner forces with his own small element.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFAD8BE32B6444AEB9D9D922A82042A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hearing that one of his soldiers was wounded, Lieutenant Dockery moved inside a courtyard to defend the small, isolated group of United States soldiers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0A4587D95744EE9B3909D6E9E64E278"><enum>(5)</enum><text>He assaulted into the next room to kill 1 enemy fighter with his carbine.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H968A73674C4C4A3BBB4A6CADB073E4D5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Surrounded by more enemy fighters, Dockery rallied the remaining 4 United States soldiers to continue to defend the courtyard.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F6C00DB3CBB4836A08CB22751ACF532"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As the enemy continued its assault, additional RPG and grenade blasts suppressed the fire team. Attempting to regain the momentum, Dockery led a counterattack to clear the courtyard, at one point using his body to shield a soldier from an enemy grenade explosion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DA5BDB3846E485AB29CC957952F4CBC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The enemy again counter-attacked the compound with 10 additional fighters. RPG fire and grenades wounded the entire element and destroyed the last covered position of Lieutenant Dockery’s team.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB48BFB7604984F489CDB7FA2124FCD49"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Noticing that one of his NCOs was missing, Lieutenant Dockery moved into a nearby alley and found 2 enemy fighters dragging away an unconscious United States soldier. Lieutenant Dockery assaulted the 2 fighters and killed them both in close combat.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB50AD73382644918F9F425BA4102951"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Dockery then administered CPR and first aid to the soldier, saving his life.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEB131560C69487D92CAF499C7CAB8C5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>To mark the element’s position for friendly helicopter gunships to suppress the remaining embassy, Dockery then moved to the roof of the compound, still under enemy fire, and fired smoke grenades.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H698547003B8547DCA8E4D70943A9B18F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In recognition of his actions, Kareem N. Dockery received the Silver Star for conspicuous gallantry and intrepidity in action against the enemy, demonstrating heroism and selflessness above and beyond the call of duty at the risk of life, keeping with the highest traditions of military service and reflect credit upon himself, 4th Infantry Brigade, 4th Infantry Division and the United States Army.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H196E6B151C4343A788EA742D677CE439"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Kareem N. Dockery deserves the Medal of Honor for his extraordinary heroism and selflessness as he successfully protected his element from an enemy ambush and killed 3 enemy fighters, while repeatedly putting his life in danger for the safety of his fellow soldiers.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD3AB73CA316248F2872C62E5E1DF8282"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization for award of Medal of Honor to Kareem N. Dockery for acts of valor as a member of the Army while serving in Afghanistan</header> <subsection id="H0BE94AD096F94D258174084788673843"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the time limitations specified in section 7274 of title 10, United States Code, or any other time limitation with respect to the awarding of certain medals to persons who served in the Armed Forces, the President is authorized to award the Medal of Honor, under section 7271 of such title, to Kareem N. Dockery for the acts of valor described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95E4BD4DA6A441DFB2951CF6879D3CCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acts of valor described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The acts of valor described in section 2 of this Act are the actions of Kareem N. Dockery, as a member of the Army, on October 2, 2012, while serving in Afghanistan, for which he was previously awarded the Silver Star.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

