<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA33309F42F864099B31E2C73B6B42DB8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8226 IH: Helicopter Safety Parity Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8226</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish safety equipment, training, and maintenance requirements for turbine-powered helicopters carrying 2 or more passengers for compensation or hire, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9218127C830F4373925252E565C2D4B6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H76CC92770D774A3CAF996BE695D13311" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helicopter Safety Parity Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1E9CA1F7994048C39590FC299DE1A6F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H93CE83CE37134EBCB78CD69444E74C73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Certain helicopter operators conduct passenger service under part 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, that is substantially similar to part 121 of such title scheduled passenger operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29848089AE7E47AFA5DD4F702A05190E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These operations avoid the more rigorous standards for pilot training, duty and rest, maintenance, and equipment required under part 121 of such title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6D81F02CB8A4985976C69DE6586AF11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Aviation Administration has acknowledged this gap and proposed rulemaking to close it, but such rulemaking has not been finalized.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74AC8597F5DA4C5E8C88D57C6F55555B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Public safety requires that rotorcraft providing passenger service comply with standards equivalent to those governing airlines.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF82F14D70A0344A0AF376A2DC5303C26"><enum>(5)</enum><text>This Act builds on, and does not duplicate, the requirements of the Federal Aviation Administration Safety Management System final rule issued in 2024.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H310F1AAA7B8B41E986561643E75199FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A series of helicopter accidents in recent years, including fatal crashes involving tour operators, charter services, and air taxi operations, have revealed recurring issues with pilot fatigue, inadequate maintenance, and insufficient equipment, including the April 2025 Hudson River helicopter crash, which demonstrated that inadequate maintenance oversight under part 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, can contribute to catastrophic failures, highlighting the need for harmonized standards with part 121 of such title.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H242346F776CF4D019B7CE68970B843C4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB9A60038696A497C97DFEB4818ABAEE9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Part 121 operations</header><text>The term <quote>part 121 operations</quote> means operations conducted under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57C49CED8EE14FB3837097DA257ADE39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Part 121 operators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>part 121 operators</quote> means operators conducting part 121 operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE788DC380A84DD3AF0F29269EDACB51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Part 135 operations</header><text>The term <quote>part 135 operations</quote> means operations conducted under part 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF87882554C4D4846B11085613BE6AA2F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Part 135 operators</header><text>The term <quote>part 135 operators</quote> means operators conducting part 135 operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D5E72A1E6B141CD8E2F642BDFD86F96"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rotorcraft</header><text>The term <quote>rotorcraft</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF7A66AC9633447EAB2A1D877DDF50E91"><enum>4.</enum><header>Safety equipment and operational standards for helicopter operations</header> 
<subsection id="H9F8D59700A6549F189E4BE634381D43A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section applies to all turbine-powered helicopters carrying 2 or more passengers for compensation or hire.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1163F1B231C04CA6BCC1E87161E48D35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Operators subject to subsection (a) shall comply with safety equipment, training, and maintenance requirements equivalent to those applicable to part 121 operations, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H36C6516665F2447BB89ED4B54E2F0EEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>equipment capable of providing terrain awareness, or equivalent technology approved by the Administrator;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7CF09565E4C4058A19D889A99DC3283"><enum>(2)</enum><text>equipment capable of cockpit voice recording, or equivalent technology approved by the Administrator;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2249E57C17024678B320026C325B11A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>equipment capable of flight data recording, or equivalent technology approved by the Administrator; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE04890E3F64F43A8AD96FC139784D985"><enum>(4)</enum><text>compliance with standards under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, for pilot qualification, duty and rest, and maintenance programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H03CFD42AF7CE47C78DA3D2CB02A61633"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance timeline</header> 
<paragraph id="H2044D0F88DB14FDCA9C0080C424D3520"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Operators subject to this section shall achieve full compliance not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9473006E18F748BF800D94C5E7DA0E66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Administrator may grant an extension of up to 6 additional months upon a showing of good faith progress toward compliance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A07EF7906074C989D20E7652F7B12CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>This section shall not apply to operations conducted exclusively for emergency medical services under subpart L of part 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3870EB6BEB21428B9129E8676D5AFB89"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header> <subsection id="H74AB840F88164BC7B5D8236B4D049977"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue final regulations to carry out this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H57B4DE9968324E388D96ACBFEF57C50A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of inconsistent exemptions</header><text>The Administrator shall rescind or modify any exemptions, interpretations, or guidance inconsistent with this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H42F062AB8B424D97B1E83333DD347C2B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An operator that fails to comply with the requirements of this Act shall be subject to the same penalties, certificate actions, and enforcement measures applicable to violations by part 121 operators under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/447">chapter 447</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></section> 
<section id="H9DD300B6565D459C858B201203E13C82"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Aviation Administration $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out the requirements of this Act, including rulemaking, enforcement, oversight, and the hiring and training of aviation safety inspectors to strengthen maintenance and operational surveillance of rotorcraft operators.</text></section> <section id="HEFD398EF46B54F8287B68AE24A2D4386"><enum>8.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE903B97017BE4EDBAB9A8D5BDE1D3941"><enum>(1)</enum><text>staffing needs for implementation of this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B12D1175FB741F98818CAB1D0859629"><enum>(2)</enum><text>steps taken to hire and train additional aviation safety inspectors; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BDB010B1F2A4A0E9CD019DF113FEF28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>progress in integrating rotorcraft operators into oversight systems consistent with part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA3B2F463741146DFB141D39E8982CA4C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements of this Act shall take effect on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

