<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H273EDF5441C0405F8C7EA4A9392D58EA" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4626 : Home Appliance Protection and Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 4626</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prohibit the Secretary of Energy from prescribing any new or amended energy conservation standard for a product that is not technologically feasible and economically justified, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5668F08BB9634D658CB2A18FEAF3CA54" style="OLC"><section id="H0912E3B84A0844E29C1D48702A8C56E7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Home Appliance Protection and Affordability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8F4F063D966C49F28B5C617333AA0579"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prescribing new or amended energy conservation standards</header><subsection id="HCC86F9F67B0042E1843B83A1B24943D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment of standards</header><paragraph id="H16E1D78EFEA44DCFA8FB80886A7DBC25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 325(m)(1) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(m)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H863C3517646E491BA3DE835E13749F8C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HDA74E63DF98B414B923607CA6DF7C541"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, for any product, publish a notice of proposed rulemaking including new proposed standards for such product based on the criteria established under subsection (o) and the procedures established under subsection (p).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H08A0787D436C4E16B067934788D7DA3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendment of standard</header><text>Section 325(m)(3) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(m)(3)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF52E84D092E84178B28B03DE1FCCC969" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H5C8A1AE861314A7FB7A541908E881F91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amendment of standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after a notice is issued under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish a final rule amending the standard for the product.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H60DB2E31C3F34A4FA87B00363E254A2A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application to products</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 325(m)(4) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(m)(4)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4952492C54C648849DE1AE363EC9DBC4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE932DE785B004CEA9007865072DDD7DA" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application to products</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An amendment prescribed under this subsection shall apply to a product that is manufactured after the date that is 5 years after publication of the final rule establishing an applicable standard.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54541A94CC2D4B9F97EC07749204DF31" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Petition for amended standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 325(n) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(n)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC40DC33AC4094894B0214158FBC43BB8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">an amended standard</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">amendment or revocation of standard</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A0A3A03C1D54BD7B5E8FA8F3B2D6DBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or revoked</quote> after <quote>should be amended</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8FD8FB9BC2E4F7196EC0C9FA4E254EB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H672C0BD17E194E889949B470ED875C0A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HDA64470C2EB94B368A8E94CA351D2D3F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall grant a petition to determine if standards for a covered product should be amended or revoked if the Secretary finds that such petition contains evidence, assuming no other evidence were considered, that such standards—</text><subparagraph id="H86DFA0CCBF88438DA0E2503BABCCFF72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>result in additional costs to consumers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F8A78D9D3DF428FA6A097836FCA1F93"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">do not result in significant conservation of energy or water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FFBD778B95344CEA7EE5EECDAC99632" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not technologically feasible; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF1A9DD38024444CA913DD401A085391"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">result in such covered product not being commercially available in the United States to all consumers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H117109480E634110B76166C2ADE031EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="HBEA8F8F4E9A34B07B7BC8AD6C7028662"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">New or amended standards.</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">New, amended, or revoked standards.</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41E74D764F814FE6B2FA628A1F0C70FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively (and by conforming the margins accordingly);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB704AE0E77674992ADDE01A2D682CBDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Not later than 3 years</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9D9B1DD6BDB24F64B8F40CFEAEA2E1CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H74B3FADE2B324D24AED22B9C562AA09D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B2198FD74834A3C9FDEF4E0EB06DA53"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2C094BC899EA41A8A8AD95D617E521C4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H16F0A945B8E2471C87157F36D7C28135"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of granting a petition to revoke standards, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register—</text><clause id="H2FFF514A260A415B8B5872DCCC6ED7C9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a final rule revoking the standards; or</text></clause><clause id="HFFAEF4F771F847E2AB030E9AC5272068"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a determination that it is not necessary to revoke the standards.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95DCE9DD5E43461AA8AF52F882DACC35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The grant of a petition by the Secretary under this subsection creates no presumption with respect to the Secretary’s determination of any of the criteria in a rulemaking under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC9FF90736AD45BE8E792979FF120760"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Standards that have been revoked pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be considered to be in effect for purposes of section 327.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B187588463A472BAB05DF6AC5524423" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5)(B), by striking <quote>3 years (for refrigerators, refrigerator-freezers, and freezers, room air conditioners, dishwashers, clothes washers, clothes dryers, fluorescent lamp ballasts, general service fluorescent lamps, incandescent reflector lamps, and kitchen ranges and ovens) or 5 years (for central air conditioners and heat pumps, water heaters, pool heaters, direct heating equipment and furnaces)</quote> and inserting <quote>5 years</quote>;</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H314E66EA6C414EB482066A1E50F11DF0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 325(o) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(o)</external-xref>) is amended by amending paragraphs (2) and (3) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAA544E836A39423794E19600D71DFED3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H50610884FCAE492999AFAD224555EB2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="H135434F7CD1047829E8379B6B27E53FA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Design</header><text>Any new or amended energy conservation standard prescribed by the Secretary under this section for any type (or class) of covered product shall be designed to achieve the maximum improvement in, as applicable, energy efficiency or water efficiency, which the Secretary determines is technologically feasible and economically justified.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H217E34685C0E44B3B852A78F301035EB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Test procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a test procedure should be prescribed or amended in accordance with section 323 for a type (or class) of covered product, the Secretary may not prescribe a new or amended energy conservation standard under this section for such type (or class) of covered product unless the Secretary has prescribed or amended (and published in the Federal Register) a test procedure for such type (or class) of covered product at least 180 days before publishing a notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to the new or amended energy conservation standard.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1434C877C1ED42DF9A4E1C86B65132F8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Significant conservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not prescribe a new or amended energy conservation standard under this section for a type (or class) of covered product if the Secretary determines that the establishment and imposition of such energy conservation standard will not result in significant conservation of, as applicable, energy or water.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2526AEDFE11145F483386C3FAC78FC28"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Technologically feasible and economically justified</header><text>The Secretary may not prescribe a new or amended energy conservation standard under this section for a type (or class) of covered product unless the Secretary determines that the establishment and imposition of such energy conservation standard is technologically feasible and economically justified.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CB5C22A63A2492A9AAB40532997896E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>The Secretary may not prescribe a new or amended energy conservation standard under this section for a type (or class) of covered product unless the Secretary, not later than the date on which the standard is prescribed, publicly discloses each meeting held by the Secretary, during the 5-year period preceding such date, with any entity that—</text><clause id="HC981B63022804411BA0EA054E92257F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has ties to the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party;</text></clause><clause id="HF8D8A74EB53D46318BE244E1016AE346"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has produced studies regarding, or advocated for, regulations or policy to limit, restrict, or ban the use of any type of energy; and</text></clause><clause id="H3BA76EEF7DF64B1A8EE445508643218A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has applied for or received Federal funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60108EA7D2974FBF93C5188E25E0EFC0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Factors for determination</header><subparagraph id="HAB2FD3864178439B9F93165CFF4260D7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Economic analysis</header><clause id="H48CB7A40D49F4BA888BC30A07E5C7C23"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Prior to prescribing any new or amended energy conservation standard under this section for any type (or class) of covered product, the Secretary shall conduct a quantitative economic impact analysis of imposition of the energy conservation standard that determines the predicted—</text><subclause id="H056A3935077C4F64B2C2F69073EF5F5D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">effects of imposition of the energy conservation standard on costs and monetary benefits to consumers of the products subject to such energy conservation standard, including—</text><item id="HE7D75F838E584CCEA700A17AFE93AC45" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>costs to low-income households; and</text></item><item id="H7AD9B01E3B7C46229D497C9F0BBAC64B" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">variations in costs to consumers based on differences in regions, including rural populations, cost of living comparisons, and climatic differences;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H2D3B9A7418CA4C9D9DB98CB6F9A6EC10" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">effects of imposition of the energy conservation standard on employment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC96D3649C1C84869B51171B1CC7CE455" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>lifecycle costs for the covered product, including costs associated with the purchase, installation, maintenance, disposal, and replacement of the covered product.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8301B75F017B4CB5A61E657933BB3F60"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notice and comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide public notice in the Federal Register and at least 60 days for public comment on the quantitative economic impact analysis conducted under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B2F5A26D2084A0E92E429F3FD29E63F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on additional costs to the consumer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not determine that imposition of an energy conservation standard is economically justified unless the Secretary, based on an economic analysis under subparagraph (A), determines that—</text><clause id="HDFF3090F786E40169F87689D24FE6B1D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>imposition of such energy conservation standard is not likely to result in additional net costs to the consumer, including any increase in net costs associated with the purchase, installation, maintenance, disposal, and replacement of the covered product; and</text></clause><clause id="H75B1B881703D487F9524AFC80988803F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the monetary value of the energy savings and, as applicable, water savings, that the consumer will receive as a result of such energy conservation standard during the first 3 years after purchasing and installing a covered product complying with such energy conservation standard, as calculated under the applicable test procedure, will be greater than any increased costs to the consumer of the covered product due to imposition of such energy conservation standard, including increased costs associated with the purchase, installation, maintenance, disposal, and replacement of the covered product.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC65339D1F65E420D9B309A38BC229A73"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Required energy or water savings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not determine that imposition of an energy conservation standard is economically justified unless the Secretary determines that compliance with such energy conservation standard will result in—</text><clause id="H0AE3D06B9254489E9B4B17B6E39EAD11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a reduction of at least 0.3 quads of site energy over 30 years; or</text></clause><clause id="H06127A995F3E45CB8161D2394F27A9D8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least a 10 percent reduction in energy or water use of the covered product.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44955014DC1A4EB69CBEB2E60EA79186"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Criteria related to performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not determine that imposition of an energy conservation standard is economically justified unless the Secretary determines that imposition of such energy conservation standard will not result in any lessening of the utility or the performance of the applicable covered product, taking into consideration the effects of such energy conservation standard on—</text><clause id="H4147A873BF6749A8AF47F084E1CAF10C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the compatibility of the covered product with existing systems;</text></clause><clause id="H8C2B92A5896A418C93BB1169D8148725"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the life span of the covered product;</text></clause><clause id="HEFE9B15AA5D6422783673A9BAFD0A954"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the operating conditions of the covered product;</text></clause><clause id="H476AE79A200A413BB66CB4E255235186"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the duty cycle, charging time, and run time of the covered product, as applicable;</text></clause><clause id="H906C41A291024ED5A77570D9858D230E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the maintenance requirements of the covered product; and</text></clause><clause id="H0234BE1A7E834B9997EB9FC8ACF5D2E4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the replacement and disposal requirements for the covered product.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC247A25C22F49E1A48EFCFB8CD07BF2" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Technological innovation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not determine that imposition of an energy conservation standard is economically justified unless the Secretary determines that imposition of such energy conservation standard is not likely to result in the unavailability in the United States of a type (or class) of products based on what type of fuel the product consumes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14A4D46AEA0847E4AE19F6DE188F4F22" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Other considerations</header><clause id="H71BB32C6DDA648FAB881D26BEFEE6169"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining whether imposition of an energy conservation standard is economically justified, the Secretary—</text><subclause id="HAA4C653DBB4842F1943C54F806DB48E5" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall prioritize the interests of consumers;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9DD08EDC99AA42D8AA93A9EE37AD1E1F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may not consider estimates of the social costs or social benefits associated with incremental greenhouse gas emissions; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6CCA1140DA404CE49FC4CE36A4A7AE5F" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall consider—</text><item id="HD47A92B38E884D0F9F7CC0EAC36F8806" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the economic impact, including any regulatory burden, of the standard on the manufacturers and on the consumers of the products subject to such standard;</text></item><item id="HEE6A91E924F245F1A6DA239548BC576F" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the savings in operating costs, including consumer fuel costs, throughout the estimated average life of the covered product in the type (or class) compared to any increase in the price of, or in the initial charges for, or maintenance expenses of, the covered products which are likely to result from the imposition of the standard;</text></item><item id="HD1B47C4B63334F97910FCA007715D3F6" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the total projected amount of energy, or, as applicable, water, savings likely to result directly from the imposition of the standard;</text></item><item id="H3DEE422636BA450F8C733CA9F1BA934B" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the need for national energy and water conservation;</text></item><item id="H0EA6DF8C37D547138F174F98F24A949F"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the impact of any lessening of market competition, as determined in writing by the Attorney General under clause (ii), that is likely to result from the imposition of the standard;</text></item><item id="H6F0273ED54144FB1A30A730C7DBE6790"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>whether the imposition of the energy conservation standard is likely to result price discrimination; and</text></item><item id="HF4CB059628594F73AE1174BD87CA999F" commented="no"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>other factors the Secretary considers relevant.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HF44D668E77BB433993F4C947B32D700B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Attorney general determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i)(III)(ee), the Attorney General shall make a determination of the impact, if any, of any lessening of market competition likely to result from such standard and shall transmit such determination, not later than 60 days after the publication of a proposed rule prescribing or amending an energy conservation standard, in writing to the Secretary, together with an analysis of the nature and extent of such impact. Any such determination and analysis shall be published by the Secretary in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3396A3A78A754D77A99B3E8B16BB0F07" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Regulatory review</header><clause id="HBC62E920F691491FB526B45DC6E3307A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the issuance of any final rule prescribing a new or amended energy conservation standard under this section for any type (or class) of covered product, the Secretary shall evaluate the rule to determine whether such energy conservation standard is technologically feasible and economically justified and whether the regulatory impact analysis for such rule remains accurate.</text></clause><clause id="H5AFFB1240B35446698E1C59E4FA9A7B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, if the Secretary determines, based on an evaluation under clause (i), that an energy conservation standard is not technologically feasible or economically justified—</text><subclause id="H9B042B8F79CD4DC584762E74A1BC4045"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall publish such determination and such energy conservation standard shall have no force or effect (except that such energy conservation standard shall be considered to be in effect for purposes of section 327); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD661F91AA404446483C98B6093D1EC12"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary may publish a final rule amending the energy conservation standard for the type (or class) of covered product to be technologically feasible and economically justified in accordance with this subsection, which amendment shall apply to such a product that is manufactured after the date that is 3 years after publication of such final rule.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCE8F5F7725D144FA86EF5F52F0DBA873"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability of Regional standards</header><text>Section 325(o)(6)(E)(ii) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(o)(6)(E)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>shall apply to any such product installed on or after the effective date of the standard in States in which the Secretary has designated the standard to apply</quote> and inserting <quote>shall apply, in States in which the Secretary has designated the standard to apply, to any such product that is manufactured or imported into the United States on or after the effective date of the standard</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H0B22C1384E994805904C8D1216124523" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HBE84F2C5E99146138072546873A11B4C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><subparagraph id="HC7F631EE391C419D8AD0DD769791C7EB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consumer product</header><text>Section 321(1)(A) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6291">42 U.S.C. 6291(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, with respect to showerheads, faucets, water closets, and urinals, water</quote> and inserting <quote>water, as applicable</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24C1CECA2D854B89AF4A65B1C95C9B97" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Energy conservation standard</header><text>Section 321(6)(A) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6291">42 U.S.C. 6291(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, or, in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, and urinals, water use, </quote> and inserting <quote>or water use, as applicable,</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84325BA3669B4980900F6768559242FB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Estimated annual operating cost</header><text>Section 321(7) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6291">42 U.S.C. 6291(7)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, and urinals</quote> and inserting <quote>, as applicable</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H936B8635FEE046468827925428763532" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Test procedures</header><subparagraph id="H8DA2872A66714A10A388AADB73ECF2F3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Design of test procedures</header><text>Section 323(b)(3) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6293">42 U.S.C. 6293(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>energy efficiency, energy use, water use (in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets and urinals)</quote> and inserting <quote>, as applicable, energy efficiency, energy use, water use</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BA71360A3BF46BD9CDB4B15AE706BAB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Calculation of costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 323(b)(4) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6293">42 U.S.C. 6293(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by—</text><clause id="HF23A7D9991A64D158EBA06FB39054F38" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or, in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, or urinals,</quote> and inserting <quote>or, as applicable,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HA1C44ACBF3F046FCA68CEC423FFE2510" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, or urinals,</quote> and inserting <quote>or, as applicable,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H842096C212B048BEBDE122FB3F33A79F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Restriction on certain representations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 323(c) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6293">42 U.S.C. 6293(c)</external-xref> is amended—</text><clause id="H208274C8B61A4C19A28D8276C83228EC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote> or, in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, and urinals,</quote> and inserting <quote>or, as applicable,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H2B1BE3C705704F9E839DE189F650292F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote> or, in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, and urinals,</quote> and inserting <quote>or, as applicable,</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0668B6BF28D4FA0BB2E2E1AA85B91B4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria for prescribing new or amended standards</header><text>Section 325(o)(1) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended by striking <quote>, or, in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, or urinals, </quote> and inserting <quote>, or, as applicable,</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H349413A03AF049099FEF661CD30DD330" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 325(o)(6)(D)(i)(II) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(o)(6)(D)(i)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>this paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>this subsection</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBE1B9D898AA490A9FDB59143B073543" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Procedure for prescribing new or amended standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 325(p)(2)(A) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(p)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>taking into account those factors which the Secretary must consider under subsection (o)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>as determined in accordance with subsection (o)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H685911153EDF4FB0BC7DC923947C6304" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Information requirements</header><text>Section 326(d)(1) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended by striking <quote>or, in the case of showerheads, faucets, water closets, and urinals, </quote> and inserting <quote>or, as applicable,</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93329E7709F94ABE805CCE9B890026C6" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Energy conservation standards for high-Intensity discharge lamps, distribution transformers, and small electric motors</header><text>Section 346 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6317">42 U.S.C. 6317</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAD1563A8445347D6AF0E308E96F36763"><enum>3.</enum><header>Distribution transformers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 346 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6317">42 U.S.C. 6317</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4990BB27C3A44D008BBC726E97C3F8F5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H61928107F64F47E8912E832E09806A08"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No new or revised standards for distribution transformers</header><paragraph id="HAF1C03121F5640159F69AEFB63576D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary may not prescribe any new or amended energy conservation standard under part B or this part for distribution transformers, including those distribution transformers for which the Secretary prescribed testing requirements under subsection (a)(1) and low-voltage dry-type distribution transformers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF119A62DC6464FCFAD57FF17E0EA3219"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on existing standards</header><text>Paragraph (1) does not affect any energy conservation standards prescribed under part B or this part before the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE3C37505511D44729BDF944AA1864DF8" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Dishwashers; clothes washers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 325(g) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5CE0A7B3DB1247E0A504838BA9A55B8F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)(B), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H563E051629FC463A9BD10408F2DED566" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H54D7F9F555BB4AABAA009F0869E5612B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Other amendments to standards</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe a new or amended energy conservation standard for clothes washers in accordance with this section, including—</text><subclause id="H6E69B12F6D54444F90FBB495AAC28788" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a design requirement; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H292072A01086432F808DF18622DD572C" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a performance standard which prescribes one of the following:</text><item id="HC7369B845AE849358ED1E4970C38AA6E" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minimum level of energy efficiency.</text></item><item id="H676DDB1D10AD45C086B2F45CB2EE77DE" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>A maximum quantity of energy use.</text></item><item id="H3FDA48D5A1DF441EA9E20FB0114E6C35" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minimum level of water efficiency.</text></item><item id="H8FF4DF4DEDB2481794678A86A254F98B" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>A maximum quantity of water use.</text></item><item id="H44323E83164242F2AE47FA7F1D1B2871" commented="no"><enum>(ee)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minimum level of energy efficiency and a minimum level of water efficiency.</text></item><item id="H1515F80DDA95496CA3347251E41A239D" commented="no"><enum>(ff)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A maximum quantity of energy use and a maximum quantity of water use.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0BA09D08E0540A1950AF024913B767C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (10)(B), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1700A68957D74E58A7F8A70BA3028252" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H7A156578B8B945C7BFF9EC9D5ECA22E2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Other amendments to standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may prescribe a new or amended energy conservation standard for dishwashers in accordance with this section, including—</text><subclause id="H03499BC4C544421B8D8F7542E764F2A2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a design requirement; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H37908CD8F9B640718D513ABE1713F836"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a performance standard which prescribes one of the following:</text><item id="HD26ACCCF58BB49ED87387B5BD19FC90F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minimum level of energy efficiency.</text></item><item id="H8AF51795B17342DB95B0B38607B09371"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>A maximum quantity of energy use.</text></item><item id="HA32E080CCAF1475D9A8CEB4C1CB80227"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minimum level of water efficiency.</text></item><item id="HF34832458B9548ED95FBDC3FDF9DE6EE"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>A maximum quantity of water use.</text></item><item id="H5FC5746047BA4542BEECEF3992782760"><enum>(ee)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minimum level of energy efficiency and a minimum level of water efficiency.</text></item><item id="H4B3B12996AD24785904611FD54F9EA88"><enum>(ff)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A maximum quantity of energy use and a maximum quantity of water use.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260224" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 24, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

