<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8819F1C1CCEE4B809F09938AE1BB82EB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8290 IH: Exchange Rate Accountability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8290</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the use of the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any quota increase at the International Monetary Fund for member countries that employ certain exchange rate practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9DD6072464D3439A8DB955609E6B6DC9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H30E41A2045494431AAA45E4B83DA3D24" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Exchange Rate Accountability Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H518261D38CCA4433A3B2BDE0016B3122"><enum>2.</enum><header>Opposition to IMF quota increase for countries that undermine the balanced growth of international trade</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Bretton Woods Agreements Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/286-286aaa">22 U.S.C. 286–286aaa</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H098306C67E4F4875A83A1D512740AF17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the 2nd section 73 (as added by section 1901 of division P of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>) as section 74; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9873EC2AAC3476BAB036AC238D91708"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HEAF7A62F7BA94EB8B0D7E0C6C47ADFDF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA8BDC6084C1C491A88B60E3F215D7D4B"><enum>75.</enum><header>Opposition to quota increase for countries that undermine the balanced growth of international trade</header> 
<subsection id="H4B1D81CA447140CE9C5383C3BD727FE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less than 7 days before consideration of any proposal to increase the quota of a foreign member of the Fund that is one of the 10 largest shareholders in the Fund, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that sets forth a determination by the Secretary as to whether the foreign member meets the following criteria:</text> <paragraph id="H580975F607E544CAB7153294868D0737"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The member, in the preceding 12 months, does not appear to have been in violation of the obligations of the member under Article VIII of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund, based on publicly available data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37B0165A98FE45419172295E1D3FA73D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The member—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2B748C86AF84971BD1085A2AE6D534F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintains transparent exchange rate policies and practices; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75673BA5AB024076BDDD05E84FE92AAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publishes credible balance of payments data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F73B7791264484F9AD44B9CE36BC063"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To the extent that the member, in the preceding 12 months, has recorded a current account surplus, the member has not persistently managed the rate of exchange between its currency and the United States dollar for purposes of preventing effective balance of payments adjustments or gaining unfair competitive advantage in international trade.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H61A0250E4AE9433DAF18B74DB1276643"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of determination</header><text>On determining that a foreign member of the Fund has failed to meet any of the criteria set forth in subsection (a), the Secretary shall instruct the Governor of the Fund to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose the proposal to increase the quota of the member in the Fund.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H808AA523908348338CADF21E994EF913"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive subsection (b) with respect to a member of the Fund on reporting to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that the waiver is important to the national interest of the United States, with an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E2E5CE161CC40B8B72F490F436FC215"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Proposal consideration</header><text>For purposes of this section, consideration of a proposal to increase the quota of a foreign member of the Fund does not include consent to an amendment to the Articles of Agreement of the Fund that has been authorized by law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFBCB07DD287B41A4AD78A0F37A556FE9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to have force or effect 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

