<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG26424-SMV-MN-12G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 S4938 IS: Bycatch Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4938</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reduce trawl gear impacts on bycatch and seafloor habitat in the Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska, to establish gear performance standards, seafloor contact detection, and salmon excluder requirements, to improve Council transparency and participation, to prioritize ecosystem analyses, to modernize electronic monitoring, to prohibit unsustainable foreign seafood imports, and to establish a Bycatch Mitigation and Habitat Protection Assistance Fund.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bycatch Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1f26f06454c44196a060d091bf283314"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring mid-water nets do not operate like bottom trawl gear</header><subsection id="id030358890c4a4f6e8ba40d6551a0ce6c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall—</text><paragraph id="id71757363be97480e8b7b4959188af4a0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a pelagic trawl gear performance standard for vessels using pelagic trawl gear in fisheries managed under the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands Groundfish Fishery Management Plan and Gulf of Alaska Groundfish Fishery Management Plan (referred to in this section as <quote>applicable vessels</quote>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida9964f5163b2432687e19055fd385489"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement enforceable regulations to manage gear impacts from such applicable vessels on benthic habitat and reduce unobserved mortality on important subsistence, commercial, or recreational species during fishing operations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id59ea6e3e0fda4e7eaadbaaf8665e5ae3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establish a pelagic trawl gear baseline</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84e30ac14d6449f295c3b86d65a8efe7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall use methods, such as gear design standards, model and field testing verification, sensors, or technology, to identify the current baseline of the effects of pelagic trawl gear on marine benthic habitat in areas managed under the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands Groundfish Fishery Management Plan and Gulf of Alaska Groundfish Fishery Management Plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd010f7815ca541db97cddacc11377592" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independent review</header><text>The North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to review the methodology, data, and findings used to identify the baseline under paragraph (1). The results of the review shall be made publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idff28ee291ba640f6864e0ea70d285685"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Following the identification of the pelagic trawl gear baseline under subsection (b), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), in consultation with the North Pacific Fishery Management Council, shall promulgate regulations to reduce impacts relative to such baseline from pelagic trawl gear, including through—</text><paragraph id="idfa7b4980f04c499ea8f3c4ca94117a01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requiring gear modifications to pelagic trawl gear, including requiring applicable vessels to be equipped with a commercially available seafloor contact detection system capable of monitoring and verifying the net position and clearance of pelagic trawl gear in relation to the seafloor;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd460f834ab34bf5a7442c2a6fd08bd2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reductions in the amount of fishing effort that results in pelagic trawl gear making contact with the marine benthic habitat in areas that are closed to nonpelagic trawl gear;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2c8b78ad9214679808a790846debd36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prohibitions on fishing by pelagic trawl gear in areas closed to nonpelagic trawl gear; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01cdf75d80f0480db3596dd21dbba683"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prohibitions in fishing by pelagic trawl gear if there are any areas identified in section 6(c)(4) that support juvenile recruitment of important subsistence, commercial, or recreational species.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id19b0d8e7182247e7b0132e604c8d34f3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Monitoring; data retention and access</header><text>In providing consultation to the Administrator for the promulgation of regulations under subsection (c)(1), the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall consider—</text><paragraph id="id0b96d547365941e8b5a86d59f22d6a2e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing protocols for the collection, storage, and submission of data related to the use of pelagic trawl gear;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id177d95d178b34ed899663badd723e466"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requiring real-time or near-real-time monitoring of such data, with transmission of such data each week to support compliance monitoring and enforcement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id669eea1abd2d4b95aff359dd8018e7de"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring seafloor contact detection systems are compatible with existing electronic monitoring or observer programs implemented by the National Marine Fisheries Service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16a02493ddb64552b428b4b59e06b831"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing requirements for the retention, submission, and confidentiality of data collected under this section consistent with section 402 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1881a">16 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6fb2a9d2a5044d8eb600b4aebeb13f50"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>An applicable vessel that fails to comply with the regulations promulgated under this section shall be deemed to have violated the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) and shall be subject to the penalties and sanctions, including civil penalties, permit sanctions, or other enforcement actions, provided under such Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="iddc9574329d47408a81e2d6e19d2c6888"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In implementing this section, the Administrator and the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall consult with affected subsistence, commercial, and recreational participants, including harvesters, processors, communities, and community development quota groups.</text></subsection></section><section id="id06567a53a2124eaa9ba856991bf0c61a"><enum>3.</enum><header>Getting trawl nets off the seafloor to reduce unobserved fishing mortality and habitat impacts</header><subsection id="ide600fa559de24c3dbc9139d899e2cfe9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="id357b8fadc8ef42f092cb4c5105c42f7c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Gear performance standards</header><text>The North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall establish a gear performance standard system for applicable vessels using nonpelagic trawl gear in fisheries managed under the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands Groundfish Fishery Management Plan and Gulf of Alaska Groundfish Fishery Management Plan to manage gear impacts on benthic habitat and reduce unobserved mortality on important subsistence, commercial, or recreational species during fishing operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc781dcb9d0ce43bf86ce259404a4160b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable vessel</header><text>In this section, the term <term>applicable vessel</term> means a trawl catcher/processor vessel that is not eligible to harvest pollock under section 208 of the American Fisheries Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1851">16 U.S.C. 1851</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcacd57fa8b46471b8b98de8e470ef3fa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Performance review and standards</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="id7f7aa7ef53874cf3945a7ade94e5b997"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deliver a report to the North Pacific Fishery Management Council that—</text><subparagraph id="idbd797ee06b4341bc940eedc05b4af680"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies, using methods such as gear design standards, model and field testing verification, sensors, or technology, the current baseline of the effects of nonpelagic trawl gear on marine benthic habitat in areas managed under the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands Groundfish Fishery Management Plan and Gulf of Alaska Groundfish Fishery Management Plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c0f89293ba446ac92a589e27d2a1cb3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describes nonpelagic trawl gear regulations for applicable vessels and analyzes the potential impacts to marine benthic habitat and bycatch from modifying nonpelagic trawl gear; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ea9262358694c89bc19f96cb834b536"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a 1-year phase in period that requires each applicable vessel to be equipped with a modified footrope and modified trawl sweeps, as applicable, to reduce seafloor contact and maximize seafloor clearance relative to such baseline from applicable vessels using nonpelagic trawl gear.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id92114651ac2d49c19ba43125ca3c31ad" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Independent review</header><text>The Administrator shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to review the methodology, data, and findings used to identify the baseline under subsection (b)(1)(A). The results of the review shall be made publicly available.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7fef1762e89544d4bde355b7c5bc63ea"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Full compliance</header><text>The Administrator shall require full compliance with the requirements of this section not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3de5dd4e80214ffaaee911bd8d725bc3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>An applicable vessel that fails to comply with the requirements of this section or regulations issued under this section shall be deemed to have violated the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) and shall be subject to the penalties and sanctions, including civil penalties, permit sanctions, or other enforcement actions, provided under such Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id02d6c223df424b46b6d2a2d895b0b9f8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In implementing this section, the Administrator and the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall consult with affected subsistence, commercial, and recreational participants, including harvesters, processors, communities, and community development quota groups.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide463bb71d706441a91be4f611d6a2171"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving public transparency and increasing participation in the North Pacific Fishery management council process</header><subsection id="ideeb1fd2113fc40ae968c4448a9961c0c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regional fishery management councils</header><text>Section 302 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idfb13b2bb6c0d4633837fa0b567f56208"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking paragraph (5) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6175a9f38a344898abafae3888a17a97"><paragraph id="idb4766fa770244464855fd2ef698ff734"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Each Council shall hold a recorded vote on all non-procedural matters before the Council. The official minutes and other appropriate records of any Council meeting shall identify all roll call votes held, the name of each voting member present during each roll call vote, and how each member voted on each roll call vote.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5117e02335c4408b95bec06156f83fc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(2), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id283acffaf1c94331aa11344b779784cc"><subparagraph id="id4ceeca7406f94ccfbd32a25aeec4d265" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Each Council shall make available on the internet website of the Council—</text><clause id="idf602b65a2c83432aa795d24eea528500"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, a webcast, an audio recording, or a live broadcast of each meeting of the Council, and of the Council coordination committee established under subsection (l), that is not closed in accordance with paragraph (3); and</text></clause><clause id="id4f14c86219f24e27bc55968caffef8e2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>audio, video (if the meeting was in person or by video conference), or a searchable audio or written transcript of each meeting of the Council and of the meetings of advisory bodies of the Council, by not later than 30 days after the conclusion of the meeting.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide32919c825b64a8eb671bfa89108b008" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Secretary shall maintain and make available to the public a permanent online archive of each webcast, audio, broadcast, video, and transcript made available under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (G).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id9452e92507f042f0a0682b9b877fc68d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (j)—</text><subparagraph id="id052f09fac0f442469dac60981696ce66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd0238ce88204fc8bbe71ef35f72ff46"><subparagraph id="idaaa0b6f4ce8a48d9bf8e7b6f91b6a22a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>designated official</term> means an attorney employed in the Office of the General Counsel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration who—</text><clause id="id4e537991aef0450691cfd2cdf12e11c5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has expertise in Federal conflict-of-interest requirements; and</text></clause><clause id="id465a46fe4e1f4460b933ab05f1de0cfa"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is designated by the Secretary, in consultation with a Council, to attend the meetings of such Council and make determinations under paragraph (7)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d49106d4a5049078fc71762cbd0625e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(C), by inserting <quote>contractor,</quote> after <quote>partner,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec5f7440873d481d9440b37da1684f4b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(B), by striking <quote>on the Internet</quote> and inserting <quote>on the internet website of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, on the internet website of the applicable Council,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8d6ed48728fb4b49922fe8f51d85d0fc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>North pacific fishery management council written public comment procedure</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall update its Public Comment Policy and provide a minimum comment period of 4 weeks before the start of the Council meeting.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd3e6db2db29e486fbfce8f6569239368"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National oceanic and atmospheric administration recusal review process</header><paragraph id="id4891c8e720554c678be684b52113e43f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall conduct a comprehensive review of the financial interest and recusal procedures under section 302(j) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852(j)</external-xref>) and the regulations promulgated to carry out such section, including section 600.235 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a7a65ddaeb44f6d9a5b944d24c6412a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>The review under paragraph (1) shall evaluate whether there has been compliance with regulatory requirements promulgated to carry out section 302(j) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852(j)</external-xref>), including timely submission of disclosures and the effectiveness and consistency of recusal determinations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab9b861faeba4517a222f70907a35a92"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Identification of gaps and weaknesses</header><text>The Administrator shall include, as part of the annual report to be submitted in 2027, in accordance with section 302(j)(9) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852(j)(9)</external-xref>), a section identifying any gaps or weaknesses in the current disclosure and recusal process and providing recommendations on defining or clarifying the recusal standards.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id37103366eaee4b82a104ae2822f5bb51"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requiring salmon excluders in the North Pacific</header><subsection id="id780a6b0487b245b9a274fd55ffa1f09d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall require all vessels using pelagic trawl gear in fisheries managed under the Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands Groundfish Fishery Management Plan and Gulf of Alaska Groundfish Fishery Management Plan (referred to in this section as <quote>applicable vessels</quote>) to be equipped with a salmon excluder device.</text></subsection><subsection id="id948a2227d0894032ac10e8468b0c4519"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gear requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall require each applicable vessel to be equipped with a salmon excluder device that is operational and has been field tested, scientifically reviewed, and verified to reduce salmon bycatch effectively.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida1a46b3f9f0043d098dffc95d55923fe"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Salmon excluder devices</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="idc4b88f87630b4c91824917c3c28d2bb6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support field testing and scientific review of salmon excluder devices; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08c9d68679f6498aa46aa41d009c2c62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement an outreach strategy to ensure industry adoption.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id63d9ec8eb4ad4cd3beff3a5e4ee1e2ae"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance and guidance</header><text>The Administrator shall provide technical assistance and guidance to applicable vessel operators to facilitate installation and use of approved salmon excluder devices.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6f29889a8c3744478309258119497a22"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Full compliance</header><text>The Administrator shall require full compliance with the requirements of this section not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9bc67b111d364d65bdfbd3c5bee7698a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>An applicable vessel that fails to comply with the requirements of this section or regulations issued under this section shall be deemed to have violated the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) and shall be subject to the penalties and sanctions, including civil penalties, permit sanctions, or other enforcement actions, provided under such Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3ac2a4c9530f451ab2f1577f9190eb5f"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing regulations to implement this section, the Administrator and the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall consult with affected fishing industry participants, including harvesters, processors, communities, and community development quota groups.</text></subsection></section><section id="id9a6786ae968a490dbad8b68a0d635db2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prioritizing foundational investigations and ecosystem analyses to reduce bycatch and seafloor impacts</header><subsection id="id18d82edd1cda4688adec82b5be473a4e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reconstitution of the alaska salmon research task force</header><paragraph id="id9f01df423eeb431ea113088f1a4004d7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall reconstitute the membership of the Alaska Salmon Research Task Force, as described in the Alaska Salmon Research Task Force Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 5271).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80a58cdb58c145f1b4d097bb2e66b797"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bycatch reduction task force</header><text>The reconstituted membership described in paragraph (1) shall be referred to as the <quote>Bycatch Reduction Task Force</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd3f4446009e45e1ab2384e672a84dec"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall appoint an additional 7 representatives to the Bycatch Reduction Task Force as follows:</text><subparagraph id="id4b0a10f9ea5e45f389627e1f49259506"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 members who are academic experts, of which 1 member shall be an expert in salmon ecology, 1 member shall be an expert in groundfish ecology, and 1 member shall be an expert in invertebrate ecology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id871d6d92978545d59f6db121413d32e9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 member who is a resident of the Bering Sea or Aleutian Islands region and 1 member who is a resident of the Gulf of Alaska region.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94e07528ce99471b84d517369100e5b5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2 members who are subject matter experts with trawl fishing gear technology and its operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id50ec0cfa4dd24b3e857684ac26b0c593"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Bycatch Reduction Task Force shall—</text><subparagraph id="ideec4831bf31a49ecacabc59c2c4286d6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review all research conducted and reports published under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec22d39ceeec41d3858824ce5c061f50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in consultation with the Administrator, provide priority recommendations for future work as described in subsection (d)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddabde18a2dc6497bb719f841970fb1a5"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Inapplicability of federal advisory committee act</header> <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply to the Bycatch Reduction Task Force. Notwithstanding the inapplicability of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, the Administrator shall, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with protection of confidential and proprietary information, make publicly available on an internet website—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id579d7c03c4fa4b9bb0b134fbd61d36dd">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the membership of the Bycatch Reduction Task Force;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8535afef2be64a70914a2fa3bc860c6e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>meeting dates and agendas of the Bycatch Reduction Task Force;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id957d8cd7b7454239be057ff18a4b2b2f">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>non-proprietary materials provided to or produced by the Bycatch Reduction Task Force; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id23c22ed914b449afb209657b72f2995a">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>a mechanism for the public to submit written statements for consideration by the Bycatch Reduction Task Force.</text>
          </subparagraph>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id185c401a9d5e49b6ab2b1ecc1ad660a6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Salmon life history research</header><paragraph id="id4c04c036b7a4418d810f7832226e58b8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Salmon tagging</header><subparagraph id="id519ec543517c4e63b7e29ed06b3cdfbb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall enter into public-private partnerships with State agencies, nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)), and research institutions to research the marine life history of Alaska origin salmon species in the Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79e9685bd6ec4bf7bf5c265f98f4d5c3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>In entering into partnerships described in subparagraph (A), the Administrator—</text><clause id="id5b5373571be345abb53e9077ac56cce8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall involve a diverse group of Alaska salmon experts, including Alaska Natives, fishing industry representatives, commercial fishermen, and individuals who possess personal knowledge of, and direct experience with, subsistence uses in Alaska; and</text></clause><clause id="idddebcf1710e841c09203c3b55c5d2935"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include cooperative research efforts with privately owned commercial or charter fishing vessel owners.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5b050490e0848c18b851700361f2679"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Research</header><clause id="id2f9f06cd83874313b6d194013d600e22"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At a minimum, the research required under subparagraph (A) shall include satellite tagging or other intelligent tagging methodologies to better understand migration and distributions of Alaska origin salmon during their marine life history in the Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, or Gulf of Alaska.</text></clause><clause id="idcf83d9b5d2594fca86f15bb89a6115a5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Satellite tagging studies</header><text>The satellite tagging or other intelligent tagging described in clause (i) shall aim to conduct—</text><subclause id="id9d96bdb4e66c4ac8980ca2be1f32d34e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>genetic determination of stock-of-origin on all tagged salmon;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1cab5cbdd3e64a9d80da98b2b905cc47"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an analysis of movement, behavior, and habitat use for different genetic stocks;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc6c4f4e512524f2bacf1605fe21bcc8b"><enum>(III)</enum><text>systematic sampling across different ages, sizes, run timings, and cohorts rather than opportunistic tagging; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id9a64c5166ac847b287b6e3b5124a6cbb"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>research on depth occupancy patterns, vertical migration behavior, and 3-dimensional habitat associations.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6969d8486c8a4806b24b9c72ff9744ab"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Data stewardship and analyses</header><subclause id="idf284ec6fc1cf4d9794fc67fa68572f68"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure the results and analyses under this subsection are publicly accessible, usable, and directly applicable to better understanding Alaska origin salmon migrations and distributions, and to reduce bycatch in the Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska.</text></subclause><subclause id="id52241a4f606f466fa7314287572f85f1"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>In carrying out all analyses under this subsection, the Administrator, in consultation with the Bycatch Reduction Task Force and applicable public-private partnerships described under subparagraph (A), shall use modern analytical methods that may include machine learning or artificial intelligence for predictive modeling, to the extent practicable.</text></subclause><subclause id="id070766522e334474bc3e0a6e707548e5"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>All—</text><item id="id1fa9c1f5d1f04f1a8c89acb46b6f2168"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>methods and models used to carry out this subsection shall be publicly available and accessible for use in peer-reviewed venues or technical reports and shall include all algorithms and analytical code; and</text></item><item id="idc36a84af39524cb39914749387b23142"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>developed or produced tools, guides, visualizations, or decision-support products used to carry out this subsection shall be made publicly available and usable.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id85a1540bb14047a59035f590dfe47274"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Open standards</header><text>All satellite tagging data collected under this subsection shall abide by open data standards and be deposited in publicly accessible repositories (such as the Ocean Tracking Network or the Animal Telemetry Network) using standardized formats.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id264c3943bd9541d5b0af49f366602a0e"> <enum>(D)</enum> <header>Inapplicability of federal advisory committee act</header> <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply to the partnerships described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c9cd5af04fa469ab1dcbc1378a477fd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Genetic sampling grant program</header><text>The Administrator shall conduct a competitive grant program to support improving the turnaround time of genetic analyses of biological samples collected at-sea or shoreside to provide real-time or near-real-time, in-season genetic stock identification, and age composition estimates of Alaska origin salmon caught incidentally in commercial fisheries conducted in the exclusive economic zone (as defined in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</external-xref>) off Alaska).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id387b8d2a087f464388a59971ed526fc5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall publish a report—</text><subparagraph id="id09dcd52de984426ba19061bde3f08ec0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the findings of the salmon tagging research conducted under paragraph (1) and the findings of the genetic analyses grant program conducted under paragraph (2) that details how the salmon tagging research and genetic analyses can better inform Alaska origin salmon stock status and distributions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29c4d15618444f2487750d31c5eb33dc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that includes potential uses of artificial intelligence or machine learning technology to perform predictive modeling to inform potential Alaska salmon bycatch avoidance areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id60c1d93ceee947d8b628eaf9b805b511"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ecosystem analyses</header><paragraph id="idb337ad957ed64ab5b9954724bb5c7edd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall conduct—</text><subparagraph id="id1149a4d3bd7941e7a79c783c89c7cc7b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>research, through studies and models that incorporate existing data, literature, and ongoing research, including relevant international data and research from comparable marine ecosystems, of how contact from nonpelagic trawl and pelagic trawl gear impact shallow shelves or other marine benthic habitats in the Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e662d256b164ec9b033526e74287de6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of existing data, literature, and ongoing research efforts on fluctuations in Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska marine ecosystems that may affect the survivability or energetic condition of commercially or culturally important wild marine and anadromous species, including examining—</text><clause id="iddc722de118124bf5855cdf71f163c3be"><enum>(i)</enum><text>harmful algal blooms;</text></clause><clause id="idebd563d95e744b72a909ad0ee5bd3de9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>marine heatwaves;</text></clause><clause id="id583b79bf12a04a19959312737d26b177"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in-river temperatures;</text></clause><clause id="idb2eacacd3a0e4ed9a6817d98f38c4fa0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>sea ice extent and thickness;</text></clause><clause id="idbd9b5a693ad24f988267729d4deba957"><enum>(v)</enum><text>ocean acidification;</text></clause><clause id="idbab073408574484b8ea9b7c5321b5936"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>diseases;</text></clause><clause id="idc9f611468c2e4e5999a0ff591cc6580e"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>nutrient or prey availability;</text></clause><clause id="id3886f08c5434430c8d48b50118a32cdb"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>density dependence;</text></clause><clause id="idb5d0ef09a1b4441f89893b7d3578a3c0"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>shifting stock distributions;</text></clause><clause id="ide89a7532e3134ec3a32f72d60bea90a5"><enum>(x)</enum><text>carrying capacity;</text></clause><clause id="id913324321a8b412dae280775ea0c76c9"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>impacts from hatchery released species, with particular attention to foreign hatchery releases; and</text></clause><clause id="id100cf52d642c45218984a8d9771534e2"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>predator-prey interactions; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6245e7677ad4f479f461f5fa3f0b4d5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>new research, using the review of data, literature, and ongoing research efforts under subparagraph (B), to prioritize data collection that support conservation of commercially or culturally important wild marine and anadromous species.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8dd63052bf4242aca80328ebb6c6a2cc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diverse group involvement</header><text>In conducting research under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="id2f61ebdb640d410f965e2204a45bac57"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>enter into public-private partnerships with relevant entities, such as State agencies, nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), and Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92826fbc7c244335879a7d48afba8ce7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involve a diverse group of experts in commercially or culturally important wild marine and anadromous species, including Alaska Natives, fishing industry representatives, commercial fishermen, and individuals who possess personal knowledge of, and direct experience with, subsistence uses in Alaska.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c6fd07e7960480ebfac60d4f2f1575b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data stewardship and analyses</header><subparagraph id="idd0ac2c5b583d45b5a22198a0f91754ea"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure the results and literature review analyses under this subsection are publicly accessible, usable, and directly applicable to the research conducted under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfba63fe6a2e44f449545730da992289f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>In carrying out all analyses under this subsection, the Administrator, in consultation with the Bycatch Reduction Task Force and applicable public-private partnerships described under subparagraph (2) shall use modern analytical methods that may include machine learning or artificial intelligence for predictive modeling, to the extent practicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55f4ad988db54eee9e36e76466057c49"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>All—</text><clause id="id156d50a3f3ce430194ed931e23543ca6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>methods and models used to carry out this subsection shall be publicly available and accessible for use in peer-reviewed venues or technical reports and shall include all algorithms and analytical code; and</text></clause><clause id="id61a4c76e05f749b4a5009d03456ca9ed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>developed or produced tools, guides, visualizations, or decision-support products used to carry out this subsection shall be made publicly available and usable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e7dd9d403bc46deaf8b2fa3f14d57e2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Open standards</header><text>All newly produced ecosystem data collected under this subsection shall abide by open data standards and be deposited in publicly accessible repositories using standardized formats.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93f7f496e30740e2b1c64e277b37884d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Juvenile recruitment of species</header><text>As part of the essential fish habitat (EFH) review, the North Pacific Fishery Management Council shall analyze areas closed to 1 or more commercial fishing gear types that overlap with habitats that support juvenile recruitment of important commercial, subsistence, or recreational species. The review shall include an evaluation of the potential benefits associated with such closures, and whether these habitat closure areas should be expanded to other commercial fishing gear types.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id892d918131674ba28d6676dfc84abd68"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="idb347fc9262394091b52b37f6e6a7f39d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall publish interim annual reports and a final report (not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act)—</text><subparagraph id="id92e65014823a4302bf877cb6f361795c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on findings and results of the research and literature review analyses conducted under subsection (c)(1) and the status of milestones reached for all research initiatives under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf9917b53a944514ba86c686b8ebb110"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on the results from the salmon tagging and genetic sampling research under subsection (b), including modeled Alaska origin salmon migration routes and potential applications to inform how best to minimize Alaska salmon bycatch; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbac34cad537d471e89616c8733ac3d9c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that includes results from the ecosystem analyses under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id623982baaa57408ead33bbc05bc22ce5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations; findings</header><text>The reports described under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="idcacdabfbb1824357ab94b430a66f94a3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>descriptions of explicit mechanisms to connect research outputs to management processes through research products that document specific examples of how research findings are being incorporated into management decisions, fishery regulations, or industry practices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57dc1b9d62f8422eb992c603c03ff042"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations to the North Pacific Fishery Management Council on creating feedback loops that ensure collaboration through establishing regular workshops or working groups that bring together researchers, managers, industry representatives, and fishermen to coordinate research efforts and share findings related to bycatch reduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c09816ce8f74c2da93177dc9a91012a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for applying the results from the ecosystem analyses review to model potential impacts on commercially or culturally important wild marine and anadromous species in the Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska to support informed management actions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03e17fba2b3f408ab430168b2ffcc77e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other findings and recommendations for future work under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id051986f256dd42e5ad6cb4090a163c02"><enum>7.</enum><header>Prohibiting unsustainable foreign seafood imports</header><subsection id="id634adaaa33c94561b85782bc3bac77c3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="ida8853fd80e884e448cfeb0c4a220796b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beneficial owner</header><text>The term <term>beneficial owner</term> means, with respect to a vessel, a person that directly or indirectly, through any contract, arrangement, understanding, relationship, or otherwise—</text><subparagraph id="id77813091ea6f4a12aa92f0193dcd47e8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exercises substantial control over the vessel; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id940b2b0c24d443e0ae1f1b156a65f237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>owns not less than 50 percent of the ownership interests of the vessel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id88c02c413a23477c94161f76080eb6f5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign vessel</header><text>The term <term>foreign vessel</term> has the meaning given the term in section 110 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11301c4ddefe42bb85f3ae42ee0bc4e2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Seafood</header><text>The term <term>seafood</term> means fish, shellfish, or other aquatic animal life intended for human consumption, whether fresh, frozen, canned, smoked, prepared, or otherwise processed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbfad84c1ac1848ea9fad9644ef9b8663"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It is prohibited for any person in the United States to enter into or facilitate, directly or indirectly, any transaction related to the importation, procurement, or selling of seafood from a foreign vessel or beneficial owner of a foreign vessel unless the Secretary of Commerce determines that the fishery from which the seafood originates harvests fish in a way that is comparable to the national standards for fishery conservation and management under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id48e62c32bf1f4252bb2b354e664f0808"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Seizure</header><text>Any seafood in the possession of a person that violates the prohibition described in subsection (b) shall be seized by the Secretary of Commerce.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6c37eeb2b8834b65a995d2b6cbd852d2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disposal of seafood</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall determine how to dispose of any seafood seized under subsection (c).</text></subsection></section><section id="idf0b0f98f23614766b465079530806e50"><enum>8.</enum><header>Building infrastructure to support cleaner fishing gear and innovative technology</header><subsection id="id31fc8647de98417397e5c28586169483"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall enter into a public-private partnership to build a flume tank for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the fishing industry, and other researchers to test technology and improved fishing gear aimed at reducing bycatch and contact with Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska marine benthic habitats.</text></subsection><subsection id="id785c5f4d65464c01ac47d953af65ab40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Flume tank assistance fund</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a Flume Tank Assistance Fund to provide grants or other financial assistance to support entities that wish to test their innovative technology, including approaches that support prototype development and associated devices, instruments, sensors, or fishing gear designs aimed at reducing bycatch in fisheries and contact with Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska marine benthic habitat from mobile or fixed fishing gear, including workforce and training programs on such technology or gear.</text></subsection></section><section id="idbc64494a2dd64e37928418e10b92b146"><enum>9.</enum><header>Modernizing fisheries monitoring and improving observer program transparency</header><subsection id="id694d8fe3f1e24fe08f276470c26e0f5e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Electronic monitoring and reporting</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="id9c3535c433604578981507689cb45d7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create a timeline and process for reviewing and approving exempted fishing permits in Federally managed North Pacific fisheries to support innovative fishing gear types and technology for reducing bycatch, unobserved fishing mortality, and reducing marine habitat disturbances, including streamlining exempted fishing permits for fishermen and owners and operators of commercial fishing vessels who purchase or modify fishing gear, equipment, or technology with financial assistance provided under the Bycatch Mitigation and Habitat Protection Assistance Fund, established under section 322 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, if approving such permits does not interfere with fishery conservation objectives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b815c5fc47048fa817b60f31f5b02f8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>streamline the approval process for experimental or exempted fishing permits used in Federally managed North Pacific fisheries for electronic monitoring pilot projects, including owners and operators of commercial fishing vessels who purchase or utilize low-cost commercially available electronic monitoring solutions, if approving such permits does not interfere with fishery conservation objectives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52efa63dfa2e4282b1665024d5e065aa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitate cooperative research programs and regional pilot frameworks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90575093de7741b58e4848edb25d2e97"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct a public stakeholder consultation process not less often than once every 3 years, which shall include public notice, listening sessions, a written comment period of not less than 60 days, and solicit input from stakeholders, including service providers, regional fishery management councils, fishery industry participants, and data scientists, on—</text><subparagraph id="id5b75453b92eb4cf0995765945b06d5d9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>revisions to electronic monitoring and electronic reporting technical standards or operational guidance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8919bc5667ca417ab49ed3ee9095ea79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improvements to cost-effectiveness or usability; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id203056cfb09e4cfb8c1a3873b74431fb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>barriers to electronic monitoring adoption, particularly among small-scale fleets; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id59e9286d9bc14a6aa5e7efe68909e471"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide a data integration strategy that—</text><subparagraph id="id6a14c5b0adb94c0a83ee13fde1f11679"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporates electronic monitoring data directly into regional science center workflows and stock assessment models;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9ed18a8191a44db8ed3084a892dd21a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduces latency between data collection and management application; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8236a31b2504ca5869fdf848a93a15f"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>supports the development of interoperable databases that facilitate real-time or near-real-time analysis and decision-making.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id25f834f7984b474c9225e136f422f86c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="id084a51b8606b42cc822c7da54938f996"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require the regional offices of the National Marine Fisheries Service to publish, online and in layman’s terms, up-to-date observer coverage category requirements for Federal trawl fisheries specifying the Federal fishery under their jurisdiction, including prohibited species catch (bycatch) for each observer program category; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12d0ee4509184d6da99ef57d560025ee"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the National Marine Fisheries Service develops and disseminates, in print and for online distribution, public communications materials that clearly explain bycatch in Federal fisheries under its jurisdiction, using accessible, layman’s terminology and graphics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd32e32a797444ee4892c0d2cf2707e37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="ida4088a3911574dc78ee7a35f2d68869e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall publish a report on how the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and Regional Fishery Management Councils can improve and integrate the use of observer and electronic monitoring data to better inform spatio-temporal fishing activity and impacts to harvested and incidentally harvested populations, while ensuring the protection of confidential information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5aa9a96e0bf049d1b8dc2ea56fed4a2f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>The Administrator shall submit a report to Congress and publish the report on the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s website that includes the data integration strategy for increasing data review efficiency and uniformity described in subsection (a)(5). The report shall include a summary of the feedback received during public stakeholder consultation described in subsection (a)(4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ece68fd4ffa4a85b6a122dd82497c6a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The reports required under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall include recommendations—</text><subparagraph id="id7dcea80f8f0c4a908ac5d3c26e2a3bbb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the use of any technologies identified as effective for sharing real-time, or near-real-time, catch information to identify bycatch hotspots and bycatch avoidance areas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20b540b5880144fabcb62ffb0f67dcc4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to minimize bycatch and unobserved fishing mortality of commercially or culturally important wild marine and anadromous species in the Bering Sea, Aleutian Islands, and Gulf of Alaska, such as Pacific halibut, Alaska crab species, and Alaska-origin salmon.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1587687ff962449883c70c61bbfce021"><enum>10.</enum><header>Investing in cleaner fishing gear and healthy seafloor habitats</header><subsection id="id6d7da0ee2f5441ca99be290f40b923bf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reauthorization of the NOAA national marine fisheries service bycatch reduction engineering program</header><text>Section 316 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1865">16 U.S.C. 1865</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb26c42d4d98042ec9a4f6e038c0dedbf"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (a), (b), (c), and (d), as subsections (b), (c), (d), and (e), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id571c0b6fafe44588b95820b875b793f7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before subsection (b), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id042a5a1f66fc475c855a1ab15c59a441"><subsection id="idb57f34824ee543adb143c43977a3d2c8" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the bycatch reduction program established under subsection (b) is to develop technological devices and other conservation engineering changes to improve fishing practices and minimize bycatch, seabird interactions, bycatch mortality, unobserved fishing mortality, and post-release mortality in Federally managed fisheries.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id523c4cc630874398bc7b5379d8206c05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31bc11ca6eab49a9be1e691613e43568"><subsection id="idc4494ceeabff4bbfb667aec8e981245a" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id76b40220d9cf4eaaa01b79547bbfa9a3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bycatch mitigation and habitat protection assistance fund</header><text>Title III of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1851">16 U.S.C. 1851 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e5cabc89ec9453487262be0ef26f99c"><section id="idccb9ab92e5d045468fc53b2ec7b57af9"><enum>322.</enum><header>Bycatch mitigation and habitat protection assistance fund</header><subsection id="idad6c4847ab0a4338809d99ec1d03a3aa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States an account to be known as the <quote>Bycatch Mitigation and Habitat Protection Assistance Fund</quote>, which shall—</text><paragraph id="idc15860e2876343859cd791f7c7d6c1c1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be administered by the Foundation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfaeb37560e8b4948a4b8081762c7df1c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consist of donations of amounts accepted pursuant to subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id97f2cd475849429f90f77153a77d6d36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use</header><text>The Foundation shall use the amounts in the Fund to reduce or mitigate bycatch, and reduce marine benthic habitat contact from mobile or fixed fishing gear, including by providing financial assistance to fishing industry organizations, associations, fishermen and owners and operators of commercial fishing vessels to purchase or modify fishing gear, equipment, and technology, including innovative technology, prototypes, instruments, or sensors.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida73745e393c54b358ffaf2ab28884165"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>The Foundation may solicit and accept donations of amounts for deposit into the Fund.</text></subsection><subsection id="idaffa27c28162415b9009b39ceb38e3f2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In administering the Fund, the Foundation shall consult with the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, each Council, and each of the regional offices and science centers of the National Marine Fisheries Service to ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, amounts in the Fund are used in an efficient and cost-effective manner.</text></subsection><subsection id="idee69078014c94f3c8859e446e5d10d68"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, and biennially thereafter, the Foundation shall publish and post online in a manner available to the public information regarding the use of the Fund during—</text><paragraph id="id298db62f3ab74eceaa5c0de51623595c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to the first publication of information, the preceding 3 years; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0b0b48d3f6345668edf3845993b48f4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each subsequent publication of information, the preceding 2 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id99413035d1ce4a42b9fabe3b91d9b3bc"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idcf980446bc9346eabd29f684c111c8a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3dfe8a5ffefe4334a88ee643944044d0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Bycatch Mitigation and Habitat Protection Assistance Fund established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

