<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF646F7E337A74A18A79E01399CFAEACE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6304 IH: AI for America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6304</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251125">November 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify a national strategy for artificial intelligence that promotes American leadership, removes regulatory barriers, and ensures data are free from security risks and ideological bias, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H954D91DA2227485C86F688A579D357CA" style="OLC"><section id="H898583EDA37942489B6F60D544038FD6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI for America Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H069F20DAA31F4A45800EAE575350BA19"><enum>2.</enum><header>Action plan relating to artificial intelligence; NIST report on security risks relating to, and ideological bias in, artificial intelligence</header><subsection id="H871545F49A0B41FA9A8493325BB2E540" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Action plan</header><paragraph id="H55BFF3A8847E462CBEC4C0458731CF2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 31, 2027, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate an action plan relating to artificial intelligence (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Action Plan</quote>). The Action Plan shall include measurable milestones relating to the matters described in paragraph (2). The Director, in coordination with such heads, shall not less often than biennially update the Action Plan and submit to such Committees each such update.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0225CD4FAC847B1940CD43A53025319"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters described</header><text>The matters described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC18DDE8484E54193949C03993013828E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence leadership, workforce development, public-private partnerships, and measures against security risks and ideological bias.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03DB96DE6DC24A089E0770AA6DF491A8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Development and modernization of civilian artificial intelligence research infrastructure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F3CEB18348B4952B1B8B7932B1BE199" commented="no"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public-private partnerships relating to artificial intelligence, with the following:</text>
            <clause id="H5A33C589CB8B40C1916DBACB362B3A3B">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>The Department of Energy.</text> </clause> <clause id="HC643511BB9FD4C30BF6E48447637D2C7"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HB86BAC75019E4117B33534C7436B63D3">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>The National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text> </clause> <clause id="H59237BB2B10647F1A267A4D74AFBB197"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>The National Science Foundation.</text>
            </clause>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF314100FFB8B486CA84E6EDC970F3FB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of certain regulatory barriers</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Transportation, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall identify regulatory barriers to the adoption of artificial intelligence in the following sectors:</text><paragraph id="HFFDB06F5F392491EA472358301FC5CF5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Healthcare.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B66C3C6E27A44ABA6FE7AB6CC0596B0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Scientific research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FFBC1BBF3854D48AB60C8A43059CA9E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDF26DEC91B04F77B299AD850B22C61D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other sector the Director determines relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF019D7F4AC146E6AA5F869472C00202" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>NIST report</header><paragraph id="HD7A19D532DDD4CAA8037B96A4F8D793A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on measures, including internal review protocols, third-party audits, and public disclosure requirements, as appropriate, to detect and prevent security risks and ideological bias in data, training methods, or decision outcomes relating to artificial intelligence. The report shall include information relating to the criteria utilized in Federal agencies to assess such risks and bias, and any corrective measures taken relating thereto.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF0190B65A174ADBA019A0EF6770EEBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Means of submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology may submit the report under paragraph (1) as part of an update to the framework under subsection (c) of section 22A of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h–1</external-xref>) or another report the Director is to submit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D97795E59B5490889AC67DC7D01B2E2" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

