<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5AF07721427E47C48D205615F4E99A5C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5893 IH: Guaranteed Uninterrupted Access to Retiree Disbursements Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5893</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide funding for administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration during any lapse in appropriations during fiscal year 2026, to require that the Social Security Administration be responsive to Congressional offices during such a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFE87F06566DF401FB0FC40354D0F505E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2A31A38370204001AE8CBDCEAB1A8D22" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteed Uninterrupted Access to Retiree Disbursements Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GUARD Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA15275330C514C9980E8A703113DB1EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Funding for administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for fiscal year 2026 are not in effect, such sums as are necessary for administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration.</text></section> <section id="H5D265E884173454093470847B2529A93"><enum>3.</enum><header>Operations during lapse in appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall ensure that, during any lapse in appropriations occurring during fiscal year 2026, the Social Security Administration carries out all functions, including responding to communications from Congressional offices, that the Administration would carry out in the absence of such a lapse.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

