<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HFE928BD899D14905B262E07205EAEC7E" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>94 HR 4305 : Destroying Unnecessary, Misaligned, and Prohibitive Red Tape Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4305</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration to establish a Red Tape Hotline to receive notifications of burdensome agency rules, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H7533CF060CAE44B8A2FA3FBAC558B620"><section id="H93505985524640D4BB08CE4205458902" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Destroying Unnecessary, Misaligned, and Prohibitive Red Tape Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DUMP Red Tape Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1097BF15835E445E8C5E6A56259EBD10" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Red Tape Hotline</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/305">Public Law 94–305</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/634c">15 U.S.C. 634c</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDF819AD7EB0A4FF5BB304EA95DD0C03E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H1FD2C576162244B582047821AAA916D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Red Tape Hotline</header><paragraph id="HC3DD6B2CBA57482EB07EFD0D0F962CC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief Counsel for Advocacy shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE692D531CAEA4345B926966CE6949DC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish, operate, and maintain a hotline, to be known as the <quote>Red Tape Hotline</quote> to receive a notification from a small entity relating to the burden of complying with a rule, guidance, policy statement, or other activity of an agency that is applicable to such concern;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC931EF27C1FA41B49C9590115D8B8D6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an email address, submission form, phone number, or such other method as determined appropriate by the Chief Counsel for small entities to submit such notifications to such hotline; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAB0A42705F84249946770DB96789DEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a website providing such email address, submission form, phone number, or other method in a manner that is easily accessible.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80D908D201654F2DACEDE1D6B0C9EACC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Chief Counsel for Advocacy shall submit to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and Congress a report on the Red Tape Hotline that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HF2A3F68F18D8407081BC81BF008AF39E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rules, guidance, policy statements, and other activities for which notifications are most frequently received, including the affected industry sectors for such rules, guidance, policy statements, or other activities (as applicable);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEB3A4A404E34A04A544BF70190985A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the notifications received, including the type of small entity or other organization that submitted the notification and the geographic area and industry category from which the notification was sent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB630F2398F2246E190D652C2423DD0B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of the agency that issued each such rule, guidance, policy statement, or engaged in such other activity, including an identification of which such rule, guidance, or policy statement such agency issued or an explanation of which such other activity the agency engaged in, as applicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D8B8AA272434EDD9DC48EFBB2EECCEA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for each agency that issued such a rule, guidance, policy statement, or engaged in such other activity, for reducing the burden of such rule, guidance, policy statement, or other activity on small entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4521317ABA4640BFBB87EDA34DE3C020"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of actions taken by the Chief Counsel to address such rules, guidance, policy statements, and other activities, including any such rules, guidance, policy statements, or other activities (as applicable) for which the Chief Counsel submitted comments or analysis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36E9971B67FA4C3B80B7D2B544F50AD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HE7635FFBB6324CDC8CFD4FDC49D2488C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF03BF1F9A46947C48B205119721EF96F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terms <quote>rule</quote> and <quote>small entity</quote> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 601 of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20251203" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 3, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

