<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6D4CE84A437F448A9633B57F581DE854" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>108 HR 6262 IH: Taiwan Interpol Endorsement and Inclusion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to develop a strategy to obtain membership status for Taiwan in the International Criminal Police Organization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H081F167D64434E1C82DA385D741B279B" style="OLC"><section id="H673CBD2EF9194C75B63579B7F5D5E441" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan Interpol Endorsement and Inclusion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD1F78722DD78445C80852C01ACF5C438"><enum>2.</enum><header>Participation of Taiwan in the International Criminal Police Organization</header><subsection id="H50FDFF4FF81046868FA802C9DE972155"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H469A0B8A9DB449A38E5C02CF087B5515"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Taiwan is an important contributor to peace and stability around the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7E3B528E51746A1A4CC3D0553DC35AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Taiwan Relations Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>) states that it is the policy of the United States <quote>to preserve and promote extensive, close, and friendly commercial, cultural, and other relations between the people of the United States and the people of Taiwan</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9F5A9C2EF644525983E88AC94D1DB73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States, in the 1994 Taiwan Policy Review, declared its intention to support Taiwan's participation in appropriate international organizations and has consistently reiterated that support.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H518A94C2AB7F4C5FB71EC01D9AB0B28A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Following the enactment of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/235">Public Law 108–235</external-xref>, a law authorizing the Secretary of State to initiate and implement a plan to endorse and obtain observer status for Taiwan at the annual summit of the World Health Assembly and subsequent advocacy by the United States, Taiwan was granted observer status to the World Health Assembly between 2009 and 2016 under the name <quote>Chinese Taipei</quote>. Both prior to and in its capacity as an observer, Taiwan contributed significantly to the international community's collective efforts in pandemic control, monitoring, early warning, and other related matters. Since 2016, the World Health Assembly has rejected any bids for Taiwan’s inclusion as an observer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41FF99DCABA1499AA1EFE168F70F424A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Safety, security, and peace is important to every citizen of the world, and shared information ensuring wide assistance among police authorities of nations for expeditious dissemination of information regarding criminal activities greatly assists in these efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5F37C6A79034D6496072F3A0FEF87A8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Direct and unobstructed participation in the International Criminal Police Organization (Interpol) is beneficial for all nations and their police authorities. Internationally shared information with authorized police authorities are vital to peacekeeping efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0AC0EF356BB44ECA0884CA6DF6B81C8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>With a history dating back to 1914, the role of Interpol is defined in its constitution: <quote>To ensure and promote the widest possible mutual assistance between all criminal police authorities within the limits of the laws existing in the different countries and in the spirit of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1156469042A415088F05572ECCE8734"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ongoing international threats, including international networks of terrorism, show the ongoing necessity to be ever inclusive of nations willing to work together to combat criminal activity. The ability of police authorities to coordinate, preempt, and act swiftly and in unison is an essential element of crisis prevention and response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55EB7BAE2A56473EB1D395CB2BA0DED3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Taiwan maintained full membership in Interpol starting in 1964 through its National Police Administration but was ejected in 1984 when the People's Republic of China (PRC) applied for membership.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26A56D0B24034279AA2A5F2D0B8E53C3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Nonmembership in Interpol prevents Taiwan from gaining access to Interpol’s I–24/7 global police communications system, which provides real-time information on criminals and global criminal activities. Taiwan is relegated to second-hand information from friendly nations, including the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94EB5FEEF3A942F2BCAB637BB7D6A75B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Taiwan is unable to swiftly share information on criminals and suspicious activity with the international community, leaving a huge void in the global crime-fighting efforts and leaving the entire world at risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3696B17B284EC59C6762FDEFF8034A"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interpol’s constitution allows for observers at its meetings by <quote>police bodies which are not members of the Organization</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF7987C3E4AB48C18DDEC4D21C9111D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It should be the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HA44979E141D64BE8B768E1C00B0EF842"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to advocate, as appropriate—</text><subparagraph id="HD38F31075D1043E088B0C735CF6D3A20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for Taiwan’s membership in all international organizations, including Interpol, and in which the United States is also a participant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BC74EE341D9413D96EFCD45B2EA789B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for Taiwan to be granted full membership status in other appropriate international organizations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B4765CAD44847608C761F92C1600C33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to instruct, as appropriate, representatives of the United States Government in all organizations described in paragraph (1) to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to advocate for Taiwan's membership or observer status in such organizations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56F788475C854038A63293AAF3555182"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for the President or the President's designees to advocate, as appropriate, for Taiwan's membership or observer status in all organizations described in paragraph (1) as part of any relevant bilateral engagements between the United States and the People's Republic of China, including leader summits and the U.S.-China Comprehensive Economic Dialogue.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB34C5322DA10429496D16A8C5BCE4ABF" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Taiwan’s participation in Interpol</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall—</text><paragraph id="H1CD02F7ED9D3442D8C9B9596D83C5B84" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a strategy to—</text><subparagraph id="HBB5934F8F0864172B6FE9AC01B9E5AF9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obtain membership status for Taiwan in Interpol and at other related meetings, activities, and mechanisms thereafter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H369830CF6AC342F59973599F7FA7180B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage meaningful interaction, including information sharing, with U.S. National Central Bureau (Interpol Washington) and Taiwan on issues related to global crime fighting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06E2AB5981774582961343055DE92131" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involve Taiwan in Interpol meetings, events, and related activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBB4295473AA4910A5CD0051447B6B76" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in certain cases as appropriate and in alignment with United States interests, assist Taiwan in increasing its economic, security, and diplomatic engagement with countries in the Indo-Pacific region and around the world; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403E40DD2F2847838233633E14F717A7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instruct Interpol Washington to officially request membership status for Taiwan in Interpol and to actively urge Interpol member states to support such membership status and participation for Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F17DC3694D44CBBAB9EFE5D2CA0FFC3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with Interpol Washington, shall transmit to Congress a report, in unclassified form, describing the United States strategy to endorse and obtain observer status or membership status for Taiwan in appropriate international organizations, including Interpol, and at other related meetings, activities, and mechanisms thereafter. The report shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HFDEC851F3D314D2AAA53C967B10A0937"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the efforts the Secretary has made to encourage member states to promote Taiwan's bids to obtain observer status or membership status in appropriate international organizations, including Interpol.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A425644A02488C9CE3E99F1813D767"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the actions the Secretary will take to endorse and obtain observer status or membership status for Taiwan in appropriate international organizations, including Interpol, and at other related meetings, activities, and mechanisms thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE96DC267B22B481A8FE3D63E2607DA82"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H1407B9BD9DBB40BBAE282C0A666A48EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the U.S. National Central Bureau (Interpol Washington) shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on any and all threats posed to Taiwan’s criminal intelligence as a result of their non-member and non-observer status in the International Criminal Police Organization (Interpol) and, therefore, Taiwan’s lack of access to Interpol communications and data.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC18CD9BDC29F45ABAD902999B5672BEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

