<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HF13D4DF61763446F94D3DF7F13227956" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>109 HR 7022 : Mystic Alerts Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7022</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the transmission of emergency alerts by satellite, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HB714D4BF126B4CD0AF956BBADAC0427D"><section id="HC66A002BF6E548BCAE2558C1B65332DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mystic Alerts Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4A063AF4EAED48BAB4A0359FBB49A4B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transmission of emergency alerts by satellite</header><subsection id="H82B6ED20C74A40E09B5D1AC92E1DAD0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Service provider election</header><paragraph id="HE5BC96C1208F417D87720FBAF159FC48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the effective date of the final rule required to be issued under subsection (b), each covered service provider shall file an election with the Federal Communications Commission with respect to whether the provider intends to transmit emergency alerts by satellite to the subscribers of the commercial mobile service of the provider who receive such service on devices capable of receiving such alerts, in addition to the transmission of emergency alerts under the Warning Alert, and Response Network Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30E030CD44D04E37B628454D22AD2222"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification; agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a provider elects to transmit emergency alerts to subscribers by satellite under paragraph (1), the provider shall—</text><subparagraph id="H96A98DA954EB4F3CA9466C7F44C58A7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the Commission of that election; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56B5B6F011E34B469EA1CDFE587563BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agree to transmit such alerts in a manner consistent with the technical standards, protocols, procedures, and other technical requirements implemented by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17E2D82F81DA401AA5E5BECEF3AD2627"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Election not to transmit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a provider elects not to transmit emergency alerts by satellite under paragraph (1), the provider shall provide notice to new and existing subscribers described in such paragraph of that election in the same manner that is required under subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 602(b)(1) of the Warning, Alert, and Response Network Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23B90CC2396B4739BC6CE6315F022EF1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consumer choice to opt out</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a provider elects to transmit emergency alerts to subscribers of such service by satellite under paragraph (1), the provider shall prevent the device of any such subscriber that opts out of receiving emergency alerts pursuant to section 602(b)(2)(E) of the Warning, Alert, and Response Network Act, or classes of such alerts, from receiving such alerts by satellite.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F64AF4C48B34E0CB012A49C228146B5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No fee for service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a provider elects to transmit emergency alerts to subscribers by satellite under paragraph (1), the provider may not impose a separate or additional charge for such transmission or capability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA8F487A975144BD8943E0EF59EC4AC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Satellite alert regulations</header><paragraph id="H9D5361A57F5F433EB9DBEED652C49357"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of proposed rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall publish a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking to establish any requirements necessary to facilitate the satellite alerting capability of covered service providers. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF5C9B221384082803A53717AA9EFED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements required by paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC28E7E9668174DD8A29B4BC21302A05A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take into account the capability of—</text><clause id="HAF433FAB963E4CFF8EE2356B6434B89F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>satellites to transmit emergency alerts; and </text></clause><clause id="HD7C811B2059E4BD1BE9B0EE6504818C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>mobile devices to receive and display such alerts; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F1CC73DAA5E482EA7BB01146E3019BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>minimize the impact of emergency alerting on other voice and data communications, including 9–1–1 communications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32BFAD590DBB464B999E90E3A5310B3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, issue a final rule establishing the requirements described under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA85F33A47342FAB536BE11A3D994AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date of rule</header><subparagraph id="HFB5320F98F2D40CBB3D20A022A849942"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Date</header><text>The effective date of the final rule described under paragraph (3) shall be the later of—</text><clause id="H7B8AD855930A4813B8102136E68ED9DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>36 months after publication of the final rule in the Federal Register; or</text></clause><clause id="HF80C9359651E4F9ABEF8E126486CD387"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">12 months after the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency implement any standards, protocols, or procedures necessary to support the transmission of emergency alerts from alert originators to covered service providers, the Secretary and the Administrator shall notify the Commission of such implementation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA034CA730E7E46AD8DAD6106A646F50B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall notify the Commission of the implementation of any standards, protocols, or procedures described under subparagraph (A)(ii) for the purpose of determining the effective date of the final rule described under paragraph (3). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H766E149DBC5146A89666BFFC08D63C6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><paragraph id="H23D516F503DD4DB9A292EC23765A67B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered service provider (including its officers, directors, employees, vendors, and agents) that transmits emergency alerts by satellite and meets its obligations under this Act shall not be liable to any subscriber to, or user of, such person’s service or equipment for—</text><subparagraph id="HC23D60813F664788B3FBA48DAEE809EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any act or omission related to or any harm resulting from the transmission of, or failure to transmit, an emergency alert by satellite; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB4F08712660439798B087A9218EC73C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the release to a government agency or entity, public safety, fire service, law enforcement official, emergency medical service, or emergency facility of subscriber information used in connection with delivering such an alert.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CAA6E5842F544A1AACB82DAC0917255"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election not to transmit alerts by satellite</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The election by a covered service provider under subsection (a)(3) not to transmit emergency alerts by satellite shall not, by itself, provide a basis for liability against the provider (including its officers, directors, employees, vendors, and agents).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF4056D58C2C4519B27BC1D5CF0AF5B5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered service provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, <quote>covered service provider</quote> means a provider of commercial mobile service that—</text><paragraph id="H2B9DB865AA0B40279FBBD0CC86C76F7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>voluntarily elects to transmit emergency alerts under section 602(b) of the Warning, Alert, and Response Network Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/347">Public Law 109–347</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1201">42 U.S.C. 1201</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H195D5BF0839644A4AF9919FE02A6D58F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes satellite voice and data communications service available to subscribers of the commercial mobile service of the provider. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260420" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 20, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

