<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF13D4DF61763446F94D3DF7F13227956" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>109 HR 7022 IH: Mystic Alerts Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7022</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260112">January 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the transmission of emergency alerts by satellite, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD09B5485929542988205905B79A65038" style="OLC"><section id="HB6DAC02CF7EF4DE5BC0486CD62FDA1F7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mystic Alerts Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4175067C6DAF409793B7DA94D0524F40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transmission of emergency alerts by satellite</header><subsection id="H97B74FC5270B4838AC0B6852F27F2C05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Service provider election</header><paragraph id="H5CC2D2DC820548509F6B2F067EBC0C22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each provider of commercial mobile service that voluntarily elects to transmit emergency alerts under section 602(b) of the Warning, Alert, and Response Network Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/347">Public Law 109–347</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1201">42 U.S.C. 1201</external-xref>) shall file an election with the Federal Communications Commission with respect to whether the provider intends to also transmit such alerts by satellite to the subscribers or users of the commercial mobile service of the provider.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FB4F32F993143F091B80EE938F689DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification; agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a provider described under paragraph (1) elects to transmit emergency alerts to subscribers or users by satellite, the provider shall—</text><subparagraph id="H782C9CBED3104611BC0690D93F67AC22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the Commission of that election; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE67D66C90F14A67A962B16C8455DC3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agree to transmit such alerts in a manner consistent with the technical standards, protocols, procedures, and other technical requirements implemented by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3F10908706B4959A1E4E3257DC977EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Election not to transmit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a provider elects not to transmit emergency alerts by satellite under paragraph (1), the provider shall provide notice to new and existing subscribers and users of the commercial mobile service of the provider of that election in the same manner that is required under subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 602(b)(1) of the Warning, Alert, and Response Network Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D18D41A644F4CD48A295B7608A9E9F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consumer choice to opt out</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a provider of commercial mobile service described under paragraph (1) elects to transmit emergency alerts to subscribers and users by satellite, the provider shall prevent the device of any subscriber or user that opts out of receiving emergency alerts pursuant to section 602(b)(2)(E) of the Warning, Alert, and Response Network Act, or classes of such alerts, from receiving such alerts by satellite.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59C8195E79044F478D466E2416347E54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Satellite alert regulations</header><paragraph id="H1CE2AE7C3BDF466C9D75BAF53ED33B9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of proposed rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall publish a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking to establish relevant technical standards, protocols, procedures, interoperability requirements, and other technical requirements necessary to enable satellite alerting capability for providers of commercial mobile service that voluntarily elect to transmit emergency alerts, including standards for training such providers on enabling such capability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE07A2C60725A48379DF20F7C9F449FFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, issue a final rule establishing the standards, protocols, procedures, and requirements described under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

