<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26013-2MJ-RR-KT8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3588 IS: School Access to Naloxone Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3588</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide funding for trained school personnel to administer drugs and devices for emergency treatment of known or suspected opioid overdose, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA096A1F97C324B74B0F7E59B0A448F99"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEB606E29A9E943E6907C9585E6287325"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>School Access to Naloxone Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3681797ADDAE429F83E5F426E355D852"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for reducing opioid overdose deaths</header><subsection id="HE4A0BEEBB8A243B1A780B644291EDAC7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 544(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd-3">42 U.S.C. 290dd–3(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1B260EDD1D8F4EE4A703C8B86CB52B4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or administering</quote> after <quote>prescribing</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF81237DB8842419585CDB24544310BCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or on the administration of</quote> after <quote>prescribing of</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF96BA556DC6848E39AA3CF8A73D5D403"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 544(g) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd-3">42 U.S.C. 290dd–3(g)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>to carry out this section</quote> and inserting <quote>to carry out this section and section 544A</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA4EC336DF348464184A0AE5A8784043D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for reducing opioid overdose deaths in elementary and secondary schools</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 544 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd-3">42 U.S.C. 290dd–3</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9122A26F3524483B9D01FD62452A837"><section id="H0078959A946B407983B63A4F464BACD7"><enum>544A.</enum><header>Reducing opioid overdose deaths in elementary and secondary schools</header><subsection id="H34C7391D2FCD425DA10F9C1DADA92E73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to provide for the administration, at public and private elementary and secondary schools under the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, of drugs and devices for emergency treatment of known or suspected opioid overdose.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB05C5537CEA444609F7636D3DB87D1E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing—</text><paragraph id="HE001B59A92B948FB8EB801FBE03348D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the information required under section 544(b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A193E1A14844A71BC1134AFFB02320B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the certifications specified in subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA56EBCEC147B49A8B044F5B5F5594CA4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary shall require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD40D8A0BF7F54C0890BB865C3F4BB23E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The certifications specified in this subsection, with respect to each elementary school and secondary school in the eligible entity’s jurisdiction, are the following:</text><paragraph id="H031E67B9C9E64480A1431DB2F688FB95"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The school has in place a program under which the school will permit trained personnel of the school to administer drugs or devices for purposes of providing emergency treatment of known or suspected opioid overdose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BFC3F6F216F4B769DFC66A9B83032F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The school will maintain a supply of such drugs and devices in a location that is easily accessible to trained personnel of the school for the purpose of administering such drugs and devices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H661D5DC1ACD54EE6A8AB6FD3B423242F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The school has in place a plan for having on the premises of the school during all operating hours one or more individuals who are such trained personnel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB66D70F430742549E07D4668823B26D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State attorney general of the State in which the school is located certifies that the State—</text><subparagraph id="HA45A76B090DA4D0095675CE5DF38058D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has reviewed any applicable civil liability protection law to determine the application of such law with regard to elementary and secondary school trained personnel who may administer drugs and devices for emergency treatment in the case of a known or suspected opioid overdose; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAADDDE3A9304A8EA059E1881BA2A0FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has concluded that such law provides adequate civil liability protection applicable to such trained personnel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE519831CFD44917863E12E313F0BDEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC826EE2DA7D94EE085D54FCFB3C4FCF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>civil liability protection law</term> means a State law offering legal protection to individuals who give aid in an emergency to an individual who is ill, in peril, or otherwise incapacitated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16F1A7D0BB0F4C1AB91660FFEC59971F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 544.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D93ED2F7804038902F6FC348BDE794"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>trained personnel</term> means, with respect to an elementary or secondary school, an individual—</text><subparagraph id="H260314A3B49C431F921C6E97FE62195F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is a school nurse, a trained school-based health center staff member, or another individual designated by the principal or other appropriate administrative staff of the school to administer drugs or devices for emergency treatment in the case of a known or suspected opioid overdose;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A4E4A65F56E435083C45E6FC41066CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who has received training in the administration of such drugs or devices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DD668A5608349049CDDC1EE40E80E91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whose training in the administration of such drugs or devices meets appropriate medical standards and has been documented by appropriate administrative staff of the school.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

