<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC26873-TY3-55-2HF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4609 IS: Strategy for Crisis Management Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4609</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy for crisis management in the South China Sea, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strategy for Crisis Management Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id79440d8f1b194e8ab3516dfccbd1b523"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy for crisis management in South China Sea</header><subsection id="id38b5fd3209ab42e2b2edf84235d06f1e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Crisis defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>crisis</term> means an incident or situation that creates a condition of such national security importance that the President or the Secretary of Defense may consider a commitment of the United States Armed Forces or Department resources, or the initiation of activities by the Department of Defense, to achieve or defend national objectives.</text></subsection><subsection id="id88c6322cda30460a8e93351793b503ff"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a strategy for crisis management in the South China Sea that—</text><paragraph id="id86938f456eac49ed8040a9bb1ed02286"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies the exact locations of the most likely flashpoints in the South China Sea that could lead to scenarios of crises short of war that would require heightened interagency and international coordination; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id501b93d8e76f4102a08fc0fcf6b7174b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes, for each major likely flashpoint, a crisis playbook with sequenced response options and a plan for coordination with foreign partners.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6602355aeee04576bb824eb34f756cb3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (b) shall be designed—</text><paragraph id="idf25e24d493b44d4a8a568100ab2ccbff"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to deny the aim of the People’s Republic of China and deter further People’s Republic of China provocation or actions that expand the crisis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d4ba6f6a14c448d984b6ac98e906612"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure the safety of United States citizens and residents in the region and in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id15f4872da9f2475eb9b14babb2c516eb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure the safety of members of the United States Armed Forces in the region, including safety from accidents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a0eb32cdfb94536b14e8c16a9f4454c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to preserve United States economic interests in the region, including protecting key trade and commerce routes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id290f8067f24048fd8fccb7dc383de6b8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to protect United States national security interests, including by upholding treaty obligations and protecting allies and partners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f74512783fc4a28881e30b7aa55177a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to manage possible escalation into combat operations by taking opportunities for de-escalation and maintaining strategic stability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcf382566e4ea4b009e543e1feba56cbf"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Crisis playbooks</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b1705585321431fb173c966879b592e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each crisis playbook required by subsection (b)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="id58bf8412da9a4cb4b4d84d8058237dcc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be developed by the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the applicable Chief of Mission, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the head of any other relevant agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f43a48582ac44cc9b32284a7c89db76"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be informed by the intelligence community and relevant experts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fedaa59463241d6bb59b770cbda1028"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each crisis playbook shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="iddb3309d0d02b4364af68244d1b4bf310"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of specific indicators that would elevate a scenario from a baseline of gray-zone conditions to the level of a crisis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c4a2b98f02e4819a8f63daf9185e2d6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not less than one planning scenario that could lead to crisis, with clearly identified assumptions, phases, and likely branches.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33e4999b4f5b4eaab4b2e738c001125d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Anticipated decision points and recommended options, sequenced across all identified phases. The Secretary of Defense shall consider at least the following types of recommended options:</text><clause id="ida9773d12c01749afac51b31eae25774e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Response options for Department action, across the range of possible decisions across the Department, including force employment, military posture, Department official statements or travel, engagements or public announcements, capability demonstrations or tests.</text></clause><clause id="id51d048fc90684d618fbc5d208c725bda"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Recommendations for types of ongoing Department activities to consider ceasing, reducing, or changing in scale or type.</text></clause><clause id="ide350ba5e859c45218adbfb96c8bbc1d8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Diplomatic and economic options, developed in coordination with the Secretary of State, the applicable Chief of Mission, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the head of any other relevant agency, to accompany the options for the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id254bb70b3ba04e3eb6c78374dafee27f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Each option recommended under subparagraph (C) shall include a cost-benefit-risk analysis, specifically—</text><clause id="id7d2902c437df4a92930f27ad252a18ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the projected benefit of the option;</text></clause><clause id="idd4fd34c296bf4974adf1ea5599088ae8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the assessed risk to members of the United States Armed Forces;</text></clause><clause id="idf1b044dcc41c4180870b3b7a1a76e80d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the estimated financial cost;</text></clause><clause id="ida324b733e49a48e79957150843d28dc7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the projected humanitarian impact, including the impact on local civilians;</text></clause><clause id="id3ef61f0649ee46838a4d3c357e6fd400"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the projected impact to escalation risk; and</text></clause><clause id="id202972ad70244832bcaeee99bfc8440a"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any accompanying risk mitigation strategies.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb79341b1604046a38354c657a765891c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A list of possible off-ramps, including a description of indicators of such off-ramps and recommendations of options for the Secretary of Defense to take advantage of such off-ramps.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28cf9dfbece04912bf5fc4d0517be44a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An engagement plan—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb89a8e5b1ebb4984ab9359937a8132c6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for streamlined communication and coordination with relevant foreign partners during each phase of the crisis to design collective diplomatic, economic and military responses to People’s Republic of China coercion and avoid potential actions that could unnecessarily provoke or exacerbate a tense situation; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f852f90cb6d46178bf2d5dd2a625b98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that identifies recommendations for specific immediate actions the Secretary of Defense should take now to pre-coordinate with foreign partners.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id001292b084ae40a7af0c7d5b1d9ed004"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Semiannual review</header><text>Not less frequently than semiannually, the Secretary of Defense shall review, update as necessary, and validate each crisis playbook developed under subsection (b)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="idc6410e4686004c28bb6b8c44c1f649f3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Interim report</header><paragraph id="id5121293877cb4c99a997752409837c37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a progress report that—</text><subparagraph id="id36cb5d91d72b47ae89224b770c5b5fbd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>details the list of locations and scenarios identified under subsection (b)(1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b773e5bd6414f78b940f79c72597726"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides a status update on the development of the crisis playbook required by subsection (b)(2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00bc43fe6d6645049537bc5cf4c9625f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sets forth a plan for the completion of such playbooks not later than March 2027; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9abfc1f5b0a34fdea00d7517e38af424"><enum>(D)</enum><text>details the process by which such playbooks will be reviewed, updated as necessary, and validated under subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38aeec58e95746dca51a0552203321ec"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The interim report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idde20f065f9b8419da25c0a7aa1d75bee"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="id3aa971fb1ef04bd791cefbfe90eeb3b3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate the House of Representatives a report that summarizes the strategy developed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5aa28818cd6f491b819d49a0cf128cfd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id092b366c0462466d93aa13ff356b488d"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require the options set forth in a playbook developed under subsection (b)(2) to be the only options considered or followed in a crisis scenario.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

