<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA856272E081B4F8EA62A1B75E569A18B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 993 IH: Recognizing and expressing support for the Iranian people protesting for a free and democratic Iran.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 993</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260113">January 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and expressing support for the Iranian people protesting for a free and democratic Iran.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, for nearly five decades, the people of Iran have endured brutal repression under the Islamic Republic, a regime that denies basic human rights, silences dissidents, and responds to peaceful protest with violence;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, once again, the people of Iran are courageously taking to the streets to demand economic opportunity, human rights, dignity, and freedom;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Islamic Republic has responded to the ongoing protests with brutality by killing protestors, arresting thousands, and restricting internet access and telephone lines;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the people of Iran are in part protesting the Islamic regime’s economic mismanagement, corruption, internal suppression, and unjust executions;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas access to free expression, open information, and uncensored communication are fundamental human rights;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the inspiring 2022 Women, Life, Freedom protests demanded an end to the Islamic Republic and its violence, including against Iranian women and ethnic minorities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the barbaric so-called morality police and other arms of state suppression have a lengthy history of repressing the Iranian people’s fundamental freedoms, including the freedom to assemble, the freedom of religion, women’s rights, and LGBTQ rights;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Islamic regime has engaged in systematic efforts to intimidate, harass, detain, and harm political dissidents, activists, and journalists both within Iran and beyond its borders;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the people of Iran deserve the right to dignity, democracy, and self-determination and to be free from the brutality of the Islamic Republic; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on January 26, 2023, the United States House of Representatives passed House Concurrent Resolution 7, commending the bravery, courage, and resolve of the Iranian people: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9AF1FF94D9A24AFABE90FE4690A5FCEF"> 
<section id="H7391AE2ED3F346FB98D956C3B620D8DB" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HD477CAC6D0874A8897C4111974E2FB57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the bravery and resolve of the Iranian people in their fight for a free and democratic Iran;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70DA905159B648818906AE456D775935"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strongly condemns the brutality of the Islamic Republic, which uses violent military force to suppress civilian protesters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H498758CF4A8642AA88434FD1E1330920"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demands that the Iranian regime cease its threats, intimidation, and violence against peaceful protesters, release all political prisoners, and allow unhindered medical assistance to demonstrators wounded by the regime’s violent repression;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H513A8BF508154217B998DC681A161FBA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the right of the Iranian people to freely determine, through free and fair elections, the nature of their political regime;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1BF0954E0764DB2A671D963A104AAE5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges immediate expansion of unrestricted internet access and civilian lines of communication across Iran; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H925DD5903171480198301DA7CDE3EB7C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>implores the Government of the United States to work in coordination with its allies to consider and implement concrete measures to deter further lethal violence against protesters.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

