<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H963812CD50D84498A90C4EB87083274A" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7388 : Smart Space Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7388</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of General Services to convene consultation meetings to identify alternative financing solutions for the construction of new public buildings that will reduce costs to the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HFCAEC70F238746BCB0C017BCC81895C3"><section id="H14E74A2EF0494B44AA2959CF5AFE2DC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smart Space Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA081DA6E9D3543D68F0F50AC85463A90"><enum>2.</enum><header>Project recommendations</header><subsection id="HFEE883A4CD7B4FC9B5069C3FCCE9859B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Meetings and consultations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall convene consultation meetings to identify alternative financing solutions for the construction or renovation of public buildings, or necessary work to prepare such buildings for disposal that will reduce costs to the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC712E6669E5446E983C5FED11F83F29C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>In convening consultation meetings under subsection (a), the Administrator shall include—</text><paragraph id="HC268CF6F842A4212A6AF04D6D57B38B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>experts related to private commercial real estate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0182B4299F1B48729A7CFD673CB0D39A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experts related to Federal real estate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B243B07640F4833B3FD15FD0AB956AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if available, State, including the District of Columbia, real estate experts experienced with leveraging private financing for public buildings and facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H510BAA54DA204D5F8F553638CBA29D60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report and recommendations</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the President—</text><paragraph id="HF58C415A4B0E48538D6AAAFCE0FD34C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations on types of public-private partnerships and alternative financing methods best suited for meeting the public building needs of the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52A95D5F01724142A25DA0ABD77EC122"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of recommended projects related to public buildings for which such methods should be used with details on which methods and types of public-private partnerships are recommended for each project.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H688A20EBCCBE414B85053BB390637C2A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recommended project list</header><text>In submitting a list of recommended projects under subsection (c)(2), the Administrator shall submit projects that the Administrator determines—</text><paragraph id="H6E39561480164133849F10D0BC21E26F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve core missions of the Federal Government for which maintaining the functions in federally owned space over the long-term is critical;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E61A04B24354AFC92087743D2B3C3AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will result in either consolidations or relocations of Federal departments or agencies out of costly, inefficient, and underutilized space that the Administrator intends to sell or dispose of once vacated; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H111E5E35FE12422B831D2F4414959C92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to standard office space, will result in meeting a minimum building utilization of 60 percent or greater as defined in section 2302 of the Thomas R. Carper Water Resources Development Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/584">40 U.S.C. 584</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCACBA2A7F0664B729FC6673549CEB66C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transparency</header><paragraph id="HE6BAF164267D45079BEB2874C25CC92D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Administrator shall submit the report under subsection (c) to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure in the House and the Committee on Environment and Public Works in the Senate and make such report publicly available on the website of the General Services Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3079BAE19C9A4AA4A0252817C1495B10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeline</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall maintain on the website of the General Services Administration information on the process under this Act, including any timelines and milestones.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB046BFCD0C6A45BDAF32B783494ADE8E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Delays</header><text>The Administrator shall report directly to the President and Congress any delays with respect to the timing and milestones described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE273BA76B314684A475A0584489C907"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Meetings pursuant to subsection (a) shall be noticed and open to the public and shall not be subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D82A7C9DCBE43049FE35699B6C61879"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC545F8440B1D400C8ED85DB1F3D1FB0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alternative financing; public-private partnership</header><text>The terms <quote>alternative financing</quote> and <quote>public-private partnership</quote> may include—</text><subparagraph id="H48B7A281E5ED49A1B84A0C62B95598A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agreements that reflect an obligation by a non-Federal entity to design, build, finance, operate, and maintain an asset, or a combination thereof; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EA5248E5A5F4C62A27A05EC1C184349"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a ground-lease to a non-Federal party with a subsequent lease back of the improvements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H519E0D7E73F849E68D06BD825B1F0CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public building</header><text>The term <quote>public building</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3301 of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260324" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 24, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

