<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDCE6BD0A27114469A63A0DE3FCC2BCB3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8169 IH: Export Control Enforcement and Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8169</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260330">March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to provide for expedited consideration of proposals for additions to, removals from, or other modifications with respect to entities on the Entity List, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA69880EC4B3247869719B35636086371" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4959AE46382D4751AC182D32ED869A5A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Export Control Enforcement and Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9206C3C981024E86AC05CB084B38373C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited consideration of proposals for additions to, removals from, or other modifications with respect to entities on the Entity List</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1754 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H098C969F082B4E44ACADFB6F760ACA41" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H7EC5709FFAAA46F5A02A18782A3ED416"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expedited consideration of proposals for additions to, removals from, or other modifications with respect to entities on the Entity List</header> 
<paragraph id="HB7CFA66D38DC400EB65B59CC89C5F088"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member of the End-User Review Committee may submit a proposal directly to the Committee requesting a vote of all members of the Committee for additions to, removals from, or other modifications with respect to the Entity List. A proposal to add an entity to the Entity List shall be made in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA8D900F1F694E6DA502B0D2C9C13C30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4)(B), the End-User Review Committee shall vote to approve or disapprove a proposal submitted under paragraph (1) not later than 30 days after the date on which the proposal is submitted to the Committee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F3C1A4C3C6C4780AEAFBF06941A8582">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
                        <header>Additional information</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair of the End-User Review Committee, with the concurrence of the member of the Committee that submitted a proposal under paragraph (1), may suspend for an additional 15 days the time period specified in paragraph (2) with respect to consideration of the proposal if the Chair and the member determine that additional information is required in order to make a determination with respect to the proposal, including the impact and effect of the proposal.</text>
                    </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5B5575CE315428EA9985FA6811F5930"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additions to the Entity List</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD7C67F1D23B743F9951C90E35A7740FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity may be added to the Entity List if the End-User Review Committee by majority vote of its members has determined that the entity has engaged, is engaged, or is at risk of engaging in activities contrary to the national security or foreign policy interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8CC7B67647C4A1AA1B7614F5775B0E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Licensing policy</header> <clause id="H436FE91C4C184E5FB440DCA90BB9020D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), there shall be in effect a policy of presumption of denial for all applications for a license to export, reexport, or in-country transfer any item subject to the Export Administration Regulations if an entity added to the Entity List under this subsection is or would be a party to a transaction with respect to which the application applies.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H11604E825CFC49B7BA6F54E06BA1A496"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The licensing policy required by clause (i) shall not apply with respect an entity described in such clause if the members of the End-User Review Committee that voted to add the entity to the Entity List under this subsection agree by majority vote of such members to apply a different policy with respect to the entity for all or specific types of items subject to the Export Administration Regulations that would be in the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68B67F863246423BBB2536EEB475BF24"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to limit or otherwise affect the escalation procedures described in part 750 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CFB35EC819D4C0391F09D1B67E54293"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDE837D881A0F474BA3C9F1C98DA990F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member of the End-User Review Committee shall have 1 vote with respect to matters described in this subsection. The chairperson of the Committee shall not have the authority to make determinations or override any voting decision with respect to such matters.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5C1C9D6848B4DC8AD416A9BB41DCA0F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Suspension of voting period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chairperson of the End-User Review Committee may suspend the 30-day voting period described in paragraph (2) if the members of the Committee unanimously agree to postpone the vote.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB5EE156AA5464FB189F0F8E7A80447CD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice; implementing authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chairperson of the End-User Review Committee shall notify the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration of all final decisions of the Committee with respect to additions to, removals from, or other modifications with respect to the Entity List under this subsection so that the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration may implement all such modifications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40B6E646CBB14E9B9F10D072B158F1DB" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE7C98C2440394D7099E9731B42BFBC5C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the terms <term>End-User Review Committee</term> and <term>Committee</term> mean—</text> <clause id="HC375653F07B248F08E572D05FC5E4D3C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the End-User Review Committee established under section 744.16(d) of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBA3E7EE95F3C4FBABAA61D4999E3419A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any successor committee; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBE2E4D4FA644BD4A349C4DA9A7C0E51" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>Entity List</term> means the list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations, or successor regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

