<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H63B2DE6B6B114164B2C3C17C0D915200" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7603 IH: To amend the Act of August 28, 1937 (commonly referred to as the “O&amp;C Act”) with respect to timber production.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7603</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Act of August 28, 1937 (commonly referred to as the <quote>O&amp;C Act</quote>) with respect to timber production.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9B97F88572743F48F5B6319E0EF16F7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD6D7D164F41A48859CD2D91B633FFBE3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>O&amp;C Renewal Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H97B081BD7CA340BAB58E3F31A297FC0F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Timber production affirmed as primary purpose of O&amp;C lands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The first sentence of the Act of August 28, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2601">43 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>O&amp;C Act</quote>) is amended by striking <quote>sustained yield</quote> and all that follows through the colon and inserting <quote>sustained yield. The primary purpose with respect to the use of such lands shall be for permanent timber production carried out in accordance with the principle of sustained yield to generate revenues to support county government services. The secondary purposes with respect to the use of the land are to contribute to the economic stability of local communities and industries, protect watersheds, regulate water flow, provide recreational opportunities, and reduce the risk of catastrophic wildfires:</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H060E3A8F86874E389D645069BFB3FCC5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fire protection for O&amp;C lands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Act of August 28, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2601">43 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>O&amp;C Act</quote>) is amended by striking <quote>Provided</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote><italic>Provided, </italic>The Secretary shall, with respect to such timberlands (1) meet or exceed the fire protection standards and capacity and readiness applicable to lands adjacent to such timberlands that are under the jurisdiction of the State of Oregon; (2) enter into fire protection agreements with the State of Oregon and applicable forest protective associations to meet the requirements under paragraph (1); and (3) provide compensation for services provided under any agreement entered into pursuant to paragraph (2).</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3BC50332283749249A48A6B1B499AF85"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition of timberlands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Act of August 28, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2601">43 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>O&amp;C Act</quote>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79DF95489A7C4774AB37B14E78E497B6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H2E42915B54C6483DA0B01E64065390BD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definition of timberlands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>timberlands</term> shall include lands bearing or capable of bearing a growth of timber not less than 300,000 feet board measure on each 40-acre subdivision.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H3F047D22B27C46A68B22AF9D4A9F3288"><enum>5.</enum><header>Revision of resource management plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall issue a record of decision revising each resource management plan relating to the lands under the Act of August 28, 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2601">43 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>O&amp;C Act</quote>) and designating timberlands in accordance with the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

