<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25963-4JV-DD-7TL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4837 IS: District of Columbia Courts Judicial Vacancy Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4837</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to provide for the automatic appointment of judges to the District of Columbia courts without the advice and consent of the Senate, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H25C9C00ADDB34EBF8B4C61B77525AF6A"><section section-type="section-one" id="H92DF8046FDB745E3A6866444CFE3E787"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Courts Judicial Vacancy Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H85B87039F61E428D85267132D8B1FCBC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Automatic appointment of judges to District of Columbia courts</header><subsection id="H769EFD175665472D933C670EBAB04B8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointments by President</header><paragraph id="H9F9BB1BF63B947ACAA2A2A8C519A9E7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 433(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–204.33(a), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>the President shall nominate</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>from the list of persons recommended by the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission established under section 434, the President shall appoint all judges of the District of Columbia courts.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DA2C9600583462998BB09869E16DE57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 433 of such Act (sec. 1–204.33, D.C. Official Code) is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="H1C6D72B928F840948E8D8466F75F0C2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional">nomination and</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F4E5EE30FA74807B780064FE3BC74A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0886c534e1334f4cb3427bbf3e15f1db"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>nominated or</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H63C60663EFED4D9E8D917E69C0D5D152"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>his nomination</quote> and inserting <quote>the appointment</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H9CA18EDE01644BD380B9C5E8A7C58950"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>his nomination</quote> and inserting <quote>the appointment</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HD7C1257C27724878898FD250D85478D1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>the President, for such nomination and appointment,</quote> and inserting <quote>the President for such appointment</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H76010851FD564C7EB0DCD994C82D2B57"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>his nomination</quote> and inserting <quote>the appointment</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DB18F9E1CDD4990B9684300DF1B29A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id886db4c0c3424fa88a83366f1633f3eb"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the fifth sentence, by striking <quote>then the President may nominate</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>the President may reappoint such candidate as judge.</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H442E457CD64C48A0B1425E40E3C16E1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the sixth sentence, by striking <quote>not to so nominate such declaring candidate, he shall nominate another candidate</quote> and inserting <quote>not to so reappoint such declaring candidate, the President shall appoint another candidate</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H82F0FD5568A64F259848B8AED7C70EAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the seventh sentence, by striking <quote>then the President shall not submit to the Senate for advice and consent the renomination of the declaring candidate as judge</quote> and inserting <quote>the President shall not reappoint the declaring candidate as judge</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BAE06262D7644EC966A9A1986C23EC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by amending the item relating to section 433 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D7AF7500C2843F5A09D8E8571A97E80"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 433. Appointment of judges.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6F56C4D5461471B87BCB8668511F879"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointments by Judicial Nomination Commission</header><text>Section 434(d) of such Act (sec. 1–204.34(d), D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H98B31A6F14394E78A18C65B766676595"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d01fd33498b49f082f160e71c3d962e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence, by striking <quote>for possible nomination and appointment</quote> and inserting <quote>for possible appointment</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H473473D22495418BA3B606E2696FD6E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>more than one nominee</quote> and inserting <quote>more than one person</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3468E6C7F1044544943472245FF45A6F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>of nominees</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B8717AA8676403083E4A741855818F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the fourth sentence—</text><clause id="HB50280DE2DC34453BE3129EA8F17AC14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the President fails to nominate, for Senate confirmation,</quote> and inserting <quote>the President fails to appoint</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HA7DD54DA3CE74C2E8E47E3ECD6567D4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Commission shall nominate, and with the advice and consent of the Senate, appoint</quote> and inserting <quote>the Commission shall appoint</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26BD05DD3F744413B753B2BD2F566407"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>nomination</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>appointment</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1B600B445A60446FA37B7FDA973B6D01"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorizing Congress to prevent appointment through resolution of disapproval</header><subsection id="H5948009AFE984D1AB99254800A7C3FF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Resolutions of disapproval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part C of title IV of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–204.31 et seq., D.C. Official Code) is amended by inserting after section 434 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C8D19D5BAC445FD9C5C85EBA2A2AD9A"><section id="HD9E3CFE44BFE483F8020C8F13E49081F"><enum>434A.</enum><header>authorizing Congress to prevent appointment through resolution of disapproval</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0CE28DB0747B4BDCAAE7C38463FC9668"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring transmission of notice of appointment to Congress</header><text>Notice of the appointment of a judge of a District of Columbia court under this part shall be transmitted to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate by—</text><paragraph id="H3F0F32BF214B43D88E54A108DEB3B4A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President, in the case of an appointment under section 433; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF50B0931AB24318A1CCDCEEA5B2EC34"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission, in the case of an appointment under section 434(d)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DB7F3CC88A64117B05C04407CC06B23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing of appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appointment of a judge of the District of Columbia courts shall take effect upon the expiration of the 30-calendar-day period (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays, and any day on which neither House is in session because of an adjournment sine die, a recess of more than three days, or an adjournment of more than three days) beginning on the date on which notice of the appointment is transmitted to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate under subsection (a), unless during such 30-calendar-day period there has been enacted into law a joint resolution disapproving of the appointment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H55E9A2F092AE4FE2986C754C87409F1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of expedited procedures for consideration of resolutions of disapproval of Council acts to consideration of resolutions of disapproval of appointment of judges</header><paragraph id="H0CA6ED0A04114C1B9ECDA4581436DB6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 604 shall apply with respect to a joint resolution described in paragraph (2) in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply to a joint resolution which is described in section 604(b) and which disapproves an act of the District of Columbia Council which is transmitted pursuant to section 602(c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AB2028A1CC24C32B825AC24B05D56C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resolutions described</header><text>A resolution described in this paragraph is a resolution, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That the ________ disapproves of the appointment of ________ as a judge of the ________.</quote>, with the first blank filled in with the name of the House of Congress involved, the second blank filled in with the name of the individual involved, and the third blank filled in with the name of the District of Columbia court involved, but does not include any resolution which specifies more than one action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3C57E5362FEC4265A37A07CEE4DBBF3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 434 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94AFA7E22882446F9DD39E98EC45DCE2"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 434A. Authorizing Congress to prevent appointment through resolution of disapproval.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H4A86B413C7834F319B4B711885C1E9A0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><subsection id="H19DA5A4B9977490FA5571118746B49E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to appointments of judges of the District of Columbia courts which are made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H267DE1D3CCA0445083D43D2CD9A7CFC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition rule for current nominees</header><text>Section 434A of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (as added by section 3(a)) shall apply with respect to an individual whose nomination as a judge of the District of Columbia courts is pending as of the date of the enactment of this Act as follows:</text><paragraph id="H7813660F5B384B22BB9E40E8115549F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual nominated by the President under section 433 of such Act (as in effect prior to the effective date of this Act), the President shall be deemed to have transmitted notice of the appointment of the individual as a judge of the District of Columbia courts to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AAF6B9D2B0245A2A57FBA279BDAF3A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual nominated by the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission under section 434 of such Act (as in effect prior to the effective date of this Act), the Commission shall be deemed to have transmitted notice of the appointment of the individual as a judge of the District of Columbia courts to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

