<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC26429-8ST-K1-NRR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4264 IS: NASA UAS Detection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide NASA the authority to detect, identify, monitor, and track unmanned aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NASA UAS Detection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H793FC5AC4D2C4F449E800DAC051E7C53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority with respect to unmanned aircraft system identification and detection</header><subsection id="HD78D7ADB80B845639A3D964F745B32C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3E1625C476F481286341908D816A49F"><section id="HF9AF6AF0C1C849638B460B300DF9B115"><enum>20150.</enum><header>Detecting, identifying, monitoring, and tracking unmanned aircraft systems and unmanned aircraft that threaten certain facilities and assets</header><subsection id="H5230B236FC714F5A8ED9F2EBB47E2399"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1BBA1CF684C9469FB6494A45F393F81E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H5939202BF9B04BACA2D795A919481509"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C1CBFF415C24B00914FDB722AD99DAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94E4ADDDD48D401083AB51BC4008E8E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered facility or asset</header><text>The term <term>covered facility or asset</term> means a facility or asset of the Administration that—</text><subparagraph id="id7b6597393a81423d950f5566a19d94f6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a NASA center; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80279734c05645a98a76e163edf0e1d9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located within the property of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9B13D809AC4D2BAFEAD0FE88D8EC9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic communication; intercept; oral communication; wire communication</header><text>The terms <term>electronic communication</term>, <term>intercept</term>, <term>oral communication</term>, and <term>wire communication</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2510 of title 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2132EC54F55B4E50871E08CBBFADB331"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1106CD6719644E4A57455058CA1D603"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personnel</header><subparagraph id="H36E9677C777442018CD4D112372CBD81"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>personnel</term> means an officer, employee, or contractor of the Administration authorized to perform duties that include safety, security, or protection of people, facilities, or assets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A2FDB4483E84E9C85BD8762B9D1531B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of authority</header><text>To qualify for use of the authority under subsection (b), a contractor conducting operations under such subsection shall satisfy the following:</text><clause id="HBE79432FD06D47C284ED912787B87D1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Be directly contracted by the Administration.</text></clause><clause id="H96146ED006284677AB598A3A12416969"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Be assigned to law enforcement duties within the Office of Protective Services of the Administration.</text></clause><clause id="HE8E65833171F4B4C92B6671096789398"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Operate at a Government-owned or Government-leased facility.</text></clause><clause id="H6A76DA0127FA48C99F155C1BFE00B145"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Not conduct inherently governmental functions.</text></clause><clause id="HD2951330EC6F447187AB7C030581120E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Be trained and certified by the Administration to meet the established guidance and regulations of the Administration.</text></clause><clause id="H7E6AD29BA75C4E1986D7F2FF2D24C6E7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Be subject to the penalties specified in section 799 of title 18.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7685927BAA934A94B85BFF0AFF99A344"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft; unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The terms <term>unmanned aircraft</term> and <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 44801 of title 49.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6212662841f047dd8d14cadb0e56ae97"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 1030 and 1367 and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, the Administrator may take, and may authorize personnel with assigned duties that include the security or protection of people, facilities, or assets to take, the actions described in subsection (c) that are necessary to detect, identify, monitor, and track an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft that poses a credible threat (as defined by the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation) to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</text></subsection><subsection id="H834E3EBDFC624EFD95884718DC3770B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The actions described in this subsection are limited to such actions to detect, identify, monitor, or track the unmanned aircraft systems or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire communication, an oral communication, or an electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></subsection><subsection id="id58d70438ea3b4c08a7f529f31fed1067"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Required coordination</header><text>The Administrator shall develop the actions described in subsection (c) in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1cfe4ac303e64d10a195b0442c044c07"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training of personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall provide training on the actions described in subsection (c) to personnel authorized to take such actions.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAD34D94C397941648808A9CD6EDE8BE1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Aviation safety</header><text>In carrying out any activity under this section, the Administrator shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration in the case of any action authorized under this section that might affect aviation safety, civilian aviation and aerospace operations, aircraft airworthiness, or the use of the airspace.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4E8D8EE850304F5DA3FCA56B8F85A365"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Identification and assessment of covered facilities or assets</header><paragraph id="H05238880C84C47FEA2D75E0DA85009E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inventory</header><text>The Administrator shall identify each covered facility or asset.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a915080929643ecb156cfc0c6942d9e"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Risk-based assessment</header><text>The Administrator, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall conduct a risk-based assessment of each covered facility or asset identified with respect to the risk that a credible threat by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the operation of each such covered facility or asset, that includes an evaluation of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H70F29A148D42491197AB2EF38FF0A553"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Threat information specific to each such covered facility or asset.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7402F53A34B64B098E8F2FE0E00D61EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each of the following factors, with respect to potential impacts on the safety and efficiency of the national airspace system and law enforcement and national security needs while carrying out the actions described in subsection (c):</text><clause id="H34278AFC9778493B90F5DE97F75F539A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Potential effects to safety, efficiency, or use of the national airspace system, including potential effects on a manned aircraft, an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, aviation safety, airport operations, infrastructure, or air navigation services related to the use of any system or technology for carrying out the actions described in subsection (c).</text></clause><clause id="HA079FA18102B4E4E8539E56BEFDA9C5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Options for minimizing any identified effect to the national airspace system related to the use of any system or technology, including minimizing any effect to civil aviation or air traffic control systems, for carrying out the actions described in subsection (c).</text></clause><clause id="H4F97BE602A1C4A32821BA841FBCB0594"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Potential consequences of the impacts of any actions described in subsection (c) to the national airspace system or infrastructure if not detected, identified, monitored, or tracked.</text></clause><clause id="H7EEC0728AED54C1D9EF3DDCEA0898078"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ability to provide reasonable advance notice to aircraft operators consistent with the safety of the national airspace system and the needs of law enforcement and national security.</text></clause><clause id="HEF0EFE4D2C064448A6F530483C3A2240"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The setting and character of the covered facility or asset at issue, including the following:</text><subclause id="H413909D26DFB4338B2B6EBDC4B07D223"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Whether the covered facility or asset is located in a populated area or near other structures.</text></subclause><subclause id="H2791344BC45F44F6AEDBD9AFE19D4F09"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Whether the covered facility or asset is open to the public.</text></subclause><subclause id="H3306F58336F84399A84C664592D81E08"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Whether the covered facility or asset is used for nongovernmental functions.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC8F8C4556B1040978D70DD46A1CC116C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Any potential for interference with wireless communications or for injury or damage to persons or property.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBE37AAA1152B49FAAB34E4E74BBF506D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Potential consequences to national security, public safety, or law enforcement if a credible threat posed by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft to the covered facility or asset at issue is not detected, identified, monitored, or tracked.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef0b9f84a19c4442819dc44c42b87c40"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall distribute to each relevant department or agency (including the Department of Transportation) and the appropriate committees of Congress, through appropriate means, a list of facilities and assets identified as covered facilities or assets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H423C980B575348B29373098215CD1B7B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Technologies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technologies used by the Administration to take actions described in subsection (c) shall be limited to systems or technologies that are included on a list of authorized technologies maintained jointly by the Department of Justice, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, the Department of Transportation, the Federal Communications Commission, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD9FD015BD1A441ABA9FEAFD99E92404E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Guidance and procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration—</text><paragraph id="id1c1b073d354d482082c38e8c8a7632a7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall issue guidance, and may prescribe appropriate procedures as necessary, for the Administrator to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35df1d8e19a04ccdadc0415e02164691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in developing such guidance and procedures, shall consult the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information, the Secretary of Transportation, and the head of any other agency determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCE5FDC9E09304AC7BC69C4AA1E7D062F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Coordination</header><paragraph id="idbdbef366b7f74b039090dcd4d011eb6c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coordination with Federal Aviation Administration</header><text>With respect to the development of guidance under subsection (i), the Administrator—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5b0e30a4a594361afd801e18f66676d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf240df95f2df4f5ca85fc053cf09ec86"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may coordinate with the heads of other agencies, as determined relevant by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9991f162ac3a4264b2174f7001a0ec2c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on aviation safety</header><text>The Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration before issuing any guidance or otherwise implementing this section, if such guidance or implementation might affect aviation safety, civilian aviation and aerospace operations, aircraft airworthiness, or the use of airspace.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE300ED40406B40F09ED1919681E05760"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Privacy protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidance or procedures issued to carry out an action described in subsection (c) by the Administrator shall ensure the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H48F165A8DC4A4BA9931F33E3850D7E27"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interception or acquisition of, access to, or maintenance or use of, any communication to or from an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft under this section is conducted in a manner consistent with the First and Fourth Amendments to the Constitution of the United States and any applicable provisions of Federal law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8B897CCE1F14C3CB1387B2B57F7B623"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any communication to or from an unmanned aircraft system or an unmanned aircraft is intercepted or acquired only to the extent necessary to support an action described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d5ae6e119344aeda8a0592101e42532"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any record of such communication is maintained only for as long as necessary, and in no event for more than 180 days, unless the Administrator, in consultation with the Attorney General, determines that maintenance of such records is necessary to investigate or prosecute a violation of law or to directly support an ongoing security operation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB723F945A70148618217B1441E0F5246"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such communications are not disclosed to any person not employed or contracted by the Administration for the purposes of carrying out this section unless the disclosure—</text><subparagraph id="HA99C50C4281C4B92B1900B44B658B25C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary to investigate or prosecute a violation of law, including by the Department of Defense or a Federal law enforcement agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id639c771d5c354b8a8ea7465009278f67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would support the enforcement activities of a regulatory agency of the Federal Government in connection with a criminal or civil investigation of, or any regulatory, statutory, or other enforcement action relating to, an action described in subsection (c); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id768b33fc55ae4c829b41c5f25b393a13"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is otherwise required by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA0C4851D83D47739692A6E7842AF480"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Semiannual briefings and notifications</header><paragraph id="HE6F4E06130FA4AAAAC991ED908979ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a semiannual basis beginning 6 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall provide a briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress on the activities carried out pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB27EA0ADDB594D7188CCBE305E6E8DED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each briefing required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFAB4CF4DD6BC4CCDAB9F527ECD81B3AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to policies, programs, and procedures to minimize or eliminate impacts of the actions carried out pursuant to subsection (c) to the national airspace system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC25CD7ADFE3C4FE49E0F555F92A5D544"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the following:</text><clause id="HB50125DF2A76407984AB296856C3A013"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Each instance that an action described in subsection (c) was taken, including any such instance that may have resulted in harm, damage, or loss to a person or to private property.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA92BED2C98D34E668C23FCE3C3723628"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The guidance, policies, or procedures established by the Administrator to address privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties issues implicated by the actions permitted under subsection (c), as well as any changes or subsequent efforts by the Administrator that would significantly affect privacy, civil rights, or civil liberties.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H46D5DEF645CD43388A5B8092ABD9FA2D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Options considered and steps taken by the Administrator to minimize any identified impacts to the national airspace system related to the use of any system or technology, including minimizing any effects to civil aviation or air traffic control systems, for carrying out the actions described in subsection (c).</text></clause><clause id="H49867158B7ED42CDB001DE22B3058244"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Such consultation conducted by the Administrator with other agencies with respect to each action described under clauses (ii) and (iii).</text></clause><clause id="HC3D652AB1C1F448F8A7B34306A984C7C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Each instance in which a communication intercepted or acquired as a result of an action described in subsection (c) taken during operations of an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft was—</text><subclause id="H8D09FDB64D1049E5BE8F10BAE8972938"><enum>(I)</enum><text>held in the possession of the Administration for more than 180 days; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H379787F394CD42F1A6CD13394D907C4F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shared with any entity other than the Administration.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE07CEED858794973BC1DA85A3C381168"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An explanation of how the Administrator—</text><clause id="H278430B43F574606B6F3A43E91250052"><enum>(i)</enum><text>informed the public with respect to the possible use of authorities granted under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="HC56648DC27B94F8CB7F714E9DE513673"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engaged with Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies to implement and use such authorities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFACB07B0D74640E8A57972E18AA1453C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of whether any gaps or insufficiencies in laws, regulations, or policies impede the ability of the Administration to detect, identify, monitor, or track the credible threat posed by malicious, inappropriate, or unauthorized use of an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46C978F147A74E46B55801392598E01E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recommendations to remedy any such gaps or insufficiencies, including recommendations relating to the potential need for changes in laws, regulations, or policies, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1B310AF56B34AA0A999E829733BDF03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unclassified form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each briefing required under paragraph (1) shall be unclassified but may be accompanied by an additional classified briefing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFFFFD511E03342F19666B7D76A02A4EC"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Scope of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may not be interpreted to provide the Administrator with any additional authority other than the authorities described in subsections (b) and (g).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7778B1EDEFEB475CA5289CF7776DBC08"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall cease to have effect on September 30, 2031.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D8BF071AF354B499FFE65DA6639978F"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text><paragraph id="HF6AC958DCAB84F209E152BE13843493E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to vest in the Administrator any authority of the head of any other Federal agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23B27F452044489D81A13BE1636BD426"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to vest in the head of any other Federal agency any authority of the Administrator; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce29eb3f847d42ada0885dae7ee80995"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to modify the spectrum management authorities of the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information under the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/901">47 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7508607B958441E4944EE1DB727A1D1D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/51/20149">section 20149</external-xref> the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide272c5309a8e4eec9d7fe9ba207b27e1"><toc><toc-entry level="section">20150. Detecting, identifying, monitoring, and tracking unmanned aircraft systems and unmanned aircraft that threaten certain facilities and assets.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

