<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25252-6C5-51-K18"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 533 IS: Condemning white supremacy, hate, and antisemitism, and efforts to give a platform to these dangerous ideologies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 533</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251208" legis-day="20251204">December 8 (legislative day, December 4), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning white supremacy, hate, and antisemitism, and efforts to give a platform to these dangerous ideologies.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Nick Fuentes is a white supremacist leader, organizer, and podcaster;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes identifies himself as a <quote>White Identitarian, race realist, <quote>Jewish aware</quote>, counter-Zionist, authoritarian</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes is a frequent Holocaust denier and supporter of Hitler who—</text><paragraph id="id2b2803c9db454776bc2178d5eee7c1d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has said on his show that <quote>Hitler was awesome. Hitler was right. And the Holocaust didn't happen.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec05e6d9a4684e42a9abaa5e05a453bc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>described Hitler as having an <quote>aura</quote> and being <quote>really...cool</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb1ef28c56b24301ba48b108de0863f8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has hosted <quote>Hitler Friday</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf04bbd27d93c45289181c8bd1408e947"><enum>(4)</enum><text>criticized Polish people for <quote>this bad habit of hating Hitler all the time</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ae543216273401c9bad2aec2e27d4a1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>popularized the phrase <quote>six million cookies</quote> to express doubt about the 6,000,000 Jews killed during the Holocaust;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes expressed support for killing Jews on his show, saying, <quote>There is an occult element at the highest levels of society, and specifically among the Jews...When we take power, they need to be given the death penalty.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes used the 2017 <quote>Unite the Right</quote> rally in Charlottesville, Virginia, during which hundreds of torch-bearing demonstrators chanted <quote>Jews will not replace us</quote>, to mainstream his ideology;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the <quote>Unite the Right</quote> rally was followed by a broader cycle of antisemitic, racist, and xenophobic attacks, including the 2018 mass shooting at the Tree of Life synagogue in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, which was the deadliest attack on the Jewish community in the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes has repeatedly peddled the white supremacist <quote>Great Replacement Theory</quote>, which Fuentes calls the <quote>Great Replacement REALITY</quote>, an antisemitic, racist, and xenophobic conspiracy theory that claims that Jews are orchestrating the replacement of native white Europeans from their countries by non-white immigrants;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 6, 2024, Fuentes posted that <quote>there are basically two things that are going on: White genocide and Jewish subversion</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in March 2023, at a rally in Maryland, Fuentes declared, <quote>I love Hitler</quote>, and targeted <quote>Talmudic Jews</quote>, which is a white supremacist and antisemitic term for Jewish people, saying, according to reporting, that <quote>Talmudic Jews need to either leave the county or be converted</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes, during his livestream of the inauguration of President Trump in 2025, said he believes <quote>Jews are in the way of the <quote>sovereignty</quote> of the U.S.</quote> and are the <quote>most influential faction in our government</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes has likened <quote>organized Jewry</quote> to a <quote>transnational gang</quote> and repeatedly uses rhetoric such as <quote>globalists</quote> and <quote>cosmopolitan elites</quote>, which are dog whistles to classic antisemitic tropes that suggest Jews secretly control media, finance, and government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in March 2025, Fuentes said on Rumble that <quote>Jews are running society, women need to shut the ——— up, Blacks need to be imprisoned for the most part, and we would live in paradise, it's that simple.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in November 2025, Fuentes posted on X, <quote>No to the Christ-hating Talmud...No to our Jewish oligarchy.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes has stated that the Hamas terrorist attacks against Israel on October 7, 2023, were <quote>staged</quote> and denied acts of rape and the killing of babies by Hamas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fuentes and Tucker Carlson, a former Fox News host, have a combined 17,800,000 followers on X alone;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 27, 2025, Carlson hosted Fuentes for a lengthy interview;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during such interview, Fuentes perpetuated antisemitic conspiracy theories, including—</text><paragraph id="id13c23a6997a34e738d333b035791823d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>blaming <quote>organized Jewry</quote> for undermining cohesion in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ecf6ba5556c4935adc7272a63597c18"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">telling Carlson that the main obstacle within the conservative movement was <quote>these Zionist Jews</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id243467cd66be4a85b92659e3842e671d"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">claiming that neoconservatism is <quote>Jewish in nature</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacc4472244f247edaab3a8c81febe6d0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancing the dual-loyalty trope by saying that Jewish Americans are loyal first to Israel and that <quote>they have this international community across borders, extremely organized, that is putting the interests of themselves before the interests of their home country</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61a7d08b17bc492cab17ecf021c2c413"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">claiming that he sees <quote>Jewishness</quote> as the defining trait of his political opponents;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Carlson did not push back on or reject the claims made by Fuentes during the interview and platformed the views of Fuentes, at times even validating his framing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Carlson spoke on the main stage of the Republican National Convention in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Heritage Foundation President Kevin Roberts—</text><paragraph id="idb01e2b8f500f47f1a4b35de038cc452a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>filmed a video in response to criticism of Carlson for his October 27 interview of Fuentes, defending Carlson and saying that those who opposed Carlson were <quote>the globalist class</quote> and a <quote>venomous coalition</quote>, terms that are antisemitic dog whistles; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d605e28394b4fd89c3c9e29cce31a7d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">defended Fuentes as expressing ideas that are worthy of debate rather than rejecting the ideas outright;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Roberts refused to fully retract his video, despite apologizing for parts of what was said in the video, and has not taken the video down;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Trump administration nominated an individual who said, <quote>I do have a Nazi streak in me from time to time</quote>, and then appointed that individual to another position after his original nomination was withdrawn following bipartisan opposition; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Executive Order 13899 (84 Fed. Reg. 68779, relating to combating anti-semitism), Executive Order 14188 (90 Fed. Reg. 8847, relating to additional measures to combat anti-semitism), and the United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism affirm the importance of fighting antisemitism in the United States and around the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id74e6e7edec4d49d59347a990622d5d42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strongly rejects the views of and platforming of Nick Fuentes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7179e797520c4f11a7f14404a4319f39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns the effort by Tucker Carlson to platform and mainstream Fuentes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2f0d3f156c34adbb72cb1f8ccb05359"><enum>(3)</enum><text>condemns Nazism, honors the sacrifices of the United States Armed Forces who gave their lives to defeat the Nazis, and affirms that Nazi Germany and its collaborators murdered 6,000,000 Jews in the Holocaust;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc445373c7ba49e1893cf1dce8e9732a"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unequivocally condemns antisemitism and white supremacy whenever and wherever they occur; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id170399003c4c4b648cae0304d2aee6ca"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges all elected officials, thought leaders, and community leaders to reject and condemn white supremacy and antisemitism whenever and wherever they occur.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

