<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H30C31B2D2A2C4095A746C3F72C520630" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1359 IH: Supporting the designation of the second Friday of June as “National Service and Conservation Corps Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1359</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of the second Friday of June as <quote>National Service and Conservation Corps Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there exists a network of National Service Programs (in this resolution referred to as <quote>Service and Conservation Corps</quote>) that receive funding pursuant to subtitle C of the National and Community Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas such network includes more than 140 Service and Conservation Corps across the country;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these Service and Conservation Corps annually provide education, workforce development, and support services to nearly 22,000 young adults and post-9/11 veterans;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas today’s Service and Conservation Corps are locally based organizations that engage young adults (generally ages 16 to 25) and veterans (up to age 35) in service projects that address recreation, conservation, disaster response, and community needs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these Service and Conservation Corps are direct descendants of the Civilian Conservation Corps, a Great Depression-era Federal work relief program that mobilized 3,000,000 young men to dramatically improve the Nation’s public lands;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Civilian Conservation Corps participants received food, shelter, education, and a $30-a-month stipend;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, from 1933 to 1942, the Civilian Conservation Corps planted 3,000,000,000 trees and helped build trails, roads, campgrounds, and other park infrastructure still in use today;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States will commemorate the 250th anniversary of its founding in 2026, a milestone that highlights the enduring importance of civic engagement, public service, and stewardship of the Nation’s natural and cultural resources;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas most modern Service and Conservation Corps are nonprofits or are operated by units of State or local government;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, through public-private partnerships, Service and Conservation Corps work with a range of organizations, government agencies, and institutions to engage Corpsmembers in meaningful projects that address local and national issues;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, through a term of service that could last from a few months to a year, Corpsmembers experience the <quote>Corps Model</quote>, where they gain work experience and develop in-demand skills;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Corpsmembers are compensated with a stipend or living allowance and often receive an education award or scholarship upon completing their service;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, additionally, Corps provide participants with educational programming, mentoring, and access to career and personal counseling, and some Corps operate or partner with charter schools to help participants earn their high school diploma or GED;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas Corpsmembers contribute to the preservation of historic sites, cultural resources, and public lands that reflect the Nation’s 250-year history;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Corpsmembers complete thousands of community improvement, resilience, and resource conservation projects every year, strengthening the Nation’s communities as it approaches its 250th anniversary;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Corpsmembers typically serve on crews alongside other young adults, or in <quote>individual placement</quote> or internship positions that provide additional capacity to Federal, State, and local resource management agencies;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Service and Conservation Corps have longstanding partnerships with Federal, State, and local community development and resource management agencies to engage Corpsmembers in meaningful and necessary projects across the country;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Service and Conservation Corps projects include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF5D05F8224944918ABDD5E79FB50655"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the enhancement of neighborhoods and community public spaces, including urban gardens;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5A75B4E215144C583F456ED4791499F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the preservation and protection of public lands, shorelines, waterways, habitat, and wildlife;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB64B1B9B8F34948AF103C20AC51FD9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the preservation of historic structures;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B595F0E2CDF40229AEF5588CFD6CADF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing access to and the enhancement of recreation on public lands and waters;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECC678D24DD8476D9537E83AB75765AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>enhancing resilience to natural disasters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4002DDA2A75402895DE4DBAEBF70069"><enum>(6)</enum><text>mitigation, response to, and recovery from natural disasters, including hurricanes and wildfire;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEAF9390CFDFB4B1B84B7105B68340D6B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving energy efficiency and resource conservation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H884E333B7F274EBC87E683DD3DFC321F"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">building and maintaining alternative transportation and sustainable infrastructure;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States needs to respond to decades of deferred maintenance on public lands and waters and make its communities more resilient;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States also has millions of young people facing unemployment and barriers to opportunity; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the existing network of more than 140 Service and Conservation Corps are ready to meet the needs of these young Americans: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3B6351D108D14A99B9FA855DFF400448"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H385E5DCE04AC4A7D8FF375E09072B31F"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HAA80BB214E85458983993E6BD0BB7FB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of a <quote>National Service and Conservation Corps Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F67367661414D8080161FDD1AB46E4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates the existing network of more than 140 Service and Conservation Corps on their contributions to the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A8D775FAA2044949FBB929B86AC5D6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the citizens of the United States to recognize the importance of national service;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD73FE86C16A4B6A91CDE031F5FB3DFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the continuation and expansion of the national network of Service and Conservation Corps under the National and Community Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12501">42 U.S.C. 12501 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57D84723D4DE435DAF7B5FCBE664B756">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the role of Service and Conservation Corps in honoring the Nation’s 250-year legacy of civic engagement and public service.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

