<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H98C5EADD4AB2431BAE5F25037751A893" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8360 IH: Commission on Advancing Restorative Justice in Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Education, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to establish an interagency advisory Commission on Advancing Restorative Justice in Elementary and Secondary Education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C6539792169490BB48A3613041AC6EE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCBA9E464FA374DB2888AEF48B56E0E35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commission on Advancing Restorative Justice in Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0D27AA29FF834F6D84023D7DD8B049DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="H56C988C256D14F57B395E21F695F0EC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HD72EEC286A714B28B8CF53CBC1D93B9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Students of color often experience harsher disciplinary measures and greater barriers to educational opportunities due to racial and gender biases embedded into school codes of conduct, discipline policies, and dress code policies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8E8421218574DC5B9EB062E80997747"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Racial and gender biases in school discipline practices and limited requirements in educator preparation and professional development all influence how school personal react to behavior by students of color.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3B3CB0452DE64996BC37BDE7395D477E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improved and increased opportunities for culturally competence professional development programs can help teachers and related school personnel more effectively respond to student behavior misbehavior and thereby decrease the disparity between how Black and White students are disciplined.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBE326D399D7A44D4A408C861D72913B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HBC1E19E558C4433DA4195323CC8FDEE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To support the mental and behavioral health of students of color.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF23BD0EA033B480D943DDA4062C8CE73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To increase capacity for providing mental health support and counseling services that are accessible, culturally competent, and responsive to the needs of students of color.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6165821B63F348A0AC9B2A4E4486F735"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To provide recommendations on universal school psychologist-to-student ratio and Counselor-to-student ratio to ensure evidence-based healthy school climate interventions, accessible mental health support, program evaluation, and teacher consultation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H467377AAE2874461AA49FD7683BC95D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To codify restorative-level practices that create equitable learning environments, developmental relationships, and build academic engagement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HDA65AF5265284F33AD1438D506BD5E60"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interagency Advisory Commission on Advancing Restorative Justice in Elementary and Secondary Education</header>
<subsection id="H43787345F9F34A29AECC87FF51C90F8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish a commission to be known as the Interagency Advisory Commission on Advancing Restorative Justice in Elementary and Secondary Education (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDDCF54D8EBE94219A1026C2E494BA4B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Commission shall be to—</text>
<paragraph id="HBDFB1950D83A414D836ADC69FEA52051"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create guidelines for elementary schools and secondary schools to track and report the groups of students who most frequently participate in mediation, restorative practices, and other similar practices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3595CCA58AB6436FAF2CD3A4846060A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop definitions of the terms <term>restorative justice</term> and <term>restorative practices</term> to be used by the Department of Education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFC1827FAB72B43D48036C0F6C293A468"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and distribute training materials for school personnel that—</text> <subparagraph id="H288AC8DA598448BCA4DEC9645688B048"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include practices that align with the definitions developed pursuant to paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H001037831BFD4581AE2AEB63DF244358"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide information on emotional and social disruptions and delays, accountability checks, peer discussions, and other classroom approaches that reduce bias, enhance cultural competency, and allow for critical reflection;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC15B28A70B741D9924BBF09E4E56539"><enum>(4)</enum><text>increase the ability of school personnel to provide mental health support and counseling services that are accessible, culturally competent, and responsive to the needs of students of color; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C6EB8E80A184003B44B8D310AF695A4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop and recommend, to elementary schools and secondary schools that receive funds under an applicable program, school psychologist-to-student and counselor-to-student ratios that ensure lower caseloads, evidence-based school climate interventions, accessible mental health support, program evaluation, and teacher consultation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE5EE1A531E9541EAA2482E8666F2F2C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="H14BE6174B6874FDC825788F5D3B10977"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of not more than 13 members, appointed not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act by the Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as follows:</text>
<subparagraph id="H738CA653C9584DF7B91501090716AECD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 member from each of the following:</text> <clause id="HAAA14967555842CEA638307645FAF157"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Office of Elementary and Secondary Education of the Department of Education.</text></clause>
<clause id="H5489440BFD694C1291F4DADBC0D9A05E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services of the Department of Education.</text></clause> <clause id="HEFC1CF7C5B224547893654F95C842CF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education.</text></clause>
<clause id="HE481C57567B342FA9C5508BC63BDC1CE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Office of Early Childhood Development of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></clause> <clause id="H69B0F2C3F288428F9C57F273F8EFE230"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Office of Child Supportive Services of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></clause>
<clause id="H2232A62862E34E3690085FE0440E0EF4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The White House Initiative on Advancing Educational Equity, Excellence, and Economic Opportunity for Black Americans.</text></clause> <clause id="HDEC19BB48B7D40C2A53D58D15C721DE1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>An organization that represents restorative justice and the behavioral health of young students of color.</text></clause>
<clause id="H972A1E625D03453BABF523B4CD164C91"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>An organization that advocates for mental health services and suicide prevention in elementary schools and secondary schools.</text></clause> <clause id="HD6BA33E59FAE43309BB6D43235CAF94F"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>An organization representing secondary and postsecondary students of color with special education needs.</text></clause>
<clause id="HF28125493F034E6D96FEE43891892645"><enum>(x)</enum><text>An organization representing psychological and counseling directors at elementary schools and secondary schools.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H285E753001C94F038980E4F92D62FA5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 member who is a scholarly expert and practitioner in the areas of schooling experiences of students of color and equity and school discipline reform.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H395EA7597E6647BC835088726A486BF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2 members who are—</text> <clause id="HA09652B184AD40988603AE4786078155"><enum>(i)</enum><text>students of color; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H128898513A504186BB3FEE10F8A7ABE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>family members of such students.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A0E66E1F06E461D97EA9588C96FD79F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson; vice chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson and Vice Chairperson of the Commission shall be selected from among the members by the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H449895295B274E808FD3BDEC5A4793B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rates of pay</header><text>Members shall serve without pay.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56B1E364B4FD423CA5458D62A9DEC464"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0DA22478FE0048D5B89045643B9083F0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
<paragraph id="H56CB05004E234DBBADD96021ED705FB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Commission shall meet not later than 60 days after the appointment of the members of the Commission under subsection (c).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB793B75DCF144FD8A90C1E96090FD52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional meetings</header><text>After the initial meeting required under paragraph (1), the Commission shall meet no fewer than 7 times at the call of the Chairperson.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7F258083541943C8AB76AC3D4AF62F9B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Secretary may appoint personnel as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H850CAD5123F2491088476875E7C04A47"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H0649244EE8544DCD985201140EF93360"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Annual reports</header> <text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which all members are appointed under subsection (c), and on an annual basis for each of the 4 years thereafter, the Commission shall submit to the Secretary, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives a report on the progress of the Commission, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H84DA9FE991F44984A96A4D2F6366DF72" commented="no">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a summary of the information gathered pursuant to carrying out the duties described in subsection (b), including any conclusions reached from such information;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H38F217C8C75B4D8C818541F4AF3AEFFC">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a description of how the training materials developed under subsection (b)(3)—</text>
            <clause id="H72FD391F1D754ED1B0820D0A4D2CB1CB">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>were distributed by the Commission, including with respect to how such distribution focused on students of color; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HA016FE149F1A4E3E9265EA7D47384444">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>increased the cultural competence of school personnel and reduced disproportionate discipline of students of color, as compared to before the distribution of such materials;</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC4FB659F6E914CED9BBD0B58F919A648">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a description of the efforts taken to increase the ability of school personnel to provide the mental health support and counseling services described in subsection (b)(4); and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H00718BC0888D4436A33A964245CF856D">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>a description of the steps taken to—</text> <clause id="H84FEC21C498A4701B8CFDDB38F5E8315"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>increase the capacity of school psychologists and counselors in the ways described in subsection (b)(5); and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H461AD10A2F244C4798EAFFEC2FCD4DC7">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>reduce disproportionate discipline.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD93649DDDA04BD08D3BDD6DE36262CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>The final report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, in addition to the information required under such paragraph, the final findings, conclusions, and recommendations of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD5EA4A5DA1144AF59A0A4103B6BDB090"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate 90 days after submitting the final report described in subsection (f)(2).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H78391ECBE85B4E928BD6502BE45393B2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="HCFE96BA43B1141D783C5B4F4F350F621"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 400(c) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2C1E0A744D544574A894A1BDE7748A35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>Secretary</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

