<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26476-RT0-V5-9J8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3920 IS: Unifying American Security Interests Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3920</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To strengthen homeland security by expanding Urban Areas Security Initiative grant eligibility criteria to promote cooperation with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and to advance election security protections.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section id="id148deb54c7954d89b0d6eb143c26b97a" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unifying American Security Interests Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UASI Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6adac29e31f4506b5a19cfb73021587"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idafde45351e26467191cbd40ba9475679"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Urban Areas Security Initiative provides critical funding to high-risk urban areas to enhance preparedness against terrorism and other threats under the Homeland Security Grant Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1084637fad5b4b30818098a8f766adb7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Effective border security and immigration enforcement are integral to national homeland security, requiring collaboration between Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcee965207b2846a4a5421f65fb36de39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The fiscal year 2025 Homeland Security Grant Program Notice of Funding Opportunity established National Priority Areas to address emerging threats, including support for border crisis response through cooperation with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97087bfa94e0459a951ae53c8d61b84a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Codifying the requirements referred to in paragraphs (1) through (3) will ensure consistent application and prevent future circumvention through administrative or judicial actions.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7acda0ce63504e50ab26c61f6da3e911"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility for Urban Areas Security Initiative grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2008 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609">6 U.S.C. 609</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f16ba80981d477fb6bc3c39f7ce5dda"><subsection id="id96ec67a50dcf4446a3733de9bc771b74"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Eligibility for Urban Areas Security Initiative grants</header><paragraph id="id121d98b338e14b45aeeace211a867213"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National priority areas requirement</header><text>As a condition of eligibility for a grant under the Urban Areas Security Initiative, each applicant (including State administrative agencies and eligible urban areas) shall demonstrate in its application that it will allocate not less than 30 percent of the total award amount across the following National Priority Areas:</text><subparagraph id="id5acaba96721a46a9b50a98a3dfbd744e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Enhancing cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id168c054723de4d4bada0f6a92f45a812"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Enhancing the protection of soft targets and crowded places.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78946793f8694e5aa07800ffaf6aed54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Supporting Homeland Security Task Forces and Fusion Centers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8d83a1fa5b54fc6ac3b199c46e12541"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Enhancing election security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63bbd82ba2f44257b36944d44e4a9289"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Supporting border crisis response and enforcement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ff621afe74e4fd7a601de752d801820"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum allocations</header><text>Of the amount required to be allocated under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="idcc82e56e5a0f4636b0045fcadbcc082d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 3 percent of the total award shall be dedicated to activities in support of enhancing election security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2251dd25cbb5412a94a4924daef87620"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>not less than 10 percent of the total award shall be dedicated to activities that supporting border crisis response and enforcement, which shall include—</text>
                            <clause id="id3a84784debff4920883862c7a5f8540e">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>participating in the program authorized under section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>), including training and authorizing local officers to perform immigration enforcement functions such as identifying and processing removable noncitizens in their custody;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id86cec0cdb50b4e20a93390114b611d7a">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>cooperating with detainers received from U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and other jurisdictional responsibilities related to immigration enforcement;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id5771213d264448c9b8e9653bb38436a3">
                                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>training for law enforcement personnel in immigration law, civil rights protections, and procedures under the program referred to in clause (i);</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id652fd94f63d547088e076c005d61a48b">
                                <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>developing information-sharing platforms or secure networks between local agencies and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id72c1d0cf904b4bd489a72d85e652b6f0">
                                <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>procuring technology for screening, detection, and communications to support immigration enforcement;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id1c2bde1a219144858d3a88f6dcc041a5">
                                <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>participating in joint training exercises with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to improve coordination; and</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="id5fc7b186a7c44826a4a680551bf8725d">
                                <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>staffing and operational overtime directly tied to activities described in clause (i), such as expanding screening in correctional facilities.</text>
                            </clause>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc8a3d991b4d4e91922cf591b1bd18cc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investment justification and coordination</header><text>Each applicant for a grant under the Urban Areas Security Initiative shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security a dedicated investment justification for projects that supporting border crisis response and enforcement that details alignment with border security goals. All such projects shall require coordination with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement field offices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf78db270f2824409b725dc3f8807e6e4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance certifications</header><text>Each applicant for a grant under the Urban Areas Security Initiative shall certify to the Secretary of Homeland Security that funded activities will comply with all applicable Department of Homeland Security terms, including prohibitions on benefitting or incentivizing illegal immigration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id75c32618d52d4fb5a2e99cddc4bf8500"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Noncompliance penalties</header><text>Failure of a grantee to meet the minimum allocations required under this subsection may result in the Secretary of Homeland Security—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id677619fcef824a738629a3577fd95dee"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">denying eligibility for a grant under the Urban Areas Security Initiative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a6b89b5bb574a2ab0e3235f5abde675"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">placing a hold on up to 30 percent of the award until such failure is remedied; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id133bc26c89d24079b62bd36a729bdda8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imposing another remedy, including award termination or debarment of the grantee from future grants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e3127cb48d148c4b2a6e169f1cbafa8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The requirements under this subsection shall apply to all Urban Areas Security Initiative grants awarded for fiscal year 2027 or for any fiscal year thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id658a3b94fe534e688eb5600551482ead"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to preempt State or local laws, except to the extent necessary to ensure compliance with the conditions for Federal grant funding established under section 2008(h) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609">6 U.S.C. 609(h)</external-xref>), as added by section 3.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

