<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H10553A03E6A74C0FB235F8480FA6F9F3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6828 IH: Transnational Fentanyl Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6828</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee
                    on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency to submit to Congress an intelligence assessment on the Sinaloa Cartel and the Jalisco Cartel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1A6F5FDDD30D486A944A9F6374F25B77" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2C9302C603564ABCA27B663D52F0CCB7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transnational Fentanyl Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6B044B14C2D7421389330A5413C18F32"><enum>2.</enum><header>Central intelligence agency intelligence assessment of Sinaloa cartel and Jalisco cartel</header> <subsection id="HA4AC87E7BC3443BC8B5DC7FFA3F4BD48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, in consultation with the heads of the other elements of the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>)) that the Director determines appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an intelligence assessment on the transnational criminal organizations known as the Sinaloa Cartel and the Jalisco Cartel.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H802854D6FC124824BB41330D310468A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The intelligence assessment under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to each transnational criminal organization specified in such subsection, a description of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2DE647BCD5204A9B928294A744DE7BEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The key leaders, organizational structure, subgroups, presence in the states within Mexico, and cross-border illicit drug smuggling routes of the transnational criminal organization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC182B7B84A944E6BAC9FF8DD96D881E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The practices used by the transnational criminal organization to import the chemicals used to make synthetic drugs, to produce such drugs, and to smuggle such drugs across the border into the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDFDC17A6AA24847917C9BC53623C65B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The main suppliers and the main brokers that supply the transnational criminal organization with precursor chemicals and equipment used in the production of synthetic drugs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA381DA30D3B6438A975ABC41551CD76C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The manner in which the transnational criminal organization is tailoring the fentanyl products of such organization to attract a wider variety of United States consumers, including unwitting users.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7151107667254F1BB9B9DBA2751B18FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The degree to which the transnational criminal organization is using human and technical operations to undermine counternarcotics efforts by United States and Mexican security services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8C0499CCFDF48F5A2BF6393972BCC52"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An estimate of the annual revenue received by the transnational criminal organization from the sale of illicit drugs, disaggregated by drug type.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E518381C7584BD0A90D2B977E72ABAF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other information the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency determines relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H86A90272EC6A4B1A9102BE558E2697BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The intelligence assessment under subsection (a) may be submitted in classified form.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA840C18F181C410CB66C4D796768520F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress</quote> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD892066A4C714574B722F2158787E14E">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the congressional defense committees (as such term is defined in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code);</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H944E31AD94EC49B598CD244956944973"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the congressional intelligence committees (as such term is defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>));</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3255724CFB0A46A7BD141625AEF53F30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA87D6941221D49C59EBC3E95244B6CA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

