<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF94ED8F3D8B04218AFD35DC16684ECB1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9211 IH: Jewish American Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9211</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen Federal efforts to counter antisemitism in the United States and protect the Jewish community.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7BE0B2A2D6D04DC382D53D191A47130D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC0576B3347A84F7C988948B9ABB7A856" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CAC62A955CE4BF3A43D003B0E26DB7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jewish American Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D37752488B34AB2AE0CB75A5011F244"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HC0576B3347A84F7C988948B9ABB7A856">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HF23C34CEE53B4719A8A6371A9E7244A9">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H6EC51BA046E846A69BDE733897CF45FB">Sec. 3. Statement of policy.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H7A70E66AF39C4B4AACED67E90339ED80">Sec. 4. Protecting Jewish students.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HC03F1207C80647B0848A444C5565499C">Sec. 5. Securing Jewish communities.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H2CB485AFB9514D76BB948094A90AEAD0">Sec. 6. Documenting online antisemitism.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="HF23C34CEE53B4719A8A6371A9E7244A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H54FDBCF940094799AF25FB99A7D07731"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Antisemitism, which is often called <quote>the oldest hatred</quote>, is a serious and growing danger for the Jewish community in the United States and around the world.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9FCEB203ACF04EC0B5DC9B0A52D94F14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Antisemitism has unique characteristics, including the evolving use of conspiracy theories that blame the various ills of society on Jewish people or attribute to Jewish individuals a variety of evil and harmful characteristics, as well as the portrayal of Jewish people as too powerful or controlling and deserving of hatred and mistrust.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF72E4A12747488BA02968A48BD4E99E"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Antisemitism also exists when Jewish individuals are held responsible for the policies of the Israeli government, or attacked, disparaged, or demonized based on their real or perceived connection to, affiliation with, or support for, the State of Israel as a Jewish state.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF66D8BEB688E4AC19113F01AFEC26117"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Holocaust denial and distortion, including intentional efforts to excuse or minimize the impact of the Holocaust and dishonor Holocaust victims and survivors, reinforce the need for advancing accurate and comprehensive Holocaust education globally.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA051C762AF54D2390C80E0815568186"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Protecting the history of the Holocaust and recognizing and confronting Holocaust denial and distortion are critical to preventing antisemitism.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF9348D19E5F645E0A9590388FE61F976"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As stated in the American Jewish Committee’s report entitled <quote>State of Antisemitism in America 2025</quote>, the Committee found that 31 percent of American Jews reported being the personal target of antisemitism at least once over the preceding year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00BE67964F524EC58FEDE89E420EA839"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2024, the Federal Bureau of Investigation identified the highest number of anti-Jewish hate crime incidents ever recorded by the Bureau since it began collecting data in 1991, which number represented an annual increase of 5.8 percent in those incidents.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2A349DD87D81426E8B71279CD930788D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Although Jews only make up around 2 percent of the United States population, reported single-bias anti-Jewish hate crimes comprised 16 percent of all reported hate crimes and nearly 70 percent of all reported religion-based hate crimes in 2024, which percentages reflect increases from prior years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H725BF3C461A448BF98B5EF24D7FBACB1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 2024, the Anti-Defamation League (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>ADL</quote>) reported 9,534 antisemitic incidents in the United States, including physical assault, vandalism, and harassment, which is a 344 percent increase over the average number of such incidents during the prior 5 years and an 893 percent increase over the average number of such incidents during the prior 10 years. The 2024 number of antisemitic incidents is the highest number on record since the ADL began tracking antisemitic incidents in 1979.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA1B982C04A5D4D99A603A518358E6DCA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Jewish Americans have faced an unprecedented rise in antisemitic incidents following the October 7, 2023, Hamas terrorist attacks on Israel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDD0E400251A4E5CABC0B7D64CADC224"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Increasing antisemitism in the digital universe marked by the amplification of antisemitic harassment, comments, tropes, and violent conspiracies on online platforms, often can lead to increased security risks and additional offline acts of harassment, assault, and vandalism.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H389AA5FA65D04CC7A9F5136C91F58957"><enum>(12)</enum><text>On April 13, 2025, on the second day of Passover, an individual set multiple fires at the Pennsylvania Governor’s residence in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, while Governor Josh Shapiro and his family were inside, with the attacker stating that he was upset by the Governor’s stance on the Israel-Hamas war.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H959C830BEF4149D29B553DF504332AE8"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On May 21, 2025, a gunman shot and killed 2 Embassy of Israel staff members, Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim, as the staff members were leaving an event at the Capital Jewish Museum, in Washington, DC.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H365198A779E54C1D854CC78FD8B31CF9"><enum>(14)</enum><text>On June 1, 2025, a man used a makeshift flamethrower and Molotov cocktails to attack a group in Boulder, Colorado, as the group gathered to express solidarity for hostages being held by Hamas, which injured at least 13 people and resulted in the death of 82-year-old Karen Diamond, a Holocaust survivor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17B4E4F673E54D56B6D48ED482893DF1"><enum>(15)</enum><text>On January 10, 2026, an attacker set fire to the historic Beth Israel Congregation in Jackson, Mississippi, saying he was animated by its <quote>Jewish ties</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD9FDBB6A8906476382834093A31423CF"><enum>(16)</enum><text>On March 12, 2026, an individual drove a vehicle containing explosives into Temple Israel in West Bloomfield, Michigan, targeting a synagogue and preschool filled with more than 100 children and staff.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36555BC7135C4F96A466C92FD51541AF"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Antisemitic incidents have increased dramatically in many educational settings over the past several years, with many Jewish students facing discrimination or a hostile environment at schools, yet antisemitic incidents in schools remain underreported.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC69E0ACA44B64070B0622DCECA84EB2D"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Department of Education’s Office for Civil Rights is tasked with ensuring that all students' civil rights are protected on campus, yet there is a backlog of discrimination complaints that remain pending before the Office for Civil Rights.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31AEA3BB0B094AEE8D223F6BB417EF22"> <enum>(19)</enum> <text>On December 11, 2019, President Trump signed Executive Order 13899 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2000d">20 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> note; relating to combating anti-Semitism) which instructed all executive departments and agencies charged with enforcing title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to consider the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance Working Definition of Antisemitism and its 11 contemporary examples of antisemitism.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8EE605323344EAF8BBE54A7E8D76869"><enum>(20)</enum><text>On May 25, 2023, the Biden Administration issued the first-ever U.S. National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism, which outlined a whole-of-government and whole-of-society approach to tackle antisemitism and included more than 100 actions for Federal agencies to take and calls to action for Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA6E97693614410D9D77E3CC5BFD0922"> <enum>(21)</enum> <text>On January 30, 2025, President Trump signed Executive Order 14188 (90 Fed. Reg. 8847; relating to additional measures to combat antisemitism), to combat the surge of antisemitism on college campuses and in communities in the United States.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7D7D32A7BC2460DBBF5D378DE95C464"><enum>(22)</enum><text>While antisemitism most directly and intensely threatens those who identify or are perceived as Jewish Americans, it also undermines democracy and threatens the safety and rights of all Americans.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6EC51BA046E846A69BDE733897CF45FB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text>
<paragraph id="H0272AD4CF2704F66BBFE9C96E60E4D4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>raise awareness of and educate the United States public about the history of Jewish Americans, the Holocaust, and antisemitism in all of its forms and manifestations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C1EBF2B81584EBB83EB223B6B9F6A45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide resources to oppose antisemitism; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H55F0CA0D0C20478FB08A9188BDF869A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implement whole-of-government and whole-of-society efforts to combat antisemitism, including through close and consistent collaboration between the Federal Government, the private sector, civil society, faith leaders, law enforcement, and community leaders.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H7A70E66AF39C4B4AACED67E90339ED80"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protecting Jewish students</header> <subsection id="H12DC52361629499985FA7386F3F90375"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H5DCFDFF148D243A3B35B9C9FB0289859"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recipient</header><text>The term <term>recipient</term> means any entity receiving Federal financial assistance from the Department of Education for a program or activity covered by title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7181845EC2041439802FB9A872A9B67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCE4EC952735A469D97FF041D88286FD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB96591F677FC4CF2942EAB9DFF67E105"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act and every year thereafter for a period of 5 years, each regional office of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education shall offer trainings, which may be conducted virtually, to all recipients in the office’s region regarding recipient responsibilities under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and subsection (g).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B345B533BE9461999B22F91BAE91533"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the first day on which such an office offers such a training, and annually for 5 years thereafter, the Office for Civil Rights shall prepare and submit a report on the status of the implementation of paragraph (1) to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H35850BCE54484AC6ABA26103FF5EF52B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Title VI awareness campaign</header>
<paragraph id="H99C1329A90BA4EDFB3FC07CE9B069C27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights of the Department of Education, shall carry out a public awareness campaign for students that attend institutions that are recipients, regarding the rights protected by, and the responsibilities of recipients under, title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and subsection (g).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEABF3EC3AEC94DF48C7092202600E504"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Awareness campaign</header><text>The public awareness campaign shall include appealing visual and auditory elements. Materials for this campaign shall be updated annually and distributed to recipients for physical posting in 1 or more high-traffic public places, such as a cafeteria, gymnasium, or student center, and digital posting on 1 or more high-traffic institution web pages, such as a web page for a student services department. The campaign shall utilize such methods and materials to maximize accessibility to students and parents.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA9E31C6E253445BA4F426E2BCA4957C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ability to contract</header><text>The Secretary may carry out this subsection by contracting with an entity that specializes in public awareness communications.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H257E6F503A9E4D5DA6F49EAD1ADEBACA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Written reminder of title VI obligations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act and every year thereafter for a period of 5 years, the Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights of the Department of Education shall issue a written reminder to recipients including—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27482D36190C4C1BBF29F9A96E7FFBD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of a recipient’s responsibilities under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and subsection (g) to address antisemitism; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19B4621263C649DA8216FC85092578A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific examples of discrimination, including examples of different treatment and harassment, and of K–12 curricula that could create a hostile environment for Jewish students.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC652AB6A8D4B4B7F950A4B60CD4FB688"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Antisemitism coordinator</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall designate an employee to coordinate the Department of Education’s work on countering antisemitism as the <quote>antisemitism coordinator</quote>. The antisemitism coordinator for the Department of Education shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD804801D877142F787A1194592D1A0FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve as the principal advisor to the Secretary on the Department’s efforts to counter antisemitism;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3AB781668E1D4E21B22DCCEA3BFC728E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oversee the Department’s efforts to counter antisemitism, including implementation of Federal Government strategies to counter antisemitism and increase public awareness of the availability of rights provided to individuals under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF56BCC7A643F46AAB676BBBC86433D02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>oversee the Department’s efforts to provide technical assistance, training, and written guidance, including Dear Colleague Letters, to recipients regarding their responsibilities under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and subsection (g) to provide to all students, including those who are or are perceived to be Jewish, a school environment free from discrimination based on race, color, or national origin, including shared ancestry or ethnic characteristics;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1436D1C40D944F09AC39C82B082D716E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that the public is provided with information about how and where to file complaints of discrimination regarding antisemitism with the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19B747EE084247CEA994C4B2BA896574"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conduct biannual reviews of the nature. trends, and status of all complaints, directed investigations, and compliance reviews regarding antisemitism under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 pending at the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education and, in conjunction with the relevant regional office, develop a plan with deadlines to resolve all such complaints that have been pending for more than 180 calendar days;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89EE6371BE5742A18DE28081527D67D6" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>conduct an annual review, which will be conducted for a period of 10 years, of the implementation of the Department’s strategies to counter antisemitism, which review shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HABCA395DE07440BDAC6E8DC01685A2F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of all actions taken by the Department to counter antisemitism; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAB61EB2EB8444788BFC741ED85B3DB1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for any changes to those actions, as necessary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB812A8E2C3EC4BF2B6C884DFE2DCEF98"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure the Department has programs, including training, and resources to assist the Department’s employees in understanding and responding to antisemitism.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6B0DECA9331C41C5A9B370C29760113A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Disaggregating certain campus crime data</header><text>Section 485(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(f)</external-xref>) (known as the <quote>Jeanne Clery Disclosure of Campus Security Policy and Campus Crime Statistics Act</quote>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H56E8789B19794493A1B6A840725E314F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(F)(ii), by striking <quote>according to category of prejudice</quote> and inserting <quote>based on the bias category and bias motivation as used in the Uniform Crime Reports of the Federal Bureau of Investigation</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADBB21ACED944B5DB8C3E10122B25427" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADB8EE6B392D4D87BCC5F44031A1635D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26DBDF461C4946D68D3024B8406104F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5154C5DD95B4F42B045ADDD7950CE9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECD3B5C8BB75498FB23D038D5843B14F">
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFACBB57AF4154979A2E7352AD1C41303" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>make copies of the crimes statistics submitted to the Secretary under clause (ii) of paragraph (1)(F) available to the antisemitism coordinators for the Department of Education.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4881F0F373544BD6A7A569EE4B376F91" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (17)(B), by striking <quote>and stalking</quote> and inserting <quote>stalking, and crimes described in clause (ii) of paragraph (1)(F)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H52F6B326740F417EB64B12C1D39C017F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Recipient responsibilities</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEA42637093049DEA25707FA051F2704"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Designation of a title VI coordinator</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA57A26DF4784760A9F953C3E6F276D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each recipient shall designate and authorize at least 1 employee (referred to in this section as a <quote>title VI coordinator</quote>) to coordinate the recipient’s efforts to comply with the recipient’s responsibilities under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), including regulations implementing that title, and under this subsection. If a recipient has more than 1 title VI coordinator, the recipient shall designate 1 of its title VI coordinators to assume and maintain ultimate oversight over those responsibilities and ensure the recipient’s consistent compliance with those responsibilities. The title VI coordinator may perform other relevant responsibilities as established by the recipient.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FB21EE2A8AF4BB9905B1A2758E856A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Delegation to designees</header><text>As appropriate, subject to subparagraph (A), a recipient may delegate, or permit a title VI coordinator to delegate, specific responsibilities described in subparagraph (A) to 1 or more designees.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7C67F6B3631B4D08BA2DE1F2A6830C1E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Training</header><text>Each recipient shall ensure its title VI coordinator and any designee receive training sufficient to perform their duties—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF44C12D1C4F4615B3CA219A24302B60"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promptly after their hire or a change of position that alters their duties under this paragraph; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B9DB488ADD14999AB401912F6DD555F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annually thereafter.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7977548945A4F54813626F57415C300"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination policy requirement</header><text>Each recipient shall adopt and implement a policy of nondiscrimination on the basis of race, color, and national origin in any program or activity the recipient operates, as required by title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, including regulations implementing that title, and by this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3E8E2283C7A841E3B903158402F80651"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Title VI grievance procedure</header><text>Each recipient shall adopt, publish, and implement a title VI grievance procedure that—</text> <subparagraph id="H1FBDB0E460004FEEBCD8DDBF7EA5F5EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>states—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44B49F4F824E4C7CA3FAEBC7DD59DA35"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that anyone may report conduct, alleged to be discrimination under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) in the recipient’s program or activity, to the title VI coordinator;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81622EED399745AD9168B131BA76BEC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to report such conduct; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94360AE7A3AF4F8FB46FD64A4948896A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contact information for the title VI coordinator of the recipient;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B5E6BFF23CE43A081C2C126898AA6FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires that when the recipient receives a report of conduct that reasonably may constitute discrimination under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, in the recipient’s program or activity, the recipient shall notify the person who submitted the report of the recipient’s grievance procedure;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFD20E1DBA1DC46F4AEEB016520B394BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offers supportive measures, as appropriate to protect safety or to restore or preserve access to the recipient’s program or activity, to any student or employee who reports conduct that reasonably may constitute discrimination under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, in the recipient’s program or activity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8C430AB104A48A6B0F4453990AB36EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>includes a process for the recipient to investigate and resolve any report of conduct that reasonably may constitute discrimination under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, in the recipient’s program or activity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H54864896C563469C87D82C9F3CA99C22"><enum>(E)</enum><text>applies to reports of conduct that is alleged to be discrimination under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and is committed by the recipient, a student or an employee of the recipient, or a third party, whether known or unknown;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H672495D242044917B9C77C360A948F5A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>requires that if conduct occurred that is discrimination under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the recipient will take steps to stop the conduct, prevent its recurrence, and correct its discriminatory effects; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1F0B989E6B4A4E9CA96CE2B59B593357"><enum>(G)</enum><text>requires that the recipient provides notice of the outcome of any report under this paragraph to the person who made the report and any other affected person or entity, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78EC51A58329482992024BA2BB7B8889"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Website requirement</header><text>Each recipient shall post all policies and procedures for reporting allegations of discrimination, under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, by the recipient on the recipient’s website in a prominent location.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE65C8AB78C2849CCA3C648DE383A3088" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text>Each recipient shall provide annual notice of the recipient’s grievance procedure, described in this subsection, to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB23ED06049E4074A3519771255DA014"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all students of the recipient;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BF93902E5DB4B6E9A170B5A1BC2B080"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">parents, guardians, or other authorized legal representatives of elementary school and secondary school students of the recipient;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BF1DE692CE04B2AA63EC775E5CAC864"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees of the recipient;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8057504B08744E0A9AF646D1BAA68FCC"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicants for admission to or employment by the recipient; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A9AAD3A5F2848E9851F74855425EB03"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all unions and professional organizations holding collective bargaining or professional agreements with the recipient.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5293E800B5B9496480CB8B0C9015F4FA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recordkeeping requirement</header><text>Each recipient shall maintain for a period of 7 years—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C1F2CD1F64C4E8AB98F3274597AE65A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">records related to any reports of allegations of discrimination under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), including regulations implementing that title, including all records related to assessments of such reports, and any corrective actions taken;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H808D9AF9C2B34E7194E26345F86639FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">records documenting actions the recipient took to meet its responsibilities under that title VI and this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC59E58565D204A5C9EFD5F70CA52943D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any records of training attendance and materials relating to that title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB3489D7D41E24AD6AC9CE1B7F6B78C0D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Title VI clearinghouse at Department of Education</header>
<paragraph id="H128984D57527495391EC67074FAC3A82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
<subparagraph id="H2751C7F0C73D42FF8FD1D6D8B660FE09">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall establish, within the Department of Education, a Federal Title VI Clearinghouse on Safety, Security, and Best Practices at Institutions of Higher Education and K–12 schools (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>clearinghouse</quote>).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6AFD068C6C4B44F3B5018240C0FF0133"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The clearinghouse shall be the primary resource of the Federal Government to collect, consolidate, and publish online title VI best practices and recommendations from United States postsecondary institutions and other entities specified in paragraph (2)(A) of section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>) relating to safety, security, and means of facilitating dialogue and mutual understanding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38FE2D0AB3FB44139EAF000A941CC1BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification of the clearinghouse</header><text>Not later 30 days of the establishment of the clearinghouse, the Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives a notification and a briefing on the clearinghouse.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HC03F1207C80647B0848A444C5565499C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Securing Jewish communities</header>
<subsection id="HABC77A457152487D95AC29010D1C29B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonprofit Security Grant Program</header><text>Section 2009 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609a">6 U.S.C. 609a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBFE081A9B9DD462DB74DABD162847D9C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A1C265F4B3A4D0896F329010EF9D870"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(D), by striking <quote>5 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>10 percent</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2A303AE4BE64661AAEE8C3E7C41B8A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>5 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>10 percent</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3BA5AE367DA4D3D9D1B65471FA70042"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2028</quote> and inserting <quote>for each fiscal year for which there is an authorization of appropriations under subsection (j)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6073879B6674069A8A065F4B2FF16DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (j);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBBDE42EBBCE3435CB431AB66E9C55D3A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (h) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB615337B5F894DFAA77D22C89E5EB5EB"> <subsection id="H69AD05C2100040A8AC0EF94241B55639" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sufficient personnel and resources</header> <paragraph id="HF159726D1BDF48D299F31C0A745CDB95" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Personnel and resources</header><text>The Administrator, in coordination with Director of the Center for Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships of the Department of Homeland Security, shall ensure that the Federal Emergency Management Agency has sufficient personnel and resources to carry out this section, including to support—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16C4508695A1414D80FA0CA0932EC2E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to streamline the application process and post-approval process for a grant under the Program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81F2258EAE5F45D2BE382CDBD66802E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the increase of technical assistance to applicants for awards under the Program; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68FD4EECFEF648F989BCC19F10ECCA64"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the swift disbursement of amounts from a grant under the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H296F095014304529A57F011096895609" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with States</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3444894DDAAD46418A493A69901DAFC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall coordinate with each State through which an eligible nonprofit organization receives a grant under the Program to ensure that, not later than 90 days after the date on which an eligible nonprofit organization submits a reimbursement request to the State, the State reviews, processes, and completes that request.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27D017032790406B9BCD83D11DACC5DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subparagraph (A) shall not apply if a reimbursement request requires additional documentation under Federal or State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0429496B15449CCBB34C873E048E286" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notices of funding opportunity</header><text>The Administrator shall coordinate with each State through which an eligible nonprofit organization receives a grant under the Program to ensure that—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD458F88FA8BF4562846B79381254CEF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 90 days after the date on which Congress appropriates amounts to carry out this section, the Administrator clearly posts on any required portal a notice of funding opportunity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF159DE421DA4DDA934ABC7CAE1BE24D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not earlier than the date on which the Administrator posts a notice of funding opportunity described in subparagraph (A), the State notifies eligible nonprofit organizations within the State regarding the notice of funding opportunity and the timeline to submit applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H08BA4D8205BC49CFAAF7B6290F6456CC" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds for security personnel</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7FE4D316863F46BAB73F79A6D9938FF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall issue guidance to each State through which an eligible nonprofit organization receives a grant under the Program that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30355652D3294B0EAAB3B94EAF2C5F0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (B), prohibits the imposition of limits or percentage caps on the use of amounts from a grant under the Program for contracted or proprietary security personnel; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29FB13B4FAE4429D907F3ABF24EBCEA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensures that the State determines allowable security personnel costs based on threat, vulnerability, and risk assessments.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H914155419A0E4D0DA7F62F5059E0EB7A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prevention of misuse and fraud</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidance issued under subparagraph (A) may allow limits or percentage caps on the use of amounts from a grant under the Program to prevent misuse or fraud.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB54489801CC14A34BE18AC75A7B44A69" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Uses of amounts from a grant under this program may include employing personnel, grant management, procurement support, and financial and audit support.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA586762159D64B5AA5CA17D5C96A2B21" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reporting on personnel and resource allocation</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report on the personnel and resources assigned to carry out this section that includes—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB12735363D4C471D827B5E55B5DCA5DF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of full-time equivalent employees dedicated to carrying out the Program, including employees funded through the Israel Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/50">Public Law 118–50</external-xref>; 138 Stat. 896) or any subsequent appropriations Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4786732DCB3F4C879A21D7D21E8BD551" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how that personnel are deployed to support applicants and grantees of the Program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H33E2ABB0D1D9488E8695C81D4A40BF30" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of whether staffing levels are sufficient to meet statutory obligations under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06C98F8FBFAE41BB8AD57081E1F98796" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of whether each State through which an eligible nonprofit organization receives a grant under the Program is in compliance with paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2ABE633C98F14DC98AA49C429B8284D2" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Pre-award congressional notification</header><text>Not later than 7 days before making a public announcement or distribution of awards under this section, the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report that includes a list of recipients of grants under the Program and award amounts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0638D733C9F04186918AAEAFA7CC9CEB" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Publicly available information</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AE301A67F514B658DBB3EA74D87BA2F"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall make publicly available information relating to, with respect to the previous fiscal year—</text>
<clause id="HD53A083070B94AED8321AB32C7B1B7C0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of applications received for a grant under this section;</text></clause> <clause id="H5F35DF59F9C4490F87B7909A3F0483D6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of grants awarded under this section;</text></clause>
<clause id="H5EBC3E1AE04F47D2AAB3213615F7E1DE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of eligible nonprofit organizations that applied for a grant under this section and did not receive the grant; and</text></clause> <clause id="HABE6E00E54D9408484340C652583C527" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the criteria and scoring methodology used to evaluate applications for grants under this section, including any changes made from the prior fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE53B8AEF0A354BABB3154B0C33B209F6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Administrator may not make public any identifying information of applicants for or recipients of grants under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9F8F541F04C4200AD299D844D6430EA" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Neutral administration</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA334C2987DB14E9CAD6E6859FE9F1F18"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall administer the Program in a nondiscriminatory manner.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88289EE986BC4E9599D228E2CF7239B1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator and any State through which an eligible nonprofit organization receives a grant under this section may not impose eligibility terms or conditions on applicants, recipients, or beneficiaries of the grant that would advantage or disadvantage those applicants, recipients, or beneficiaries based solely on the religious, political, or ideological affiliation of the applicants, recipients, or beneficiaries.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BF2EF8FA9FF46E69BBA0C26105412A8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Administrator to ensure compliance with Federal civil rights laws, nondiscrimination statutes, or national security vetting requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H11CD9BF4A7A34BCDA297DE211515AE8E" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Review of allowable costs</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E29D426710D4CFFB5A0D15E138C69DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than frequently than annually, the Administrator, in consultation with recipients of grants under this section, nonprofit organizations, security professionals, and States through which an eligible nonprofit organization receives a grant under this section, shall review and, as necessary, update the Eligible Equipment List of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to reflect up-to-date threats, security risks, technology advancements, and community needs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87885F61761649798FFAEC28F7008017" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a review is carried out under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall publish on the website of the Federal Emergency Management the review and any updated list resulting from the review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7273A2ACD7364E7296F4C83B037DDFE8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (j), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79D69493E1E242659B3DD2602EF6078E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>$360,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BC0EEA9BFF5449FB0783A74E971F117"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>$180,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$500,000,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD091A2C4AC064B6CB520ABE39EC2D01D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>$180,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$500,000,000</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC1F8036EF4204FB5AC72C73E138A138A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policing support to houses of worship</header>
<paragraph id="HCFB6E021294F48DF8D6F52A98B618E75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall collaborate with State and local law enforcement agencies seeking to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81B4F6750CDC4336AD0287A09847C0F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance security measures for at-risk religious institutions as a result of increased acts and threats of violence against houses of worship; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3960C7819C184732B7F792B2E37756A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address the precipitous increase in hate crimes targeting individuals on the basis of religion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66F97ADB278D442D95E95397CE681EA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Attorney General may award grants to State and local law enforcement agencies to—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85E2381132E94D9D8102ABB51C98C03A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support increased policing presence, patrols, and training; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H858E73224E694E92B0C164A628D3D3C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide other forms of assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC2793DBD5CA849919AC5F306CE592F70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>During each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031, the Attorney General may use such sums as may be necessary out of the amounts reserved pursuant to section 506(b) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10157">34 U.S.C. 10157(b)</external-xref>) to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6ECFF27D3F6048B180932064BBF8401F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Threat assessments</header> <paragraph id="HD3CDA5669C7B4DC4A6BDFEA7FB571CA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Joint annual domestic threat assessment</header> <subparagraph id="HA69C334D9F0D420A81BF2F27133F6F61"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center shall jointly produce an annual threat assessment of antisemitic violent domestic extremism in the United States.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B382027C58A4B39BA09FE312E1129D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The joint annual domestic threat assessment required under subparagraph (A) shall include, for the period covered by the report—</text> <clause id="HCB53640EF7D14E9E8EDE51AF98C22501"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an overview of violent extremist ideologies that include antisemitic components;</text></clause>
<clause id="H04CBF6BAF73A44E7B3A5825B5E4C5F68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a review of the extent that actors in the United States have engaged in violent conduct in furtherance of the ideologies described in clause (i);</text></clause> <clause id="H2DD0E79569E64F71AE477DB7D3C819F5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the origins and online platforming and online activity or presence of antisemitic domestic violent extremist ideologies, groups, and individuals, including any evidence of—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A4659318D1E4C2BAE3FA5A3B56117B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inauthentic amplification, such as bots or algorithmic manipulation campaigns; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9557580E81E84F95B2EB3C8D5EF857AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the involvement of foreign state and non-state actors; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H0D577E607573433896CECE9EC0F382CF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an assessment of the threat that antisemitic domestic violent extremism poses to the United States homeland.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33EA2B5FC9D3451FB9A9EDFB85039633"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dissemination</header> <clause id="H9378E87B489E45768F1BE77C3A079083"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center shall submit the joint annual domestic threat assessment required under subparagraph (A), including any classified annexes, to—</text>
<subclause id="H7D52F463A1664A1B8C22F6B6C168291C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H18F9A0BF4B5F46EFAD1E1E948C71DD15"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H1F0933CAB4794AD2B8E209C79EF004B6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H89C7365319C4407BAD7D5754ACB86E32"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H1C597D4C6A564548B80EA231558195C7"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H52A3254B67B24EC0A976DEE2A2DAB62F"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H6214B043FBFE44EB9AC0BB2D4C7EEE25"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2556840BF8ED4FA9B75A7BA17195CF5D"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H9244C91CDB0446E7859DB80B543C06EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Declassified version</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall make publicly available a declassified version of the joint annual domestic threat assessment required under subparagraph (A) on the public website of the Federal Bureau of Investigation concurrently with the version submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7B87A6005FC46E5BB1DCC4A7A8F0616"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No version of the domestic threat assessment required under subparagraph (A) shall include personally identifiable information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA0A729CA62B94E07A889329CB9988747"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint annual threat assessment of antisemitic transnational violent extremism</header>
<subparagraph id="HD58C23462DB14BE8B80B91167FE4C0E7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center shall jointly produce an annual threat assessment of antisemitic transnational violent extremism.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3857BB91E786417D9D28FDFAC9614483"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The joint annual transnational threat assessment required under subparagraph (A) shall include, for the period covered by the report—</text>
<clause id="H5DE3BA21394A465EAAFC6E3EA51F660C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an overview of transnational violent extremist ideologies that include antisemitic components, including international and domestic extremism;</text></clause> <clause id="H74227BA44DAC42C79CDAAC09DE54515B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a review of the extent to which actors in the United States have engaged in violent conduct in furtherance of the ideologies described in clause (i);</text></clause>
<clause id="H8EDE3927341C412187BC69F8515C94C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the origins and online platforming or online activity of antisemitic transnational violent extremist ideologies, including any evidence of inauthentic amplification on digital platforms, such as bots or campaigns, and any involvement of foreign state and non-state actors;</text></clause> <clause id="H924E8CFDFCD247A8986499FDBAACF916"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an assessment of the threat that antisemitic transnational violent extremism poses to the United States homeland, United States citizens abroad, and United States military personnel; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H2F96AF580B5B47A4BA97EE4F60DFC055"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an overview of how antisemitic transnational violent extremism impacts the interests and the global standing of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80A1AFAB935846999AD13E0F17088E49"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dissemination</header> <clause id="HFBA021B8EA1E4F4AA8A09FABF1C63406"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center shall submit the joint annual transnational threat assessment required under subparagraph (A), including any classified annexes, to—</text>
<subclause id="HA3F12AB0B0B8487180461D0A61A53DEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H85803093F8D9409AAC2DC8D560C15984"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H197E0A0DACF949EF977D94C529A0A698"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF9A3896C887C4586B98544DBAC64ABB0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H0EF2094FB37147A9A1A76D53B3E86AD9"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Committee of Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCFD0EECDD4AD4278BFC09D8B2B121776"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H7FC39F0CFCE5418DA619AB6C03A3B4D3"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0F4AC2475E95455DAA3810EEE2EB7C05"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H39F3DB045C924317952194314B2DFD82"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9B1A3DF41B3A417DA0033693764B05C2"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HB8F66B22747448D2B2C89BB504FA1850"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Declassified version</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall make publicly available a declassified version of the joint annual transitional threat assessment required under subparagraph (A) on the public website of the Federal Bureau of Investigation concurrently with the version submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H750B1D6A36054767B817865683043FC9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No version of the domestic threat assessment required under subparagraph (A) shall include personally identifiable information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H2CB485AFB9514D76BB948094A90AEAD0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Documenting online antisemitism</header>
<subsection id="H3375F52556894B8EAA71F1F14FC4E5E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Online platform transparency reports</header>
<paragraph id="HE6D2C3D8CEC94074A504BE32AC46C29E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, an online platform shall submit to the Commission and publish in a publicly available and easily accessible manner a transparency report regarding the online platform's content moderation practices and efforts to detect, remove, limit the visibility of, and prevent the amplification of antisemitic content on the website or application of the online platform.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H48CADCCA70284D15B8DE57FF66542278"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each transparency report submitted and published in accordance with paragraph (1) shall include the following information:</text> <subparagraph id="H85D75C70083C4731A2764DCBB02FE376"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of each safety mechanism in place on the website or application of the online platform, including—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE233F75C929488BA79A94E53E244CE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of any automated system or human review; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B5447DB18124FD7B538C8792C1A8BD4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a human reviewer, a summary of the scope and training related to reviewing and making content removal decisions.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC3B6EFA1E9D94E59AA301F6EB847A708"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the practices or tools used to make content moderation efforts against extremist antisemitism more effective.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7091D4F5ADAA4401B24ED20B780180DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>What, if any, information is shared with law enforcement when there is evidence of extremist antisemitic calls or threats to violence on the website or application of the online platform.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7631E831CCC24508B2AB918F119954AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>What, if any, changes to content moderation policies or management are made in the wake of antisemitic violence and extremist attacks and how long such changes remain in place.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48CDFEF04C3D471EAAE97FB3B33B1491"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The total number of instances during the reporting period that content on the website or application of the online platform was determined to be violative by the online platform because such content was identity-based hatred or harassment, including the amount of such content that was violative as antisemitic (in this subsection referred to as <quote>antisemitic platform content</quote>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H54B1274E0DCB4817A148E778A18AFEC3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The amount of antisemitic platform content for which the online platform took a responsive action, including the amount with respect to each category of responsive action (such as removal, demonetization, or deprioritizing or limiting the viewing capacity of such content).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA95473A1CF4546AFA64F9B8784C873C2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Out of the total amount of antisemitic platform content that was removed, the percentage of such content that had more than 100 views.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H229905D4DED24BAC918655BB1C8F64EC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The percentage breakdown and prevalence of which specific digital policies or community guidelines were violated with respect to the antisemitic platform content that was subject to a responsive action.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55A938243F7347D88398F8FC483FD64B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The percentage and total amount of antisemitic platform content that was promoted, suggested, amplified, or shared by an online platform’s recommendation algorithm.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEFB8D17ED887445DAD380E81CD3EA20D"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An estimate of the amount of content that violates the content policies of the online platform, but remains on the website or application of the online platform.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H659240E066E34745B250202D6512DE7A"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A description of how any changes in enforcement policies, processes, or technologies implemented during the reporting period have impacted the amount of antisemitic platform content that remains on the website or application of the online platform.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2465479F9C474375B1F64EEC61765B5A"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The total number of accounts suspended or removed for violating the online platform's policies related to antisemitism, including the number of such accounts that were—</text> <clause id="H6C259E96354849E28390961613115AB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inauthentic or bot accounts;</text></clause>
<clause id="HE703E9196774411F9F7C20DEEEA67ECA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identified to be associated with foreign terrorist organizations;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15B21E9D98B94543A431FCA15ED443E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified to be associated with unverifiable or inconsistent geolocation patterns; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HBCDE27614C2F4EA0B1F61037B616C7AC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an account that meets 2 of the criteria described in clauses (i), (ii), or (iii).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0440930D8E0F49999A52F6B6150E25CC"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The amount of antisemitic platform content and corresponding engagement metrics, including views, likes, shares, and comments generated by an account described in subparagraph (L) prior to the suspension or removal of such account.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDC22D4FE80AF4B259BDC0B4B54E03E1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Commission</header>
<subparagraph id="HAA55A8940BB24F9B86A21F56EABDD203"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EA9ABBE38454B06BDDC44D56C026DAF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> <clause id="H15E3F06CC3F14763BAC1DD2DEADD6F7C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section and any regulation promulgated under this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></clause>
<clause id="HB7968A2879EA4A7AA75FBB88745014F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this section or any regulation promulgated under this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause> <clause id="HB4481801EC3848DB9AD77DDC2FAE4327"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></clause>
<clause id="H8D1A547BF4D24AFCA335AEBB5039B8D0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBB9C3D1C4AB43D9B5C2402138E06345"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph id="H6E8D87A2EC4147C8BC9F5DEA662B6774"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7738224FE084169B5046149CA62611D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Online platform</header><text>The term <term>online platform</term> means any entity subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) that—</text>
<clause id="HE47D5E68D0A545B6A7BA231DF56503E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>operates a website, desktop application, augmented or virtual reality application, or mobile application that—</text> <subclause id="H41622F2ABC744D488B76CDD975265285"><enum>(I)</enum><text>permits a person to become a registered user, establish an account, or create a profile for the purpose of allowing the user to create, share, listen to, or view user-generated content through such an account or profile;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H50555765C90C41A8B4EAD1A086F8B820"><enum>(II)</enum><text>enables 1 or more users to generate content that can be listened to or viewed by other users of the online platform; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCBCF088EF9454C419C8BB22BEFCC80E7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>primarily serves as a medium for users to interact with content generated by other users of the online platform and for the online platform to deliver ads to users; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H07820E442F704FB2BACB32B9DB1FA6E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has at least 50,000,000 unique monthly users in the United States for a majority of the months in the most recent 12-month period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9A949D700191481EBBA8226E75F271D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports relating to antisemitic content</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H941DAB96E3154B0F8730946B045A3035"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86063D074EAB45B6B3AFB525FCBE012C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trend data regarding online antisemitic content that has been linked to offline antisemitic violence; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F86346818AE434087576904E38B9052"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations relating to Federal policies and transparency requirements that may be adopted and actions that may be taken by online platforms to prevent antisemitism online from turning into real-world violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD97A7EAB9E0344D681AACBCD321C7950"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5293B90E8E3B4FF0BB89D2268A7002FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCA3DB667AE84307AEE28EC22FC25AB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB36826553F6449819A79F9AE07E6B400"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBD6C3D6C2DD46978BFC23C5CC9F94F3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE9B5F3709CD4499963332BDE67D10A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6BCB59C4A6EB4436948125EBB04160C4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H119DB22E1DFF44B4948796F676AAF831"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF987921728E94F459B81DB8DF5C140CE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H224FED830CD34F819021C53CAED8A0EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision or phrase of this section, or the application of any provision or phrase of this section to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional or otherwise invalid, the remainder of this section, and the application of the provisions and phrases of this section to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

