<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25C59-CLP-RF-H4W"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3077 IS: Safer Supervision Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 3077</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20251030">October 30, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide appropriate standards for the inclusion of a term of supervised release after imprisonment, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H701C0FA614F5448CB1DC3E6A1219342A"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="S1"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Supervision Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="id049ab728ffdf470c8d68acd6669d8210"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Findings</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="iddf00cc2f18444c749d67690fd06782d4"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Over 110,000 people were on Federal supervised release as of December 2024.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id02fac7365b6943948393bd88af8030c5"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The Supreme Court of the United States explained in Johnson v. United States that <quote>Supervised release departed from the parole system it replaced by giving district courts the freedom to provide postrelease supervision for those, and only those, who needed it. ... Congress aimed, then, to use the district courts’ discretionary judgment to allocate supervision to those releasees who needed it most.</quote>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id02ea30ed330f438c973751a7861288bd"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Federal probation officers report significant caseloads that can exceed 100 cases per officer. This can create a difficult burden for the officers and limit their ability to provide appropriate supervision to those who need it.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ida5aa8ad761f349198dd4f2ecc7a66579"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>The potential for early termination or other modifications of supervision, when consistent with public safety, can not only reduce burdens and save valuable judicial resources but also create positive incentives for compliance and rehabilitation consistent with the purposes of supervision. Requests for early termination and appeals from the denial of early termination are not challenges to the original sentence but rather an integral part of the rehabilitative scheme established by Congress. In the 12-month period ending in December 2024, early terminations were 29 percent of successful supervised release closures.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id619cfe043f7c48e3b2f20b561e700177"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>The Administrative Office of the United States Courts has explained that <quote>excessive correctional intervention for low-risk defendants may increase the probability of recidivism by disrupting prosocial activities and exposing defendants to antisocial associates.</quote>.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id85b6af784f0b4f88bdf93cf67430d217"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>Supervised release is and should remain an important tool for the Federal courts to use, as appropriate, to, among other items, protect the public from further crimes, deter future criminal conduct, and help the defendant become a contributing member of society by recovering from substance use disorder, participating in rehabilitation and training programs, and providing restitution to victims, among other outcomes.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ida1e196497aed4aa884d72b2edf3a40f2"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text>Better tailoring when and how supervised release is imposed, encouraging early termination when appropriate, and expanding judicial discretion on certain revocations will reduce burdens on law enforcement officers and taxpayers, encourage compliance and improve public safety, and better assist defendants in their pursuit of rehabilitation and reintegration, to the benefit of themselves, victims, and communities.</text> </paragraph> </section> <section id="id82bd36a6c4184b5ba844da3bff802574"> <enum>3.</enum> <header>Inclusion of a term of supervised release after imprisonment</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3583 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="id2aa6212bc1de46a6b91037eaf46bc911"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="id04e0493e9d9f445c9c72572dab979f78"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>The court</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id519ead1baa3c4456b3edb6ebe223fb66"> 
<paragraph id="id624d0cd8ec1f4ba8b3a7cad9891de9a8"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The court</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idf9087027939c46b894dec1ac7bd0c13b"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f9a65ca7fdd430aba37f2e824065eaf"> 
<paragraph id="id1ca7c8ae70d3499e867f1c9a9b7dd686"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Individualized assessment</header> <text>When determining whether to include a term of supervised release as part of the sentence, and except to the extent that a term of supervised release is required by statute as described in paragraph (1), the court shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idef9f283e722c4d35bf44acff2fcf3c05"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>make an individualized assessment under the factors set forth in subsections (c) and (d) as to—</text> 
<clause id="idd01506d112344e8392a0d6c9afdc628a"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>whether such a term is appropriate; and</text> </clause> <clause id="ide6068a0b43f649f18d30c70761415fb8"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the appropriate length and conditions of such a term; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id56858c9b073940a98d337f50e33a5ba7"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>provide the reasons of the court for imposing or not imposing such a term on the record.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id684013df6d7d4c8c8e42bc2b21a43628"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in subsection (d), in the fifth sentence, by striking <quote>shall also</quote> and inserting <quote>may also</quote>;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idf7ebe3d66a7f43f58ff14320d52c3b71"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>in subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph id="idc5f75c5770d8441d9d41a41a0e47dea8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (4) as subparagraphs (A) through (D), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id4311f70663f04205a650cbbf8f52a6df"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>The court may,</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id996c322cd5624fb79ab04829b977bdad"> <paragraph id="id99f2dc2e38494c0aac41373ece3f2f03"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Subject to paragraph (2), the court may,</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id0b1a9b53287b4673a79e69f667600b27"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (A), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>after the expiration of one year of supervised release</quote>;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4d0f1a3904374c56baeca1a7e02f6cdb"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (C), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>this paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>this subparagraph</quote>;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id8ab28677ecc84541abf86d84327f5065"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (D), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>this paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>this subparagraph</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ide97a7e30134f4758be03a96ddcbd0f52"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48bd13f29e3447b4a8147fdf6d205337"> 
<paragraph id="idfe867e782a9444e6a78ecc5b3482b763"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Termination of supervised release</header> <text>For purposes of the termination of supervised release under paragraph (1)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="id8306463429ea4caa88bc53bbd6a115e1"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>after a defendant has served the lesser of 1 year of supervised release or 50 percent of the term of supervised release imposed on the defendant, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall provide notice to a defendant, defendant’s counsel, and any local Federal Public Defender Organization or Community Defender Organization of the opportunity to seek early termination of supervised release under paragraph (1)(A) and the process for doing so;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idf483097f2bc943fb80a8b5bd2a51a8d9"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>there shall be a presumption of early termination of supervised release for a defendant under supervision if—</text> <clause id="id645fcb75e2024c818aaca39b16fe2771"> <enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id91baa650d2b844c2bfcc213ced78b718"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>for a defendant serving a term of supervised release imposed in connection with a conviction for an offense described in subsection (a) of section 16, the defendant has served 66.6 percent of the term of supervised release imposed on the defendant; or</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="ideb116658088c4c67975bd232f7d9a258" indent="up1"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>for a defendant other than a defendant described in subclause (I), the defendant has served 50 percent of the term of supervised release imposed on the defendant;</text> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="idf129e6d4c04d41caac82d09f78982b61"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the defendant has demonstrated good conduct and compliance while on supervised release; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="idc30f4db74f7749e3a4239f714f4356c0"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>the early termination will not jeopardize public safety;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idf6bd084e0eb14868b39d08060f16bcd2"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the Government shall have an opportunity to object to a request for termination of supervised release and to present evidence, which the defendant shall have the opportunity to rebut, in any proceeding relating to such request; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idb26788201b484589a80bcc8fc818cc45"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>crime victims’ rights under section 3771 shall apply to any proceeding relating to a request for early termination of supervised release.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id9b4144da46af473896eb544c0fed53f6"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Public safety</header> <text>In assessing whether early termination of supervised release will not jeopardize public safety under this subsection, the court shall consider the nature of the offense committed by the defendant, the defendant’s criminal history, the defendant’s record while incarcerated (including good behavior and violations of prison rules), the defendant’s efforts to avoid recidivism, the defendant’s health status, any statements or information provided by victims of the offense, and other factors the court may find relevant to public safety.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idfa11fdfc4f7a479b9dcb4411a6a399af"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Good conduct and compliance</header> <text>In assessing whether the defendant has demonstrated good conduct and compliance under this subsection, the court shall consider the defendant’s efforts to reintegrate into the community and the defendant’s substantial compliance with the conditions of supervision.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idd1c346925e8c4ee4bc0e86de051e7892"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Assistance of counsel</header> <text>The court may appoint a Federal public defender, a community defender, or other counsel qualified to be appointed under section 3006A to assist a defendant seeking early termination of supervised release under paragraph (1)(A) or modification of conditions under paragraph (1)(B).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id0ed55d27e6fd484d9c6a8b9aecaaf38e"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Rule of construction</header> <text>Paragraph (2)(B) shall not be construed to limit the discretion of a court under paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idff2d2c76dae446779a7c41bae527c16e"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Clarification</header> <text>The early termination of supervised release under paragraph (1)(A) does not require extraordinary conduct or unforeseen circumstances.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idd2f53c8e62bc453f83b66c9a40716d88"> <enum>(8)</enum> <header>Applicability</header> <text>The ability to seek the early termination of supervised release under paragraph (1)(A) shall not be affected by the plea agreement of the defendant.</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ide5aae18c6db6481186df386dacfbdc58"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>in subsection (g)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id10ad869fb9f7418ebb0939c0feb3868f"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">possession of controlled substance or firearm or for refusal To comply with drug testing</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">distribution of a controlled substance or possession of a firearm</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8042fef790b146faa708dda7eac6a5d7"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d50ca69f3c34015885d1515ef2ae476"> 
<paragraph id="ida3c9b4d8a26a4c8d8246c5131d525d9e"> <enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ided909c5c075a4252a066b3949db48447"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>possesses a controlled substance with the intent to distribute; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id1ced14ac686e4bf5a051dc9c6d7f7de3" indent="up1"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>possesses a controlled substance, the possession of which may be punished under Federal law by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idf688d252185949d0a379777461a0c742"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6a818c68b551450db73c1fdda19a9d00"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf386518a5b4841b6b5a704820ddb2d99"> 
<paragraph id="ide990e288eae441d9a2411462d32672b4"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>willfully refuses to comply with drug testing imposed as a condition of supervised release;</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id922f9080cdab4c07917722f94959d851"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>by striking paragraph (4); and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="ide89afd3342674f05ae7599b85257565f"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>in the matter following paragraph (4), by striking <quote>subsection (e)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e)(1)(C)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id4ca1db7826194bb28d93de578a029838"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>in subsection (k), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>subsection (e)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e)(1)(C)</quote>.</text> </paragraph> </section> 
<section id="idf13441f835854ec392429de44181d15f"> <enum>4.</enum> <header>Law enforcement availability pay for probation and pretrial services officers</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report containing a legislative proposal, and considerations for implementation of the proposal, that would provide law enforcement availability pay to Federal probation officers and pretrial services officers that is equal to that provided to criminal investigators under section 5545a of title 5, United States Code.</text> </section> <section id="id19489864b5494e1e8457ab25c73739ae"> <enum>5.</enum> <header>Allowing prisoners not sentenced to supervised release to apply earned time credits</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3624(g) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a6d08576d8d4053b1d76e30f5e8777c"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="USC" level="subsection">Supervised</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0641d5b5d76546d5823f49ac99597a2e"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in paragraph (1)(D)—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84923ac55cdf4710b1ee3f79c24fd92a"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), by striking <quote>supervised</quote> each place it appears; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1963b8a143841ffa7a7fa580d115b12"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>placed in supervised release</quote> and inserting <quote>released</quote>;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide80a9e57c5bd4ecba4c4558bc91541a1"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e2e92a194b740eda8505d48fc48a71c"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(3) <header-in-text style="USC" level="paragraph">Supervised release</header-in-text>.—If the sentencing court</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id270791d515c7498c96e5e23527fecd96"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcf045fd6933455688455ea80528525c"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Release</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb35cee1d17d44499bef886245bbf92e"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supervised release imposed</header> <text>If the sentencing court</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01d25b70e24e4c9596cff4acc5e60dbd"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1862db1b3cf4ac391d09339ef16d28b"> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5faf17c839f4d21b23df236e20a925b"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Supervised release not imposed</header> <text>If the sentencing court did not impose a term of supervised release, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons may release the prisoner at an earlier date, not to exceed 12 months, based on the application of time credits under section 3632.</text> </subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6b7a5924b7f4544b1d503f6d3df0a1b"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>in paragraph (6)(A), by striking <quote>supervised</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e16ba855e654a5b99c218a490320386"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>in paragraph (7)(B), by striking <quote>supervised</quote>.</text> </paragraph> </section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id14b193f2a94d4dfaa31345c8f653e727"> <enum>6.</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">GAO report</header> <subsection id="idbd43546f9ade4fb1af88c3e8def8243d"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Initiation of study</header> <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate a study on Federal post-release supervision and reentry services.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="id37eb137424ee4abc9a74ac994fed1c99"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Report</header> <text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report regarding the study under subsection (a), which shall include findings and potential recommendations related to—</text> <paragraph id="idb18f3619a5f04a708c9280cd7f16a679"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the number of individuals that have been placed on Federal probation or supervised release since 2019;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idda5d80df15a040218acb61fb5a8a7e96"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the process for transitioning an individual from the custody of the Bureau of Prisons to the Office of Probation and Pretrial Services or the custody of the United States Marshals Service;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id7db763024d334062ba0c817f86be3680"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>a review of Federal programs or funding sources that aim to assist individuals from the custody of the Bureau of Prisons with reentry, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="ida51c64ed5cbc4341b61938719c214ebb"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>ongoing mental health and substance use counseling, housing, medical care, education, and job placement; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id79f4a495ddbd49c18494fe7fc9173a4f"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>any changes in such programs or funding since 2019;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id6a65bffee78b48d4b2e4e7f20a64c2f4"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>a workforce assessment of judicial districts, including an analysis of—</text> <subparagraph id="idbc26211cb5c54e738e96d90b107ec3b3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>during the most recent 2 years for which data is available, the number of officers, officer caseloads, and overtime hours worked, reported, or accrued; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id0aab33084f1d4307943c532606540f8e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the system for tracking overtime hours worked by officers of the Office of Probation and Pretrial Services; and</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id837efd0db5a346aca483f0d5bacc7984"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>the funding formula for probation offices, including an assessment of how that formula affects incentives for the recommendation of early termination of supervised release.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body>
</bill>


