<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26026-6VR-HP-7T5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 589 ATS: Congratulating the Montana State University football team for winning the 2025 Division I Football Championship Subdivision Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 589</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Montana State University football team for winning the 2025 Division I Football Championship Subdivision Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 5, 2026, the Montana State University Bobcats football team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Bobcats</quote>) won the National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Football Championship Subdivision (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>FCS</quote>) national championship by defeating the Illinois State University Redbirds 35 to 34 in a thrilling overtime victory;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bobcats secured their first FCS Championship since 1984 and fourth national championship title for football in school history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach Brent Vigen led the Bobcats to a second consecutive national championship appearance and third appearance during his 5-year tenure;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bobcats secured the 2025 Big Sky Conference Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bobcats defeated their archrivals, the University of Montana Grizzlies, in the game known as the <quote>Brawl of the Wild</quote> on November 22, 2025, in Missoula, Montana;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, on December 20, 2025, in Bozeman, Montana, the Bobcats defeated the University of Montana Grizzlies again in the first postseason matchup between the two programs since the rivalry began in 1897;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bobcats finished the season on a 14-game winning streak, defeating seven ranked opponents;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President of Montana State University, Dr. Brock Tessman, former President, Dr. Waded Cruzado, and Athletic Director, Leon Costello, have fostered a dedication of athletic and academic excellence at the institution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas five Bobcats earned FCS Football Central All-American honors, including offensive lineman Titan Fleischmann, safety Caden Dowler, defensive lineman Kenneth Eiden IV, running back Julius Davis, and defensive lineman Paul Brott;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 44 players on the Montana State roster are from Montana and embody the State’s values of possessing a strong work ethic, toughness, and dedication;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the national championship game, quarterback Justin Lamson rushed for two touchdowns and threw for 280 yards and two touchdowns, including the game-tying touchdown pass on fourth down in overtime, earning the game’s Most Outstanding Player;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Taco Dowler, from Billings, Montana, caught eight passes for a total of 111 yards, including the game-tying touchdown catch in overtime.</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bobcat special teams blocked a fourth quarter field goal attempt and overtime extra point attempt, preventing Illinois State from taking and extending crucial leads late in the game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Myles Sansted kicked the game-winning extra point in overtime to secure a hard-fought victory; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bobcats were supported at the game in Nashville, Tennessee, by the Spirit of the West Marching Band, cheerleaders, and thousands of faculty members, students, alumni, and fans from around Montana and the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id28de03097b6e44c0aede54ae9461a047"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Montana State University Bobcats football team for winning the 2025 Division I Football Championship Subdivision Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad69a581e0ee4dcdabcc8997ce0a8c9a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the players, coaches, staff, and fans whose hard work and dedication led to the championship; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id649f5bc565bd43fb998310b341d502cc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate prepare an official copy of the resolution for presentation to—</text><subparagraph id="id35b148dff7f14c89bf7bcabf26b16e86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President of Montana State University, Dr. Brock Tessman;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfc760004e004bb695bef7dafb58fca6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Athletic Director, Leon Costello; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ad7a4ce255347ef8bc7042d1561bfa6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>head coach of the Montana State University football team, Brent Vigen.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

