<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3ACC2B9E018E466285DD0866D099FF4A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6693 IH: Streamlining Authorizations for Listed At-risk Marine and Aquatic Natural Disaster Emergency Resources Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6693</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish expedited permitting procedures for post-natural disaster recovery activities, incorporating interagency coordination and best management practices to ensure timely rebuilding while protecting endangered species, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H98034B18F1AB43F89438EAAB195045D8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE64187F6BC5848D2B7D6F0937484C16E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlining Authorizations for Listed At-risk Marine and Aquatic Natural Disaster Emergency Resources Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SALAMANDER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H0190F6167B704B14B9EDA883FD811ED2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9730850C621B4AEBB53F8BBE14D74950"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Natural disasters cause significant damage to communities and infrastructure, requiring rapid and efficient recovery efforts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE691842531E46AE9A92EABC3EAE6C8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Timely repair and restoration of damaged property and assets after a natural disaster are essential for public safety, economic stability, and the swift return of private property to rightful owners.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13CBA436AA784917858742F93F721761"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Corps of Engineers nationwide permit program serves as an efficient mechanism for managing activities that involve discharges into and rehabilitation of waters of the United States, as defined in the Federal Water Pollution Control Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A197D0E272145FF836EFC58BE0A85BA" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Endangered Species Act of 1973 requires Federal agencies to consult with the Directors of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the National Marine Fisheries Service, as applicable, to avoid actions that could jeopardize listed species or critical habitats of such species.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC183E7CB488B41CABB021CB581ECB56A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>While environmental protection is critical, current consultation processes can sometimes contribute to delays in post-disaster recovery.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE582422A3851451BB7CFF1084CC37059"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive, coordinated, and expedited approach for post-disaster permitting that leverages the biological expertise of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the National Marine Fisheries Service, and incorporates approved best management practices, will reduce regulatory delays while maintaining robust environmental safeguards.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H1E7D8A8C4315487E8091F5EAA064DBCB"><enum>3.</enum><header>General permits for dredged or fill material disposal in post-disaster recovery</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404(e) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD41A5519C3E84551BF75287CEED6D6A4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H94ACF01A02F24CF69F38DD69BA962FC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>General permits for post-disaster recovery activities</header> 
<subparagraph id="H272ED25A4D2B40D99222EF45028779EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any geographic area with respect to which the President has declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) that a major disaster or emergency exists, the Secretary may issue or modify a general permit under this subsection for any category of activities—</text> <clause id="H627E4E287E784784AF741FFFE33BC410"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary develops pursuant to a programmatic consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, Secretary of Commerce, and Secretary of Agriculture, as applicable, under section 7(a)(2) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(a)(2)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H026CA3B4B46E4AF9990BDB147B0DDE9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which activities—</text> <subclause id="H62FF7DD5B42E4940B7D76A263663050D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are directly related to recovering from the major disaster or emergency; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H707DDA1D83B34F3394FFC0D314DC8AD3" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior, Secretary of Commerce, and Secretary of Agriculture, as applicable, have determined through such programmatic consultation will avoid or minimize adverse effects on any species listed as a threatened species or an endangered species under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>) and the critical habitat (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>)) of such a species when adhering to best management practices described in subparagraph (B).</text> </subclause></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA0EACF402DE4AB2810AC0CFFAEA7B5D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Best management practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A general permit issued or modified under this paragraph shall require the use of best management practices that have been—</text> 
<clause id="H6DDBF401FE4B4B4D9795417B584265F9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>agreed upon by the Secretary and, as applicable, the Secretary of the Interior, Secretary of Commerce, and Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2210209A45EF4144A4DA824FAE6094ED" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designed to avoid or minimize adverse effects on species listed as threatened species or endangered species under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>) and the critical habitat (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>)) of such species.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA2F9B8735CC4BDFA7295441F56F8C64"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A general permit, or modification to a general permit, issued under this paragraph shall be for the period of 18 months beginning on the date of the declaration of the major disaster or emergency by the President.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0F4D335BC164BEFB2964E91C86D9A25"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Effect on individual consultation</header><text>An activity authorized by a general permit issued or modified under this paragraph and carried out in accordance with the requirements of such general permit is not subject to section 7(a)(2) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3C62C11EFE4406E8EFBDA2B441BCF15"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Coordination with States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate with relevant State fish and wildlife agencies in carrying out this paragraph, including by engaging with such agencies not later than 30 days after the date of a declaration of a major disaster or emergency by the President.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDC62AE8C2434B4EBEA0ED2E4919EE05"><enum>(F)</enum><header>National guidance</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall establish guidance to ensure consistent implementation of this paragraph across each district of the Corps of Engineers.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

