<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B8D2A8D084E4A47AF75F483533327C0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7610 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a credit for adult child caregivers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7610</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a credit for adult child caregivers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9D693446CD1A4B00A39777D991D1C6E6" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB78EEEA6764442B8936D33FC860CAD4C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H7A38FB75862E4680940DDA5AAEC2C378"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Once formed, multigenerational families tend to live together over time and utilize less paid and unpaid formal support. Adult child proximity may be more directly linked with reduced need for formal care than availability of a spouse.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8DADB056D06B4F218596D1D20FDD3A95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Older adults in multigenerational homes experience less depression and isolation, and show improved cognition with concurrent hearing loss.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09989C262907420EAEBEF1D4EC693F52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An older adult with dementia and disability co-residing with an adult child has a 50 percent lower risk of transitioning from the community to a nursing home in the subsequent 2 years, compared to older adults supported by children living outside the home.</text></paragraph></section>
<section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5899531D9434853AA4AE134B686C429"><enum>2.</enum><header>Multigenerational home caregiver credit</header>
<subsection id="H7ADF2B126CF64440985607C601176B40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 25E the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H970521AEB11042A09D2CAFBBFD9184F9"> <section id="H65CB99FC70AA49389A6975F31108A4BD"><enum>25F.</enum><header>Multigenerational home caregiver credit</header> <subsection id="H608B9C11E8F24728AA6E1D0DAA193AD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle for the taxable year an amount equal to $2,000 for each qualified relative with respect to the individual.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD1936D788CF34F339F33EC30C0FAF089"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED7ACF3005CF4260AFD6E59D11787000"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible individual</term> with respect to any taxable year means an individual—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53BDF62AA3B54D93BE8C75349253DC22"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has attained age 18, or has attained age 16 and is legally emancipated, as of the last day of such taxable year,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B05FCD6DF6B49ECAB1D815EA023A5DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is a United States citizen,</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B0C3FE0583A4DBC8F2645595B4ABC7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who has the same principal place of abode as a qualified relative for not less than 6 months during the taxable year,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H385C8C79DBD742DEA3300D872EE82A93"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who provides a total of not less than 10 hours per week of the assistance required by such qualified relative pursuant to paragraph (2)(A)(iii), and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAB47E7D7AEB490E91BEFF5312DCFF21"><enum>(E)</enum><text>who includes with the return of tax for the taxable year an attestation signed by a licensed health care provider that, to the best of the provider's knowledge, the qualified relative meets the requirements of clauses (iii) and (iv) of paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C082A8C7B7A4A4B88C4AC5D5B0B6BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified relative</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0F61C488A1949378AA4D3B4810DD462"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified relative</term> with respect to an individual means an individual—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2733B6BDB3E74C35A89E09011F74E76D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who bears a relationship described in subparagraph (B) to such individual or to such individual's spouse,</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3AB8F1CA9094BF8841EF35FE8962BA0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who has attained age 55 as of the last day of the taxable year,</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDF75BAADCD0467DB3B7A4A80E374B10"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>who is unable to perform (without substantial assistance from another individual) at least—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DCAADBD733E43B0B6A584878E04DCA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 activity of daily living (as defined in section 7702B(c)(2)(B)), and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33BA5DAB827148069647E63D72B207FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>3 instrumental activities of daily living,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">requiring a total of not less than 10 hours per week of assistance with such activities, and</continuation-text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06ACD1F95A7948A7B8AB95D2D0827D89"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with respect to whom the period during which clause (iii) applies has lasted or will last for not less than 180 days or the life of the individual, whichever is shorter.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE388FC9B85246479148D10050888E39"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relationship</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a relationship described in this subparagraph is a relationship described in subparagraph (C), (D), (F), or (G) of section 152(d)(2), except that only a father-in-law or mother-in-law shall be taken into account for purposes of subparagraph (G) thereof.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H740257FFA1B44F869BB50024E79F5F57"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Instrumental activities of daily living</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00BE083E43A84FF3996B128D424C4F22"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The term <term>instrumental activities of daily living</term> includes meal planning and preparation, managing finances, shopping for food, clothing, and other essential items, performing essential household chores, communicating by phone or other media, and traveling around and participating in the community.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83E19569908F4064A5D50390EA23A312"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In prescribing regulations or other guidance for purposes of clause (i), the Secretary shall to the extent practicable coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure consistency with programs under chapter 7 of the Social Security Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8AC983C653F43EAA071503EE9E221AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for qualified relatives dying during the taxable year</header><text>In the case of the death of an individual who would be a qualified relative with respect to the taxpayer but for subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) (determined without regard to this paragraph), such subparagraph shall be applied for the taxable year in which such individual died by substituting <quote>3 months</quote> for <quote>6 months</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84948962A71D4E7885CC19F7362AE078"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H363A0024AE9B4F50AECC935E2656CDCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation based on adjusted gross income</header><text>The $2,000 amount in subsection (a) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by 1 percent of the excess of the taxpayer’s adjusted gross income over $75,000 ($150,000 in the case of a joint return).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A6412F9206F49DCBB5C1845DDE76C94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Only 1 taxpayer may claim qualified relative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is the qualified relative by reason of whom the credit under this section is allowed, the credit under this section shall be allowed to only 1 taxpayer with respect to such individual for any taxable year. If (but for this paragraph) such individual is a qualified relative of more than 1 taxpayer for the taxable year, such individual shall be treated as the qualified relative of the taxpayer with the highest adjusted gross income.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E9C97B57DA94B5F873300F32411BC76"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on qualified relatives</header><text>Not more than 2 qualified relatives with respect to the taxpayer may be taken into account for purposes of the credit under this section for any taxable year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1DA6B9D13164335AFC734D2C31925FE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Married individuals must file joint return</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the taxpayer is a married individual (within the meaning of section 7703), this section shall apply only if the taxpayer and the taxpayer's spouse file a joint return for the taxable year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC52831E01EAF48C983F958041C65C0FC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination with child and dependent care credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) (after the application of paragraph (1)) with respect to any qualified relative shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount of any credit allowed under section 21 with respect to such qualified relative.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA09748E9737D4BAA94E95D81618FC9B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25E the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H84C45C9A11F5458CA0B1B77196AA805B">
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H65CB99FC70AA49389A6975F31108A4BD">Sec. 25F. Multigenerational home caregiver credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HE37BAD06371F474FB81780FB039118EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

