<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H14A1245479374B749E7933F8534020C1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7435 IH: DHS Intelligence Transparency and Oversight Program Office and Ombuds Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7435</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an Intelligence Transparency and Oversight Program Office and Intelligence Ombuds within the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC16941B1425498DA7D8556DB87676BD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD34920AE85194872816548544A92C6DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Intelligence Transparency and Oversight Program Office and Ombuds Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA887DD89C63C4B9FA88594A25BB32A01"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the transparency and oversight program office and intelligence ombuds</header> <subsection id="H481292B6F0374298A44D2B7BC9BECF6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H2C390164BD5E4B5D884868218EE578C4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA119996717134F1FB4F6C2E1F24CBFBA"><enum>714.</enum><header>Intelligence transparency and oversight program office; Ombuds</header> 
<subsection id="H56AAE79BF5224CFBBB1B4F18F0A518F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="H34E928360F8E42808899D18778184927"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish within the Department an Intelligence Transparency and Oversight Program Office (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>) to carry out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7C903B1C2D554A66A96C73224E8D49F2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Review and assess information concerning intelligence activities of the Department, including relating to the timeliness, objectivity, and independence from political considerations of such activities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H349700E813394A16A6522C10B734DEAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facilitate departmental decisions regarding making information publicly available in a manner that enhances public understanding of such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H416340443FF94B0FB1EBEF139E9242E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ombuds</header><text>The Office shall be headed by an Ombuds, who shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD2FBC38CF30648A7BC216955FE0AAC24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a senior, career employee;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E94C69AD1E843A69D1C62491B4D4B91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not hold any other position within the Department;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74028F2BE94644D4AFC057FFC245BE8A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have a background in—</text> <clause id="H82F6FA044C3B4B8E96A07F05A3F5E239"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intelligence;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4C7CB53CFCBB4D55BFA02B8DF9FC9BA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>civil rights enforcement; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDEAEEEC632E94F57AAB0E7D056F77BF6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addressing matters of intelligence timeliness, objectivity, and politicization;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA43C964840B34C8A8057CEFCF59B9AF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report directly to the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC187217E433F4B0EBACCFBF1A3CFA350"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report directly to Congress with respect to any urgent concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H113BF78B59B7495FA471AAFFAF20F009"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of the Ombuds</header><text>The Ombuds shall have the following duties:</text> <paragraph id="H55B4D7BD7E8644E3B7882C9AC032DB04" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Serve, in consultation with the Privacy Officer appointed under section 222 and the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, as the Department’s principal advisor regarding the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3735D2062469420F8320DDFC479EBCFA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Safeguarding objectivity in intelligence activities of the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H108D11726F8E436099136602104AD837" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ensuring such activities are independent from political considerations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H587AF5CBFE7B4479A526B893B284081A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Remain current and well-informed of issues affecting intelligence activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F92FB107B314430A1F0AF4CBF1B4F2C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Promote awareness among intelligence components of the Department of the requirement that all intelligence activities of the Department shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6C670CCA8EB4524B42A05D480844C9A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducted in a manner consistent with the protection of privacy rights, civil rights, and civil liberties; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC03F17208244D03998820F4571216F0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>objective and independent from political considerations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2616D80F281543ACAB1699C75B033300" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provide, without fear of retaliation, confidential forums to hear and help resolve individual and organizational concerns regarding intelligence activities of the Department, including relating to real or perceived occurrences of civil rights or civil liberties abuses, or politicization of analysis, biased reporting, or lack of objectivity in intelligence collection or analysis.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC91AB91DE1B44845B1894082A9523E9C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initiate reviews and make recommendations to the heads of the intelligence components of the Department, as appropriate, related to the matters described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF4DBDC5807A48BE8B6AC9657ABA814D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Facilitate departmental decisions regarding making information publicly available in a manner that enhances public understanding of the intelligence activities of the Department, while continuing to protect information when disclosure of such information would harm homeland security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23075C3D621449AB8BF68A9428E77334" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ensure that the functions performed by the Ombuds are complementary to existing functions within the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H599CB2C83DEC4CD3AEFE5592898B0188" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with intelligence components of the Department</header> 
<paragraph id="HFAA510192E2B4F75A8E7B5D207A9730D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The heads of the intelligence components of the Department shall each establish procedures to provide formal responses to recommendations submitted to such officials by the Ombuds pursuant to subsection (b)(5) within 60 days of receiving such recommendations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBF9B837F5084D81BC2C772FDF682CC3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access to information</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures to provide the Ombuds access to all departmental information necessary to execute the responsibilities of the Ombuds under this section. The Ombuds may submit to the Secretary a request for such information, and not later than 60 days after receiving such a request, the Secretary shall provide the Ombuds with such information.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H511E6B58AA5642B1B5D9F6C4C66A4E92" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Ombuds shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a report on its activities, findings, and recommendations of the Ombuds over the immediately preceding 12-month period.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H89EBCD390D2849E5A0AF0CEB429BA5EC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section the term <quote>intelligence activity</quote> means the collection, gathering, processing, analysis, production, or dissemination of information, including homeland security information, terrorism information, and weapons of mass destruction information.</text> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDD1CE0250FCE4155B8DA0638D0C002AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 713 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79309FB65CCB49A3BC6D7AA6C57A1157" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 714. Intelligence transparency and oversight program office; Ombuds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

