<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26183-H73-SR-MD6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 630 IS: Honoring the lives of fallen Missouri police officers and expressing condolences to their families.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 630</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260310">March 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the lives of fallen Missouri police officers and expressing condolences to their families.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas police officers, sheriffs, deputies, and all other law enforcement officers serve and protect their communities with honor and sacrifice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all law enforcement officers make a great sacrifice every day by putting their lives on the line to serve their fellow citizens;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas violent crime is abhorrent in all instances and especially affects law enforcement officers and the communities they serve;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the spouses and family members of our brave servicemen and women carry a great burden when their loved ones head into the line of duty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 23, 2026, the residents of Christian County, Missouri, experienced a violent and wicked attack against its law enforcement officers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4 police officers in southwest Missouri were shot in the line of duty, 2 of whom suffered injuries that were fatal; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these fallen officers include—</text><paragraph id="id5b8e003671aa4b26a10d4347b07d9d8f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Deputy Gabriel Ramirez of the Christian County Sheriff's Office, who passed away in the line of duty after attempting to administer a traffic stop; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id375d6cf15928439eaa889e2a9854390e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Deputy Michael Hislope of the Christian County Sheriff's Office, who passed away in the line of duty after bravely attempting to reach wounded officers under fire: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idfee4750fef934e749c4a5c93a71e865f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses deep condolences for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5e89bab1869435aa3af0237ff284917"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Missouri police officers who made the ultimate sacrifice in the line of duty; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11d009c17a274cd1a8426986f6dbe794"><enum>(B)</enum><text>their families;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id273c7d6bbd0b4f2697baa387ab94419a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the countless selfless and heroic actions carried out by Missouri law enforcement officers every day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66fc65ae9c444af1bd107fc2c26a1a67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses strong support for police officers and law enforcement officers across the United States that serve and protect their local communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7fb3ee7b9b1846b8b6293da75fbb9a68"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges the importance of honoring and remembering fallen police and local law enforcement officers killed in the line of duty;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4be13b2993834352a62c376bf8fc4dc9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns all violent acts taken against law enforcement officers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7c30e9488e14a6fbe8788a59029de53"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commits to supporting law enforcement officers in their work to fulfil their duty of making our communities safer.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

