<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25869-P7H-09-GLX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 434 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of October 5 through October 11, 2025, as “National 4–H Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 434</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251006">October 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of October 5 through October 11, 2025, as <quote>National 4–H Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas 4–H is the largest youth development organization in the United States, supporting nearly 6,000,000 young people across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4–H helps young people become confident, independent, resilient, and compassionate leaders;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 4–H is delivered by the Cooperative Extension System, a community of more than 110 land-grant colleges and universities across the United States that provides experiences for young people to learn through hands-on projects in the important areas of health, science, agriculture, and civic engagement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Institute of Food and Agriculture of the Department of Agriculture serves as the Federal partner of 4–H in collaboration with land-grant colleges and universities, the Cooperative Extension System, and National 4–H Council;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National 4–H Week showcases the incredible ways 4–H provides opportunities for all young people and highlights the remarkable members of 4–H in all 50 States and across the globe who work each day to make a positive impact on other individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 4–H network of nearly 500,000 volunteers and 3,500 professionals provides caring and supportive mentoring to all members of 4–H, helping members to grow into true leaders, entrepreneurs, and visionaries; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas members of 4–H will celebrate National 4–H Week during the week of October 5 through October 11, 2025: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idecbe635557664355ab3f123ccddad310"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of October 5 through October 11, 2025, as <quote>National 4–H Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e464e6db5c6430f823a9d0d3fa34124"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the important role of 4–H as the youth development program of the Cooperative Extension System and the Department of Agriculture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id598eb42e1bbf46b49bfe0d8f839da1a1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all citizens to recognize 4–H for the significant impact the organization and members have made and continue to make by empowering youth with the skills needed to lead for a lifetime; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6570a06563944208cbc10c36fc560d3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>celebrates the work of 4-H in developing engaged, healthy, and productive citizens who are <quote>Beyond Ready</quote> for work and life in a world of change.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

