<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HEF04145F54EF4C52A5DD7949BF723D55" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1100 IH: Directing the Committee on Ethics to preserve and publicly release records of the Committee’s review of violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment) and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1100</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> submitted the following
                resolution</action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc>By motion of the House, referred to the Committee on Ethics</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Directing the Committee on Ethics to preserve and publicly release records of the Committee’s review of violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment) and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas there is no place for sexual harassment or unwelcome sexual advances in the House of Representatives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas clause 9 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House provides <quote>Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House may not discharge and may not refuse to hire an individual, or otherwise discriminate against an individual with respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment, because of the race, color, religion, sex (including marital or parental status), sexual orientation, gender identity, disability, age, or national origin of such individual, including by committing an act of sexual harassment against such individual</quote>;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas clause 18(a) of Rule XXIII of the Rules of the House provides <quote>A Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner may not engage in a sexual relationship with any employee of the House who works under the supervision of the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner, or who is an employee of a committee on which the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner serves</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas clause 18(b) of Rule XXIII of the Rules of the House provides <quote>A Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House may not engage in unwelcome sexual advances or conduct towards another Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House</quote>; </text>
        </whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas sexual harassment and unwelcome sexual advances by Members, Delegates, or Resident Commissioners, in violation of clause 9 and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House, affect the safety, dignity, and the integrity of the proceedings of the House of Representatives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H602A0E1C99E248FCA7CDC08BDCD8110D"> <section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEF05145F54EF4C52A5DD7949BF723D55"><text>That the Committee on Ethics shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HEF06145F54EF4C52A5DD7949BF723D55">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>preserve all documents and investigative materials related to any violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment), clause 18, or any other clause (to the extent an act of sexual harassment, unwelcome sexual advance, or sexual assault constituted a violation or alleged violation of such clause) of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House by a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner; and</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEF07145F54EF4C52A5DD7949BF723D55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, make publicly available all final reports, or in such cases where there is not a final report, the most recent draft report, conclusions, recommendations, exhibits, and attached or accompanying materials, with the personally identifiable information of victims, alleged victims, and witnesses redacted, related to the Committee's investigations into violations or alleged violations of clause 9 (as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment), clause 18, or any other clause (to the extent an act of sexual harassment, unwelcome sexual advance, or sexual assault constituted a violation or alleged violation of such clause) of rule XXIII by a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

