<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDE6F9D4B928B44ABABC28C0DC6EF80A8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8301 IH: RSF Terrorist Designation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8301</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to conduct a comprehensive review of whether to designate the Rapid Support Forces of Sudan as a specially designated global terrorist organization.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6AEF83075F9249F99A470DF57060D74B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3C5065274F7C4D21B6A4A5BFB8D8EA0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>RSF Terrorist Designation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6C467CCF8A0246B09126DDA12EFE61BD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of the rapid support forces as a specially designated global terrorist organization</header> 
<subsection id="H259485B457964218806FEBBCBE4004AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and Secretary of Treasury shall jointly conduct a comprehensive review whether the Rapid Support Forces of Sudan meet the criteria for designation as a Specially Designated Global Terrorist Organization pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (66 Fed. Reg. 49079; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H16ED78C71D374F4E89A3836E98C15B24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of results and determination</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and Secretary of Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEE3F6D944A6A4E8EAD89FDEEF34220CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the comprehensive review set forth in subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24AD8CCB19524406A3539ECC1337F8A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the determination of the Secretaries whether to so designate the Rapid Support Forces of Sudan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6BA6C03273944AC58FE60C0E9D6509D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>Upon making an affirmative determination described in subsection (b)(2), the President, acting through the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Treasury, shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (d) with respect to the Rapid Support Forces of Sudan.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H57BE405C7ADF4B07A442E2BF1BDC3B16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD389DCD9011D4149A59339F0F8F9994B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President may exercise of all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1C00E43548D43D3AAEBB45495BD01D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens inadmissible for visas, admission, or parole</header> <subparagraph id="H349F2F11172B4719BCAB0C6F375CF984"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an alien described in subsection (c), the alien is—</text> 
<clause id="H274F649C0E9E43DCB84FD9017D16B8D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H461199A811414542BCB718ACD4A4F5B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H101E4D32ED1B4FD38E259E3A4546C9CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AFCFB23A8E848C3B3CBE548D86B304E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header> <clause id="HA75C210CEDFD49AB9A443450A8D84321"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) shall be revoked, regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE3575DDE1B8415C84EB1D17474129AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="HD6AAF01953434EE7BE6EF62AECA29B73"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF37F26BAA49949D29E30EC32062CE2C1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3927A5DE136946FC841A0E049636163D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> <paragraph id="H5F83B1EB3FEF4C8D83B7A937BCA8785E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text>Sanctions imposed pursuant to an affirmative determination described in subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32FAE8A90EAE44C2A2D6ECDE9CE6375C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions imposed pursuant to an affirmative determination described in subsection (b)(2) may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text> <subparagraph id="HBBB7CC24AF0B4E4B9D28C31445CBC792"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBF5AC0893DF4E1DA04FA1E0909C2DD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF89D7DA56743422FA356B2B84312E127"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8672F5C7CDB04B5B9F4C9574D94BD62D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D490E798D5E46EAA3E38AF8AD66258A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions imposed pursuant to an affirmative determination described in subsection (b)(2) shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H371649D9937440829976C4E4750413E8">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Classified information</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any judicial review of a determination made pursuant to an affirmative determination described in subsection (b)(2), if the determination was based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act) such information may be submitted to the reviewing court ex parte and in camera. This paragraph does not confer or imply any right to judicial review.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77F0E6889EF74A3296CE61D63F554A06"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may waive the imposition of sanctions pursuant to an affirmative determination described in subsection (b)(2) with respect to a person if the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="H76F6D580257D41308F47E23531A65F50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is important to the national security interests of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB80280C9895C4AE5BDD60998EE7FBDC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 15 days after issuing the waiver, submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of the waiver and the reasons for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEC9F452D055A4DF6A62192BF687A7E8C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on designation</header> <subsection id="HB88AE6D9DCA44898AC5D1564F1DFF2AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Concurrently with the submission of the report required by section 2(b), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Rapid Support Forces of Sudan that includes each of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5A1D9E7491EB4AFA8701638A7D4E45AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whether the Secretary of State will support the designation of the Rapid Support Forces as a specially designated global terrorist organization and a detailed explanation of why and how that decision was reached.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E57D232E96A4E8D82C1A033D8E5E53B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Detailed information on the countries and entities that provide material support to the Rapid Support Forces, including to the extent practicable what manner of support they provide and the approximate monetary value of that support.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7286A840D51D41CC94F02B19CDD22D2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the ability of the Rapid Support Forces to maintain its operations if external support to the organization were ceased.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF31F576B02804C60AA9816FC64C811E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A detailed explanation of implications for United States security and foreign assistance if the Rapid Support Forces were designated as a specially designated global terrorist organization.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H319112DB9C1943D19AB48F0A5DD93EBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a separate, classified annex.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H772F687ABBAE4026AF8F87B794E0C43A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="HE6EF1C77510D416CA634C460AA0A5E6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <quote>admitted</quote> and <quote>alien</quote> has the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD62698C1BF154E3E9BAAAA11746326E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF9FA395CFBB748B9BE3A6F0ACEA20A90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7DFD62EDFE545DBB424BBA414AEAE2A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="HEBCE888168A04CBFB47E67F4BE24B243"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a United States citizen;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9305D96E66C44669B053EB64699BC1F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a permanent resident alien of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA72E26DB5CD4DE2B82F1204EA574F2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D9D6C69F3AE4370BE6A9FB3F0F893A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a person in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

