<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8C28BD48A4B14FF997C235EE9ED3EE13" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1227 IH: Condemning State-level energy policies that restrict domestic oil production, increase gasoline prices, and undermine American energy security and national defense.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1227</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning State-level energy policies that restrict domestic oil production, increase gasoline prices, and undermine American energy security and national defense.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas affordable and reliable energy is essential to the economic well-being of American families, small businesses, and the broader United States economy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas residents of certain States, including California, consistently face gasoline prices significantly higher than the national average due in part to State-specific regulatory policies that restrict supply and increase costs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas such elevated fuel prices disproportionately burden working-class Americans, increase the cost of goods and services, and contribute to inflationary pressures across the economy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas policies that limit domestic oil production, refining capacity, and energy infrastructure development have constrained supply and increased reliance on imported energy sources;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas over-reliance on foreign oil undermines United States energy independence and exposes the Nation to geopolitical risks and supply disruptions;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the greenhouse gas intensity of United States oil production, particularly in the Gulf of America, is significantly lower compared to most other regions around the world;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States Department of Defense is the largest institutional consumer of fuel in the world and depends on stable, affordable energy supplies to maintain global operations and force readiness;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas elevated fuel costs increase operational expenses for military installations, diverting resources away from training, modernization, and readiness priorities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas high fuel prices also increase the cost of living for servicemembers, civilian defense personnel, and contractors, negatively affecting recruitment, retention, and morale;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas supply constraints and price volatility in fuel markets may hinder force mobilization, logistics, and sustained military operations during times of crisis; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the adoption of similar restrictive energy policies nationwide would likely increase gasoline prices across the United States, reduce domestic energy production, and weaken national security: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDF6B49EEB5F146EDBD3507CA1870D261"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HBAC4ED29669A4606BADD025544329356"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8BB0CE2DAF2A41BBBDE0BF37B56CABEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns State-level energy policies that intentionally or effectively restrict domestic oil production and refining capacity, resulting in higher gasoline prices for American consumers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D0CDEC20BB34A2AB1F14BDC7115553F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>finds that policies implemented in States such as California have contributed to significantly higher fuel costs, placing undue financial strain on families and businesses;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4623F7FD276842C7BE7A411B4C49D4D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes that affordable, reliable, and domestically produced energy is critical to United States economic stability, energy independence, and global competitiveness;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3ABE79C712144B6A721F4CCB95230A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms that access to abundant and affordable fuel supplies is essential to maintaining the operational readiness and strategic capabilities of the United States Armed Forces;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D6458E6185A45ACA755E4D54BEE30D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses concern that high fuel costs and over-reliance on foreign energy sources pose risks to United States national security and military preparedness;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71D8D6689B094EF3B172418ED1D1A553"><enum>(6)</enum><text>warns against the adoption of similar restrictive energy policies at the Federal level that would exacerbate fuel price increases and undermine domestic energy production; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F324D70D58F4AE4806A91545CB30639"><enum>(7)</enum><text>encourages policies that support responsible domestic energy development, strengthen supply chains, and ensure long-term energy affordability for American consumers and national defense.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

