<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F280FD002424FAE90A48156699FE09E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7439 IH: Uniform Standards for Federal Law Enforcement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7439</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that Federal law enforcement officers may only use deadly force when necessary to prevent imminent danger of death or serious bodily injury to the law enforcement officer or another person, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBEC904BCC0924315991BEC2831E2C686" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8DA51E3649EA46A18F65B6BB5DEB637A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Uniform Standards for Federal Law Enforcement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA55F5C7E74B54A0AB8A19800B753E5A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on the use of deadly force by Federal law enforcement officers</header> 
<subsection id="HB74469AA367C4B0DBAD5E5DC4F0F7975"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal law enforcement officer may only use deadly force when the officer has a reasonable belief that the use of such force is necessary to prevent imminent danger of death or serious bodily injury to the law enforcement officer or another person.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC7F41415462E41EF9CC87B7230567658"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarifications</header> <paragraph id="H5F29FC3D9FF041BD8633085B55C8A0B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The use of deadly force may not be considered necessary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAFA7217EA7004201AA52CC09EB3FFCE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solely to prevent the escape of a fleeing suspect;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E84FC0F829F4375889F91EA49FF032F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solely to disable a moving vehicle; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E52E2548C0B42FE88A32B094ADD4CE0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">against a person whose actions are a threat solely to themself or to property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FB5B1D2224843EC87320037FFAC9901" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discharge at a moving vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The discharge of a firearm by a Federal law enforcement officer at a moving vehicle may not be considered necessary unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3419A2998BC546ABBF0D3263DB136FD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person in the vehicle is threatening the officer or another person with deadly force by means other than the vehicle; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F3D777920B34291844077BB08906164"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the person operating the vehicle is doing so in a manner that threatens to cause death or serious physical injury to the officer or others, and no other objectively reasonable means of defense appear to exist, including moving out of the path of the vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E0DDD68D92C461286D41E3E8A70BBDD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Verbal warning</header><text>Prior to using deadly force, a Federal law enforcement officer shall give a verbal warning to the individual on whom the officer intends to use such force, to the extent practicable, and only if giving such warning would not increase the imminent danger of death or serious bodily injury to the law enforcement officer or another person.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H48F2B38C785F494D83C80431272C03D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on warning shots</header><text>Except in a Federal prison, a Federal law enforcement officer may not discharge a firearm as a warning.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H16F81770F04447DA9EDC1E24B510965F" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies that employ Federal law enforcement officers, shall develop and provide training to Federal law enforcement officers on methods and tactics to use in conducting law enforcement activities in situations, with respect to which, the use of deadly force is prohibited under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H191909605182429FBCDB3AE3A80AB65A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Federal law enforcement officer</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF8DC010DD8C94AE1B6979FE984002D35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Federal law enforcement officer, as such term is defined in section 115 of title 18, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED06868DF33A4FF9A548DC932692BF60"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>an immigration officer, as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text>
        </paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

