<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HB539676DEAA342D0A4DD46D109568F3A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 375 EH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as “Renewable Fuels Month” to recognize the important role that renewable fuels play in reducing carbon impacts, lowering fuel prices for consumers, supporting rural communities, and lessening reliance on foreign adversaries.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 375</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Expressing support for the designation of May 2025 as <quote>Renewable Fuels Month</quote> to recognize the important role that renewable fuels play in reducing carbon impacts, lowering fuel prices for consumers, supporting rural communities, and lessening reliance on foreign adversaries.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="OLC" id="H4842B11679E5456D9A588485265526A4">
<section id="H2DB15D11240E4F83AD9982CD58946AA0" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HFE38A02AF27643458CC0A1416D192D9C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishes the E–15 Rural Domestic Energy Council (<quote>Council</quote>), appointed by the Speaker of the House, to develop legislative solutions to address the crisis facing our nation’s farmers and refiners.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE1EBADE235C54B0281C83A7EE99FBF46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>directs the Council to investigate topics including, but not limited to, the sale of Ethanol-15, U.S. refinery capacity, the Renewable Fuel Standard Program, Renewable Identification Numbers, access to markets, and federal regulations that hinder American energy dominance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADF62AB1251E4F60AA9BA4B11B57D081"><enum>(3)</enum><text>directs the Council to meet regularly to develop legislative solutions and to submit those solutions to Congress no later than February 15, 2026, with the intent to consider legislation no later than February 25, 2026.</text></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


