<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA1FF350E34DD44418555A4CFBDE6EA2D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7743 IH: Stop ICE Intimidation Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7743</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260226">February 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a limitation on the obligation of funds for certain immigration enforcement purposes until a report on the use of databases by immigration officers is submitted.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC0098B79ACC3476E912635F3A96FEF4D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2E0E955BA8E14C17A8299CB5E8751011" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop ICE Intimidation Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H305ECF45C68845ECBA7BD0E026A4FDF5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on obligation of funds</header> <subsection id="H8AE83E1EC3E24DDBB261D11DB51E426F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and until the date a report is submitted under subsection (b) the Secretary of Homeland Security may not obligate any amounts made available in any Act for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3C911DBFDA5640618BB03791F0F948A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the operation of biometric or other surveillance system, including the Intelligence Records System of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4ACA6EFE745B4D6DA9725F866EC37301"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the entry into or continuation of any contract for the operation of any such system; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBB6108221C24E41B3E5D0BB2A6FCEBC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the hiring of additional officers, agents, or employees at the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HE729D2BB4B494F67BF2B2AFAD11F2C94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report under this section shall comply with the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE9D58C8BD4D34A98B1EF3939384C5E6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such report shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and of the Senate, the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC56360D561674874A1C9C4580201EA96"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such report shall set forth a policy of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement governing use of biometric or other surveillance systems, including the Intelligence Records System, in enforcement or removal operations under the immigration laws (as such term is defined under section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act) that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEA3A5833A8A64D56A753880143D749FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits that the use of such a system to access or store information pertaining to person that was collected because that person was exercising any right or privilege protected by the Constitution of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F57CF8C71E8443281F0E8B49D0C3EE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rules for—</text> 
<clause id="H8E0CDED4A2644604BF4C3EFB9B7E0C8D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of such information;</text></clause> <clause id="HA49207BF09BE488680C104C909077648"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identification of persons are permitted to access such information;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFF8FDF06573E4B139110947C03DFD7DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>storage of such information and what protections are in place to prevent unauthorized access to such information and the misuse of such information by any person who gains such unauthorized access;</text></clause> <clause id="H9588A96F3C2F4066AC4FC703A5EA4112"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how long such information will be retained and how it will be removed from the system thereafter;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA9342A8877FD42C1A5D61AADCCEEB011"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing notice to any person whose information is included in the system and an opportunity to review, contest, or remove such information if it is determined that such information was collected while such person was exercising any right or privilege protected by the Constitution of the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H2604C08FD0D14E70B56FFD51C2C77927"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how activities protected under the First Amendment will not be identified as <quote>credible threat activity</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2404D012458546EB8EDFBE30E4790F42">
              <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of what activities may be lawfully identified as <quote>having made a credible threat against ICE personnel or facilities</quote> (as such term is referred to in subclause 13 under the heading <quote>Categories of Individuals Covered by the System</quote> of the System of Records Notice published in the Federal Register on July 21, 2025 (90 Fed. Reg. 34282));</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H880C2781B72843AAAF6DC2300AEF532C"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detailed information on the costs of such databases and the contracts related to the use, creation, and maintenance of such databases;</text> </clause> <clause id="H7148DABF9D294BE799DEDF91EFE28B47" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>how officers and employees of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement are complying with local law providing for privacy protections; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H37B7EB6D25DD4B4EAA077265430F2BC0"><enum>(x)</enum><text>what training such officers and employees receive regarding compliance with the law in jurisdictions where facial recognition software is prohibited.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFDF567FADE8F44BDA7456783E560CC7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance</header> <text>All information collected by an immigration officer (as such term is defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act) for use or inclusion in or derived from a biometric or other surveillance system, including the Intelligence Records System of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, during the period beginning January 1, 2026, and ending on date of enactment of this Act, shall be deleted and removed from such system not later than the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act unless the Secretary, by rule (including as an interim final rulemaking), establishes the policy described in section 2(b)(2).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H97238FB4C8364C5CAF85BFC83D3B1B26"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security under any provision of law may be used to restrict the ability of an individual to record or document enforcement or removal operations under the immigration laws (as such term is defined under section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act) to the extent that such actions do not interfere or obstruct such operations.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

