<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25218-VTC-KY-8J0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 512 IS: Designating November 30, 2025, as “Drive Safer Sunday”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 512</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 30, 2025, as <quote>Drive Safer Sunday</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas motor vehicle travel is the primary means of transportation in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every individual traveling on roads and highways needs to drive in a safer manner in order to reduce deaths and injuries that result from motor vehicle crashes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, wearing a seat belt saves more than 15,000 lives each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate wants all people of the United States to understand the life-saving importance of wearing a seat belt and encourages motorists to drive safely, not just during the holiday season, but every time they get behind the wheel; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Sunday after Thanksgiving is one of the busiest highway traffic days of the year: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide85d2c6e4d3c4b3191c6961a7a1a639e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourages—</text><subparagraph id="idcb8d2e3a83d246b3a81d6cba171cfdf9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high schools, colleges, universities, administrators, teachers, primary schools, and secondary schools to launch campus-wide educational campaigns to urge students to be focused on safety when driving;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide18d83234cc842c292cefd51a6a79759"><enum>(B)</enum><text>national trucking firms to alert their drivers to be especially focused on driving safely on the Sunday after Thanksgiving and publicize the importance of the day through use of Citizens Band (commonly known as <quote>CB</quote>) radios and truck stops across the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89e47184c39b43fc8939a63e2c1d58dd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clergy to remind their members to travel safely when attending services and gatherings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6468e4810824aa88e3dec00eb46854e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>law enforcement personnel to remind drivers and passengers to drive safely, particularly on the Sunday after Thanksgiving; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32195861ba92468a8253f2974b53b2fc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>all people of the United States to use the Sunday after Thanksgiving as an opportunity to educate themselves about highway safety; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9101d8f1c3f64244aa8b8f2a359e2965"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designates November 30, 2025, as <quote>Drive Safer Sunday</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

