<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE1BEDA20116C404E89FAF32D1B3477E0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9006 IH: Locating Our Unclaimed Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9006</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a centralized portal within the Department of Veterans Affairs for the storage of information with respect to the unclaimed remains of veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC2F37B427DE94126A209F2C651C5283C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0BFFDA250F1F4CAA8D35320181B5538C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Locating Our Unclaimed Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC7DDAF1830F04E01869C9E8C7B7C1470"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs system for storage of information with respect to unclaimed remains of veterans</header> 
<subsection id="H3259A583D47144718EBC9D466475ACC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Process for storage and evaluation of unclaimed remains received by the Secretary</header> 
<paragraph id="H46968F213B4C4B2AB29828D8A2D8F644"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Under Secretary of Veterans Affairs for Benefits, shall establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs a centralized system to store information with respect to the unclaimed remains of veterans. Such system shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H8C0C3638F50F4FFAA656CB6A24A9576C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information with respect to unclaimed human remains suspected to be the remains of a veteran transmitted to the Department from—</text> 
<clause id="HCA74F81FDB9A4FCB86D8E9D318F546D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coroners;</text></clause> <clause id="HF9E6F57751C6467EACA4F86D5EADC5B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>State governments; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H097084EA25EB430EA4AB4E37401FEAE5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>funeral homes; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC9D73C6A6224253A1377DAB6D25018F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to unclaimed remains of a veteran in the possession of the Secretary—</text> 
<clause id="HAAC5228A031B48BD860B110242E135FC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the veteran, if available;</text></clause> <clause id="H6007880BB8B1496B92790374DD821F05" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fingerprints of the veteran, if available;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF75047E03F8249F3A7127A235FE0B634" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the estimated age of the veteran at death, if determinable; and</text></clause> <clause id="H84496BC0749B43B2B235B48B566C2417"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such identifiers as the Secretary determines necessary to make reasonable efforts to confirm veteran status of such unclaimed remains and identify suitable next-of-kin, to the extent practicable.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE63FEB02D517426FBFF270C61F2585D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header> 
<subparagraph id="H94BCCF440FC84588A4290F616F31717C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Existing memoranda</header><text>In developing the system required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, pursuant to applicable memoranda of understanding with respect to data sharing in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act, request such other information from the following Federal agencies as the Secretary determines relevant to efforts to identify unclaimed remains of veterans:</text> <clause id="H682959C1BB984A7E98B62A7807A8FA35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Social Security Administration.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HED4365C7688344D9856D7A3DB96210C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></clause> <clause id="H8D8F348D870548BEA77416B424091EB3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB89DF499D414B16BE69EF14E65B0C3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supplemental memoranda</header><text>The Secretary may seek to enter into such memoranda of understanding with the heads of Federal agencies, or seek to modify the memoranda of understanding described in subparagraph (A), as the Secretary determines necessary for identifying whether unclaimed remains in the possession of the Secretary are the remains of a veteran.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1E8CF5E59014F3CBF0F8043A92BAAC7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a request for information from the Federal Bureau of Investigation pursuant to a memorandum of understanding described in subparagraph (A) or (B), the Secretary shall consider information collected and maintained under the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF3B5D7A4B2A49B49A433C9E8D6F6F04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>This section shall expire on the last day of the third fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3246EE7236BB4771BD94BE63C4822F16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and on an annual basis thereafter for three years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the system required under subsection (a) that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5857B768428A466AB36084513566E516"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the implementation of such system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CC6DFC57F864322900D12F371B2F0CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of outreach activities carried out pursuant to such implementation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C96F512FA44467F906720E57317D80A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total number of unclaimed remains of veterans successfully identified using such system during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

