<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL26232-4C3-TC-514"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4476 IS: Workforce Transparency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4476</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for voluntary disclosure by developers and users of artificial intelligence regarding workforce data and for reporting by the Secretary of Labor regarding the workforce data, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Transparency Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9eef8dcf02cc4217a51ce36e353e3359"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header><subsection id="idda89ab56a977470e8ebacfccb094090c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idcb7279e274e4498bbed931129cf71cbf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence systems are already, as of the date of enactment of this Act, widely used by workers, employers, and consumers across sectors of the United States economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec11c9a4d643405ea8b3c38a2af4cd99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The most immediate labor-market effects of artificial intelligence are currently occurring at the task, skill, and workflow level, rather than through the wholesale elimination of occupations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b9c13db66c542d18864807e963c7e6b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research shows that artificial intelligence is also improving workforce productivity by accelerating routine cognitive tasks, enabling workers to focus on higher-value functions, and contributing positively to aggregate economic growth, even as adoption and impacts vary by sector and over time. Artificial intelligence also has the potential to create new roles, consistent with previous patterns in which technological change has led to significant changes in the types of jobs people do over time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32576f33f90640f4917b292a66f5ea00"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Policymakers, workers, educators, and employers lack timely and standardized information about how artificial intelligence systems are being used and how such use affects productivity, skills, and workforce outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idacbb57b88a414200b4675d0d0e9868f3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Aggregated, privacy-preserving transparency, including information voluntarily shared by a covered AI system provider and complementary data published by the Federal Government, can meaningfully improve workforce development, education policy, and economic planning without revealing proprietary information, trade secrets, individual-level data, or other information that would undermine individual privacy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id07233744324345e08bd2cbe8eb78b296"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A Federal transparency framework that encourages participation and supports modernization of government data systems can establish a consistent national baseline, reduce fragmentation across States, and provide a level playing field among covered AI system providers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id219d580d26554284abfbd37ed19f830f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text><paragraph id="id98fca327b6594e98b5a1291f5bb92b28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a Federal framework for aggregated, de-identified transparency or data-sharing regarding use of artificial intelligence systems relevant to workforce impacts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0096b9dd0414da7af607a63625693f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support evidence-based workforce, education, and economic policymaking through both voluntary participation by a covered AI system provider and improved Federal labor-market data;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b80476c473648ecb8231fa7c79133f3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protect individual privacy, confidential business information, and competition; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa1459006a2f4f8c98bd26de59f5c5a5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote public trust through consistent, responsible, and privacy-preserving data-sharing.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id7c50f2354fa840eca67e0fb7c73db4e0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7979fede7ccc461d877de4f32f7bd5af"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aggregated workforce transparency data</header><text>The term <term>aggregated workforce transparency data</term> means statistical information that—</text><subparagraph id="id1f782109c3654ffeadfbb147df0dadf0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is aggregated across users, accounts, interactions, or customers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id259fed25fccd48ada061c76ec1de682c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not identify or reasonably permit the identification of a particular person, household, or employer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8bc7191be1d4087969b19b5835df978"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not disclose—</text><clause id="id28d6fc7795ea4ff2ad2d966dcbaaf4b9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>proprietary model weights, training data, source code, or system architecture; or</text></clause><clause id="id95f306ff846b4c96948d05d7183385c2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information that a covered AI system provider has contractually defined as confidential or not subject to disclosure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc978223eaf3446bea6ae62d6664c58ba"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ea9779f60d14c219cc3742334adfc4c"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered AI system</header><text>The term <term>covered AI system</term> means an artificial intelligence system made available to consumers or businesses other than such a system that is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e4abbd339e44fd29e49159f62ca6797"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designed and marketed by a person primarily for internal business use by the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddabe13df77834195a332e1df3101c04b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used solely for academic or non-commercial research; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb7c012c5d0b47c9989e3760f3d9aff2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designed for a narrow, discrete technical function without general-purpose capabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7703b5a37bfa4e77bf25df3a695c6ad9"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered AI system provider</header><text>The term <term>covered AI system provider</term> means a person that develops, deploys, or makes available a covered AI system.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa8afba427d14836bcb763b0ebbd5e95"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enterprise customer</header><text>The term <term>enterprise customer</term> means a business, governmental, or institutional customer that accesses a covered AI system pursuant to a negotiated contract governing data use, confidentiality, or disclosure.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b381bfce656402ebf29500838507e0a"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participating entity</header><text>The term <term>participating entity</term> means a covered AI system provider or enterprise customer that elects to submit data in accordance with section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9863d11e00004ae5b681a0d50024bceb"><enum>(7)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf47e2b85c99847caa0a474e48f36dfa6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Workforce transparency reporting</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66cb32c3ed5f49cf86c5b35768df44c4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A participating entity may submit to the Secretary, in accordance with this Act and any regulations promulgated by the Secretary under this Act, aggregated workforce transparency data, including (as reasonably feasible) such data regarding the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2d1571e33ed490b8377ccfbece502b7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Task or activity level use</header><text>Aggregated distribution of interactions across broad task or activity categories, such as writing, coding, research, analysis, translation, or job-related assistance (as established and periodically updated by the Secretary through notice and comment rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b3be23c31704d5bb72482b91ab13baf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>Aggregated distribution of interactions across broad task or activity categories, by State or by metropolitan statistical area or comparable geographic unit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3cfca51a6a3b45e1866c0024f1ead6c5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Age ranges</header><text>Aggregated distribution of interactions across broad task or activity categories, by adult age ranges, as reasonably feasible and consistent with privacy safeguards or laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc301f5a0ae244d3b166e6a3e26fa1fb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Temporal trends</header><text>Changes in usage patterns over time based on task or activity category.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc8df1ebbbbd14b5687b569f909c8436a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting windows</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a system for submissions under subsection (a) that allows for such submissions by a participating entity only for aggregated workforce transparency data concerning information that is not more recent than 91 days before the date of the submission, including, for purposes of the first submission by the participating entity, such data with respect to the 2-year period preceding the date on which the participating entity first elects to make such a submission.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86439c3da0d440c8bf4431ef8e54e767"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This Act shall not be construed to require a covered AI system provider or enterprise customer to elect to submit or otherwise be required to submit aggregated workforce transparency data under this section.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id119ded5c1bd24a14961e6b79174ff33e"><enum>5.</enum><header>Privacy, security, and confidentiality safeguards</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d4783a816ac4e7da5b64bfdc82eab07"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibited disclosures</header><text>A participating entity may not submit under section 4(a)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d00ae0243d549e3b6528aa4a8795987"><enum>(1)</enum><text>personal data or information linked or reasonably linkable to an individual;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacfd6fa7bbc7425e97cf2d9cd71ad91b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employer-specific, customer-specific, or individual-specific performance data;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e36ea34c04141a993e77b2ebe89de9d"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trade secrets, proprietary algorithms, model weights, training datasets, or source code;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a2ab0fbc3584f0ab7dad98e58104e21"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information that a participating entity is contractually prohibited from disclosing pursuant to agreements or terms with consumers, users, or enterprise, governmental, or institutional customers or that the participating entity otherwise commits to protecting from disclosure in policies or representations, including restrictions or commitments on data use, aggregation, or secondary disclosure; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc9a53c857844ca48f2942a307713905"><enum>(5)</enum><text>data in violation of a contract or other terms with an enterprise customer, consumer, or user, including contractual restrictions on data use, aggregation, disclosure, or secondary analysis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc982669f705d4615a0e4a36a7560105b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance with applicable laws</header><text>In making submissions under section 4(a), a participating entity shall exclude or further aggregate data as necessary to comply with other applicable laws.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcaa470846fc74c179b34ebd4340c8604"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance with contract terms</header><text>This Act shall not be construed to obviate the terms, including privacy or data protections, in any contract between a participating entity and its customers, users, or other consumers.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99c0ee44bfaf4aac8e1a570995306ad1"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Safeguards</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing data for purposes of making submissions under section 4(a) and making such submissions, a participating entity shall apply aggregation, anonymization, and de-identification techniques consistent with guidance issued under section 6(c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a98c92fca8d4ec897840c846775a6b3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Freedom of information act</header><text>Any aggregated workforce transparency data submitted under section 4(a) shall be exempt from the disclosure requirements under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id5860c6f14d5042a1861dcc75048dd95c"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting and regulations</header><subsection id="idfe09219584c24b79a8ccdeaf795d744a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Lead agency</header><text>The Secretary of Labor, acting through the Commissioner of Labor Statistics and in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce acting through the Director of the Bureau of the Census, shall administer this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb3a826ac8e742fd9e461592a6e935c0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data reporting</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59d131a2bc0642a5b2c5fca50cfb6b98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and maintain a publicly available, online database containing aggregated workforce transparency data derived from submissions under section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6aeb317f72d04486b75f0d8dc5a5d27d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall annually submit a report to Congress summarizing aggregated workforce transparency data derived from submissions under such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0b76f400393496faf763d5f09e56ccf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for data</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall aggregate data from submissions by participating entities under section 4(a) and ensure that any published dataset, analysis, or report does not attribute any submitted data to any specific participating entity or any identifiable person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb73f00fa231c47358d25c48c10ce8307"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue non-binding guidance regarding—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2033eec677b64df19497b3aac8dce308"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">standardized reporting formats and taxonomies for purposes of submissions under section 4(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ff42303d5eb46999a0cba90bee758f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acceptable aggregation, anonymization, and privacy-preserving methods for purposes of submissions under such section;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc7c95ffbb614c6c9cc62b9a1f30d7de"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures to minimize reporting burden for purposes of such submissions, including alignment with existing Federal data-collection efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf14dadac311496b9986052d0b0734e0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">definitions and classifications for broad task or activity categories used in workforce-related artificial intelligence usage reporting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id363878bf9f814109b7c4b80b9c116d72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b1c5b8858744721b065fab30d6484a6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue regulations necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cace6a429954f5c876a2f8202d1e834"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall clarify the extent to which a participating entity shall aggregate, anonymize, or otherwise ensure privacy safeguards for aggregated workforce transparency data submitted under section 4(a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id951e5cfa2d0141b09ae3fb43d5374a3b"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Working group</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Labor Statistics and in coordination with other relevant agencies, shall establish a working group to develop a process to publish or enhance public labor-market data that combines age and occupational information, in order to improve understanding of how artificial intelligence affects entry-level workers and early-career professionals.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5825aa1e3413468b89971d8175e12bc9"><enum>7.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition regarding adverse inferences</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A Federal agency may not draw an adverse inference against any covered AI system provider or enterprise customer that elects not to make submissions under section 4(a).</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id1188642f541541b585d68d3ce8236db6"><enum>8.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may seek injunctive relief in any court of competent jurisdiction against a participating entity with respect to aggregated workforce transparency data submitted under section 4(a) that the Secretary determines is a knowing and willful misrepresentation by the entity of the data.</text></section><section id="id1cf59c2c57794c0282d2ba195ba22320" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>9.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provision to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

