<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5E35E0A7A72B407A8348A936F09CCF7D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6376 IH: Supporting Military Families Exposed to Toxic Substances Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6376</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide health care for family members and other individuals who resided at or worked at locations where there is a presumption of service-connection for certain illnesses and conditions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFD204A86DFF24C1F9EB5FFD0952544C9" style="OLC"><section id="HAE3BC9982C1A456BB00A094D1D39B521" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Military Families Exposed to Toxic Substances Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0590397711AB42CAA57255DE622BF1BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs provision of health care for family members and other individuals who resided at or worked at locations where there is a presumption of service-connection for certain illnesses and conditions</header><subsection id="H85C036C0541D4BDBBD37D59C0A4143F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H160CC3F9AE224F2A95BD474049B07CD3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE483C190AA1D468A9D6DB9D90AB9D0D3"><enum>1790.</enum><header>Health care for family members and other individuals who resided at or worked at locations where there is a presumption of service-connection for certain illnesses and conditions</header><subsection id="H34259A3679CB40FAADF5945BF2961A20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92DED573A9104E389E3B3B4CD91E4F19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An individual described in subsection (b) shall be eligible for hospital care and medical services furnished by the Secretary for a covered illness or condition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17040D0F79FB4C08AD749788E69D5ACA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual described in this subsection is an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H0EABB0BAD5F9446D9161F52342ADA5D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resided at, worked at, or was in utero while their mother resided at or worked at a location for which the Secretary has established a presumption of service-connection for any illness or condition under or pursuant to chapter 11 of this title for the time period required for such presumption; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H505A5AB25442491EB95B59B073329B27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can demonstrate that the individual was exposed to the same condition or conditions that qualify veterans for such presumption, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB4D8C5C6CC24005A288B17D6CA45228"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H08E1E8EECE4A4D01A2FB7F34B2FA37BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may only furnish hospital care and medical services under subsection (a) to the extent and in the amount provided in advance in appropriations Acts for such purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB70DC75CF1AF41C7B7D94117965B6789" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hospital care and medical services may not be furnished under subsection (a) for an illness or condition of an individual that is found, in accordance with guidelines issued by the Under Secretary for Health, to have resulted from a cause other than time spent at a location referred to in subsection (a)(2)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C32D28938CE4B509F1A108CA11B9F75" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary may furnish hospital care or medical services provided to an individual described in subsection (a)(2) only after the individual or the provider of such care or services has exhausted without success all claims and remedies reasonably available to the individual or provider against a third party (as defined in section 1725(f) of this title) for payment of such care or services, including with respect to health-plan contracts (as defined in such section).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B032CBBA58B4D1182F7F5DE593103E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered illness or condition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered illness or condition</quote> means, with respect to an individual who resided at, worked at, or was in utero while their mother resided at or worked at a location, an illness or condition for which the Secretary has established a presumption of service-connection under or pursuant to chapter 11 of this title based on service in the Armed Forces at that location, notwithstanding that there is insufficient medical evidence to conclude that the illness or condition is attributable to such residence or work.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0AF8D1DC67354F0D954C78CB745B1387"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1789 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H184DCE727B4943079B83BED26E825D37" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1790. Health care for family members and other individuals who resided at or worked at locations where there is a presumption of service-connection for certain illnesses and conditions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1D06A00E5FB648679DCE9D41BB54E2F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of each of 2027, 2028, and 2029, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the hospital care and medical services provided under section 1790 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a). Each such report shall include each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H3E4677B29C354C1AB052039F2EB200A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of individuals who were furnished hospital care or medical services under such section during the period beginning on January 1, 2026, and ending on the date of such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H874B7B84D3794722973BF9323AE1EEC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The illnesses and conditions for which such care or services were provided and the location associated with the presumption of service-connection for each such illness or condition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17671067836B47849DD7565336087F8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of individuals who applied for care or services under such section during that period but who were denied, including information on the reasons for such denials.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A2ED840737B48A78F7CC9A299D8E778"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of individuals who applied for care or services under such section and are awaiting a decision from the Secretary on eligibility for such care or services. as of the date of such report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

