<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ26335-KP4-X7-T6X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4619 IS: Protect Domestic Oil and Gas Small Business Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4619</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Clean Air Act to exclude marginal wells from certain standards of performance and other requirements under that Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Domestic Oil and Gas Small Business Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ide2657bc4715441918e8f9b04aa104bb4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusion of marginal wells from standards of performance and other clean air act requirements</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1be8e318c75492e8afbc7d4b16a8cda"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idDD9DDD4AE12E48A8A9D7BA732687DE7D" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="id1D9A1EBE0FD6440EAAA4F1381579603C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Exemption for marginal wells</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id155f36dbac0441dbbf00b6621698d1b7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide49760845a9a47209dc9288363008a40"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Associated equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>associated equipment</term>, with respect to an oil or natural gas well site, includes any multiphase separator, treater, knockout, gun barrel, test vessel, pump, storage vessel, compressor, process controller, dehydrator, gas shack, meter, heater, methanol pump, natural gas liquid loadout or storage vessel, gathering line, flowline, dump line, transmission line, water tank, oil tank, gunbarrel, or storage tank, or any other equipment used in association with that well site.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb749eebae5f42d5963c17e83aed5535"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Marginal well</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>marginal well</term> means an oil or natural gas well site the average daily production of which, over the preceding calendar year, is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31476f1d8d354020aed6da95de1dac4f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an oil well site—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d45f08185f64d1da1ca1878090ce1e6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">15 barrels of oil per day per well or less; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb667aa4e1cd24c3ab67da3ba2be6b72a"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">15 barrels of oil equivalent per day per well or less, using a conversion factor of 6,000 cubic feet per barrel of oil equivalent; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fc1fc9c5fd44150beb2d01aaed940b4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a natural gas well site, 90,000 cubic feet of natural gas per day per well or less.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfedef5d251474d32bc0262b418174f3e"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Well site</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>well site</term> includes any well located at a given site, and associated equipment, but does not extend beyond the point of custody transfer of natural gas or oil produced from such a well.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida26a2fc0acf04bfcbde0eecbd1d789f3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No standard of performance or guideline prescribed by the Administrator under subsection (b) or (d)(2), including in any regulation issued by the Administrator under either subsection, and no requirement for monitoring, reporting, recordkeeping, conducting a fugitive emission survey, detecting or repairing leaks, estimating or measuring emissions, or any other related requirement prescribed in regulations issued by the Administrator under this section shall apply with respect to any marginal well or, as applicable, the owner or operator of a marginal well.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb46a24ac9aaf43719a415d0b2c2be4ba"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No requirement in State plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may not require any plan submitted by a State to the Administrator under subsection (d)(1) to include a standard of performance applicable to marginal wells or, as applicable, owners or operators of marginal wells.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29f083178f50486dac080251cec10341"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expedited consideration</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25525c4243384924a64ed1ee71d5e270"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>If a State makes a revision to a plan submitted to the Administrator under subsection (d)(1) to make a standard of performance inapplicable to marginal wells or, as applicable, owners or operators of marginal wells, the Administrator shall, not later than 180 days after the date on which the revision is submitted, approve, disapprove, approve in part, or disapprove in part that revision without further review.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4fc8e9c8c7d14e79a30fd2be3f86e03c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deemed approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator fails to act on a revision described in subparagraph (A) by the end of the 180-day period described in that subparagraph, the revision shall be considered approved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1195520875f14061845250ef7f7e1f4d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d96632f43a749329a483dde3534d2cf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conforming revisions</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall revise such regulations and guidance as may be necessary to implement subsection (k) of section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) (as added by subsection (a)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79a680cf1269412d84a00fdd6204b076"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pending enforcement actions</header><text>Any action to enforce a standard of performance or requirement described in subsection (k)(2) of section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>) (as added by subsection (a)) with respect to marginal wells that is pending on the date of enactment of this Act shall be terminated.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

