<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2CABD12A3ABC4583BE61958C6A07D70F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1031 IH: Condemning the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran for its violent repression of peaceful protesters, its documented pattern of human rights abuses, and its sponsorship of extremist militant groups across the Middle East.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1031</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260202">February 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran for its violent repression of peaceful protesters, its documented pattern of human rights abuses, and its sponsorship of extremist militant groups across the Middle East.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since late December 2025, widespread peaceful protests have taken place across Iran, driven by public frustration with economic hardship, political repression, gender discrimination, and the denial of basic civil liberties;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas credible human rights organizations and activist monitoring groups report that the Iranian regime has responded to peaceful demonstrations with excessive force, including live fire, arbitrary detention, intimidation, censorship, and broad restrictions on communications and independent reporting;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas current civil protests have resulted in at least 3,000, and as many as tens of thousands of, fatalities, including children and noncombatant civilians, and an extraordinary number of detentions, even as verification remains impeded by internet blackouts;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, over the past decade, Iranian authorities have repeatedly employed state security forces, notably the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (hereafter in this preamble referred to as the <quote>IRGC</quote>) and Basij militia, to violently suppress dissent, including during major protest movements, resulting in significant casualties, detentions, and systematic rights abuses;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Government of Iran has been designated a state sponsor of terror and has used its foreign intelligence and military apparatuses, especially the IRGC’s Qods Force, to provide funding, weapons, training, and material support to militant groups in the Middle East to pursue its foreign policy objectives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Iran has continued to provide substantial support to extremist groups designated as terrorist organizations by the United States and other allies, including Hezbollah, Hamas, and the Houthis, which have utilized Iranian funding, material, logistical, and intelligence support to directly target the United States, its allies, and global shipping lanes;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Iran’s provision of financial support, often tens or hundreds of millions of dollars annually, as well as weapons and operational training, to these groups has been documented in multiple United States Government reports and is central to Tehran’s regional proxy network;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas freedom of expression, peaceful assembly, and due process are universal human rights recognized under international law, including the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives reaffirms its commitment to human rights, democratic principles, and international peace and security: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H565AB240088F4EB2948F9E34DFF18F6B"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCDCEB3E4D6574081AEA6D1F3D357345D"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H593F0AE8448A475DAD195E36E35D3AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran for its violent repression of peaceful protesters, including the reported deaths of thousands of Iranian citizens as of February 1, 2026, as well as its longstanding pattern of serious human rights violations and suppression of civil liberties;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF96C8D7903A944748C7A6A808ABFD621"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns the Iranian regime’s sponsorship of extremist armed groups through the provision of weapons, funding, training, and strategic support, and the threat these programs pose to regional security and United States interests;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C19FEAB27534BE885DC41CB1EC147BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demands Iranian authorities to immediately end the use of lethal force and abusive tactics against peaceful demonstrators, restore internet and communications access across Iran, cease arbitrary detentions, release those held for exercising fundamental rights, and ensure transparency, accountability, and respect for human rights;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A0D46D8ADE64BEFBB80E628C095DDFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the President, the Secretary of State, and relevant United States agencies to continue coordinating with allies and international partners to promote accountability for human rights abuses and terrorist sponsorship, including through targeted sanctions, diplomatic measures, and multilateral actions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CE69817AC7F415D9B0E6E696596A752"><enum>(5)</enum><text>affirms the solidarity of the United States with the Iranian people in their pursuit of dignity, justice, freedom, and the rule of law, and with all international efforts to uphold human rights and reduce regional violence.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

