<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1AA00E8488F546189941B413AF6E958C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7662 IH: Railroad Safety Enhancement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance safety requirements for trains transporting hazardous materials, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H61BCC6A0A65B429AB111108DE7A704F0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFE9CB48AEC1340F99101C6AC5D64C4E7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H91E55B9FD279415CBF0ACCFD93A067E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Railroad Safety Enhancement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5BD0F7B6E48F482DA9D789E459ABE43C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="HFE9CB48AEC1340F99101C6AC5D64C4E7" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H525288CD614A4BB38AF8C878872D350E" level="title">Title I—Rail Safety</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H66F75DCBB04A43ECBEBFC28676467328" level="section">Sec. 101. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H97E9D60C514A4572904C6BEB89C2E1E4" level="section">Sec. 102. Safety requirements for high-hazard trains.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9ECC059FC23044D3AF7FDA54B84D5F1D" level="section">Sec. 103. Ensuring the safety of long trains.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0722143DCCF5423A82409FE5BA39709E" level="section">Sec. 104. Blocked highway-rail grade crossings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD0F1FA06DEC049FF8A15550880E52674" level="section">Sec. 105. Inspections.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H484EDAECE5884E348D05EA231ADCD4FC" level="section">Sec. 106. Emergency brake signals.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4FA1B1FED1BD4C7ABC55CBB743F1B571" level="section">Sec. 107. Defect detection systems.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA511321A64834B4FB59B6F18003E51B5" level="section">Sec. 108. Safe Freight Act of
            2023.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H346D708409154A10A765F7CAE8595020" level="section">Sec. 109. Increased penalties for violations of rail safety regulations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H046BA2124D8B4762A120879537BC3692" level="section">Sec. 110. Safer tank cars.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H1729C54297B54C34A7D6F08840F04DB2" level="section">Sec. 111. Rail safety infrastructure research and development grants.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H897AA9D9005A4A7DB445F55EF48DD2B3" level="section">Sec. 112. Authorization of appropriations for tank car research and development.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4C13CDF6519443AC8A64FDE50F3211D5" level="section">Sec. 113. Federal Railroad
            Administration safety culture.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB5E5B31C82374CF8AFE0D866E7A86886" level="section">Sec. 114. GAO report on roadway
            worker protections.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3E66871430D04E6196F5831391F9B0EA" level="section">Sec. 115. Federal Railroad
            Administration safety workforce management.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3380965D97B042D0A290B5E258339365" level="section">Sec. 116. Office of Personnel
            Management review of safety inspector and specialist classifications.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H47AC48327E2C4EDC90D4743C9A9CCFC7" level="section">Sec. 117. Alcohol and drug testing.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC158CAC49D1A4C768BEBA8CC895E80D1" level="section">Sec. 118. Confidential close call reporting system.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6635AF7749714D96814A27605BBA4DE1" level="section">Sec. 119. AskRail
            application.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE3FE97FF7EB24B389EE1566112CA6774" level="section">Sec. 120. Increased funding for the railroad crossing elimination grant program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H01428949AEED45F8BF97A7B1BECDDA90" level="section">Sec. 121. Train approach warning.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB1D424B7D26F4FC0A1E176D6FA8B0ABF" level="title">Title II—HAZARDOUS MATERIALS EMERGENCY RESPONSE AND PREPAREDNESS</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB3032B8D051C4F4BBB01A1A81BC09B72" level="section">Sec. 201. Hazardous materials registration fees.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5A4A2008EBE745D0B471680BA82035F4" level="section">Sec. 202. Virtual training options.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF97FB613524A4448A956D465B7291A79" level="section">Sec. 203. Hazardous materials transportation emergency response and preparedness grants.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H70776C5EF9CC4C23A839CFC4FD9A6A13" level="section">Sec. 204. Emergency response assistance.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<title id="H525288CD614A4BB38AF8C878872D350E"><enum>I</enum><header>Rail Safety</header>
<section id="H66F75DCBB04A43ECBEBFC28676467328"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="HD95353C22F2044468583B15BE70D06F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, terms used in this title have the definitions given such terms in section 20155 of title 49, United States Code, as amended by section 102(a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6753087C8F624813BE429615FC890313"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H97E9D60C514A4572904C6BEB89C2E1E4"><enum>102.</enum><header>Safety requirements for high-hazard trains</header> <subsection id="HAB7AE7B5ED0E4D2FB9DB2DAADD84648C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tank car safety requirements</header><text>Section 20155 of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="HC1F8DC51F7884E23BF8F4F94922D7BEE" style="USC">
<section id="HF583351279AB4910AA0C1F9A71196243"><enum>20155.</enum><header>High-hazard trains</header>
<subsection id="H2AB2208CAE894245BA2B2909B99C27EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H84FA2709255D4DE99958D3AEFFB5AEB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Explosives</header><text>The term <quote>explosives</quote> means Class 1 explosives categorized in Division 1.1, 1.2, or 1.3 (as such terms are defined in section 173.50 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89A9616A32654955977EBD386D6F8827"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flammable gas</header><text>The term <quote>flammable gas</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 173.115(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAAE2A32F1464B208758DA960730BA02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Flammable liquid</header><text>The term <quote>flammable liquid</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 173.120(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8A9A3AD29D1F4ADBBB3A1279329ACB73"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Hazardous material</header><text>The term <quote>hazardous material</quote> means a substance or material designated by the Secretary of Transportation as hazardous pursuant to section 5103 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DB2387614AB4E0EA5F124B67A4B5A62"><enum>(5)</enum><header>High-hazard train</header><text>The term <quote>high-hazard train</quote> means a single train transporting, throughout the train consist—</text>
<subparagraph id="H292DEB2B988C4D75AD72E5AE764EC29E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>20 or more tank cars loaded with a flammable liquid;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CFB58C8D27842DEBF51594706FC7989"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 tank car or intermodal portable tank load with a material toxic or poisonous by inhalation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H43AA64E3F0204C558B64EEDE1A917335"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 or more cars loaded with high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64C984D175F647E3B9CB8C4B593D1211"><enum>(D)</enum><text>10 or more cars loaded with explosives;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0C57CD85D4CE45EDA7109D5BFB4E919F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>5 or more tank cars loaded with a flammable gas; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C23E9CDBE8343F8BA3521978273D985"><enum>(F)</enum><text>20 or more cars loaded with any combination of flammable liquids, flammable gases, or explosives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE15A1F5CE56341C892C37F60149050C3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>High-level radioactive waste; spent nuclear fuel</header><text>The terms <quote>high-level radioactive waste</quote> and <quote>spent nuclear fuel</quote> have the meanings given to a <quote>type B package</quote> or a <quote>fissile material package</quote>, respectively, in section 173.403 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBA374246BC745148B30D878EDAC327C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Material toxic or poisonous by inhalation</header><text>The term <quote>material toxic or poisonous by inhalation</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>Material poisonous by inhalation or Material toxic by inhalation</quote> in section 171.8 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8660E086335B478181D558E7D6F83D54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Railroad Safety Enhancement Act of 2026, the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, shall issue regulations that—</text> <paragraph id="HE0AA0FF1A646434A8F29430E537F8A0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>rescind the requirements set forth in paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 174.310(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, with respect to tank cars carrying hazardous materials other than Class 3 flammable liquids;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H32F1EF92966C400AB069B5B805ECEE32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revise the requirements set forth in section 174.310(a)(2) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="HD943CFB5D5844FBEB5C25FCC21BA61DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to limit all trains to a maximum speed of 50 miles per hour; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFEBB080F00344A379B3FB2B560D5E161">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>to limit high-hazard trains carrying 20 or more cars loaded with flammable liquids to a maximum speed of 40 miles per hour while that train travels within the limits of high-threat urban areas (HTUAs) (as defined in 1508.3 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations), unless all tank cars containing a Class 3 flammable liquid meet or exceed the DOT specification 117 standards, the DOT specification 117P performance standards, or the DOT specification 117R retrofit standards set forth in subpart D of part 179 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, including DOT–105A, DOT–105H, DOT–105J, DOT–105S, DOT–112H, DOT–112J, DOT–112S, and DOT–120S tank cars;</text>
                  </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HACCCAA32058D4D2FA143C11E49E8C71E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require rail carriers operating high-hazard trains to comply with the requirements applicable to high-hazard flammable trains under section 174.310 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5ED899E59744A11935EECA1DFD77486"><enum>(4)</enum><text>require any Class I railroad transporting hazardous materials—</text>
<subparagraph id="H15EF2D6745A04F7F823A9BA828F1BD36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to generate accurate, real-time, and electronic train consist information, including—</text> <clause id="H6F4A0016C1D94E70966466219CAAD303"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the identity, quantity, and location of hazardous materials on a train;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA719D30AE9F54789A6BE8B07198FEEC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the point of origin and destination of the train;</text></clause> <clause id="HF505014AF5B1459989CA5A63FE3FE0F1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any emergency response information or resources required by the Secretary; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H80EEA23C02E34F14ACE20A31D4D842E5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an emergency response point of contact designated by the Class I railroad; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A3E138671A945039313F9CDA3F3B443"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enter into a memorandum of understanding with each applicable fusion center to provide the fusion center with secure and confidential access to the electronic train consist information described in subparagraph (A) for each train transporting hazardous materials in the jurisdiction of the fusion center;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C3BF4C3B7DB4E1281B16841D1566648"><enum>(5)</enum><text>require each Class I railroad to provide commodity flow reports of the hazardous materials transported by a high-hazard train to each State emergency response commission, Tribal emergency response commission, or other responsible State or Tribal agency, consistent with the notification content requirements under section 174.312 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), including—</text> <subparagraph id="H79C703904E2C4E45861B82C3F1E4CE1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a reasonable estimate of the number of high-hazard trains that are expected to travel, per week, through each county within the applicable jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD6FE34540B6A4DDC90749003788D573D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>updates to such estimate when making a change in volume of 25 percent or more;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37770CAD2F6447F2B7BAC2DD4EA87BFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the hazardous materials being transported on such trains;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8BF65579CF3A43DD82253608D6A418AE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>applicable emergency response information, as required by regulation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H468B91A99D594EBE9EE2B43D5F01B7AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identification of the routes over which the hazardous materials on such trains will be transported; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6C28B2E2485F4FA9BB932FFC9A024CF1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a point of contact at the Class I railroad who—</text> <clause id="HCD8723BDE35C4220A2FB5DC36BBFAA26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has knowledge of the railroads’ transportation of hazardous materials; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HB829F6BA056E431B940E9FFAADC41DFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is responsible for serving as the point of contact for the State emergency response commission, Tribal emergency response commission, or other State or Tribal agency responsible for receiving such information;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23B16FD8655C4749AF552A435E39FD6B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>require each applicable State emergency response commission to provide to a political subdivision of a State, or the public agency responsible for emergency response or law enforcement, upon request of the political subdivision or public agency, the information the commission receives from a Class I railroad pursuant to paragraph (3), including, for any such political subdivision or public agency responsible for emergency response or law enforcement that makes an initial request for such information, any updates received by the State emergency response commission;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAC43FFCA64EE4288B5E932B17EDB9232"><enum>(7)</enum><text>prohibit any Class I railroad, employee, or agent from withholding, or causing to be withheld, the train consist information from first responders, emergency response officials, Federal and State agencies, and law enforcement personnel described in paragraph (2)(B) who are responding to an incident, accident, or public health or safety emergency involving the rail transportation of hazardous materials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA66CD0F0DF4647649DAB4E54A065E369"><enum>(8)</enum><text>establish security and confidentiality protections, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, including protections from the public release of proprietary information or security sensitive information (as defined in section 15.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations), to prevent the release to unauthorized persons any electronic train consist information or advanced notification or information provided by Class I railroads under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5C78AB7D4CD8466DA444382C3DEC86BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a Class I railroad from voluntarily entering into a memorandum of understanding with a State emergency response commission or an entity representing or including first responders, emergency response officials, and law enforcement personnel.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7F054EB082C6455E92E4A6D1480BCD43"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safety improvements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Railroad Safety Enhancement Act of 2026, the Secretary shall evaluate and update, to the extent necessary for safety and in compliance with Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review), the operational requirements for high-hazard trains to ensure the safe transportation of hazardous materials by rail, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H90D7AD20964544D9A4D47D7F2D996657"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preventing the placement of blocks of empty railcars in locations within the consist of the train that increase the chance or severity of a derailment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42D2448A3DC546D4A600CFF7CCB0FFAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requirements for an adequate number of buffer cars between a locomotive or railcar and tank cars transporting hazardous materials.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDE80508F581B4585B7AAF6A0A033CE94"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Hazardous materials emergency response plans</header>
<paragraph id="H2A3E67ACD8524C62BDA70A1401A44C77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan contents</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations, in compliance with Executive Order 12866, requiring all Class I railroads that operate high-hazard trains to submit to the Secretary hazardous materials emergency response plans that are consistent with the format of the National Response Team <quote>One Plan</quote>. Such plans shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H536DA924849B4691BF4E56351A36B888"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consideration of potential hazardous materials release for the hazardous materials identified under subsection (a)(7) that the railroad is transporting;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H94E1B8E5C1E04A56A42CEDEB17802933"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identification of the railroad’s hazardous materials response teams that can quickly respond to a release or potential release within a reasonable amount of time;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H586B05253F064780B1329441CB555C7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identification of the equipment and resources available to the hazardous materials response teams;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB6D91FE31EB74D18AF0A9256AB35B77B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>organizational charts for the hazardous materials response teams; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED59A36C29C841EEB0B999D0126FD8D8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>plans to facilitate hazardous materials release liability claims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAAD77E388904031B5BF471A4C60B01A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>Railroads shall coordinate with relevant States and Tribes when creating the plans required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F124FFC9CAF43C2AA0D9BF03325C95C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Triennial review</header><text>Not later than 1 year after a Class I railroad submits a hazardous materials emergency response plan pursuant to paragraph (1), and on a triennial basis thereafter, the Secretary shall review such plan. If the Secretary identifies deficiencies during such review, the Secretary shall describe the nature of any deficiencies and allow for correction.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H996F84ADA38F43B3B904113C2EF8A217"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>The Secretary shall periodically audit a railroad’s hazardous materials emergency response plan.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7F199D2A42054C6DA3E54120F310B9DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/20154">section 20154</external-xref> the following: <quote>20155. High-hazard trains.</quote>.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H9ECC059FC23044D3AF7FDA54B84D5F1D"><enum>103.</enum><header>Ensuring the safety of long trains</header>
<subsection id="H294E87EEC09D4062BD40BEC682A6F339"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reviewing and updating safety regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress the report required under section 22422(d) of the Passenger Rail Expansion and Rail Safety Act of 2021 (title II of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), the Secretary shall independently evaluate any safety concerns identified in the Comptroller General’s report titled <quote>Freight Trains Are Getting Longer, and Additional Information Is Needed to Assess Their Impact</quote> (GAO–19–443) and in the report required under section 22422(d) of the Passenger Rail Expansion and Rail Safety Act of 2021, by reviewing and subsequently updating, if necessary for safety and in compliance with Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review), existing safety regulations to ensure the safe transportation of goods and passengers by rail, including consideration of the impact that train length and weight have on the safe transportation of high-hazard trains.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9EAFB98146D445FAA1C45B8848E74749"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the Secretary submits the report required under subsection (a), if the Secretary has not addressed any recommendation contained within such report, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that justifies such inaction.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H011C78AEE4D24F34AE950F9CA3F353BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header>
<paragraph id="H59956EA2D80F4387BBC5810A9CE223D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall revise the existing railroad accident or incident reporting forms to require railroads to report the weight trailing tonnages of any train involved in a reportable accident or incident.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA80CD056660F4F0BB91BBE1E505E25C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Federal Railroad Administration shall publish on its Rail Safety Data website a summary of all reportable incidents and accidents, categorized by train length and weight.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H0722143DCCF5423A82409FE5BA39709E"><enum>104.</enum><header>Blocked highway-rail grade crossings</header>
<subsection id="HB5258D9E45D547D9AE4BE1AB44B75585"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences under which the National Academy shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAC8E927332E645DEA689801F1863BEEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study of 20 most frequently blocked highway-rail grade crossings in not fewer than 10 different States, as determined by the Secretary based on—</text>
<subparagraph id="H98DF413542C4414883CB70654C711E90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal Railroad Administration data;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3696AF6DE89E4CB7B49A0FC368B1776A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the work experience of the Office of Railroad Safety’s Grade Crossing and Trespasser Outreach Division;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H19CA63A5631D447790104C1F72D4F4AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data from the blocked highway-rail grade crossing portal; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BB7B600331C48A8B297587198F55D8D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>geographic diversity; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC0C8A5EC3B2C400CA9C37A05F20AC20E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Secretary for solutions in preventing or reducing occurrences or repeated occurrences where highway-rail grade crossings are blocked for extended periods.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF65A9DE790BB48039783481A7C66C9F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members</header><text>In establishing the membership to conduct the study described in subsection (a)(1), the National Academy of Sciences shall appoint not fewer than 3 of its members who—</text>
<paragraph id="H44C9101DC34D433FAA9B36B219B9C049"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are engineering or rail experts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE98FA07465C44567990529ED2411F4D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are not railroad carriers, or entities funded by railroad carriers;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA08347A7C2942ABA40436951FB70AE8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have relevant experience in railroad safety technology or railroad operating experience; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF412F9B0EA824A52BC62D73C1F23AD8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have no financial ties to the rail industry.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA4D401B1E7AD478394F6EE415F8885EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA9BAF5983B1647CC972EB11E1DC3D815"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine any potential impacts to railroad and community safety due to blocked highway-rail grade crossings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD35D3CE591F64015B0A55DAEEF38758D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify potential financial impacts incurred by the railroad or its customers due to blocked crossings;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B703ADCE2E44ACE927CD1329DE360FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify potential freight network efficiency impacts due to solutions that will reduce or eliminate the impacts of blocked crossings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBA997ED0E2C43978DB5985B2CE1990C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examine community impacts that result from blocked crossings;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC9E7ADCAC9B44DFB352909BB28F6787"><enum>(5)</enum><text>examine causes for blocked crossings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2091200972E94BA2A24DD59966391FF4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>examine the potential impacts on railroad operations of the recommendations made in the report submitted pursuant to subsection (c), including reliability of service to customers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDC403B9743C476E8F0D45E32655BB88"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify practical solutions to prevent blocked crossings.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE25DB4A5E71543B8871A9C1A1AA3AC6E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that contains the results of the study conducted by the National Academy of Sciences pursuant to this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H735E81A479A245068C452E4CA9E3E2B6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>From the amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2026 to carry out section 20108 of title 49, United States Code, the Secretary shall expend such sums as may be necessary, but not more than $2,000,000, to carry out the study required under this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3486485C96D44EFDBE95222FBCD9CD63"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Railroad crossing elimination program</header><text>Section 22909 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H31EE3724498E4F509AB43C0868B99363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(2)(C)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0F2FF06C4878430CBFBCAB97A3B91A35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H706C46009B6045B180DFB76FF160536A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5DB95C107FEA45AC8177A09B17E74AC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFD6F8665D7F1408BA1B55F095A01EEE5" style="OLC"> <clause id="HE8F3504AFA834C7890C1AA267C86C226"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a bus route to a school or within 1 mile of a school;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBB1D3EA0C2E841C29A34EA581CAE73E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> <subparagraph id="H435AC9B212D146EDA3C92F2A5C575EF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HA9599188609D43638E106A150BA6D26C" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H59A2B8F0213448D5B91811468D308C6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCAA2EB0E25D4BB1AB4FF53CB4883085"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HB53313521EBF45AB812DFA9DE5F6AFB0" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H66545FA218754DFEAD940FC0D1E2239B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain bus routes</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project given additional consideration under subsection (f)(2)(C)(iii) may not exceed 85 percent.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H306D133EF33D439099E2171F887992F7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Railroad point of contact for blocked crossings</header> <paragraph id="HA22363B300FA40429AD043CF6C602741"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, each railroad carrier shall establish and maintain a toll-free telephone service for rights-of-way over which the railroad carrier dispatches trains to directly receive calls reporting blocked highway-rail grade crossings.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H83B00DF4E5F84BF09F75C94915D38989"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of existing number</header><text>A railroad carrier may comply with the requirement under subsection (a) by using the telephone number that is being used to comply with section 20152(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE43EF62E32474CECBDC068F570F3767F"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Publicly available</header> <text>Each railroad carrier subject to this subsection shall notify the Secretary of the telephone number referred to in paragraph (1) or (2), who shall post such number on a publicly available website of the Department of Transportation.</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29CC8B6B261E420897EC4AA1B6D95A22"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive the requirement that the telephone service be toll-free for Class II and Class III rail carriers if the Secretary determines that toll-free service would be cost prohibitive or unnecessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD0F1FA06DEC049FF8A15550880E52674"><enum>105.</enum><header>Inspections</header> <subsection id="HC0C332490A6941818AE5A89B26B8C62D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Time available for inspection</header> <paragraph id="HF8D4821F4ACC4C5498D6850BEFC9AE74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H0DCF3FC842B749DE92451A2C02BCCCCE" style="USC">
<section id="HCEF92A6846A34604B7AACA6FD4DDAA37"><enum>20172.</enum><header>Time available for inspection</header>
<subsection id="H6E6C59E0D5EF40E5A88BCB2434654E2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No railroad may limit the time required for an employee to complete a railcar, locomotive, or brake inspection to ensure that each railcar, locomotive, and brake system complies with safety laws and regulations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2D7F9A95F3144ECAA8A08B6AA29E8390"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Employees shall perform their inspection duties promptly and shall not delay other than for reasons related to safety.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H398813344EC446B8A56ACAC925D15C4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>20172. Time available for inspection.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8B92831120894689905B88811B1E07F8"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Pre-Departure railcar inspections</header> <text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the pre-departure inspection requirements for Class I railroads under part 215 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (as written on such date of enactment)—</text>
          <paragraph id="H0605E6895F734DECB146D66A9B47DDA2">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to ensure that after initial consultation with the Federal Railroad Administration, and after each subsequent annual consultation, each railroad identifies inspection locations and, at such locations, has inspectors designated under part 215 available for the purpose of inspecting freight cars;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H38FE52E3B4AD46D1936DBE54B8911095">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to ensure that all freight cars are inspected by an inspector designated under part 215 at a designated inspection location in the direction of travel as soon as practicable; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB036E856180A4CC0BEFDE5C56F844EFB">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to require each railroad that operates railroad freight cars to which such part 215 applies to designate persons qualified to inspect railroad freight railcars, subject to any existing collective bargaining agreement, for compliance and determinations required under such part.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H63F1BC99D5C54B00917F7D0CAF209939"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified locomotive inspections</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall review and amend, as necessary, regulations under chapters 229 and 243 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations—</text> <paragraph id="H523CC4D35008416D8ED280906255513F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure appropriate training qualifications and proficiency of employees, including qualified mechanical inspectors, performing locomotive inspections; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9414C0B74AD1493484B5918160921645"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for locomotives in service on a Class I railroad, to require an additional daily inspection to be performed by a qualified mechanical inspector between the current intervals under section 229.23(b)(2) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFB0E17784B4F4E74B7A8E9B8A8831751"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Audits</header> <paragraph id="H57B8390F72FB4CD98AB789EBFF3E8B37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall initiate audits of Federal railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspection compliance with chapter II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, which—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8DE53F96129747F4966AE128E8E3D38F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider whether the railroad has in place procedures necessary for railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspection compliance under such chapter;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA01CF76682544568AB0DA2C388C0DDEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess the type, content, and adequacy of training and performance metrics the railroad provides employees who perform railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspections, including the qualifications specified for such employees;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H197FF581E22442558EFC2A810E0904B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine whether the railroad has practices that would interfere with an employee’s responsibility to perform an inspection safely;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H650A8FF4F191433585D170813E53679F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>determine whether railcars, locomotives, and train brake systems are inspected on the railroad’s network in accordance with such chapter;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H673876BBDFF34F7080AB58A471A10E68"><enum>(E)</enum><text>involve proper communication of identified defects to railroad personnel and make appropriate use of remedial action reports to verify that repairs are made;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8B99B81C8AE458697AD649A56F2B9E1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>determine whether managers coerce employees to sign off on any documents verifying an inspection or repair of a railcar, locomotive, or train brake system;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB47687038BB540AC8AD12F6311F6B069"><enum>(G)</enum><text>determine whether the railroad’s inspection procedures reflect the current operating practices of the railroad carrier; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6A7FA9BA595461382C0773E20C9D74E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>ensure that railroad inspection procedures only provide for the use of persons permitted to perform each relevant inspection under such chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F98CAE184724AA59F396224D918DDFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audit scheduling</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B3ECCCC2BC94C3AB3EDAE101A405D9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>schedule the audits required under paragraph (1) to ensure that—</text>
<clause id="H81D9550F3F8548219850D3C5B7BEDDC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>every Class I railroad is audited not less frequently than once every 5 years; and</text></clause> <clause id="H74827F7262C6464EBF245710670EC408"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a limited number, as determined by the Secretary, of Class II and Class III railroads are audited annually, provided that—</text>
<subclause id="H9E9A97478A9945529E8C58BF8CD069C3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no audit of a tourist, scenic, historic, or excursion operation may be required under this subsection; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE3D9D9D10DF745F78229D7CBC613B3ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>no other Class II or III railroad may be audited more frequently than once every 5 years; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4C33445B601142F0802CF03469907294"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct the audits described in subparagraph (A)(ii) in accordance with—</text> <clause id="H0D221B2493404115B06F03D5E22A8782"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H8A3F960255604327858E3AF33638E660"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appendix C of part 209 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33EEA82A9AF0479EA8610886F764DC63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates to inspection program and procedures</header><text>If, during an audit required under this subsection, the auditor identifies a deficiency in a railroad’s procedures or practices necessary to ensure compliance with chapter II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, the railroad shall eliminate such deficiency, after first being provided the opportunity to address whether such a deficiency exists.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF22ED292E1404A3DA26F37C52987C520"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation and cooperation</header>
<subparagraph id="HB7CC0167C42F40D28760941F24AC1C98"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting any audit required under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with the railroad being audited and its employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing the employees of the railroad that conduct railcar, locomotive, or train brake system inspections.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H514F496C7F88450CB28B201ED98DF84F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>The railroad being audited and its employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing mechanical employees, shall fully cooperate with any audit conducted pursuant to this subsection—</text>
<clause id="H2CAD3AD9D81640E9A91D02E03F0D4A43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by providing any relevant documents requested; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1457ABF3677C436DA8E9406272BFC1E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by making available any employees for interview without undue delay or obstruction.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3061BF7965E44E1DB1677DB1F592A3AB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Failure to cooperate</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a railroad or any of its employees, including any nonprofit employee labor organization representing mechanical employees of the railroad is not fully cooperating with an audit conducted pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall electronically notify the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives of such noncooperation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H18CBF0E440E0488DB9A6042C31857C11"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review of regulations</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and periodically thereafter, the Secretary shall determine whether any update to chapters I and II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, is necessary to ensure the adequacy of railcar, locomotive, and train brake system inspections.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC6B5B71DA16F493484AFC37ACC45D460"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall publish an annual report on the public website of the Federal Railroad Administration that—</text> <paragraph id="HCEFDFBB6AAD44A3C988B234F186E459F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes the findings of the audits conducted pursuant to subsection (c) during the most recently concluded fiscal year;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADF6B4ACCF6D430AB0642AF5D200207A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>summarizes any updates made to chapter I or II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, pursuant to this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC65D53AE8B5149AEA71EBF5FC6BFD284"><enum>(3)</enum><text>excludes any confidential business information or sensitive security information.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9363A617BEC94666AF6260297D333846"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H7153D0BFBC3B44B8B84C0B0D4B82C2AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide the Secretary with any authority to interpret, revise, alter, or apply a collectively bargained agreement, nor any authority over collective bargaining, collectively bargained agreements, or any aspect of the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HECAEE6E8AEDE4F6D8D3C7BE2FAC98462"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to alter the terms or interpretations of existing collective bargaining agreements; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27EFFD10FAB04490B3807FE50DFB2626"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to abridge any procedural rights or remedies provided under a collectively bargained agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H484EDAECE5884E348D05EA231ADCD4FC"><enum>106.</enum><header>Emergency brake signals</header>
<subsection id="H4417EB81BE544317B959DEDF7F14ECE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall convene a meeting of the Railroad Safety Advisory Committee for the purpose of considering a regulatory safety task on the functioning of emergency brake signals.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H68F7A7E3FE23483FB1E78809286E2CFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Railroad Safety Advisory Committee shall consider—</text>
<paragraph id="H3B4B36C9A75B4EFF92C8368B8CB5F828"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sufficiency of the regulations under part 232 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, with regard to end-of-train and head-of-train device communications;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA823E348D95D45ECB313ECE1AFA50343"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether National Transportation Safety Board Safety Recommendations R–20–028 and R–20–029 have been adequately addressed;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4698F5211EBA4393A0F337D398647C61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether more frequent communication checks between a head-of-train device and an end-of-train device would improve rail safety; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33E2E41BD24246C9B13BD32120FE8D1F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether repetition of the emergency brake signal transmission until it is received by the end-of-train device would improve rail safety.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC44F5CB191344FD4A4C455B94B0BA13C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations and work plan</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the meeting is convened pursuant to subsection (a), a working group of the Railroad Safety Advisory Committee should—</text> <paragraph id="H70FD2F53C502418EA116847A027DC5F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop initial recommendations with respect to the matters considered under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCEDB54D75BD04D1290794D658AD838B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>complete a work plan for implementing such recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4FA1B1FED1BD4C7ABC55CBB743F1B571"><enum>107.</enum><header>Defect detection systems</header> <subsection id="H4D805245DC8E486591FE1E5238430EAA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, as amended by section 105(a)(1), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HDA55B7DF20AE4C5A8AA492611976AEFE" style="USC">
<section id="H6BC4EEB95BCF4E2F846D3C51BD0CD926"><enum>20173.</enum><header>Defect detection systems</header>
<subsection id="HECC2DCE62DFC43FABBEA6D47C1A7280C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3C42A1827F984FFCBCDAA574EE4C2EBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered rail carrier</header><text>The term <quote>covered rail carrier</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>Class I carrier</quote> in section 10102.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3C1DCE3A89B84421BCB12C69CEDD2162">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Defect detection system</header>
 <text>The term <quote>defect detection system</quote> means the use of defect detectors, the analysis of the data defect detectors produce, and any other aspects a system that help railroads identify and understand the severity of known safety conditions.</text>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00C96EE0DCD64D128D5879ED85BDDA1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Defect detector</header><text>The term <quote>defect detector</quote> means any device or equipment situated within the rail system that can detect and communicate a potential or known safety condition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4135E249C1ED40B3BCBD74D9FDF1A6BA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-hazard train</header><text>The term <quote>high-hazard train</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 20155(a)(6).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6D15DAE2EE94CCC99CE9EC9A04A7824"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Main line</header><text>The term <quote>main line</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C5F19487A6D470FB570101FBA4E5E71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a segment or route of railroad tracks—</text>
<clause id="H4C1183E396454C9098B2B8C508360582"><enum>(i)</enum><text>over which 5,000,000 or more gross tons of railroad traffic is transported annually; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8144BE169E624AE6B759075EC0622421"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that has a maximum authorized speed for freight trains in excess of 25 miles per hour; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H79D6C190A5C841E6ABA5DC4FE03A7797"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intercity rail passenger transportation or commuter rail passenger transportation routes or segments over which high-hazard trains operate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H979A5158AA0D4E1BAA62DEE91197206F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Physical characteristics</header><text>The term <quote>physical characteristics</quote> means the physical terrain and operating considerations related to the physical terrain for the relevant main line.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDB05CD9AFCDE4C1FA105D82804800ECD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Defect detector analysis program</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a program for the research, development, testing, and evaluation of defect detector systems to inform and support the rulemaking required under subsection (d) and the evaluation of plans under subsection (c), which shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H797321B36E8241B5A8DF0111924CB13C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of existing manufacturer recommended practices, industry-developed voluntary consensus technical standards, and railroad safety data to inform appropriate standards for commercially available defect detector systems and ensure the integrity and reliability of their use on the general railroad system, including standards relating to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H34FE1328556D41928A11A687FC4DDD55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintenance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H794F03B8FBAF448D8C6541B06B3CEC40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>testing;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H10485E32D75846D6AF5365F3E818F56F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inspection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C3A0542D0F04EF8B120204078DF592B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>installation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF514EDC8DC9243269B277EB0EDF52EB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of existing alert thresholds and trending algorithms to determine appropriate metrics and levels to ensure that defect detector systems identify unsafe equipment or operations in time to take appropriate safety actions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAA1D6F3FB8F40918F579B9E56294168"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>an evaluation of existing processes and procedures for decisionmaking and communication of appropriate safety actions necessary to address unsafe equipment or operations, including—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H9A2A56B557D34EED80E23E414FA33371">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>stoppage of rail equipment;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA68FA9CA96C740C8B05F5E0AC25E3091"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>setting out rail equipment;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HA052056A87264D649CAA7132AAA4B32E">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>train speed reduction;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82DFE00B140F41819CE1E1BB2D3FB247"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>diverting a train; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H59D55F6495F34917A5C910453D4AC76B">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>inspection requirements;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB1836CE4C9049C0A342EA03F0E40939"><enum>(4)</enum><text>research to understand the capabilities and limitations of existing technologies in use or developed to better assess the plans required under the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (c); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B9B25F7044540A8A58A61A504F482D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>research to understand new or developing technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H99A4D93C5EF642AFA0B30D5086E49BF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan elements</header> <paragraph id="HA210226642B74E06A2FF21A9BA35E7B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Risk-based</header><text>Each defect detection system plan required under the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (d) shall be risk-based.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCD7B0709632943E481CCC5D780F1B5B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each plan referred to in paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H408E4A580EBB49BC86F5E7E2B5D22E9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the railroad’s proposed defect detector network, including—</text>
<clause id="HAE99B15742B04B5CB3519E85FA2CB646"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how the network will reduce the risk of incidents near population centers and on high-hazard train routes; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF649F2DE5C0644ACB0082A154E5D7B02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the network will be implemented by the deadline set forth in subsection (d)(1)(B);</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7C1E1597017B4DEDA8E3A7742C7335B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the railroad’s defect detection system meets or exceeds the defect detection performance standards described in subsection (d)(1)(D);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB72F44C5CCAE4CFD904B28024F981F37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (3), a risk-based approach for identifying overheated wheel bearings that require the placement of the types and spacing of defect detectors—</text>
<clause id="HB83752A33E0A4FFD80F5100F38CF14FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for main lines traveling within an urbanized area with a population of at least 75,000, at a distance that provides for any train operating along the railroad’s route to undergo detection not less than 10 miles before entering such an area;</text></clause> <clause id="H61218FEF4B7D4BA7A7B2D463148F0F42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for main lines not equipped with acoustic bearing detectors or other similar technology, at a distance averaging 15 route miles to the extent possible based on the physical characteristics of the route; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H02C938A514EB4CECA99CB771817A87DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for main lines equipped with acoustic bearing detectors or other similar technology, at a distance averaging 20 route miles to the extent possible based on the physical characteristics of the route along which such detectors are being installed;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5578C5C0477A4C9AB8D58A84BA5EA402"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the types and spacing of other wayside defect detectors required to be placed, to the extent such detectors are utilized;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H34FB5487E7D041DF97129C5BC1EF8523"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the manufacturer’s expected performance for each type of defect detector and how the carrier will assess compliance with such performance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3093ADE3FFCB4E61AC744D63B5D620C6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>procedures for promptly providing pertinent safety alerts to train employees, including locomotive engineers and conductors, train dispatchers, and relevant maintenance employees;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA348FD605BCA4C33A79D30128E3B1182">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>the ability to share relevant safety data from the defect detector network with other railroad carriers and with railcar owners;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC1DD0B0B938946208EDF48945D7531FA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>policies and procedures for training employees regarding relevant elements of the defect detector system, including—</text> <clause id="H4CDF61A34BC7447C8A46B323263893F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>persons whose duties include installing, maintaining, repairing, modifying, inspecting, reviewing data, and testing safety-critical elements of the railroad’s defect detector, including central office, wayside, or onboard subsystems;</text></clause>
<clause id="HDEC9FFF0F79A4A47814C129C1DFAB205"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>persons who receive and review defect detector alerts; and</text></clause> <clause id="H892E9F7624654E2F99474A915DDF21BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>persons who operate trains or serve as a train or engine crew member;</text>
<subclause id="H08DBBF1A07A54C0AB0DB1B70C6467235"><enum>(I)</enum><text>policies for maintaining records regarding the required elements of the rail defect detector network for not less than 5 years, which shall not include data on individual alerts; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BE1F8E0E44E4D5A97DD470D23CB567E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>designs for the collection and analysis, including applicable alerts, thresholds, and corresponding safety actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBD21963AE8745EE98098E0CC1CA7FDE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alternative hot bearing detection plan</header>
<subparagraph id="HFE2B48331E1845C5881F820175A84DD4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>A rail carrier may comply with an alternative hot bearing detection plan instead of the requirements described in paragraph (2)(C) if—</text> <clause id="HD8312C93D75242F7B39AC08A8F09EDFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the rail carrier submits such plan to the Secretary and the Secretary approves the plan; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H03AB0D7245344578A816AAD503FEC91E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the plan provides an equivalent or higher level of safety as the requirements described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H815FD04AFB80425EBFCA3FB37BCD3D38"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Triennial reviews</header><text>Not less frequently than triennially, the Secretary shall review each alternative plan approved pursuant to subparagraph (A) to determine its continuing effectiveness at detecting bearing-related defects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H32CC27CDDB2E4262A55C877435D036BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
<paragraph id="HD5232DFB3907421E9412A799ED919F6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Railroad Safety Enhancement Act of 2026, the Secretary shall initiate a rulemaking, and not later than 2 years after such date of enactment, the Secretary shall issue a final rule, in compliance with Executive Order 12866 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/601">5 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> note; relating to regulatory planning and review), that—</text> <subparagraph id="H75759223C2E24355B2C759974F6EA656"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requires covered rail carriers to submit, not later than 1 year after the issuance of such final rule, defect detector network plans that include the elements described in subsection (c)(2);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD678B4D411E44A17AB3CF71D1A1EB5CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires the covered rail carrier to implement the plan required under paragraph (1) not later than 3 years after the issuance of such final rule;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC83CFDBBBB8D4251AE6ED9EAB9243FC4"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>creates procedures to review, approve, and monitor compliance of such plans;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B3292CBC79B46F495114670259C0C37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishes performance standards measured by the ability of a defect detection system to identify defects before a condition that is likely to result in an accident or incident, including how such ability will be measured and reported for data related to requirements;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB884FBE9D1674B98BACB04FA377711C2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>requires the reporting of data regarding the defect defector network effectiveness, including defect detector failures;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDEC16510ECDE462EAFF393B3305F42F9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>creates requirements for covered rail carriers to test, inspect, and maintain any defect detector based on the evaluation completed pursuant to subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF33FF27930D54C5DAEC87D81FB7DC4D2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>establish appropriate thresholds for alerts and corresponding safety actions, to the extent necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC2B48656CB454DB4854487D70A61A78D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updated standards</header><text>The performance standards established pursuant to paragraph (1)(D) shall be updated not less frequently than once every 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H856AA2BF3EC44755BA7792931BD1001E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Updates and approvals</header> <paragraph id="H0C8AE11910DA40F69D7A64D219C6E871"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Each entity subject to the mandate in subsection (a) shall update the plans required under subsection (d)(1)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF5A9DA69018A4E5EA69B9BE1CA118CD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to reflect material changes to its railcar defect detector network; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0AC4ABDD3004473399B90534B92F3245"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to address changes made to the performance standards pursuant to subsection (d)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H738E7AE767D742E6A8631A8C14F2B808"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approvals</header><text>To ensure safety, the Secretary shall promptly review each plan submitted pursuant to subsection (d)(1), including the sufficiency of the performance standards required under subsection (c)(1)(D), and approve or reject each plan and update that is required to be submitted under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB1B7B80CF5E470EAC98FB9DB3C870C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reviews for compliance</header><text>Not less frequently than biannually, the Secretary shall conduct reviews to ensure that railroad carriers are complying with the plans required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA29E0E52DE81465088BE11F1BD8365AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Not later than 60 days after receipt, the Secretary shall make available to the public on the website of the Department of Transportation any plan or update submitted pursuant to this section, but the Secretary shall redact—</text> <subparagraph id="H6DCDD50F59F5411A910A32CF489A27F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proprietary information, as verified by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2B371250AF2045328EFFB7D1D77D6D6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>security-sensitive information, including information described in section 1520.5(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation), as verified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB7DA0BE6C6F4261AB9124AB5547B9EA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary may assess a civil penalty under chapter 213 of this title for any violation pursuant to the rulemaking under subsection (a) for—</text>
<paragraph id="H25F4C9E1CDC84DB9B8A42FD41F1BBC29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each accident or incident on a route where the railroad is noncompliant with the plan approved under subsection (e)(2); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1764370CC113417488BA976CA4D85D22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>failing to take any corresponding safety action to an alert as set forth in the approved plan pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(J).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2869E985AE6A49CEAF883033E2CBD073"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preservation of authority</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to restrict the authority of the Secretary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF56601AFE08549F4981C881A0FB77FE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, as amended by section 105(a)(2), is further amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>20173. Defect detection systems.</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1DD985F9B3BE4337846BAD525F0D97B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Temporary defect detection assistance</header>
<paragraph id="HB0ACF95DFF56424E935266022575974B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Formula grant program</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall establish a formula grant program to assist commuter railroads with installing defect detection technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB99A312273E9430CB680625ACD3F66B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>A commuter railroad that has a contract with a Class I railroad, as of May 1, 2023, that requires the commuter railroad to install defect detection technology that complies with the approved plan submitted pursuant to section 20173 of title 49, United States Code, is eligible to receive a grant under this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52778036A42C45E1AFB5F4EFC28C564F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Formula</header><text>Grant funding under this subsection shall be allocated based on the number of defect detectors required to be installed to comply with section 20173 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12773C3373524C96901372DBB7CCF9B9"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Requirements</header> <text>Any eligible entity that receives grant funding under this subsection shall comply with the grant conditions set forth in such section 22909(j).</text>
          </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H02665C4FB1F34EAFB009BE05428689F6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Railroad Administration such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the formula grant program under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA511321A64834B4FB59B6F18003E51B5"> <enum>108.</enum> <header>Safe Freight Act of 2023</header> <subsection id="HFA9BAF0E49F444E38A5A3A5720F91947"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text>This section may be cited as the <quote>Safe Freight Act of 2023</quote>.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H84C5413F49F847CB9EDB6696CA7EB6B1">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Freight train crew size</header>
 <text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/20153">section 20153</external-xref> the following:</text>
          <quoted-block id="H6F455DCB1526450991C3BC5794BCB6B5" style="USC">
            <section id="H6D5B7C746F924BBD8CB8AC8A0F8A2FB6">
              <enum>20154.</enum>
              <header>Freight train crew size safety standards</header>
              <subsection id="H1DE35232722A48E8B6BEA1B461C2412B">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Minimum crew size</header>
 <text>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), a freight train operated by a Class I railroad may not be operated without a 2-person crew consisting of at least 1 appropriately qualified and certified conductor and 1 appropriately qualified and certified locomotive engineer.</text>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H6FADC7B756B24BEB81586B2390A1A7E8">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Exceptions</header>
                <paragraph id="H638AC686565B47B1B65669F8F88F4085">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
 <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="HF8946DA10CAF4F8F8AB5BB82753B81F8">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>train operations on track that is not a main line track (as defined in section 20173(a)(2));</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2805402699254558B8573EC31D963480">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>locomotives performing assistance to a train that has incurred mechanical failure or lacks the power to traverse difficult terrain, including traveling to or from the location where assistance is provided;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HDE91FA38E29B46F388DD01BEE2F4BC7B">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>locomotives that—</text> <clause id="H218ED1D2D94D4AD6BD3A8D83FC956C40"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>are not attached to any equipment or are attached only to a caboose; and</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HE84EC805D91C4C888962671A8F88A4A8">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>do not travel farther than 50 miles from the point of origin of such locomotive; and</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H3B3F83567F8E47EDBE60101A012B2059">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>train operations staffed with fewer than a 2-person crew at least 1 year before the date of the enactment of the Safe Freight Act of 2023 unless the Secretary determines that such operations do not achieve an equivalent level of safety as would result from compliance with the requirement under subsection (a).</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H686244FAEB704AD5A0A1058E71354EC0">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Trains ineligible for exception</header>
 <text>The exceptions under paragraph (2) may not be applied to—</text> <subparagraph id="H5936E92EA8BA48B8A12C4079009C1B85"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a high-hazard train (as defined in section 20155(a)); or</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HC4F844C7210D4B1B8A8D27DDD382F81C">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a train consist with a total length of at least 7,500 feet.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HDDDBD027F02D4DC2BFEECE5065D5BAB4"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Waiver</header> <text>A railroad carrier may seek a waiver of the requirements under subsection (a) in accordance with section 20103(d).</text>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H56CDF6FB31D64412A4D96B31694C1F6F">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Preservation of authority</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to restrict the authority of the Secretary.</text>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H82173B1FEB11414C913262E5B1714C96">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The analysis for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/20153">section 20153</external-xref> the following: <quote>20154. Freight train crew size safety standards.</quote>.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H346D708409154A10A765F7CAE8595020"><enum>109.</enum><header>Increased penalties for violations of rail safety regulations</header>
<subsection id="HF7838711E9EC43FCAF93A65C27B7A3B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Railroad safety violations</header><text>Section 21301(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1DD4A1B81B024F7DB2DA28EE874127BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) and (2) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H3D28FADD4DE040F29209B22996D2C58A" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H78EEDB878BDA44D6A3AA068BF1DBDFCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person may not fail to comply with a requirement of, a regulation prescribed under, or an order issued by, the Secretary under chapters 201 through 211. Subject to section 21304, a person violating a requirement of, a regulation prescribed under, or an order issued by, the Secretary under chapters 201 through 211 is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty. An act by an individual that causes a railroad carrier to be in violation constitutes a violation of this paragraph. A separate violation occurs for each day such violation continues.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H798228FD838E4CCCB0C9A158725BB0BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall include in, or make applicable to, each requirement of, regulation prescribed under, and order issued under chapters 201 through 211 a civil penalty for a violation of such requirement, regulation, or order in an amount equal to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3D59C520A91F42FB9A5594A1007A1866"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least $5,000 and not more than $1,000,000; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2574005C857349419F7DB934E7F2EE40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the person committing such violation is a small business concern (as such term is used in part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), including a Class III railroad, at least $1,000 and not more than $200,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA92561C1B434127AEDBCA89F232208F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9929E7189F884B248052D0924691FC85"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H693EDF072D474B9BAD44EE3902AA6BA4" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HABAB0E0793B54829B978CD5E1DA6C494"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If a violation described in paragraph (1) results in death, serious illness, or severe injury to any person, causes an imminent hazard of death or injury, or results in the substantial destruction of property, the Secretary may increase the civil penalty required under paragraph (2) to—</text> <subparagraph id="H4EB22CC70C504DC78D86FBAD14FA0694"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a maximum of $5,000,000; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6BA4DE8C02FE420896BBA60F078D5DB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the person committing such violation is a small business concern (as such term is used in part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), a maximum of $500,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EF83983E66E427AA21E39DC2F63D462"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary may double the civil penalty otherwise required under paragraph (2) or (3) if the violation follows a pattern of repeated violations or otherwise reflects a deliberate indifference or conscious disregard to the consequences of the conduct.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H88A81D55B1F243BF9422D035925B4911"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), as redesignated, by adding at the end the following: <quote>Such civil action may be brought in the judicial district in which the violation occurred or in which the defendant has its principal executive office. If the civil action is against an individual, the action may also be brought in the judicial district in which such individual resides.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE58F8BFFCBAD4F53BC687C14361C2216"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hours of service violations</header><text>Section 21301 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H0A0F3513A8DD45D3B9969D71BD189A54" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HF9D7CD8331BE479BA6BA227ADF654058"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional provisions related to violations of chapter 211</header>
<paragraph id="H36DFEFA5D07545068D254853AC3DEB0C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In any proceeding involving a violation of chapter 211, or a violation of a regulation or order issued pursuant to such chapter, a railroad carrier is deemed to have knowledge of the acts of its officers and agents.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C56E11117764D07861AE774D6F172D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A civil action involving a violation of chapter 211, or a violation of a regulation or order issued pursuant to such chapter, shall be brought in an appropriate district court of the United States not later than 2 years after the date of such violation unless administrative notification under section 3711 of title 31 is given within such 2-year period to the person committing the violation. If such notification is given, the action shall be brought not later than the last day of the 5-year period specified in section 2462 of title 28.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB1CBFC2192A240DBA0BC03E9863F440E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A separate violation of section 21106 occurs for each day employee sleeping quarters are not in compliance with the requirements under such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC37D4D6229954D9BAFA0C6F2DBD540AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates of penalties for inflation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the Federal Civil Penalties Inflation Adjustment Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/2461">28 U.S.C. 2461</external-xref> note), the inflation adjustment—</text>
<paragraph id="HE5AAE3A5AD534A93A2797C447614F2B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for minimum penalty amounts amended by this section, and any discretionary inflation adjustment of guideline penalty amounts by the Secretary, shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H819C9A35189C4133B6FBA6155816A709"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for maximum penalty amounts amended by this section, shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDB56B4007B5143A1B23EA9B7825E81B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Repeal</header>
<paragraph id="HB8B5CC38B8FD4C95BE6F586482F840E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/213">Chapter 213</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking sections 21302 and 21303.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17846A9E5B89497B85DE47C43A0F0E2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/213">chapter 213</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the items relating to sections 21302 and 21303.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H046BA2124D8B4762A120879537BC3692"><enum>110.</enum><header>Safer tank cars</header>
<subsection id="H1076B977D5324B8F87FD76374B141FDF">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Class 3 flammable liquids phase-Out schedule</header>
 <text>Beginning on December 31, 2027, no railroad tank car, regardless of its construction date, may be used to transport Class 3 flammable liquids in packing groups II and III (other than Class 3 flammable liquids listed in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 7304(b) of the Hazardous Materials Transportation Safety Improvement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/20155">49 U.S.C. 20155</external-xref> note)), regardless of the composition of the train consist, unless such tank car meets or exceeds the DOT–117, DOT–117P, or DOT–117R specifications (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act), including DOT–105A, DOT–105H, DOT–105J, DOT–105S, DOT–112H, DOT–112S, DOT–112J, DOT–120J, and DOT–120S tank cars.</text>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H162E8613E8F64395ADE6F3824EA7B6FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming regulatory amendments</header>
<paragraph id="HF097819B13664AA2A6AED80AA824D8A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC0444BFD3734DC99BE059C792E46E4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall immediately remove or revise the date-specific deadlines in any applicable regulations or orders to the extent necessary to conform with the requirement under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC7029AC6B92E4EA7ADAE1017A31CED5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not enforce any date-specific deadlines or requirements that are inconsistent with the requirement under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB35DEA5A59ED473FB56405F11C525252"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Except as required under paragraph (1), nothing in this section may be construed to require the Secretary to issue regulations to implement this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7479D43E1F9A40E486656414D026AE84">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Amending the phase-Out date</header>
 <text>If the Secretary, based on the data contained in the report issued pursuant to subsection (d), determines that the phase-out date under subsection (a) cannot be met due to insufficient manufacturing capacity or would otherwise result in significant impacts to interstate commerce, the Secretary shall delay the phase-out scheduled under subsection (a) to December 31, 2028.</text>
        </subsection>
<subsection id="H59F1609390474FC7BB1B2D72D2F656ED">
          <enum>(d)</enum>
          <header>GAO review</header>
 <text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall issue a report to the Secretary, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that—</text>
          <paragraph id="H956A10FA7BB14A9EA16C43E3FACEB5EE">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>identifies the manufacturing capacity of tank car manufacturers in North America, that manufacture tank cars to meet DOT–117 and DOT–117P specification requirements;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2B9FAD3075EE4168BC2E6F5E2F4AFCF1">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>identifies the retrofit capacity of tank car manufacturers and other entities in North America that can retrofit DOT–111 tank cars to meet DOT–117R specification requirements;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H2B8B209984A04024B94C5671926DA059">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>estimates the schedule of replacing tank cars currently in service that are reaching the end of their life cycle;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA47ECB48BD4A49BCB00E2931FBCB1541">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>identifies the number of tank cars that need to be phased out or retrofitted under subsection (a) and paragraph (2) and the number that could be retrofitted; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HDDEC5606AFAA48578522B3E9BFD4F230">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>estimates the demand for new tank cars.</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section> <section id="H1729C54297B54C34A7D6F08840F04DB2"><enum>111.</enum><header>Rail safety infrastructure research and development grants</header> <subsection id="HCE3819DD717246629633AA750F6CD00C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research requirement</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall award grants, in accordance with the restrictions and limitation on eligibility for Class I railroads under section 22907 of title 49, United States Code, which shall be used for research and development of defect detectors and the prevention of derailments of trains transporting hazardous materials.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H50910CC82B534BF3B362B9F68445B0BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Railroad Administration, $22,000,000, which shall be used for the grants authorized under subsection (a) and shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H897AA9D9005A4A7DB445F55EF48DD2B3"><enum>112.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for tank car research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, $5,000,000, which shall be used for expenses related to the development of—</text>
<paragraph id="HC227EB13B6D94CA4AEFD62505CE897E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>stronger, safer tank cars and valves for tank cars; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00A2D881D3A34263BB749E06D2E15875"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other tank car safety features.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H4C13CDF6519443AC8A64FDE50F3211D5">
        <enum>113.</enum>
        <header>Federal Railroad Administration safety culture</header>
        <subsection id="H00A4D5E739E146E9A2EA61A05D4E735B">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Review</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation shall—</text>
          <paragraph id="HE9A0EA39662F444E99E0CCFE19AAC8B1">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>conduct a review of the Federal Railroad Administration’s safety culture using the framework developed by the Nuclear Energy Agency of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HB1DAB57F9451458394E93F4FECF7F0C7">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that includes recommendations for improving the Federal Railroad Administration’s safety culture.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H6FE5FFC993A947F182541952E7472458">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Considerations</header>
 <text>As a part of the review conducted pursuant to subsection (a)(1), the Inspector General shall consider the impacts of the Federal Railroad Administration’s—</text>
          <paragraph id="H21B7F678A15E4A50A72017A0CD3BBF51">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>reorganization of its safety offices and management structure;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BAF86E5FD714C77AAFF6E78F09FC442"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>reorganization of its policy and research offices; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HE5DAAF4EF70A44908A78601B61DE7FF0">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>telework policies, including any change in policies since the beginning of the COVID–19 pandemic.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="HCA179EF74C8A4D01A2058B4C54848A52">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>Action plan</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the submission of the report required under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and post on a public-facing website an action plan that addresses the recommendations and findings made by the Inspector General in such report.</text>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="HB5E5B31C82374CF8AFE0D866E7A86886">
        <enum>114.</enum>
        <header>GAO report on roadway worker protections</header>
        <subsection id="HE42E477115D242D29204039D34A5D1C9">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text>
          <paragraph id="HFBC8945200A74150BA96D9F2B68D03A8">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>conduct a review of currently available technologies for roadway workers (as defined in section 214.7 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations) with protection from the hazards of being struck by a train or other on-track equipment in the United States; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HED8BA3238ACF4918B1A21A4BDEE4E46E">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that summarizes the results of the review conducted under subparagraph (a), including recommendations, as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H424C56913A854960A8B2A43521F5F6BF">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Contents</header>
 <text>The report submitted under subsection (a)(2) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H864FD542F7FD4B67BF918023E231E287"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>describe the frequency, type, and causes of incidences within the rail right-of-way associated with roadway workers being struck by a train or other on-track equipment, based on available data, including whether individuals were acting in compliance with the applicable rules, policies, procedures, and practices;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HC4AEF263AF7040F49B4B899D128CD3FB">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>describe the types of technologies referenced in subsection (a)(1) that are designed to reduce risk of injury and death when deployed as a secondary warning system to the standard operating procedures of a rail carrier, including for each technology—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H17145FDFD63A49F7AEB84AD09982F776">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the primary function and features;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A1E1DAD696B4D2C9DBE5DB1661FDC15"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the maturity, implementation readiness, and user experience;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HA653749F6A5643959FCDD502487DF2E9">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the frequency of implementation;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD88F1F0ED83E446FB34CD4361440030B"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>any costs, including up front and ongoing maintenance costs, of the technology and other costs associated with the technology;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H83F64C4E928642719843DE8F028955CA">
              <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>safety benefits associated with the technology relative to current rules, policies, procedures, and practices; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H3E30955D497E4012886F70517CDCFB3D">
              <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>ability to enhance protections for roadway workers without negatively impacting operational or network efficiencies;</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H03295CD691744B00A637E9A51DC6E15C">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>discuss the potential for such technologies to reduce or eliminate roadway worker accidents occurring within the rail right-of-way;</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H263CDE8AFBA94BF391D364D5494C3E2D">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>describe any challenges or barriers to adoption of such safety technologies, including operational, technical, and network efficiency challenges or barriers; and</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HEA53B89F807F4AF1AA3E7F374DE02EA2">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>assess the cost-beneficial nature of utilizing such technology as a secondary warning system.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H3E66871430D04E6196F5831391F9B0EA">
        <enum>115.</enum>
        <header>Federal Railroad Administration safety workforce management</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that contains the results of a review of the Federal Railroad Administration Office of Railroad Safety inspector and specialist staff resource management, including—</text>
        <paragraph id="H195F0B108A46474BBA97BF181AC75195">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of the changes in the number of Federal Railroad Administration safety inspectors and specialists, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H19A5309E2FAA4C61B435C3E15472B9AD">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the number of safety inspector and specialist vacancies;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BC6616F5D1941A2AD2AB4232284A253"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the number of such positions requested in each of the budget requests for the last 10 fiscal years; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8B3ED40A306B4A869BF51105DCFE499E">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the actual workforce levels during each of such fiscal years;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H37A3EB9C11B142E783BC564050FFCC5A"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>an assessment of geographic allocation plans, potential hiring and time-to-hire challenges, expected retirement rates, and recruitment and retention strategies;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H79D633E8046E460EB03270B8EBE8317A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>a description of any internal Federal Railroad Administration goals for compliance inspection rates across the network of regulated activities, and whether requested and actual safety inspector and specialist workforce levels align with such goals;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6E7D53D7ABB640C2BCAFCD4681290416">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>whether the system used for the notification, processing, or storing of civil penalty enforcement cases and other compliance actions recommended by safety inspectors and specialists against railroads, shippers of hazardous materials, and other respondents effectively supports the Federal Railroad Administration’s compliance inspection and enforcement program;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H379ACFA69A5E4B88B19EEC14D64DFB39">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>whether any macroeconomic or other conditions exist or have existed under which it has been difficult for the Federal Railroad Administration to fill safety inspector and specialist vacancies, and the degree to which special rates of pay or other recruitment and retention practices could ameliorate or could have ameliorated such difficulty; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8A04F35C18DA47668D549CBE4D02EE8F">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>recommendations for any reforms that could—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC46EE37299E4C28BA0E466E2DEB35DC"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>improve the recruitment, hiring, and retention of Federal Railroad Administration safety inspectors and specialists, including potential quality of life and workplace improvements;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB4F32AF68594444FBE871D417347A763">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>improve Federal Railroad Administration workforce management processes; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33C56FFD6E244C6AB4F0DEA59677F4D9"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>increase the capacity for inspection activities, if such capacity is identified as deficient, at the Federal Railroad Administration, including activities relating to the transportation of hazardous materials.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </section>
<section id="H3380965D97B042D0A290B5E258339365">
        <enum>116.</enum>
        <header>Office of Personnel Management review of safety inspector and specialist
          classifications</header>
        <subsection id="HBF0D25B77FCA43BEA908E3FC4A0C2294">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>Revising railroad safety series</header>
 <text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall—</text>
          <paragraph id="H31421EF70D1F42ADADD33042161129A8">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>complete a review of the Railroad Safety Series, GS–2121, TS–37; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC6B43E15F7A42F68DE1CDCBA8D82203"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>subject to subsection (b), revise the series referred to in paragraph (1), as appropriate, to reflect factors impacting the Federal Railroad Administration’s oversight of the railroad industry, including—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H4BD33B1BCF134D93AE2D2A6A5602B821">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>current critical Federal Railroad Administration disciplines; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD7C7EE8D8C9481395FD862326C4FFD6"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>technological advancements and operational conditions within the railroad industry.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H5FB71998E0E6421CB144BEB3F11F8AA2">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>Report</header>
 <text>Not later than 30 days after completing the review required under subsection (a), if the Director determines that a revision of the Railroad Safety Series is not appropriate, the Director shall submit a report to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that—</text>
          <paragraph id="H2214F59B1E44419780BC47EE860F25FE">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>explains the findings of the review required under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H22508FAF59F543C889667E6C627BABE4"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>justifies the determination not to make revisions to the Railroad Safety Series.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="H47AC48327E2C4EDC90D4743C9A9CCFC7"><enum>117.</enum><header>Alcohol and drug testing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend part 219 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to require any employee who, on behalf of a railroad, inspects locomotives, passenger cars, railcars, or other on-track equipment, to be subject to the breath or body fluid testing required under subparts C, D, and E of such part.</text></section> <section id="HC158CAC49D1A4C768BEBA8CC895E80D1"><enum>118.</enum><header>Confidential close call reporting system</header> <subsection id="H7113405943D44D53AF6F9038C32AE74B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for close call reporting system</header><text>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall jointly ensure that any close call reporting system carried out by such Administrators provides for the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HAC218110D39344D5B936742BA81BCA54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each report of a close call event made to such reporting system shall be confidential.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADB1F0691A9046E09593F4FAD02B3854"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual submitting a report to such system may include an audio or video file that was captured on the personal device of such individual.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H07F6957ED5A84E1BB3551A5DEA41FA09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Each report submitted to such system shall contain the location of the event, including, as applicable, the global positioning system coordinates of such event.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F42F6A8C1E548168831D67A51DB3770"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A report with respect to any craft shall be eligible for submission to such system.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5D34CA2E349D446CBD36DB484506F7A1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration may take a remedial action or an action to improve safety, or require a railroad to take an action, based solely on a report or a subset of reports submitted to the system.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H718CD19E8CAE4F5CA70E90E05A0B9C5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of close call reporting to amtrak</header><text>Each Class I railroad and Amtrak shall, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, enroll in the confidential close call reporting system for a period of 2 years.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6635AF7749714D96814A27605BBA4DE1">
        <enum>119.</enum>
        <header>AskRail application</header>
        <subsection id="HBB7E44743DCF42E381FF9A2E6E6B4537">
          <enum>(a)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>In order to be eligible for financial assistance under section 22907 or 24911 of title 49, United States Code, a State department of transportation shall notify first responders about the AskRail application, if a Class 1 railroad operates within the State, not later than 180 days after receiving such financial assistance.</text>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H3113378E9761462BB208B5A93C064483">
          <enum>(b)</enum>
          <header>FRA notification</header>
 <text>If a State is subject to subsection (a), each State department of transportation shall submit to the Federal Rail Administration—</text>
          <paragraph id="H20E88CDC8199442CAEE445CB94D1295D">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>evidence of the notification required under such subsection; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CB1C97481FB461CA5A7873EEE0C560E"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>a certification that such State has completed the requirement.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection id="H6D90E9596644473C8F840DAC2330E620">
          <enum>(c)</enum>
          <header>AskRail connectivity pilot program</header>
          <paragraph id="HA1AB8235BCB74302ADC6E8AE85827D49">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Establishment</header>
 <text>The Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall establish a pilot program to support connectivity for the AskRail application for first responders during railway accidents.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HDFA847707C664AFD872DF5AA6B833A2B">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Consultation</header>
 <text>In carrying out this subsection, the Administrator, the Federal Communications Commission, and the Department of Agriculture, in consultation with the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, shall identify and prioritize areas along the national rail network in most need of connectivity.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HBFEFD21D959B4811B786A6E7179DB31E">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Pilot program requirements</header>
 <text>In carrying out the pilot program required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HA5919D1F4A854BEC84C4B134369397DE">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, solicit proposals from entities or coalitions of entities to conduct activities under the pilot program; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H9E3C42697B29419DA66A96133B75EF0C">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>enter into cooperative agreements with at least 1 but not more than 4 entities to undertake activities under the pilot program, which may include past performance and experience with—</text>
              <clause id="H11B9D0C83E3D46B4AE3C59EC3C19A300">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>deploying connectivity technology and infrastructure in rural and remote locations, including satellite broadband technology, supplemental coverage from space, or fixed wireless technology; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HF8918F6A4C404E9DABABC5E635872696">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>contracting with emergency response providers, including Federal, State, and local governmental and nongovernmental emergency public safety, fire, law enforcement, emergency response, emergency medical (including hospital emergency facilities), and related personnel, agencies, and authorities.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HDC366A46AC444F389E5E03CAB154CA9C">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Activities</header>
 <text>In carrying out the pilot program required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall contract with eligible entities to provide broadband internet access service, fixed wireless technology or supplemental coverage from space.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4E3D6C4DCE244EF09E2BD004BD16DBE5">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Eligibility</header>
 <text>An eligible entity to carry out activities under the pilot program includes—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HBBAB5421DB72475EA2914A6665419217">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a broadband internet access service provider;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC25C080298AE4D3DA9D9F67375357984"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a satellite internet provider; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HF9FDD262E9214821A2B22261DD7EC18D">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a provider of supplemental coverage from space or fixed wireless technology.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H8821F82C2AE24703985062BDD823934B">
            <enum>(6)</enum>
            <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $25,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2029, to remain available until expended.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H1BFEC53E3CF54E54AAC1FBB0549D98D1">
            <enum>(7)</enum>
            <header>Report to congress</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the conclusion of the pilot program, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HC08855BF68BE48AE8092FC92B17D8B92">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the effectiveness and usage of the technologies or infrastructure utilized and deployed in such program;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H7E48227EBB814EA4A17FA7B75E9AA109">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>recommendations about their suitability for deployment across further portions of the national rail network; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAD79730816FA4436BFE788DA086239C2">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>recommendations to update grant priorities and eligibility guidance for administering railway safety Federal grant and loan programs to encourage investing in and modernizing emergency communications capabilities, including satellite internet providers, fixed wireless technology, and the nationwide public safety broadband network, as defined in section 6001 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1401">47 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
<section id="HE3FE97FF7EB24B389EE1566112CA6774"><enum>120.</enum><header>Increased funding for the railroad crossing elimination grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 22104(a) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H18BB83123CBA4EF49F564B6B714FF73D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H378B7E7FC61E45808FE6A40E33034B05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HA1838053F0A342AA85A2E25658A19F3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for grants under section 22909 of title 49, United States Code, $1,500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA37F38BAD3524F38900EDC31980BE3A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Summary required</header><text>In order to be eligible for the funds authorized under paragraph (1), a State department of transportation shall submit to the Federal Railroad Administration a summary of the most dangerous grade crossings in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H01428949AEED45F8BF97A7B1BECDDA90"><enum>121.</enum><header>Train approach warning</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate or update such regulations as are necessary to require that all railroads provide warning equipment to railroad watchmen and lookouts for roadway workers that—</text>
<paragraph id="H0396140CF21D4CFDB41BFF55162670D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include whistles, air horns, white disks or red flags, or lanterns; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF938BBFFD0654DBCBC3B4FEF0C5CCBFB"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>may only include the use of a verbal warning if a single worker receiving such warning is within arm's reach of the individual issuing such warning.</text>
        </paragraph></section></title>
<title id="HB1D424B7D26F4FC0A1E176D6FA8B0ABF"><enum>II</enum><header>HAZARDOUS MATERIALS EMERGENCY RESPONSE AND PREPAREDNESS</header>
<section id="HB3032B8D051C4F4BBB01A1A81BC09B72"><enum>201.</enum><header>Hazardous materials registration fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5108(g) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H61ECB65DD5AF4217AE0BF60FD4CB6FE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>(1) The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H1B0033A528A24D3F803EA99014763FE4" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HE47E9BC5286B4A969E4D28180C8A7971"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H290E8B9A54344FD990EE53F20F2B9691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H869513CCD1AF4EB99DB33F851723B278"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>(C) The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H30D907BAB74642D68AAC61970133576B" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H84AA50EFC7044AD380F37C029A8F0F20"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Transfer and deposit</header><text>The Secretary</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8DC48BEEE2144B11B24680741D2C6647"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>(B) The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H07599791E2324AD8ADFCEE8B1A6171C9" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC3354F6705E1453E8CEFA8697F74330B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text>The Secretary</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8007A7F4BE2D4690ACF3FAFF86ADF385"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(2)(A) In addition</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end of clause (ix) of subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAC601C71C0B4489AA4F259186390CA34" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0A26D3C77D404D9F934E4976E2060F11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual fee</header> <subparagraph id="H8D2DAF4ABF1D44B69313758DB07A4815"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>In addition to a fee established under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall establish and impose by regulation and collect an annual fee.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC68ECAB9FFBD4BE09EE4F7F5372048A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), the fee established under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text> <clause id="H861701CE258B4BE08B395762D977C0E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least $250 but not more than $500 from each person that—</text>
<subclause id="HB0E624686DB9404A9319320017A3A9C7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is required to file a registration statement under this section; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H33D9DAD91EE84B78AAEF2820B5167048"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is identified as a small business (within the meaning of part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)); and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H21D12A3F98604BE7BA253B24D2A69501"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least $500 but not more than $5,000 from each person that—</text> <subclause id="H912A6C2062CA4FBDAEB5BD426FB714F6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is required to file a registration statement under this section; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H65770ABDF426415FAE4B3D7436222163"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not identified as a small business (within the meaning of part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H5A4A2008EBE745D0B471680BA82035F4"><enum>202.</enum><header>Virtual training options</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5115(b)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H092A546D7B3446D794E6F46AFA9BAB94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CD2AE78671049CE879237E8AF4D5A5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H478476521C0D4B7FB8169E80681C9760" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H0767DCDE6BF940179F20AA0D4606C593"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for the development of courses described in subparagraph (B) that have been adapted for virtual learning and any courses for which the Secretary has recommended adaptation to provide virtual options, subject to the condition that the Secretary ensures that the virtual options recommended will provide an equivalent level of training as in-person courses; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HF97FB613524A4448A956D465B7291A79"><enum>203.</enum><header>Hazardous materials transportation emergency response and preparedness grants</header> <subsection id="H50B21F66C9FD46179239BBBFA430DA95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5116 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HFC2CF3F9B70B4B41918E6B3CB5F8DB91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the section designation and heading and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HC53F6FB6A643488E8A724981F2F13F30" style="USC"> <section id="HF81338E74C2B481286B43F61E6009087"><enum>5116.</enum><header>Hazardous materials transportation emergency response and preparedness</header></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30084FB25D2D4A128E4AA42665BF31E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE4B0E6E30ABE4BB292409DFCBC743B63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H7F0215EC154341898A1ACBB82222908B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></clause>
<clause id="H6BF723FC4E26448CB5A0DB6CDEDECF16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subclause id="H6DE274D89DFB48D7876802D2450BC29F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>public sector employees</quote> and inserting <quote>emergency response personnel</quote>; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H153A161E1DFE4D30A6B6A36358533DB5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE1A008B214494A88B2C26AFA20FC3943"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H7DC70F6505044C70873186D104F2BDDE" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H2A54A534D80A4CAEB5F6696EBDE81002"><enum>(D)</enum><text>until September 31, 2026, to purchase personal protective equipment, as determined by the Secretary, needed to respond to a hazardous materials emergency response incident, consistent with paragraph (7) and subject to the condition that not more than 50 percent of the funds made available under this subsection may be used for that purpose;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51E2477A13FB4233A6ABB6CB3E41D7AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to conduct and organize simulated and field exercises relating to hazardous materials transportation incidents; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD7D81D80997A4CC1A51C5E47AA255057"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to develop a hazardous materials transportation emergency response preparedness gap analysis in accordance with paragraph (9).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA939AF3F4904BC59E63F578DC40DE8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A)—</text>
<clause id="HE3CEE33D493B456394ED3EAE7B440E5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>public sector employees being trained</quote> and inserting <quote>emergency response personnel being trained virtually or in person</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HE347549E594945E8B417CE276EAC2325"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>employees</quote> and inserting <quote>personnel</quote>;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC510C0293F3443558C48BF41778ADC1F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii)—</text> <subclause id="HA7F4855C1B6A4EA6A7276A372030457A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>employees</quote> and inserting <quote>personnel</quote>; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE1966D10DE5A415B863ECFF17F988626"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA89DCC9C01BB400D9E80713F5D34C155"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H0D1B4F5CD6E446B5871B9F9483D02308" style="OLC">
<clause id="H844275A7A19249DCA64AB2378C2B141F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to cover the costs of personnel needed to replace any personnel being trained; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8FC56008DB5A47B3B27F473FEED00A7D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to cover lost wages for any volunteer being trained, up to a reasonable amount determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H56BCF2A8A3774DE383D0933946901AFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text> <clause id="H77BFDACE4DA4476F898F92CB07686384"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HF1C8000ECA404FD296891756D93792FB" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="HB149F32667EB4E2AB63C0E3CC336970E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether grant funds will be used to support the ability of the United States to respond to hazardous materials incidents near infrastructure commonly used to transport hazardous materials;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H1D706E345F5C4C419FB652A1FFA2F041"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>amounts</quote> and inserting <quote>number of shipments</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1D012A9693F446CCA1C013EE2CFE611D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) and (6) as paragraphs (6) and (8), respectively;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67070768F5D64B219A29EA4DC19CB728"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H76A3D0448A384385B6F0BC8E6DD7A3C7" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HBA3D4087AC204930B3DC462AF59E8236"><enum>(5)</enum>
<subparagraph id="H9E5B864A3A4C4D1D918E930216461F64" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), any State receiving a grant under this subsection shall, not later than 180 days after receiving the grant funds, make available to eligible local entities—</text> <clause id="H9FC9495ED02B43EA91B18BA044F4DAD2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 70 percent of the grant funds; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H38A0D5479D2147408407B628803FE221"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>eligible services or activities described in paragraph (1) having a value of not less than 70 percent of the amount of the grant.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19ED0C2C976C4B1D9EFC61B909B8E4B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A State shall certify to the Secretary that the State has made the distribution to eligible local entities required under paragraph (1) by providing such information as the Secretary shall require.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1F413AD1B239459BABA2830C527ACD7C"><enum>(C)</enum>
<clause id="H075F2E246D1A4CF481A1A62EDA3726F4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Governor of a State may request in writing that the Secretary extend the period under subparagraph (A) for an additional period of time.</text></clause> <clause id="H538CF6DD90FC48CAAC1774B29459BDD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary may approve a request under clause (i) if the Secretary determines that the delay in providing grant funding to eligible local entities pursuant to the extension is necessary to promote effective investments to prepare for or respond to hazardous materials transportation incidents.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA4EEC04BA80F40FE8DFF838ADDC2028F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to Tribes, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, or the Virgin Islands.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B2F8A8DE6544761AE64069957836D81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An eligible local entity may petition the Secretary to request that grant funds be provided by the Secretary directly to the eligible local entity if a State fails to apply for a grant under this subsection.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFE76D5F5C072424DAF908FD42AA3579D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>In making grant funds available to eligible local entities under subparagraph (A), States shall consider whether the eligible local entity has a high proportion of volunteer emergency responders.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H401CED4F9A034860B02C08C0FA7E4733"> <enum>(G)</enum> <text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>eligible local entity</quote> means each of the following:</text>
                    <clause id="H80D783B37E364B11932CCD14C0341B19">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>A political subdivision of a State.</text> </clause> <clause id="H29C2E823A9CE441181AAB8642B6256A2"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>A public emergency response organization.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FD8F77879344B0599A63D1F7756C3E8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H40DDA5DD423A43269D4E9B2C71EC03D4" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H881CE15A1BCB4F629F50971475FF4EF0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A recipient of funds provided under this subsection may use the funds to purchase personal protective equipment only if the recipient agrees to properly maintain and store that personal protective equipment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H53616913F8A643B5B4E2DB67C56FA0AF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (8) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H6C12DA2C693B4CE0984704B1CE3F072F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0350C330D83D4C5985150DC9309031D6"><enum>(9)</enum> <subparagraph id="H881E1B85CCEB46C79A0176CC3E8DA205" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each hazardous materials transportation emergency response preparedness gap analysis shall include—</text>
<clause id="HDE437B94F9DF41B59AB462C19CD0704E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of gaps and limitations of the hazard response program of the applicable jurisdiction, including—</text> <subclause id="H29580790C8E147BA8A43ABB8FE530514"><enum>(I)</enum><text>knowledge and personal protective equipment gaps; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H81449890AC204496B93750EA9606920D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>gaps in training, including Incident Command Management training and ASTM Standard E3241 training; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HCC0C635195EE49B2850EE361EE8A8536"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a strategic plan to address the gaps and limitations identified under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB98B2B803AB945C6AF376898555FFBC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In developing a hazardous materials transportation emergency response preparedness gap analysis under subparagraph (A), the entity preparing the analysis shall—</text> <clause id="H30ED15654A094C7A975E61F2B67B9939"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coordinate with Regional Response Teams (as described in section 300.115 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation));</text></clause>
<clause id="H536C3F0A60C74B2B8E54C58EA387F346"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include States, Tribes, hazardous materials emergency response programs, local governments, and emergency response personnel (including fire service organizations) in that development, as appropriate; and</text></clause> <clause id="H888AFF6EF09C4C829BC79A89B576EF05"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for States, Tribes, hazardous materials emergency response programs, local governments, and emergency response personnel (including fire service organizations) to review and comment on the analysis before the analysis is published.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H35FC76D8BF07413E93614F7C6569023D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H06C13E929A9043F58F11DC7113893A34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Amounts</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H0E75E105B7AD4632910C64A7BE536874" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H61BE88757AED4EBC8F11616EDAC748DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain amounts</header><text>Amounts</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H163A80CB812C42589E58BBA934D4282B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>A grant under this section is for 80 percent of the cost the State or Indian tribe incurs</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H93BAE0B972D44EE885C1B7231E2C1F7E" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H19DE5A97055F4DDF8CB6ABA8ECF786D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant under this section is for 90 percent of the costs incurred by a State, or 100 percent of the costs incurred by a Tribe,</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61E601DB64304E15B6D32E0D515FCEA0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H1C96FADD62684EB289776948CD7AF349" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H1CCE8DAFF5954A1D98017E30F6B3BD91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>In-kind contributions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the contributions of a State or Tribe toward the costs of an activity funded by a grant under this section may be in the form of in-kind contributions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DB1FD04C98C4C38964405E98FB1DD9B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA017493E4618418D84BF276145765F53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the second sentence—</text> <clause id="H15311C9B6AE04498ACFD3F2AD3781DF3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>4 percent</quote>;</text></clause>
<clause id="H6970F83442B24E4BAE466DB42F3A5857"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (4) as subparagraphs (A) through (D), respectively, and indenting appropriately; and</text></clause> <clause id="H76B1C88986044D52B956A30AF614C65A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>Without</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H87DB832AEA814A6E8CC88F4531184DF3" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HC2D0FF8995EF4BA8A552261A78D5ACEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>Without</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H293DA6DBBCAD48EC8937FFB60B530E07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text>
<clause id="H693125FB06F44FFDBFF4F25070B12F62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 5108(g)(2)(C) of this title</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5108(g)(2)(D)</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA0E448FCBA0545C4A7F6E065FE056EF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H8D26E05825A94F4A8AE1527DA692A2BC" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H487A2F1F612D4F7B974ED4EC4C105BEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H984EA0C3BFFC4BCC9E06031E53C115B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H9FDE849826DB445FB14CC7191DB3065E" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H81482982B7254BC392D7E6BC1A297546"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Set aside</header>
<subparagraph id="H59A906F49D394B4680C6210F06B6246F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amounts collected under section 5123—</text> <clause id="H3567DD7574D448D59ED4EEC45E3A41DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be set aside for the purpose of carrying out subsection (k); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HF3B1AD96594C4E798583DB6BA81977B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be available, without further appropriation, for that purpose.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DB3D8139F0E4F0DB04888F38D8465EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The set-aside described in subparagraph (A)—</text>
<clause id="HF659105C0AD44395BEBF8814E082E49A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall apply until the earliest date on which the total amount set aside and available for expenditure under that subparagraph equals or exceeds $50,000,000; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8B95939799654B66B33EDBBD4471626B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after that date, shall apply to each subsequent period—</text>
<subclause id="HF8EB8C16F0B94ECF9A3E07E57A1A2D2A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning on a date on which the total amount set aside and available for expenditure under that subparagraph is less than $20,000,000; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF6F0DEC346DD403F90D9333B5DCB664A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ending on the earliest subsequent date on which the total amount set aside and available for expenditure under that subparagraph equals or exceeds $50,000,000.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD38D13E46324ED7B2962333033DBE09"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (k)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1ACD6E34CA4748A4A4CE50CA851672A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>such planning and training programs</quote> and inserting <quote>each grant program</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9907A4E44B23402CBEB6817C85C54AAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (4) as subparagraphs (A), (B), (D), and (E), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75258900462042DC9DF0113A41127D80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) (as so redesignated) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H80C7769222A84E448CB92B0BA1E2FDA1" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H3D900CBA54614A7D862ECDDFFB9547B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of any personal protective equipment purchased using grant funds;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED3D7D7A1DA244B38ADB2926C878666D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) (as so redesignated)—</text>
<clause id="H1BD84FBB4CF94F19AD936A4728247CD3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>an annual report</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H527B8896E00C4B83904C93B2D6B16640"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the report to the public</quote> in the first sentence and all that follows through <quote>grants and include—</quote> in the third sentence and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H22CE8D24D584455DBF7D2DB6FE51FCD1" style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the public an annual report that—</text> <paragraph id="H1EE430AF775D43F18E0BEA7E13EDD3F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes information on the allocation and uses of the grants made available under—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCB4A46D54E1D4318AA57D38A4A91DD9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A1D3086928441C0B870A8912E14C5B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsections (e) and (i) of section 5107;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C12F12BCD674BFCB80CCC015D5E8AB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifies the ultimate recipients of those grants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEB02D5C830240588E7C201EF37EE45A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies the amount of funding available for each grant;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDDAAF8E5A1DE44428484C78F8946670B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describes any unobligated balances, total annual drawdown by each grantee, and recovered balances;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50F75D5D761043008AB7DF17B0F9D19F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>includes the amount of funding rescinded, by grant recipient, for each grant; and</text></paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="H95EEE087716D479FA7F3DA05994919C5">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>includes—</text> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H073B484FC6A94CC3809D4ABA9AA72757"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by striking <quote>tribe</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Tribe</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDC8F110A3E7B49388906290C7440B7DD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by striking <quote>tribes</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Tribes</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0EBFF9EB6152438F92CF9523801D81D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance for local emergency response training</header><text>Section 5116(j)(1)(A) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>liquids</quote> and inserting <quote>materials</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H942A47B38E0844C983FA9342B3FFAC39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Section 5128(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB00545BF1CD6434382EF34FC103326CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Hazardous Materials Preparedness Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>Hazardous Materials Emergency Preparedness Fund</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBC3FF5957F1F4784A10B97AB79BD1169"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>section 5116(h)(3); and</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5116(h)(2)(C);</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A46745CD8244B858EA710D607621D1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H5BEF627B3C1548D089639272AB107CFA" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H5F2638990A4B4C2ABF7184C9B2578A4D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$4,000,000 to carry out section 5116(i); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H668800BA7B3D479295674F8E13D18EEB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$1,000,000 to carry out section 5116(j).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB25C6DAFE782439693E7DAA2396E0F49"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 5116 and inserting the following: <quote>5116. Hazardous materials transportation emergency response and preparedness.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67BFC4C87D374AEBAEFD7871AC3F55C2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HCCA7A9932A6E4EAEBA7F83222F8037DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 5102 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraph (6) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H4A64068C2DCF4968B12EAA4C4505FA9E" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HD617B7BE3E67482581176F00B88BB8C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text><quote>Indian tribe</quote>, <quote>Indian Tribe</quote>, and <quote>Tribe</quote> have the meaning given the term <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CC8AC49A49E45B6B31868BB64C6D7AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 5123 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (g) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H53A46DEFDB1C4C139AF304102E894D25" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H31C6363FC3B34ED98D7FDC611ADCC5EA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transfer of amounts collected</header><text>Amounts collected under this section shall be transferred to the Hazardous Materials Emergency Preparedness Fund established under section 5116(h).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H70776C5EF9CC4C23A839CFC4FD9A6A13"><enum>204.</enum><header>Emergency response assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5116 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H67388FDEE7C945E39A899FB8C638303D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (k) as subsection (l);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68B84DB22D9B4A52B33DEA3D9197B38C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (j) the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H11E4D94FB4FA4223A20E3B4577700809" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H1BB01A94FF4841E992D8D1B881E7462D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Emergency response assistance</header>
<paragraph id="HE7CB577E2CE84F6F8578ABA61F07F57C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H3723CBBCDF034287925CCBEA9BF35F7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Significant hazardous materials transportation incident</header><text>The term <quote>significant hazardous materials transportation incident</quote> means an incident that—</text>
<clause id="H10887749AD59407D837AB10AD7D9D21D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves hazardous materials being moved by a motor carrier or rail carrier;</text></clause> <clause id="HB61F3FA38ADA4304B6A74E69F83FF56C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requires a response by at least 1 eligible entity described in paragraph (6) for which the Secretary estimates the costs to the eligible entity to be at least $15,000; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA50BAE41B7CF46DDBCECDD2C7979836E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>results in a serious injury, fatality, or substantial property damage.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7AED792877945C5AF7D189AA72B4A42"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Substantial property damage</header><text>The term <quote>substantial property damage</quote> means damage to public or private property or the environment (including clean up costs) the Secretary reasonably estimates to be more than $45,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBBB23583500E47C9BFBC48D711F58DF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Railroad Safety Enhancement Act of 2026, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, after providing an opportunity for notice and comment, shall establish an emergency response assistance program to provide immediate financial assistance to communities responding to a significant hazardous materials transportation incident.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6B28BF818E74806893F62F8A42798BC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Significant hazardous materials transportation incident</header> <subparagraph id="H785761A779D349AE93D53ACE72F5DB3B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall have the authority to declare a significant hazardous materials transportation incident.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HACA63174F4324DBCBA658F858D4F7E80"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and publish guidelines to determine whether a significant hazardous materials transportation incident has occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A6456E9DA6F4DFE8B469ACC78991C76"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Release of funds</header> <subparagraph id="H4854E53B4B1D4BC1811A8AE588D5FE55"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall immediately make available from the amount set aside under subsection (h)(3) in the Hazardous Materials Emergency Preparedness Fund established under subsection (h)(1) (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Fund</quote>) up to $10,000,000 to quickly reimburse eligible entities described in paragraph (6) that responded to a significant hazardous materials transportation incident if—</text>
<clause id="HC3EC57352C4F4C83ACF1F1C7104D7181"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary declares the incident a significant hazardous materials transportation incident; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1D3BE18064174750BF18CFFD2AB17DAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least 14 days but not later than 21 days after the declaration of a significant hazardous materials transportation incident, the Secretary determines, in accordance with paragraph (8), that the responsible party does not have an acceptable reimbursement plan.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD4A2DBC099AF49CBBDAF644E2F119FE4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional funds</header><text>In addition to any amounts made available under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall make additional funding available from the amount set aside under subsection (h)(3) in the Fund if the Secretary determines that the additional funding is necessary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4B6D3F1CED74A59B44DDE4090560E6E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary may make funds available under this subsection if the Secretary determines the responsible party is not complying with its acceptable plan under paragraph (8).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2015083429564B6A93A88BE44CDAE1C0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administration of funds</header><text>The Secretary may provide funds from the amount set aside under subsection (h)(3) in the Fund to a State in which a hazardous materials transportation incident occurred for the State to use and administer reimbursements in accordance with this subsection, including by providing funds to eligible entities described in paragraph (6).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42D1F42B6E31473B8AA9FBD82B32BAD5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible entities described</header><text>The eligible entities referred to in paragraphs (4)(A) and (5) are—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFDE3695F2D70413E9D9F47598D4DAB99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>States, territories, and Tribes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79735711D017434FB2B0363A7AD4BC64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>political subdivisions of a State or territory; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2B284D373038431BAD3B167E0CDACDBE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>public emergency response organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D96D4C9FD06407B8B84E93A8BA17EEF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <subparagraph id="HA11C2DCB471C4CC1A4B4CD65814C6F85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Funds made available under paragraph (4) or (5) may be used only—</text>
<clause id="H1D15D8B3E13E4179B4C44EFA66C5755F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the cost of replacing personal protective equipment that is damaged, contaminated, or otherwise rendered unusable as a result of the response of the eligible entity to a significant hazardous materials transportation incident;</text></clause> <clause id="H80D05FFE8E06490C9EC9300002D8917C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for overtime pay of employees of eligible entities that responded to the scene of a significant hazardous materials transportation incident;</text></clause>
<clause id="HFE922F43A2244561959E247123A7203D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for operational costs exceeding standard operating expenses that are directly related to the cost of responding to the significant hazardous materials transportation incident, such as the costs of running a supplementary emergency response center;</text></clause> <clause id="H0760023650714519B6E72F3F30614878"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for the cost of providing baseline health care assessments to emergency response personnel who responded to the significant hazardous materials transportation incident, but not more than $1,000 per person, which shall be adjusted annually for inflation; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3C8CB46F6FCD434AAA2E327324383E1D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to reimburse an eligible entity for an eligible cost described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) that is incurred within 30 days of the date of a significant hazardous materials transportation incident.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD9EEF77CDCD4E709E4745C69ECD13E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Documentation of costs</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary declares a significant hazardous materials transportation incident for which an eligible entity receives assistance under this subsection, the eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary documentation for each item for which that assistance was used pursuant to the eligible uses of funds described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1227F30923F6408281429C1D88643C5E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Misuse of funds</header><text>If the Secretary determines that an eligible entity has used assistance received under this subsection in a manner that violates subparagraph (A) or any other provision of this subsection, the eligible entity shall reimburse the Fund (if the assistance was provided from the Fund) or the responsible party (if the assistance was provided by the responsible party), for the amount of that assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDB623471626405C9CC6970F3522EFE1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Acceptable plan</header> <subparagraph id="HA0B99E83F5854DA4AA4E8C6D34F317A0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (4)(A)(ii), the Secretary shall consider a reimbursement plan of a responsible party to be acceptable if the plan seeks to review and process claims made by eligible entities for the costs described in paragraph (7) not later than 90 days after the date of the significant hazardous materials transportation incident.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9DDDEB3C00A247AC884A31C98449B801"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Advance submission; certain plans</header>
<clause id="H7562F64DBC95482384ADBFDC0C3FA16A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Advance submission</header><text>A plan to provide reimbursement to eligible entities in accordance with subparagraph (A) may be submitted to the Secretary for approval in advance of any significant hazardous materials transportation incident to which the plan might apply.</text></clause> <clause id="H2C87380ED07444F196E91F58DFC075DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain plan</header><text>A hazardous materials emergency response plan approved by the Secretary in accordance with section 20155(e) shall be considered an acceptable plan for purposes of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE613E1A7D0F74BE9AED366AA79B2980D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Reimbursement by responsible party</header>
<subparagraph id="H18879B89C3ED41639D9EE7BFA7493669"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (F), the party responsible for a significant hazardous materials transportation incident shall be liable to the Secretary for reimbursement of all amounts disbursed from the Fund under this subsection for that significant hazardous materials transportation incident.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49EBD8769D204292B69C9A1FDBFB57EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any funding recovered by the Secretary under this subsection shall be deposited back into the Fund.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD50F8F25391840B58E02D12804CB694A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>After the Secretary has received the documented costs under paragraph (7)(B), the Secretary shall provide notice to the responsible party regarding the total amount owed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E026A6C5B484CB4A39D8F1E1FA3E3EF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Final agency action</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the Secretary makes a determination of the amount for which the responsible party is liable under subparagraph (A), the responsible party may challenge that determination as a final agency action.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H61484F07B9584C4C90A9D71673107D6E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Civil action</header>
<clause id="H6508525E650642B2AD173A346CB36D5B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States to collect unpaid amounts under this paragraph and any accrued interest on those amounts.</text></clause> <clause id="HF5FCDAB42CD54C4BBBF22F6127E79656"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on judicial review</header><text>In a civil action under clause (i), the amount for which a responsible party is liable, as determined by the Secretary, unless challenged under subparagraph (D), shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H38AE5605E2184FCFAD05CEB2495E9DBF"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Discretion</header><text>If the responsible party is a small business concern (within the meaning of part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)) that is unable to fully reimburse the Secretary, the Secretary shall have discretion with respect to the amount of funds the Secretary requests from the responsible party under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54014E476D564499A348F133100F9AFC"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Streamlined application process</header><text>The Secretary shall streamline the application process for the receipt of funds under this subsection, including by—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE6DEB1998FF443B8B6911EF5361E421B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to eligible entities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB581813056F4EC399A579088A3EB252"><enum>(B)</enum><text>creating a template that eligible entities can use to apply for funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H14E2203BD99D4A478617171A8F5E3689"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Savings provisions</header>
<subparagraph id="HCF3CC56DC907495099B408079706D8EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits, or may be construed to limit, the liability of a responsible party.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED399CCB1D2E42888A0FB8526098D566"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header> <clause id="HB346534C9F6B4CC3850CC097703D81BE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A responsible party may, in accordance with any other applicable law—</text>
<subclause id="H8A082A0E765946EDBA237804D2BAB85A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>seek to establish that another party was responsible, in whole or in part (as such other law allows), for the applicable significant hazardous materials transportation incident; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB085C4CEB3B843A2A73937C995EDDF57"><enum>(II)</enum><text>seek reimbursement (to the extent such other law allows) from that other party.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HE76454160634483A972EC25002DF5595"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of subsection</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits, or may be construed to limit, the ability of a responsible party to seek reimbursement from any other party found to be responsible in any civil action arising from the applicable significant hazardous materials transportation incident.</text></clause> <clause id="HD7D909507DEA4D5A98F694043B3F4C2C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effect of determination</header><text>A determination by the Secretary that a party is a responsible party for purposes of this subsection shall not be considered or otherwise have any effect with respect to the determination of liability in any civil action described in clause (ii).</text></clause>
<clause id="H83F441B7D9784026932B43E3252EC140"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Effect of reimbursements and other activities</header><text>No activity taken under this subsection to reimburse an eligible entity, reimburse the Secretary, prepare or carry out a reimbursement plan, or otherwise comply with or make a payment under this subsection shall be considered or otherwise have any effect with respect to the determination of liability in any civil action described in clause (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BE17FC86945436D9BD162DAD93015B8"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Comptroller general report</header> <subparagraph id="HA632022623B24AD1905DD70CB430EF60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2027, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the effectiveness this subsection.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H191C1E7CA0A44EE1AB5FEB04F4008709"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include, at a minimum, information on—</text> <clause id="H889456348B1E45DFADC297184C3F1C15"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of significant hazardous materials transportation incidents that received funding under this subsection;</text></clause>
<clause id="H6DFFCCFAF14F495BB1EB83F2605185B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of financial assistance the Secretary provided to eligible entities;</text></clause> <clause id="HF6B79604CBFF46AC8A48A5A7E3137244"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of financial assistance responsible parties submitted to the Secretary under paragraph (9);</text></clause>
<clause id="H3D287C5CCFCE41BA97AF73D1F39B2CC4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the amount of reimbursement the Secretary received from eligible entities as required under paragraph (7)(C);</text></clause> <clause id="HD36F19C7DD1E47A29D9746E21A6AF056"><enum>(v)</enum><text>whether the amounts provided by the Secretary under this subsection adequately reflect the amounts actually spent by the eligible entities;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF596D48C99A64F35AA82F3E24EDD30B4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>whether the Secretary was able to provide the financial assistance quickly enough to the eligible entities so that the assistance effectively supported the preparedness of the eligible entities to respond to potential future incidents; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2E1AB1BD4D214DBD9EF2CF3312A8B4F0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other factors the Comptroller General of the United States considers to be appropriate to review the effectiveness of this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H21B8E3D4AE014B06B185E9CE17F574C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H565AE5C523B04224855621F45A02D525" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HAAC8627153634319AB12EC138D89274F"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H7BFD462D5C004D8C8EF5BF7C05122757"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergency response personnel</header><text>The term <quote>emergency response personnel</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC65E66ADF9846D2B08BF37D6A558E7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee of a State, territory, Tribe, or political subdivision of a State; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8AAE96497F6E412887775964487A66FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person belonging to a public emergency response organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC41712CEE1E3495C9E695863BF1D1C76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public emergency response organization</header> <subparagraph id="HE1D6866EC811481DB39F2A907B45D0BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>public emergency response organization</quote> means—</text>
<clause id="H65AB95325C354B0BA140CEB8E9BBF91F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a fire department that has an all-paid force of firefighting personnel other than paid-on-call firefighters;</text></clause> <clause id="HF5A921B7446D4E25B17C9F331393883D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a fire department that has—</text>
<subclause id="HDB016E9AA1C94C098483A0E48840634B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>paid firefighting personnel; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8AE3FA67E8C64D4F91A4D428F8AB77F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>volunteer firefighting personnel;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H0D72456A9B0F4888B89A6BC7F4142F72"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a nonaffiliated EMS organization; and</text></clause> <clause id="H79CB3F11026E4F889C10DF6683B362A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a fire department that has an all-volunteer force of firefighting personnel.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D67847C397643148A9B2FC2078D8730"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Associated definition</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii), the term <quote>nonaffiliated EMS organization</quote> means a public or private nonprofit emergency medical services organization that—</text> <clause id="HBEF1F3543F894011A88B520A4569F93C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not affiliated with a hospital; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H953D3BB5FD1547F5902828B6E91069F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not serve a geographic area for which the Secretary or a State finds that emergency medical services are adequately provided by a fire department.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title> </legis-body></bill>

