<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25214-6CM-48-VSN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 SRES 500 IS: Commemorating the centennial year of the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 500</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the centennial year of the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association (referred to in this preamble as <quote>ASHA</quote>) is the national professional, scientific, and credentialing association for 241,000 members, certificate holders, and affiliates who are—</text><paragraph id="id3c98c6b0bce24571bd9eedf68dac98fa" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>audiologists;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f21e182c4844e659e7dca90ffa104b4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">speech-language pathologists;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide143f4ca344e47efb392c672d351ebc2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">speech, language, and hearing scientists;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id886ae6d1991d4d6a9a4da06df5d51400"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">audiology and speech-language pathology assistants; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide803244144a94a1ebb0ba5c99914eec7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">students;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in its centennial year, ASHA remains steadfast in achieving its mission to—</text><paragraph id="id9148c8ea40694af984d983bb802edbd9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advance science;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a4250676d2a4bfbad7673358f6c46d3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foster excellence in education and professional practice; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7768c9ac1cd54d1199b09ac0d07156ec"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish standards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id081e9291884f42a7849eda8dff43bab8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advocate for accessible and quality care for all;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ASHA believes that effective communication is a human right and should be accessible and achievable for all;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ASHA led the path for licensing in all 50 States and the District of Columbia by setting the initial standards in the fields of practice for audiology and speech-language pathology to ensure consumer protections through State licensure;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ASHA’s commitment to promoting access to care and support for those with communications disorders is demonstrated through engaging in advocacy for laws, such as the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), the Steve Gleason Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/40">Public Law 114–40</external-xref>), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), the Early Hearing Detection and Intervention Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/241">Public Law 117–241</external-xref>), and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas people with communication disorders are frequently subjected to stigma that includes mockery, bullying, and myths that say they are of low intelligence and ability, which causes them to be wrongly underestimated and denied advancement at work and educationally, as well as isolated socially;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas communication disorders are among the most common conditions in children and adults in the United States, affecting tens of millions of individuals in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May is National Speech-Language-Hearing Month, which provides an opportunity to raise awareness about communication disorders and the professions of audiology and speech-language pathology; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ASHA looks to the future and how it can most effectively educate, support, and advocate for the audiologists and speech-language pathologists who are making a positive difference in the quality of life for millions of individuals in the United States, from infants to older adults: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id49edbaa7aee74224be42a5394bf97a44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association for 100 years of positive impact for people with communication disorders and work to advance the professions of audiology and speech-language pathology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id685a5f4b28d7440ca6e21a20846bc692"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commemorates the centennial year of the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

