<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H997F0FFD83704347B5CE8B2A2ABD0926" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6681 IH: National Scam Prevention Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name>Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name>the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name>Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Office of the National Fraud and Scam Prevention, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H44D4503E532242809F4CAE07F83E5ACA" style="OLC"><section id="HDD31468D874347E5886C8EFDDBE4C07E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Scam Prevention Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H805ED80FF5C743219E215682CAE6F536"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of the National Fraud and Scam Prevention</header><subsection id="H1843F1C15D98475EAF28B87EA706269A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established, within the Executive Office of the President, the Office of the National Fraud and Scam Prevention (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE714EAD900F343268730DEB9A5F207A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National fraud and scam prevention Director</header><paragraph id="H207399346BC14E7496905823ECA92D53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be headed by the National Fraud and Scam Prevention Director (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1D5FCD53CCC4C08A2F9243FE66D0B02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Position</header><text>The Director shall hold office at the pleasure of the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5911223AACB14A59A847D2B56B32E96A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pay and allowances</header><text>The Director shall be entitled to receive the rate of pay and allowances provided for positions under level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCFD4045A71049A791940A1C179F15EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of the Director</header><paragraph id="HC788175E14AE4B88A106A732F8370975"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the President, the Director shall—</text><subparagraph id="H74B9B8F347C24B3F9BC01A3F9DC6937F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as the principal advisor to the President on scam and fraud prevention policy and strategy relating to the coordination of—</text><clause id="HA3FCBB0BA151401884ABF18D13A317BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information sharing, security, and data protection;</text></clause><clause id="H687BE62C4726438789BA27B9BE676556"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>programs and policies intended to improve the fraud and scam prevention;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84B35D0C50B94402B28D23B56CBAE8B1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>posture of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H015BBD4E802648DFB6FE016AD3235828"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>efforts to understand and deter fraud and scams;</text></clause><clause id="HD6C1DDF4087E424EA0DA58C5E8BC3543"><enum>(v)</enum><text>diplomatic and other efforts to develop norms and international consensus around responsible state behavior in fraud and scam prevention;</text></clause><clause id="H21FEBABFC13C48FCB66E4079B3492C31"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>awareness and adoption of emerging technology that may enhance, augment, or degrade the fraud and scam prevention posture of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H43C45E7BB11949FF883DE948579DF198"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>efforts to educate the public on how to best prevent falling victim of fraud and scams; and</text></clause><clause id="H469C69EB9F4D4487AF280F964167844C"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>such other fraud and scam prevention matters as the President considers appropriate;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19A3619D7A504774A186350D1A016964" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a fraud data shield program allowing entities to share non-personally identifiable scam data with the Office;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37D3E77F6FD843C7AAC644DEA09F2214"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offer advice and consultation to the Domestic Policy Counsel in the White House and its staff, the Homeland Security Council and its staff, and relevant Federal departments and agencies, for their consideration, relating to the development and coordination of national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73C50EB3C1DE464E8B1DD42D6368C4D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lead the coordination of implementation of national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy by—</text><clause id="HBB1583B985C64693B9D925B947F86387"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in coordination with the heads of relevant Federal departments or agencies, monitoring and assessing the effectiveness, including cost-effectiveness, of the implementation of such national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy by Federal departments and agencies;</text></clause><clause id="HB7A96C7DCA6747369FFF20BE2BE3BF06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>making recommendations, relevant to changes in the organization, personnel, and resource allocation and to policies of Federal departments and agencies, to the heads of relevant Federal departments and agencies in order to implement such national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy;</text></clause><clause id="H5B946076C3144E9F83175B62C15CE413"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reviewing the annual budget proposals for relevant Federal departments and agencies and advising the heads of such departments and agencies whether such proposals are consistent with such national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy;</text></clause><clause id="HB739D0F675EB40F1AEA62C6FC1D274B6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>continuously assessing and making relevant recommendations to the President on the appropriate level of integration and interoperability across relevant Federal departments and agencies;</text></clause><clause id="HC5F8B9EC5EDD4F7C9CE2D84757DAFA07"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reporting annually to the President, the Assistant to the President for the Domestic Policy Counsel, and Congress on the state of the fraud and scam prevention posture of the United States, the effectiveness of such national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy, and the status of the implementation of such national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy by Federal departments and agencies; and</text></clause><clause id="H0E8E19543EAB4AF69037130310DCFE7F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>such other activity as the President considers appropriate to further such national fraud and scam prevention policy and strategy;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC24BD2C80E304EACB2475FCA5612EB92"><enum>(E)</enum><text>lead coordination of the development and ensuring implementation by the Federal Government of integrated incident response to fraud and scam campaigns of significant consequence, including—</text><clause id="H3AC31ADA1D9E4AFFA98AE952DE721CD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensuring and facilitating coordination among relevant Federal departments and agencies in the development of integrated operational plans, processes, and playbooks, including for incident response, that feature—</text><subclause id="HB65039C4E023414FB7E52C8849C89816"><enum>(I)</enum><text>clear lines of authority and lines of effort across the Federal Government;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7978E7CA1BA243C3B17F73690A9D50E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>authorities that have been delegated to an appropriate level to facilitate effective operational responses across the Federal Government; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAD3D3A621CB64869A21E9A67BBB798F5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>support for the integration of defensive fraud and scam prevention plans and capabilities with offensive fraud and scam plans and capabilities in a manner consistent with improving the fraud and scam prevention posture of the United States;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H36BAC827E1454E699B6CA5C28E885EBC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring the exercising of defensive operational plans, processes, and playbooks for incident response;</text></clause><clause id="HB6CC8336F60D4A1AA121D9142DD42131"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensuring the updating of defensive operational plans, processes, and playbooks for incident response as needed to keep them updated; and</text></clause><clause id="H8250777837D24E1291ED05A5808EE6AE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>reviewing and ensuring that defensive operational plans, processes, and playbooks improve coordination with relevant private sector entities, as appropriate;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22746ED1A7B6406E8382EDE1D03A9647"><enum>(F)</enum><text>preparing the response by the Federal Government to fraud and scam campaigns of significant consequence across Federal departments and agencies with responsibilities pertaining to fraud and scam prevention and with the relevant private sector entities, including—</text><clause id="H1477DE29DAF44CFCB8592CE67E597163"><enum>(i)</enum><text>developing for the approval of the President, in coordination with the heads of relevant Federal departments and agencies, operational priorities, requirements, and plans;</text></clause><clause id="H46738F34EC02476FB1C45EAC2585E2C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring incident response is executed consistent with the plans described in clause (i); and</text></clause><clause id="H7BD0D4F65C32444AA0A2F417ED8D1CE1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensuring relevant Federal department and agency consultation with relevant private sector entities in incident response;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE9F729A9ED24090A362FA19F47E8D59"><enum>(G)</enum><text>coordinate and consult with private sector leaders on fraud and scam prevention and emerging technology issues in support of, and in coordination with, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE7CCA21F89C4D7B940D499538D1B9DB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>annually report to Congress on fraud and scam threats and issues facing the United States, including any new or emerging technologies that may affect national security, economic prosperity, or enforcing the rule of law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB639A84243AA49BE8FB2AA1F0DDF0901"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance and strategic guidance to, without supplanting, existing interagency task forces; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H650E42A34C034D79932DB17597C8E2CD"><enum>(J)</enum><text>be responsible for such other functions as the President may direct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE38F2BBF767845A0B78066712F3C4D6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delegation of authority</header><subparagraph id="H8AB3466A7AA84B5AA6ED7BFF346E7029"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director may—</text><clause id="H56150E152EE54427BF03206C3036BAE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serve as the senior representative to any organization that the President may establish for the purpose of providing the President advice on fraud and scam prevention;</text></clause><clause id="H623EAD86AA404BDCBEF3D13EF0CA78D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), be included as a participant in preparations for and, when appropriate, the execution of domestic and international summits and other international meetings at which fraud and scam prevention is a major topic;</text></clause><clause id="H66F29B6882974D17B872552A10AC720B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>delegate any of the Director’s functions, powers, and duties to such officers and employees of the Office as the Director considers appropriate; and</text></clause><clause id="H071605CED2034CCA94CA5854ED253BD4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>authorize such successive re-delegations of such functions, powers, and duties to such officers and employees of the Office as the Director considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCC63AC35B35441B90B4DBCB7E27C1BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Summits</header><text>In acting under subparagraph (A)(ii) in the case of a summit or a meeting with an international partner, the Director shall act in coordination with the Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81E24D32FEF44392BF823D086F975803"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Powers of the Director</header><paragraph id="H2161D51A4CBB4FDA84CEECCF5C7E0441"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director may, for the purposes of carrying out the functions of the Director under this section—</text><subparagraph id="HB301FD7DCB9F4FFE97A3ECE6E7F59A1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to the civil service and classification laws, select, appoint, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees as are necessary and prescribe their duties, except that not more than 20 individuals may be employed without regard to any provision of law regulating the employment or compensation at rates not to exceed the basic rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04B8015C8B174311B6ACABB9701F9C16"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employ experts and consultants in accordance with section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, and compensate individuals so employed for each day (including travel time) at rates not in excess of the maximum rate of basic pay for grade GS–15 as provided in section 5332 of such title, and while such experts and consultants are so serving away from their homes or regular place of business, to pay such employees travel expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence at rates authorized by section 5703 of such title 5 for persons in Federal Government service employed intermittently;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC42B40817F0E445095078F94666B0C83"><enum>(C)</enum><text>accept officers or employees of the United States or members of the Armed Forces on a detail from an element of the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>)) or from another element of the Federal Government on a nonreimbursable basis, as jointly agreed to by the heads of the receiving and detailing elements, for a period not to exceed 3 years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15FFBA02019D4A20BC78A08F640C4E5B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the functions, powers, and duties vested in the Director;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF028BE98CDD5481C9F0A516951A9D1B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>utilize, with their consent, the services, personnel, and facilities of other Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75C39C8C9175483A9280681929075EA2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>enter into and perform such contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other transactions as may be necessary in the conduct of the work of the Office and on such terms as the Director may determine appropriate, with any Federal agency, or with any public or private person or entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F7F7E145F674E159DB03B7E5C8E7CDD"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accept voluntary and uncompensated services, notwithstanding the provisions of section 1342 of title 31, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C3734BB07CF463285CCF7D0EE9B0E02"><enum>(H)</enum><text>adopt an official seal, which shall be judicially noticed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF727AED676334A4BB671582A075C7FBD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide, where authorized by law, copies of documents to persons at cost, except that any funds so received shall be credited to, and be available for use from, the account from which expenditures relating thereto were made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FF09792554E4E3682CBB2457751FE61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules of construction regarding details</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1)(C) may be construed as imposing any limitation on any other authority for reimbursable or nonreimbursable details. A nonreimbursable detail made pursuant to such paragraph shall not be considered an augmentation of the appropriations of the receiving element of the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H328E24BFAC6C4485926AE86E843E7F66"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Immunity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who in good faith shares non-personally identifiable information with the Office to carry out the purposes of this Act shall not be liable under a civil action for such disclosure.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEC24116234DA4D168FFE9532186FA105"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text><paragraph id="H1E1895FBB3C847959235BEB1C79A3CD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>fraud</term> means acts that intentionally and knowingly deceive the victim by misrepresenting, concealing, or omitting facts about promised goods, services, or other benefits and consequences that are nonexistent, unnecessary, never intended to be provided, or deliberately distorted for the purpose of monetary gain, and includes both transactions authorized by the victim and those that are not so authorized;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3326701582F4DA3842579821CC6A507"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>fraud and scam prevention posture</term> means the ability to identify, to protect against, to detect, to prevent, to respond to, and to recover from completed, ongoing, or planned fraud or scams;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F69008BC0C54010BBA9CAFA5CB3DC83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>incident</term> means an individual completed, ongoing, or planned act of fraud or larger fraud campaign;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AA70FBF9FA443E1AA21D5975725B9F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>incident response</term> means a government or private sector activity that detects, prevents, mitigates, or recovers from a fraud or scam campaign of significant consequence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD9B8A1AE1E54AD59713CD56CD223188"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CEA73DB490748448CDF89A4F0D77DFA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <quote>relevant Federal departments and agencies</quote> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H4F5F161C998D47D4B6EC8F3FFB31B3A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of State, including the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs, the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs, and the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H201FB18B87294A2BBAF57F09E3281EFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8D4579FC5CA44A497C1084B54F3F1D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Homeland Security, including the U.S. Secret Service and Homeland Security Investigations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9DA7E8416DA4D5598B2DFEEF039F9DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of the Treasury, including the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence, the Office of Foreign Assets Control, and Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2E9E33448054266BB552C450F6F1C64"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Communications Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60B9EDF1A44E4487BD7F9062BC4C8868"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Trade Commission;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C68BA7D42E246DD836C5504A77449B6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>scam</term> means a type of fraud where the victim is tricked into willingly providing money or personal information to a malicious actor, who deceived the victim for monetary gain; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECDC677AA85848E6A881563266211698"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>significant consequence</quote> means, with respect to any fraud or scam campaign, that such campaign results in aggregate losses exceeding $5,000,000, affecting more than 1,000 individuals, or posing a substantial threat to national economic or cybersecurity interests, as determined by the Director in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal departments and agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B11118F224A4C9990DDE8CAE0CAD8EA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority to carry out this Act and the Office shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

