<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9F501DAC224A449488DE9EFFC4106027" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5757 IH: Tribal Housing Continuity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5757</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251014">October 14, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide appropriations for certain tribal programs during a period of a lapse in discretionary appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H7E17C35C3FC84972B932059A74BBDDF2" style="OLC">
<section id="H3F1C76A3BF3847409C0A8BD72B01A201" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Housing Continuity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD17AAD4578BB4A8C98B3EEDC415A8DD5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H8D07A9CDA19E400C91188FB570EB5077"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal government has a trust responsibility to support tribal nations and their citizens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BFCC3285CBC437687D89A580A75EAE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 provides the primary Federal support for affordable housing in tribal communities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC5658CA98BA74710A7A61496D7408EAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lapses in appropriations and lapses in orders, from the Office of Personnel Management relating to requests for information, risk delaying or halting critical tribal housing projects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC793E30B6A4B4E2D82984D3C8B990ACE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Tribal governments do not have access to financial assistance from States or units of local government, making the continuity of Federal programs essential.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H801FD2A0CE89484CA408857F9B4F233B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Appropriations during period of a lapse in discretionary appropriations</header>
<subsection id="H96E724CBCB78453BA525937F962BE01A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1.6 billion during any period of a lapse in discretionary appropriations with respect to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development during such fiscal year beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this section, for any period of such lapse to pay for the salaries and expenses necessary to—</text> <paragraph id="H1746DB30F78D444687DC187580E65F55"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to issue, process, and respond to requests for information and notices of funding opportunity that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development determines are necessary to implement any program authorized under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7985416C50244516A962E9ADC86890C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take administrative actions that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development determines are necessary to implement any program authorized under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H308C47EA446C48B6975A3B7017D28D10"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> to guarantee and pay under guarantees as required to carry out the program for loan guarantees for Indian housing under section 184 and of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H778828146A844D7AA77B65DA81D22366"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to guarantee and pay under guarantees as required to carry out the program for loan guarantees for Native Alaskan housing under section 184A and of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92B8BFD0FF814C04B52B2EA0EB40AEAE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to administer amounts obligated to tribes under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6E34BA1937344FCEBD2A3CD4E6B61A81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, not later than 90 days after the start of any period of a lapse in discretionary appropriations, submit a report to the Congress that describes the actions the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development took using the amounts appropriated under subsection (a). </text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

