<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HEB852BAEC6774BC59BA33015D2DD422D" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3190 : Bringing Real Accountability Via Enforcement in Burma Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3190</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Burma Unified through Rigorous Military Accountability Act of 2022 to extend the sunset, to require a determination with respect to the imposition of sanctions on certain persons of Burma, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HC589CC3374B442AC9488966752AD0317"><section id="H98D9D56EAB8243AC955FB82C1487A9AD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bringing Real Accountability Via Enforcement in Burma Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BRAVE Burma Act</short-title></quote></text></section><section id="H2EDA7451B0D84765BAF3E45ED7063BE3" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modifications to reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5571(e) of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10222">22 U.S.C. 10222(e)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7DC12A0FF0AF44528C42ACB93E03F929" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H5F20905E4BAE4F64BC331E8CFECF793E" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assessment and report on sanctions with respect to Burmese persons</header><paragraph id="H93E4FFA6136E40D8B2CAC4ACA3FB95AE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 7 years, the President shall determine whether the following persons meet the criteria for sanctions described under subsection (a) or under Executive Order 14014 (86 Fed. Reg. 9429; relating to blocking property with respect to the situation in Burma):</text><subparagraph id="HDEE58FB205074A818C115CDD3DB138E3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any Burmese state-owned enterprise described in subsection (c)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88AF105D9FBE48E59F1A6460592E371A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Myanma Economic Bank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44D4A07A2BB14B69A36C5A6E4AF7F734" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any foreign person that the President determines operates in the jet fuel sector of the Burmese economy, including through activities such as the provision of financial services or the importation, exportation, reexportation, sale, supply, trade, storage, or transport, directly or indirectly, of jet fuel in Burma.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BCCC075DEBF4E63BF8452FD29DAD273" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Upon making the determination required by paragraph (1), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the assessment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F0D46BC52794DDA8C9F20B5E144672E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required by paragraph (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H191D3366CED94296BE6B25DADFF92E9E" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation of shareholding benefitting the state administration council of burma</header><subsection id="H71745BFC93E24A02A21788C8827A26DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund to use the voice and vote of the United States, when assessing potential changes to any shareholding formula in connection with a governance review of the Fund, to limit, as appropriate, an increase to the shareholding of Burma if the country is subject to the rule of the State Administration Council.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB8E8601517B34048863ADC5792911151"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President of the United States may waive the application of subsection (a) upon certifying to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that the waiver is important to the national interest of the United States, with a detailed explanation of the reasons therefor.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260209" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 9, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

