<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31BF3DBCC13D40DF97B061566DFE4D66" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6665 IH: Consolidated Interim Storage Facility Restriction Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6665</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Nuclear Regulatory Commission from issuing certain licenses for the storage of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCE8F3E455BF246DBAB2A852FCE10E682" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFD69B1DAFA0B456F8491A269E2DA7432" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consolidated Interim Storage Facility Restriction Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD71BDAF7D5524891A7ACBD26A866D1B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Nuclear Regulatory Commission licenses for certain storage of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste</header> <subsection id="HC0542C72E0264DE6947528F88AA8EA54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB2D97FEE6B814A94837D63E91262E142"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nuclear industry of the United States is largely governed and regulated pursuant to authorities under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974, and the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53C16472AF594F2C91BCFEB5152AAF78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Commission issues and enforces certain regulations relating to such nuclear industry.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB20646F53E77482B980561733260C367"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress maintains the constitutional authority to repeal or otherwise prohibit through legislation certain actions taken by Federal departments and agencies, including the Commission, under section 8 of article I of the Constitution (commonly referred to as the <quote>necessary and proper clause</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBEB62C2ADE94A82A00E5979AC99C4DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission has concluded that it possesses the statutory authority to issue a license authorizing a private entity to store spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste at privately owned away from reactor storage sites, commonly referred to as <quote>consolidated interim storage facilities</quote>, and have issued such licenses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD57415CCC7B744D5A11C94BEA574593E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Commission to issue such licenses has since been challenged in court, resulting in a circuit split between the United States Court of Appeals for the 10th Circuit and the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, versus the United States Court of Appeals for the 5th Circuit.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H984977DAA634488B9A445A930F91C78D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The transportation and storage of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste pose significant threats to the health and safety of the public.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0B7610F3A944DBDA9ECFC3811C406F8"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste require stable long-term facilities for safe storage, and such storage requires proper oversight from Congress and the Commission to ensure the health and safety of the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFC88288A9EDA41ED8CD1C93DCA62BE9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Commission lacks express statutory authority to issue a license specified in subsection (a)(4).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H09B2B745D4254454B0CD9B09C4806BC3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on issuance of licenses</header><text>Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, notwithstanding any provision of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/2011">40 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), the Nuclear Regulatory Commission may not issue a license authorizing—</text> <paragraph id="H1B65130E8CB6440D9145B3285F3E89CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the interim storage of spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste at a facility other than—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD48CB2C40A6A46549181319995739065"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a facility with an operating civilian nuclear power reactor from which such spent fuel or waste was generated; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6915B7EE98BB4F5DB1B0315314243128"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a federally owned interim storage facility; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FB41473D94C4696A0B73FD17E405A7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the long-term storage, or permanent disposal, of spent nuclear fuel or high-level radioactive waste at a facility other than a federally owned repository under such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H001333DAA6E8448EB7B6384AABEE1F7E" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nullification of current licenses</header><text>Any license specified in subsection (c) in effect as of the date of the enactment of this Act shall be deemed null and void.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H732B2892FDE34440B611F7F61D9E22F0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC27471A349EE4A0BBF04C992EB3FC8A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civilian nuclear power reactor; disposal; high-level radioactive waste; repository; spent nuclear fuel; storage</header><text>The terms <quote>civilian nuclear power reactor</quote>, <quote>disposal</quote>, <quote>high-level radioactive waste</quote>, <quote>repository</quote>, <quote>spent nuclear fuel</quote>, and <quote>storage</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 2 of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC128A56499740028443F22E2873D286"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

