<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3BF1882CE34B493792978FB1E1CF5DD6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6948 IH: To amend title 49, United States Code, to require each new electric and hybrid vehicle to be equipped with technology that allows the timely extinguishment of an electric vehicle battery fire, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260106">January 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require each new electric and hybrid vehicle to be equipped with technology that allows the timely extinguishment of an electric vehicle battery fire, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC295EB6D20204DC98A9E77FA1218668F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H369E636D8ED748B79E0953C43E2787F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Electric and hybrid vehicle standards</header> 
<subsection id="H882590445D604293A6AD4DC935802D34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Electric and hybrid vehicles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HD1348743AD2342BDBF4BB93476C2232A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H60CF0B6A8C9544FB8C04D12647D44BE6"><enum>30130</enum><header>Electric and hybrid vehicles</header> <subsection id="H1BD4746977374B90803AC03AFCE5BA42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Battery safety</header> <paragraph id="HFE0D383748104F45A332EE3BC45B8BE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall promulgate a final motor vehicle standard to mitigate unreasonable risk of fire, explosion, reignition, stranded energy, thermal runaway, fire breaching the passenger compartment, loss of electrical power, and any other safety risk related to the battery used in any new electric or new hybrid vehicle manufactured for sale, sold, offered for sale, or introduced or delivered for introduction in interstate commerce in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE107A229C7934BAA8B3774413AF1E945"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promulgate such standard in consultation with a representative from each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H776FF566BA564544A59F28530640B658"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Major electric vehicle and hybrid vehicle manufacturers.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4BC78C6433E54005B5167C995727EEF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An accredited standards development organization with expertise in fire protection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA54674433EDB4669A5838E1929771EEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An organization that represents professional firefighters.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDDA121EA7EBE4F4B8074E09FE8462BD8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An organization that represents volunteer firefighters.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4DC835692C649318065FA04507E5600"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An organization that represents fire chiefs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC67649A182D041C6A5B9E2AA81B4D820"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The final motor vehicle standard described in paragraph (1) shall require any new electric or hybrid vehicle manufactured for sale, sold, offered for sale, or introduced or delivered for introduction in interstate commerce in the United States to be equipped, at a minimum, with—</text> <subparagraph id="H05CFC614C85349609BF255FB25FAE9A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>first responder access technology that allows immediate access to the battery for purposes of timely extinguishment of an electric vehicle or hybrid vehicle battery fire;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD86A340D94AE418C9DC707406BF43C70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>technology that suppresses thermal runaway if an electric vehicle or hybrid vehicle battery cell is damaged;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1468A48AF674144AAF3D9C09BABD107"><enum>(C)</enum><text>safeguards to delay breaching of the passenger compartment by an electric vehicle or hybrid vehicle battery fire, sufficient to permit escape or rescue of the vehicle operator and all passengers within a reasonable period of time from a collision or battery malfunction; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D52AAA6BDB045EAB9109CB8B54D65F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">battery and first responder access placed in uniform, standardized locations within the vehicle, subject to industry standards, in order to assist firefighters in recognizing and responding to battery fires.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D09A815D385476DB5C4C99B9065215F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance for firefighters</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the promulgation of the final motor vehicle standard described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish guidance on responding to fire incidents involving batteries used in electric vehicles and hybrid vehicles to be used as the basis for training firefighters.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4048F94E7AF34FD2A08110ED950304C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mechanical door release</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall promulgate a final motor vehicle safety standard that requires any new electric vehicle or hybrid vehicle manufactured for sale, sold, offered for sale, or introduced or delivered for introduction in interstate commerce in the United States to have clearly marked interior and exterior mechanical door releases on each door and hatch that allows safe exit of such vehicle in case of failure of the electric system of such vehicle.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBB58DA3B32D648EFAD7765592C01423E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC7BAC71905DD481FB9FB7589633A232C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Electric vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electric vehicle</term> means a passenger motor vehicle that is propelled by an electric motor drawing current from a rechargeable storage battery, fuel cell, or other portable source of electrical current, which may include a nonelectrical source of power designed to charge any such battery and component thereof.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H471047923C1D450CBB31681F6EE89D36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hybrid vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>hybrid vehicle</term> means a passenger motor vehicle propelled by a combination of an electric motor and an internal combustion engine or other power source and component thereof.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08833ED5D8EE4265A64CAAA1CFA54FDD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H20896BEB4FC5443397099850B4656CE9"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Civil penalty</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30165(a)(1) of such title is amended by inserting <quote>30130,</quote> after <quote>30127,</quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC0C890051DFB40649E07368FB4124D59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H4F45336B95D2423086930A36CF94B806" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 30130. Electric and hybrid vehicles</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HA133A94EB5344D71B27112085EBE5280"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply to each new electric vehicle or hybrid vehicle manufactured for sale, sold, offered for sale, or introduced or delivered for introduction in interstate commerce in the United States on and after the date that is 2 years after the date on which the Secretary promulgates the final motor vehicle safety standard pursuant to section 30130(a) of title 49, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDC2CFC7C3EB64D528AA2B1CE83C70DD3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on the health impacts of electric and hybrid vehicle battery fires on first responders</header> 
<subsection id="HF6796FDBBEAA4190B2D4F477D1EFA755"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study on the health effects of electric and hybrid vehicle battery fires on first responders.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H92D8923CB3AE465E9DD06CDB2D937530"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Report</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services, a report that includes the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="H98274E12A9174E9691857CC95109DF09">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The findings of the study under subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBCE2265D10264E7EB31BBE8783153E3F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Input from at least one representative from the following:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H66F2779957ED464D8B02E4B6C7579776">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>An accredited standards development organization with expertise in fire protection.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H8752F897444A4DC098B6EDDC473F6912">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>An organization that represents professional firefighters.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56636370552B42CE86D2A37AB6529267"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>An organization that represents volunteer firefighters.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H416519F683684256897EABA38FC69AB5">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>An organization that represents fire chiefs.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H402AEC0E8059487B8243A426C359E1A4"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Recommendations for legislative action to protect first responders from the health effects of electric and hybrid vehicle battery fires and improve the safety of electric and hybrid vehicle batteries.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

