<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25B71-L4V-F3-PSG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 503 IS: Recognizing the third commemoration of the anti-LGBTQ+ attack that occurred on November 19–20, 2022, at Club Q, an LGBTQ+ bar in Colorado Springs, Colorado.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 503</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the third commemoration of the anti-LGBTQ+ attack that occurred on November 19–20, 2022, at Club Q, an LGBTQ+ bar in Colorado Springs, Colorado.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 19–20, 2022, a mass shooting took place at Club Q, an LGBTQ+ bar in Colorado Springs, Colorado; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 5 innocent victims were killed, 17 community members were injured by gunshot wounds, and 32 other community members sustained injuries, including mental and emotional trauma from witnessing this violent event;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 5 innocent victims killed in the shooting were—</text><paragraph id="idce3bdc9eef6c4ed8b942c8390f76c44e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Raymond Green Vance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf6dec0460474320b928743a7f4c6cd8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ashley Paugh;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5607f3f86c2f43318cde666217fe8b58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Daniel Aston;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb503e00b6a43461c9df70c84c3c6eb13"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Kelly Loving; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14c1eecd65b740e1b0923fa393bc207a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Derrick Rump;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, at the time of the mass shooting, Club Q was a dedicated LGBTQ+ safe space in Colorado Springs, Colorado; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the shooting brought further trauma and a feeling of loss of safety and security to members of the LGBTQ+ community; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in 2022, there were more than 48,000 firearm-related deaths in the United States, of which 40 percent were firearm homicides, according to provisional mortality data; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Federal Bureau of Investigation compiled reports of 622 anti-LGBTQ+ hate crimes in 2022; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas violence against LBGTQ+ people of the United States remains an evil and destructive form of identity-based hate that destroys lives and runs contrary to the values of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the people of the United States commend the club patrons Richard M. Fierro, Drea Norman, and Petty Officer Thomas James, whose bravery in disarming the perpetrator undoubtedly saved countless lives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas local community organizations, the city of Colorado Springs, survivors, and victims’ families are working together to establish a plan for a public memorial;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the State of Colorado came together for medical and funeral expenses for those affected by the shooting; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the LGBTQ+ community of Colorado Springs, local social service organizations, and clinical partners are collaborating to open a new resource center to provide long term support for those impacted by the attack on Club Q, and the greater LGBTQ+ community: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate— </text><paragraph id="idc3ca37e7e0164f04a8ca0551f50d2b95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the 3 year remembrance of the anti-LGBTQ+ attack that occurred on November 19–20, 2022, at Club Q, an LGBTQ+ bar in Colorado Springs, Colorado; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbab02b09c72843a48adf7cd650564bc6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses continued solidarity and support to the survivors of the Club Q shooting, the Colorado Springs LGBTQ+ community, and the families, friends, and loved ones affected by the tragedy.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

