<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA25832-LRK-W3-NF7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 440 ATS: Designating September 2025 as “National Spinal Cord Injury Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 440</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251007">October 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating September 2025 as <quote>National Spinal Cord Injury Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 308,000 individuals in the United States live with spinal cord injuries, which cost society billions of dollars in health care costs and lost wages;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are approximately 18,000 new spinal cord injuries in the United States each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 42,000 individuals with spinal cord injuries are veterans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas motor vehicle accidents are the leading cause of spinal cord injuries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas almost half of all spinal cord injuries sustained by individuals 30 years of age or younger occur as a result of a vehicular accident;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the average remaining years of life for individuals living with spinal cord injuries has not improved significantly since the 1980s;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is an urgent need to develop new neuroprotection, pharmacological, and regeneration treatments to reduce, prevent, and reverse paralysis; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas education and funding in research are key factors in improving outcomes for individuals living with spinal cord injuries, enhancing the quality of life of individuals with spinal cord injuries, and ultimately curing paralysis: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id8b9a02ece74b46f0a6858f41ca64d0af"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates September 2025 as <quote>National Spinal Cord Injury Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac800ad828d94aecba15fc0ce4e7f613"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National Spinal Cord Injury Awareness Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e944963fa6a4f4e9f794464cb9244af"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continues to support research to find better treatments, therapies, and a cure for spinal cord injuries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc885712c6f7f4dc4aa5d6fe251c2e731"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports clinical trials for new therapies that offer promise and hope to individuals living with paralysis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec05925d608d4828bccfc5b4770b18b0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>commends the dedication of national, regional, and local organizations, researchers, doctors, volunteers, and people across the United States who are working to improve the quality of life of individuals living with spinal cord injuries and their families.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

