<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25C68-025-SG-FJ3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3346 IS: Freedom to Heal Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3346</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a special registration under the Controlled Substances Act for schedule I eligible investigational drugs under the Federal Right to Try law.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freedom to Heal Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idffcd88ecc0eb44eda976d182e1506d92"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special registration requirements related to right to try</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1202ecbe6c554234bc804cceb7fa0732"><subsection id="id76cbc37bd7ce491a9e588fee40ad5423"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Special registration for schedule I eligible investigational drugs under right to try</header><paragraph id="id09ed68a3872b426d99d08c91e878a4e5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>eligible investigational drug</term> and <term>eligible patient</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 561B of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-0a">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–0a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ea7fa8ad45d4df9aa748ad90295f5fa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special registration process</header><text>The Attorney General shall register physicians to directly administer eligible investigational drugs in schedule I to eligible patients under section 561B of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-0a">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–0a</external-xref>) in accordance with paragraphs (3) through (8) of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f2beda3731b4518a635ca88602d3ba4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="iddd3502003de34ae1814e392612e0bc8c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A physician desiring a registration to directly administer an eligible investigational drug as described in paragraph (2) shall submit to the Attorney General an application containing—</text><clause id="ida02ccc309f5f42afb0d830f77115dba7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evidence of a valid registration to dispense or administer controlled substances in schedules II through V;</text></clause><clause id="id53e99f6957bf4672bf3eaa5830ca2776"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evidence of compliance with section 561B of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-0a">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–0a</external-xref>), including—</text><subclause id="id093459cfd39a40c0930fba2aded322fd"><enum>(I)</enum><text>documentation from the manufacturer or sponsor verifying the investigational drug in schedule I is an eligible investigational drug;</text></subclause><subclause id="idb908242f36b9493d8d1f8d869f6546a8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an agreement from the manufacturer or sponsor to supply the eligible investigational drug, along with guidance on its administration, to the requesting physician for the treatment of eligible patients; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2812e9143d684044adb19c22fbf3f93b"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an affirmation that the physician will only directly administer the eligible investigational drug to treat eligible patients in a manner consistent with the guidance provided by the manufacturer or sponsor;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idad22814ed75c4a2982bdae27c5e4bb65"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the quantity of the eligible investigational drug to be supplied by the manufacturer or sponsor to the physician to treat eligible patients;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id523ecb62386d4a9eb9f48d8c16cf7f67"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence that the physician may treat eligible patients with eligible investigational drugs under the laws of the State in which the treatment will take place;</text></clause><clause id="idd49c8aba2aa94306aeca0916e4b3526b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>evidence of training, credentials, or experience relevant to treating patients with the eligible investigational drug;</text></clause><clause id="id5cce08164b83476bbd163787cd8b4f21"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of the site at which the physician intends to store and administer the eligible investigational drug; and</text></clause><clause id="ide7e3dbee5546400ab638c9f1f072e0ca"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any additional information the Attorney General determines necessary to prevent diversion.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1df115fad5eb43e78caf16a82f1f6bb2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>Not later than 45 days after receiving an application containing the information required under subparagraph (A), the Attorney General shall—</text><clause id="idf63036468f49487088da5e2464f7c616"><enum>(i)</enum><text>register the applicant; or</text></clause><clause id="idad70b221110040c08a205e6a3c6993a0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serve an order to show cause upon the applicant in accordance with section 304(c).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id465ff09fc8fd4d7b9d85804964f98b3c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Electronic submissions</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide a means for a physician to submit an application under paragraph (3)(A) electronically.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10a05755a4de424e8c4641bbf281b691"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A physician treating eligible patients with an eligible investigational drug in schedule I under this subsection may only possess the amounts of the eligible investigational drug identified in—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8210a0314c3c4dbe9756534e7ea120f1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application submitted to the Attorney General under paragraph (3)(A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e13c89d54894a96a5726c9c968c59a4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a supplemental notification that the physician may submit to the Attorney General if the physician needs additional amounts of the eligible investigational drug for the treatment of eligible patients, which supplemental notification—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c0911b4811440d4aa76c50fef7888bd"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9e8d4de42384024ae8f6453aa712e15"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name of the physician;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1601d90d5bcd4f1c99d32df462aefa84"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the additional quantity of the eligible investigational drug needed; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id036738a62405461aad7baf032a8407d8"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an attestation that the treatment with the eligible investigational drug is consistent with the scope of treatment that was the subject of the application under paragraph (3)(A); and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65f544c01ead4d34bd9f734bc559a854"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be deemed approved on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the physician submits the supplemental notification to the Attorney General, unless the Attorney General serves an order to show cause upon the applicant in accordance with section 304(c).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab02860e4a964f5588af9ef61daf913b"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Single registration for related treatment sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A physician may treat eligible patients with an eligible investigational drug in schedule I under a single registration under this subsection if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57bcfaff65804c4f8e7912bb91420041"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the treatment occurs exclusively on sites all of which are—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4daf25fb5864149b90fb2a6ff8b43c9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within the same city or county; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91354298ed3244da93e93bbf30ed7b28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the control of the same institution, organization, or agency; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7c245ced08141ceb1bb73ca06b2e0fe"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before commencing the treatment, the physician notifies the Attorney General of each site where the eligible investigational drug will be stored or administered in accordance with paragraph (3)(A)(vi).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id67955e5a84764ca5ad1c42ab29072652"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Attorney General shall issue an interim final rule to implement this subsection, including with respect to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c6899a95706477995648a394873493d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner in which an eligible investigational drug may be delivered to an approved registrant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a2042e57999421592cf6e02ad3af6ca"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the storage and security of an eligible investigational drug;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0281f461c25344ef8d8e8e55f66a1a5d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the maintenance of records for an approved registrant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd070a58f57d74f4793a755213579bf0d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the process for renewal, suspension, or revocation of a registration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb140500ff9414d939edebbf7a30f51da"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other matters necessary to ensure effective controls against diversion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2686d2f5822e498dafdc0d1ec209a46f"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 2 years after issuing an interim final rule under paragraph (7), the Attorney General shall issue a final rule to implement this subsection in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

