<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBD691F576BCE45E48808D35C5FEA2C2A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5989 IH: STARS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5989</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/50">chapter 50</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, to require the Department of Defense to operate a facility capable of processing identification and eligibility systems for members of the Armed Forces and their families near large metropolitan areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5424638B43984706BB723EA3C5F292FA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE50129B3C7C94E7F8861FEB47077922D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Troops’ Access to Recognition Services Act</short-title></quote> or <quote>STARS Act</quote>. </text></section> <section id="H8465401F9D90483B90CAD61446E8D6D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement for the Department of Defense to maintain identification and eligibility facilities within 30 miles of major metropolitan areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/50">Chapter 50</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H2D475C36C1B44F21B782945DB38B67A6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H33BC30A5454B49D79F47985326C624FD"><enum>996.</enum><header>Requirements for locations of facilities providing identification and eligibility services</header> 
<subsection id="H7CD3FFAE00E04922BEEECC7D2C091264"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="HD79F29955A9D4DF6952470097C6A655F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a covered identification and eligibility facility is located not more than a 30 mile distance from each metropolitan statistical area (as defined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget) with a population of 300,000 or more according to the most recent United States census population estimates available; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD292CD8A822486DADE0C6EDEDC5A302"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each such covered identification and eligibility facility is open and staffed by at least one person qualified to assist members of the armed forces and eligible dependents of such members with covered identification matters not less than two days per week during regular business hours.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFDD06CE5BA414F7CBF2A1D4D56DBCFCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7D22963281A04B32B36E7C3B6745C045"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered identification and eligibility facility</quote> means a physical location capable of assisting members of the armed forces and eligible dependents of members of the armed forces with covered identification matters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBABD173EEBBF46A289D5C431766A860A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered identification matters</quote> means matters relating to the Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System and Real-Time Automated Personnel Identification System, or any successor to either such system, including the issuance of appropriate identification related to each such system.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>


