<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB75B592DB60D48D7AD151BF6C8187FCA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7050 IH: Homeopathic Drug Product Safety, Quality, and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7050</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to homeopathic drug products, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H71EC9750FC08403AB0FC49D68F373930" style="OLC"><section id="H30B942A7316C4008B0CB725E9FCBE858" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HFEFDD8B1D49C4F7395CB54EC46AB4AD5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeopathic Drug Product Safety, Quality, and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HECFEBC750E824A8995A620EF74D7B904"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H30B942A7316C4008B0CB725E9FCBE858" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCD1071AA340B4DB38682C0C619BB60CC" level="section">Sec. 2. Purpose; sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H56F7F313E1CA49FB8B8BD55EE5569B23" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6CB32B5C8EC54046BDD90CBCF31DA1B0" level="section">Sec. 4. Safety, quality, and transparency requirements for homeopathic drug products.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD68014D6B54F4477842A8DD0C3D902E0" level="section">Sec. 5. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB661777BDB5B4EC58986EAB655B35811" level="section">Sec. 6. Withdrawal of guidance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0D43AF1378B84C47B14F5F74E07D8BF6" level="section">Sec. 7. Severability.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HCD1071AA340B4DB38682C0C619BB60CC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="HD8A5AC9782944F4691A4B3D5A13B529A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to address consumer and practitioner needs for continued access to homeopathic drug products that meet requirements for safety, quality, and transparency.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1BD893D8E3245A4B073CA4C6AF33C0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H8A78EEBD8D0C47399ADCD428E6F191DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">homeopathic medicines are important to millions of American consumers, and continued consumer access to safe homeopathic products is best ensured by enacting a distinct statutory pathway for the regulation of homeopathic drug products; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97C1C5E24F894693ADF6BFFE8F0892DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>while the Federal Government should continue to take appropriate action against products that are adulterated or misbranded, Federal agencies should not impose regulatory barriers that unreasonably limit or prevent consumer and health care provider access to safe products and accurate information.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H56F7F313E1CA49FB8B8BD55EE5569B23"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAC82406326064ED3B2F58359651F3E27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (p), by striking <quote>except a new animal drug or an animal feed bearing or containing a new animal drug</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>except a new animal drug, an animal feed bearing or containing a new animal drug, or a homeopathic drug product</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E81AD7BB0145D5AA74FEE9E090BA48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (v), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and that a homeopathic drug product is not a new animal drug</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2AE8F77AB024D5A92B0ACD15A51E229"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB0E6F0110F884AE9B9EC5DF81005AF7B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HF9CA77009F5A4C76864E79FE1F33A35D"><enum>(tt)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>homeopathic drug product</term> means a drug that—</text><paragraph id="H81268B30E0714D9B85C68C3261F78B9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contains 1 or more homeopathic ingredients; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4DE52D25B6C40F38B637905ADDAC97C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains no other active ingredient.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CC681D26216475E94A860B8AB8817AE"><enum>(uu)</enum><text>The term <term>homeopathic ingredient</term> means an ingredient—</text><paragraph id="H71A98DD50E5E4FF596C9A14DEE97D3C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>listed in the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States or a State homeopathic formulary; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8530212A070A49A8B0197C27A222ADC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepared pursuant to homeopathic safety and quality standards described in—</text><subparagraph id="HDA92DA0B41554D51B4A8AA5AEB2442EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States or any other officially recognized homeopathic pharmacopoeia; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B05E72C3BFC49979FC2880BA79497BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any accredited voluntary consensus standard for homeopathic drug products, as determined by the Secretary in compliance with section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H6CB32B5C8EC54046BDD90CBCF31DA1B0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Safety, quality, and transparency requirements for homeopathic drug products</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter A of chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/351">21 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 503D (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353d">21 U.S.C. 353d</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF9E728A20EEB404D9EE1F73F55751455" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H4437E7A99D7045F0A2CF64DC0D342116"><enum>503E.</enum><header>Homeopathic drug products</header><subsection id="HBD5B6189ECBE417FA35F665228DF936F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provisions applicable to homeopathic drug products</header><paragraph id="H3E9166F2FC3F43579B59866258AF0054"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chapter V provisions</header><text>No section of this chapter shall apply to homeopathic drug products except this section and sections 501, 502, and 510.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22A1FF152D324F0ABAA3ED6018B34D4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for all provisions</header><text>No provision of law, a regulation, or a guidance document (including sections 501, 502, and 510 and any applicable provisions of this Act outside of this chapter) shall apply to homeopathic drug products unless such provision—</text><subparagraph id="H195AAD3B45AF43C0B78B0860FB6DACE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>does not conflict with this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H669D62EDE4FF47889AFB55CD23FC67A6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not impose standards that are in conflict with standards in the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States or in an accredited voluntary consensus standard for homeopathic drug products, as determined by the Secretary in compliance with section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C6D2545CF564C21BA8950ACB3A2FCD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adulteration; good manufacturing practice standards</header><paragraph id="H2936B1ED1D0D499180697D9AE7413FC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adulteration</header><text>A homeopathic drug product shall be deemed to be adulterated if it does not comply with—</text><subparagraph id="H1F01AE70D2934FFEBD596D0B16683F12"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the safety and quality standards and manufacturing practices described in—</text><clause id="H0224581879F749499E41D6D9036F317C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States or any other officially recognized homeopathic pharmacopoeia; or</text></clause><clause id="HB1C1EE9EF77F4ADAB902ACC6ADE47817"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accredited voluntary consensus standard for homeopathic drug products, as determined by the Secretary in compliance with section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H254201B4B0004A78BEAA038713A33BD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case that no standard or manufacturing practice described in subparagraph (A) applies to such homeopathic drug product, the regulations described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDFA02BC933D4C619896FBDA309EBACC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative regulations</header><text>The regulations described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H012EDD448B3846708F7E5C86113E3453"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Good manufacturing practice regulations promulgated under section 501(a)(2) or related guidance documents, provided that such regulations or related guidance documents do not conflict with any other provision of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3442A78CAAAE4BEF91EA6245B5C6CAF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that no regulation described in subparagraph (A) applies to the homeopathic drug product, a new good manufacturing practice regulation, which shall be promulgated by the Secretary after notice and opportunity for public comment pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code—</text><clause id="H94465593E5454265B9AA79CA26CA7964"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that does not conflict with any other provision of this section;</text></clause><clause id="H3B64C97336A349109A67E81915228D14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is specific to and appropriate for homeopathic drug products; and</text></clause><clause id="H74234E3A303F411E8AECF6A410631E60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to which the Secretary has requested and received a favorable recommendation from the Homeopathic Drug Product Advisory Committee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD00BE9F8CE74015A734AAF70EBF9DBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Petition for exemption, variance, or alternative standard or practice</header><subparagraph id="HC0F52F901E78403BBBA4B4317DD23B3A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer of a homeopathic drug product subject to a good manufacturing practice regulation may submit to the Secretary a petition for an exemption, variance, or alternative standard or practice with respect to such product. The Secretary shall refer such petition to the Homeopathic Drug Product Advisory Committee, which shall report its recommendation to the Secretary not later than 60 days after receiving such petition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CB58B8C6DD14B5FA7618DD6BDE21062"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline for approval</header><text>The Secretary shall make a decision on a petition submitted under subparagraph (A) not later than 180 days after the submission of the petition. If the Secretary fails to make a decision on such a petition within such 180-day period, the petition shall be deemed approved and the proposed exemption, variance, or alternative standard or practice established.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA74D9EA3677543C89C1D2AB507C7C1FF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Standard for approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may approve a petition submitted under subparagraph (A) and establish the proposed exemption, variance, or alternative standard or practice with respect to the homeopathic drug product only if such exemption, variance, or alternative standard or practice does not affect the safety of the homeopathic drug product.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B19B8F0D93D45C68B820B26846ADAB4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>For the purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, a decision of the Secretary on a petition submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be considered final agency action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H386616085C234D85977EFD789E7507CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Final and intermediate product testing</header><subparagraph id="H7366ABEC8E8D4A54ADC8D25690AA8DE9"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Final product testing</header> <text>A finished homeopathic drug product shall be exempt from the requirement for a laboratory determination of identity and strength of each active ingredient described in section 211.165(a) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), but shall continue to be required to meet other final specifications, such as testing for contaminants and defects of the finished product, consistent with this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20B3A16781CD4EECB211BC1818398918"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intermediate testing for certain starting materials</header><clause id="H83693E14D8614893ACFA99B7BDA123D4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The manufacturer of a homeopathic drug product made from a starting material containing a substance which may present a substantial risk of illness or injury in its undiluted form shall ensure and document that the amount of such substance in an intermediate level preparation used to make all further attenuations does not exceed a safe level, as determined by the Secretary under this subparagraph.</text></clause><clause id="H938E375DE488431BB299FB3502635883"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Safe level defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>safe level</term> means—</text><subclause id="H41ED1E54C1574796AD368457D52D1E50"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a level set by nationally recognized standards for safety, including the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States or an accredited voluntary consensus standard for homeopathic drug products, as determined by the Secretary in compliance with section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H02575C9CE18C4711879CD67B12DC2C4D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the absence of a standard described in subclause (I), a level below an analytically detectable presence.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBE8A51B58383421C874F3808C5904B85"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Publication of safe levels</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may issue an order, notice of which shall be published in the Federal Register, establishing a safe level, based on appropriate scientific and technical data, for a substance under clause (i). Such notice shall include—</text><subclause id="H191F258CB76A430E9DFB6EA80F4FE266"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a statement of the basis for the Secretary’s finding that there is a reasonable probability that the substance may present a substantial risk of illness or injury in its undiluted form;</text></subclause><subclause id="HAD9C83ED30714903B54DB8B81686CA78"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a statement of the basis for the establishment of the safe level, including any available methods to establish such level; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H151616E25EE14148946EC7784275214D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a request for public comments.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF829094970548A49CBF8F28AFFCBD88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Misbranding</header><paragraph id="H0BCE9BB93BBE44C89A9911E9287E0564" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A drug shall be deemed to be misbranded if—</text><subparagraph id="HDDDCBD473E784CD1A8635DE39666EA93" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>it is not a homeopathic drug product, and its labeling bears the term <term>homeopathic</term>, <term>homeopathy</term>, <term>homeopath</term>, or such similar term as determined by the Secretary; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9F571E1C9A344C4890AD71AFFDEA32D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>it is a homeopathic drug product, and its labeling does not comply with the requirements described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4060D278B719464D88089F686227837A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Labeling requirements</header><text>With respect to the labeling of a homeopathic drug product, the requirements described in this paragraph are the requirements for the labeling of a drug under this Act, subject to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H234E30289F2148A6B21E295E786823FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The labeling need not adhere to any requirement that does not apply to homeopathic drug products under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF9BD5E65C654E599C89649487EE4794"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The dosage units of the homeopathic ingredients shall be expressed as attenuations particular to homeopathic ingredients (such as <quote>3x</quote> or <quote>6c</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE4AA66CA54B4C7AA328CA62A9721E48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the homeopathic drug product is not intended for retail sale, the label of such product need not contain a purpose or indication for use.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D23A623DE6D49A388DA8C485B81E2BD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>If the homeopathic drug product is intended for retail sale, the label of such product shall contain—</text><clause id="H4D1EA9C2AFE446088DDB8A96754F23A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 or more purposes or indications for use for self-limiting conditions that are supported by—</text><subclause id="HBF2FC267DB2D4D3396A11D517C1ABC62"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, an official pharmacopeia of another country where the practice of homeopathy is licensed or certified, or an accredited voluntary consensus standard for homeopathic drug products, as determined by the Secretary in compliance with section 12(d) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDE451B76BC4146508BD59B0D932403ED"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a traditional homeopathic reference, including a homeopathic Materia Medica in general use by licensed medical practitioners who practice homeopathy or certified homeopaths in the United States or another country;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H207B333B467347E39718DE350D718AC3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a peer-reviewed medical journal, including any homeopathic medical journal;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0DF47C6B1FF24DE2A514592215822DCC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">citation to scientific evidence, including clinical data or trials;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6A7454EA68A748119DBBB9F8D99A1528"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beneficial clinical usage documented by clinical reports from national or international organizations, professionally recognized publications of clinical indications and contraindications, national or international instructional courses providing training in the use of homeopathic drug products, or professional peer review presentations of physicians’ usage results with homeopathic drug products at local, county, State, national, or international meetings; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H862BEA0B76E34D2EAA0B7BBEB50D9602"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quality real-world data that provides sufficient evidence to support such purposes or indications for use; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDA0D503090164330A22F7DEEA0B51627"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjacent to such purposes or indications for use, the following statement: <quote>These indications have not been evaluated by the Food and Drug Administration. This product is intended for traditional homeopathic uses.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H863E1707785A4153B988A7B77A0639D1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The labeling shall not be considered false or misleading for the purposes of section 502(a)(1) due to the inclusion of a purpose or indication for use that is supported by any source described in subclauses (I) through (VI) of subparagraph (D)(i).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B161961517044459AA835A1C579E903"><enum>(F)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC2EABEF130474F7CA2B4194F18AC1970"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), the label shall describe—</text><subclause id="HC7CD1020B9FA4B568ED7AD6C8B49F693" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the source relied upon for each purpose or indication for use under subparagraph (D)(i); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF90BF0E8660C467687800C2A794E2E75" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, the name and place of business of any parent, subsidiary, or affiliate company of the manufacturer of the homeopathic drug product, if under common ownership or control.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H65FA86D0ADF648B08398C5E49322EB74" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the label has insufficient space for the information required by clause (i), in lieu of such information the label may contain a quick response code (commonly known as a <quote>QR code</quote>) or similar mechanism that links to a publicly accessible website containing such information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H691C196AC5ED42C8BD4A66F473A71061"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of other misbranding-related provisions</header><subparagraph id="H56BD497E4AE64B3782E1548CFFF0B5B9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>FTC Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Labeling or marketing claims associated with a homeopathic drug product that are in compliance with this subsection may not be considered a false advertisement or an unfair or deceptive act or practice in or affecting commerce for purposes of section 5 or 12 of the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC67F2EC71802463C954483FBC1650312"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other provisions of Federal or State law</header><text>If a homeopathic drug product’s label, labeling, advertising, and marketing materials are in compliance with this subsection, no other substantiation requirement in Federal or State law shall apply to such product.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD087EA906304B2E93224231D76D89EA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Private rights of action</header><text>No private right of action for false or deceptive advertising may be predicated on the lack of clinical trials to substantiate indications for a homeopathic drug product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFB0C1CAF0AD4D9AA85FF56957711399"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Registration and listing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of drug establishment registration and drug listing under section 510, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H7CFBC57553AD4BE48EDE86C8A63D6614"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate a homeopathic drug product establishment as a <quote>homeopathic</quote> establishment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BD444A8076941A0ACFEC6244E4F3556"><enum>(2)</enum><text>list a homeopathic drug product as <quote>homeopathic</quote>, with no other designation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11A80DE4F233436886B89011E325B5B9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No premarket approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not require premarket approval of a homeopathic drug product.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDFACDB7B307243BDB88A5B4E0E270B4C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Homeopathic Drug Product Advisory Committee</header><paragraph id="H27DD9ED77F274E22BD577065EDF678FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a Homeopathic Drug Product Advisory Committee (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to advise the Secretary on the regulation of homeopathic drug products.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H313CB7CC522F4F789FFF10DC4C631E68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph id="HABE81FCA265D4D369E6CBDB7DF20E9D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Committee shall be composed of 10 members, to be appointed by the Secretary, as follows:</text><clause id="H9F935ACB10E4434D97A049D69EC4FDEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 representative from an organization of homeopathic product consumers that has been operating for a minimum of 3 continuous years with a minimum of 10,000 members, who shall serve as the Chair of the Committee.</text></clause><clause id="HD17E62643EE14B3B8688D9EB933B346F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 representative from a domestic homeopathic drug manufacturer that produces at least 50 distinct homeopathic drug products and has no fewer than 50 employees.</text></clause><clause id="HF936E7F2E65F4859BA94E79A5527F8F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 representative from a domestic homeopathic drug manufacturer that produces at least 50 distinct homeopathic drug products and has no more than 50 employees.</text></clause><clause id="HC93E8468A0904ED9B067C2D2AE247387"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>1 representative from the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia Convention of the United States.</text></clause><clause id="HB4446B9A55DA4A478DC74B149A2F9516"><enum>(v)</enum><text>1 representative from an accredited voluntary consensus standards body for homeopathic drug products that has been operating for a minimum of 3 continuous years.</text></clause><clause id="H2C7F322D35F54AAB80DB082B8A0D9031"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>1 licensed medical doctor (M.D.) or doctor of osteopathy (D.O.) who holds a Diplomate, American Board of Homeopathic Medicine (DABHM) or Diplomate, Homeotherapeutics (DHt) and who maintains a homeopathic practice that has been in operation for a minimum of 3 continuous years.</text></clause><clause id="H9DBA0E0D979F4E21B0657E1883B3FBAE"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 licensed naturopathic doctor (N.D.) who holds a Diplomate, American Board of Homeopathic Medicine (DABHM) or Diplomate, Homeopathic Academy of Naturopathic Physicians (DHANP) and who maintains a homeopathic practice that has been in operation for a minimum of 3 continuous years.</text></clause><clause id="H098B51C97F0A4DE6A9947B473085EC1F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>1 licensed pharmacist or chemist actively engaged in the preparation of homeopathic drug products for a minimum of 3 continuous years.</text></clause><clause id="HFD3F377428654B46B92C78CF6237FD8E"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>1 licensed veterinarian certified by the Academy of Veterinary Homeopathy or accredited by a recognized homeopathy institution who maintains a practice that has been in operation for a minimum of 3 continuous years.</text></clause><clause id="HD45C70337CB54C93957ADDF81637CB92"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A5E67B17CD74F229C4FBABD122E03D0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Alternative members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary is unable to find a suitable individual to serve in the position of a representative described in clauses (i) through (ix), the other members of the Committee may appoint to such position, by majority vote, such other expert in the field of homeopathic drug products as the Committee determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3C39BCB36A4482ABE0C1C2F431931EC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Balance of membership</header><text>In making appointments under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that the membership of the Committee reflects a proper balance of perspectives from the homeopathic practitioner, manufacturer, and consumer communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEF777F24FA14A40BA9B36EE697CA3ED"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No compensation</header><text>The members of the Committee shall serve without compensation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A0A197EA086437B874D7777C7047B66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Frequency of sessions</header><text>The Secretary shall call the Committee into session at such times and in such places as the Secretary determines appropriate, but in no case less frequently than once every 3 months.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D97FF9C298452AAFA59D78F79FF63E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text>The Committee may investigate any report of a homeopathic drug product to the FDA Adverse Event Reporting System to assist in post-market surveillance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H714E85BAA32C47AFB11E292D79EAB5BF"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Termination</header> <text>Section 1013 of chapter 5, United States Code (relating to termination of advisory committees), shall not apply to the Committee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01E62186F81649F3AC27F37F62B6DEBB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Inspectors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All Federal inspectors whose duties or authorities extend to homeopathic drug products shall be familiar with the requirements of this section, including the safety and quality manufacturing standards in the Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States or an accredited voluntary consensus standard for homeopathic drug products.</text></subsection><subsection id="H068021D4291542ABA846BA7457F5A278"> <enum>(h)</enum> <header>Non-Preemption of State law on practice of homeopathy</header> <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt, limit, or interfere with State jurisdiction concerning the practice of homeopathy and related activities within the scope of the health care professional-patient relationship.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB846C8C306554BDEBE39DC2DCB02A51D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States shall bear the burden of proof to establish a violation of this section. Any Federal court with jurisdiction shall decide any matter under this section on a de novo basis.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD68014D6B54F4477842A8DD0C3D902E0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subsection id="HB3DB62A1F7A9407BA82C6538F8D72188"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pharmaceutical Distribution Supply Chain</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 581(13) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360eee">21 U.S.C. 360eee(13)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>homeopathic drugs marketed in accordance with applicable guidance under this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>homeopathic drug products marketed in accordance with this Act</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5CFDDCA254D2403097A27D98A162728D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Serious adverse event reporting for nonprescription drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 760(a)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379aa">21 U.S.C. 379aa(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H807F04C80B794440AD9194FC0446624F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HD6946F1C5AAC47258D759747D7913212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonprescription drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term nonprescription drug—</text><subparagraph id="H1220289136A8409C838A7BCE330F91CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a drug that is—</text><clause id="H2EF4B49704FA459EBFD2BB0CC310E123"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not subject to section 503(b); and</text></clause><clause id="HAB0BBEC2331F4BFFB9C01BF1788905A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not subject to approval in an application submitted under section 505; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C5D961494F148EE819BD0AF473861B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a homeopathic drug product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA00450455CCF4DAE8AAE9D8E54FD2DE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption from regulation of biological products</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 351(i)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(i)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Such term does not include a homeopathic drug product (as defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act).</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB661777BDB5B4EC58986EAB655B35811"><enum>6.</enum><header>Withdrawal of guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The guidance of the Food and Drug Administration titled <quote>Homeopathic Drug Products; Guidance for Food and Drug Administration Staff and Industry; Availability</quote> (87 Fed. Reg. 75054; published on December 7, 2022) shall have no force or effect with respect to homeopathic drug products (as defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(3)).</text></section><section id="H0D43AF1378B84C47B14F5F74E07D8BF6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act (including the amendments made by this Act) is declared unconstitutional, or the applicability of this Act (including the amendments made by this Act) to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the constitutionality of the remainder of this Act (including the amendments made by this Act) and the applicability thereof to other persons and circumstances shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

