<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25973-T6L-3D-9Y2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3284 IS: Streamline Transit Projects Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3284</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, to allow funding recipients to assume certain responsibilities relating to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamline Transit Projects Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6727c87f08cb4d82bd664e670b21a67e"><enum>2.</enum><header>NEPA reform for categorical exclusions</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fd9301cba4d423d9dab5a6a607cdf77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">Chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5321">section 5321</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5117130fc428460b9469391a284500b6"><section id="idc2a2fa786bf54a058dc98a6c643f2d26"><enum>5322.</enum><header>Transit agency assumption of responsibility for categorical exclusions</header><subsection id="id975daae4ac0d40288e22c8241aae836b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible recipient</term> means a direct recipient of funds under this chapter that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89a38a5f68a04a629903108e10757f7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in an urbanized area with a population of more than 200,000 individuals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29bd0d75b2f346c580a3e4aec7983f6e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates to the Secretary that the recipient has the legal, technical, and financial capacity to perform the responsibilities required under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64761b70c0214a768de74595f37e7737"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Categorical exclusion determinations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99c962ee70864eb293929521f3cf1002"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary may assign to an eligible recipient, and an eligible recipient may assume, responsibility for determining whether certain designated activities are included within classes of action identified by the Secretary that are categorically excluded from requirements for environmental assessments or environmental impact statements pursuant to the interim final rule promulgated by the Secretary at part 771 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6dace593797b4737b1b798b54780a276"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of authority</header><text>A determination described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bb4338fa9794adba76baf336da34d88"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be made by an eligible recipient in accordance with criteria established by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf549b52a4cdd4fdab1f4dc5cdfc00a29"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only be made by an eligible recipient with respect to a type of activity under this chapter specifically designated by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id753616b53cbd4a8c9338268d608db961"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The criteria under paragraph (2)(A) shall include provisions for public availability of information consistent with section 552 of title 5 and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0aa7e639c6254c9abb55c8e034dc4732"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preservation of flexibility</header><text>The Secretary may not require an eligible recipient, as a condition of assuming responsibility under this section, to forego project delivery methods that are otherwise permissible for transit projects.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id39194533a6fc458980dc8efd36a5fe4d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other applicable Federal laws</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2311d7a8ef8b4188a289fbb3e88e6f26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an eligible recipient assumes responsibility under subsection (b), the Secretary may also assign, and the eligible recipient may assume, all or part of the responsibilities of the Secretary for environmental review, consultation, or other related actions required under any Federal law applicable to activities that are classified by the Secretary as categorical exclusions, with the exception of government-to-government consultation with Indian Tribes, subject to the same procedural and substantive requirements as would be required if that responsibility were carried out by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id031537bfce0747e3b97083b497b3e2e6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sole responsibility</header><text>An eligible recipient that assumes responsibility under paragraph (1) with respect to a Federal law shall be solely responsible and solely liable for complying with and carrying out that law, and the Secretary shall have no such responsibility or liability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id371aa255f5d84e4789515e43fce959c1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb69719f44aa747dbad4b5b1711d1bec4"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary and an eligible recipient, after providing public notice and opportunity for comment, shall enter into a memorandum of understanding setting forth the responsibilities to be assigned under this section and the terms and conditions under which the assignments are made, including establishment of the circumstances under which the Secretary would reassume responsibility for categorical exclusion determinations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1f9a0344beb4bc78b54be4ea179c0cf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>Upon request by an eligible recipient, the Secretary shall provide to the eligible recipient technical assistance, training, or other support relating to—</text><subparagraph id="id092e985a5b364da18b8db2ff3284b9d0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assuming responsibility under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfdaa8b66f62042c4bda4c5f6e1ccd21c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing a memorandum of understanding under this subsection; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a9d1d2e357a4365b0df2dc3f21cb977"><enum>(C)</enum><text>addressing a responsibility in need of corrective action under subsection (e)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id706e6ff0a0a6415c9030eed08e730b57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term</header><text>A memorandum of understanding under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="id96d2eb77b6714d249b125eb04219af8d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided under subparagraph (C), shall have a term of not more than 3 years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75437b87837d4280a2e3ba2903b51c30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be renewable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41cf1805b71c4e51bc6d0b387fc4aef3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for an eligible recipient that has assumed the responsibility for categorical exclusions under this section for a period of not less than 10 years, shall have a term of 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id621ae7cf4fdd4608950e14147315a181"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Acceptance of jurisdiction</header><text>In a memorandum of understanding under this subsection, the eligible recipient shall consent to accept the jurisdiction of the Federal courts for the compliance, discharge, and enforcement of any responsibility of the Secretary that the eligible recipient assumes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id431d0db95bdb408588414c757506493a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="id404521ba6aef477da29b9afdd60cd3c9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitor—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4779a732866f415ebfb5546bdeb5e484"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compliance by an eligible recipient with the memorandum of understanding entered into by the eligible recipient under this subsection; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85886b37a28b440bb0bd0bcd82267bcb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provision by the eligible recipient of financial resources to carry out the memorandum of understanding; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ccaaa96463b417e9858269286958dee"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take into account the performance by the eligible recipient when considering renewal of the memorandum of understanding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id47f83b9f064d406dad19e956cc65672f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddde7c2571bcd44078d1f55adc96ceb47"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Termination by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary may terminate the assignment of responsibilities to an eligible recipient under this section if—</text><subparagraph id="id228f24989dfd42e38cd7cc974ddf9999"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the eligible recipient is not adequately carrying out the responsibilities assigned to the eligible recipient;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06317e924c4a4892b2d7e7843b58c947"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary provides to the eligible recipient—</text><clause id="id03e2746a2c8544a6b5c888c3df7f9805"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a notification of the determination of noncompliance;</text></clause><clause id="id2b19bf6a8bfa4d75b12d28bd1aeed6a6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a period of not less than 120 days to take such corrective action as the Secretary determines to be necessary to comply with the applicable agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="id1dd19b5fc0164c9195c69b65d675e246"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>upon request by the chief executive officer of the eligible recipient, a detailed description of each responsibility in need of corrective action regarding an inadequacy identified under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ac5127ec3ad4218a47d8ea1d67c4365"><enum>(C)</enum><text>after the notification and period described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (B), the eligible recipient fails to take satisfactory corrective action, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf84aa69643b04811be37fa51a68a82e2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination by the eligible recipient</header><text>An eligible recipient may terminate the assumption of responsibilities by the eligible recipient under this section—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id746900e91a664f3aa1a66c2ab32e725a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by providing to the Secretary a notice not later than the date that is 90 days before the date of termination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide00bf5a103a94fdeb0f8f80cee1ce629"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may provide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id568432f24b6a46fda640277a1093b2e5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recipient agency deemed To be Federal agency</header><text>An eligible recipient that is assigned a responsibility under this section shall be deemed to be a Federal agency for the purposes of the Federal law under which the responsibility is exercised.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3968350e364e4706a29b92e64d7f61b3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Legal fees</header><text>An eligible recipient assuming 1 or more responsibilities of the Secretary under this section for a specific project may use funds apportioned to the eligible recipient under this chapter for attorney's fees directly attributable to eligible activities associated with the project.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idabcde75de877477c9964e535d1b6da96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5321">section 5321</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id980c5d19-9f43-4118-b05b-a4db50099c5a"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc2a2fa786bf54a058dc98a6c643f2d26">5322. Transit agency assumption of responsibility for categorical exclusions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

