<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25D88-L47-4F-5HW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3983 IS: End Foreign Abuse of United States Courts Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3983</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 28, United States Code, to establish a procedure to dismiss strategic lawsuits against public participation brought by governments, agents, instrumentalities, and entities of foreign adversaries and other countries that have engaged in a pattern of frivolous litigation against United States persons intended to deter the free exercise of rights under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HAAC22762A8564DEAABC27865BEA3AF4A"><section section-type="section-one" id="HBAC8F10AF0974D938C1FF447BB4CAFEF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Foreign Abuse of United States Courts Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF978DE5F137947F3A7F5EF37F40A9C66"><enum>2.</enum><header>Measures to end strategic lawsuits against public participation brought by certain foreign actors</header><subsection id="H22B4087E922D41029AF5BF51B8A99B77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part VI of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 181 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5C4FFCE8B4046BDB1D18D1DDE523C59"><chapter id="HB3CD558BB09B431ABD92B7B20EA1C283"><enum>182</enum><header>Procedure to dismiss strategic lawsuits against public participation brought by certain foreign actors</header><toc><toc-entry level="section">Sec.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H421AB5D48A5141259822EEF0187100A0">4201. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida6915ba1176041d49d17681b5273e781">4202. Special motion to dismiss a strategic lawsuit against public participation brought by certain foreign actors.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0fe46d3dcbec416fb4cd45f3a130449e">4203. Exceptions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id87147a9a76d24cb5934db3e7aed8f826">4204. Interlocutory appeal.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2B2013F021E1497DA727053773038D2B">4205. Attorneys' fees and costs; punitive damages.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H375D3DF2F7A64323863DA577C88D01A0">4206. No limit on other remedies.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id211051fdd84544749982cd667f74d12e">4207. Removal and remand.</toc-entry></toc><section id="H421AB5D48A5141259822EEF0187100A0"><enum>4201.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text><paragraph id="id8BF46B4430DE4A8BAD5D25B9A85C7274"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claim</header><text>The term <term>claim</term> means any civil action, complaint, cause of action, counterclaim, or other court filing seeking damages, declaratory relief, or equitable relief.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26FC42328C9344998F36EAC34EA2EE44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered claim</header><text>The term <term>covered claim</term> means a claim—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbca8fc6605b1478ead7df88e7e8d7982"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">brought by—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91b23cd6c3b34b18b1c2bc69fba82173"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the government of a covered country;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd268e853232040af9d3b681faba23751"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a foreign agent or foreign instrumentality of the government of a covered country; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2525b2e7b2a248b9b7d55a9daa589dc4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a covered foreign person; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id595ab6da42d140a1831163f123bab774"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is based on, or in response to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideedf69e2174540408ca5f1d5fa35de98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a political opinion of a party; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b204b4f33254d5a8100c361ae81f222"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered protected speech or political activity by a party.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2018921534c479c9c0c3021dd0de03b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered country</header><text>The term <term>covered country</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb269c4a6eae24e8a902382f34d80db87"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a country the government of which is listed as a foreign adversary under section 791.4 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id107a7777564545c7b670e3f65034864f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a country the government or citizens of which have been determined by the Secretary of State to have engaged in a pattern of frivolous litigation against people in the United States that is intended to deter the free exercise of rights under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5c43a75d5a948559772dea8dd991767"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered foreign person</header><text>The term <term>covered foreign person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id4ef9b1921dd54cbc9bea159c1c03b185"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6096abd19924a49bc9b8d4020ae750b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a citizen of a covered country, which shall be determined in the same manner as citizenship is determined for purposes of section 1332; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9eda7d3cfe44573adafd911fba33eff"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not lawfully admitted for permanent residence, and domiciled, in the United States; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ef898df2acb4c5eba39e31bf4f940f0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a corporation, partnership, association, joint-stock company, limited liability company, business trust, or similar entity that is substantially owned by or subject to the control of 1 or more individuals described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e1a8f267a0943a09ae99015f03fa2f8"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered protected speech or political activity</header><text>The term <term>covered protected speech or political activity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id2fffd5e604b8403bb395920303b09059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a communication in a legislative, executive, judicial, administrative, or other governmental proceeding in the United States or a foreign country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0109a8c6fe19463c86070e94e19bb8cd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a communication on an issue under consideration or review, or recommending consideration of an issue, in a legislative, executive, judicial, administrative, or other governmental proceeding in the United States or a foreign country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc501c3f2e2a64b778064f448ec6285e0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a complaint made to a law enforcement agency, to a licensing board, or through a grievance mechanism in the United States or a foreign country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id779421ffda5b4cfe9e8ea06eed0b396a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a communication about a public official, public figure, or other natural or legal person of the United States or a foreign country whose act, omission, fame, notoriety, or celebrity has become a public issue; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab1ada4ef3284f35811da816ab3f7b7b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the exercise of the right of freedom of speech or of the press, the right to assemble or petition, or the right of association guaranteed by the Constitution of the United States on a matter of public concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3371b4d85dd54579848f30c12a8f5bf4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign agent; foreign instrumentality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>foreign agent</term> and <term>foreign instrumentality</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1839 of title 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id178f7d8ba91142c9b37a05c5c3c2ed27"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Political opinion</header><text>The term <term>political opinion</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b7e20a4bd854c8a957400cb45ef7501"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the manifestation or expression, either overt or imputed, of political beliefs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16eac0cf47e944ac9615d38e64ebc380"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall have the same meaning given the term <term>political opinion</term> for purposes of section 101(a)(42) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(42)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="ida6915ba1176041d49d17681b5273e781"><enum>4202.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Special motion to dismiss a strategic lawsuit against public participation brought by certain foreign actors</header><subsection id="ida9b868a199d4478b88386b8166a47bdf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Motion</header><text>A court shall grant a special motion to dismiss and dismiss a claim with prejudice if—</text><paragraph id="id377b7060764f4da1811b52ceca163300"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the moving party presents evidence establishing that the claim at issue is a covered claim;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a9add2550c4453383459da1a572c417"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the responding party fails to establish that an exception under section 4203 applies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id450cb20c993b4124899bcb13dcb7b700"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the responding party—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b1e4d7accd84e7d915d78a0c86c0c2d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fails to present evidence establishing a prima facie case as to each essential element of the claim under the standard of rule 56 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id767b3747378147d8a582ce8b085206cc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>presents evidence establishing a prima facie case as to each element of the claim, but the moving party has established that there is no genuine issue of material fact and the moving party is entitled to judgment as a matter of law on the claim under the standard of rule 56 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H754FDD8CED7E494C90BBD78FD03A2C25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 days before the filing of a special motion to dismiss a claim alleged to be a covered claim, the moving party shall provide written notice to the responding party of the intent of the moving party to file such a special motion to dismiss with respect to the claim.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF868D1ADCD99415ABC794E2CB5EDA5F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing of motion</header><text>A special motion to dismiss pursuant to this chapter shall be filed not later than—</text><paragraph id="H07B66EDDC4A24653B3B96A8E57A07602"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for a claim filed in Federal court, 60 days after the date of service of the pleading that states the claim alleged to be a covered claim; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDACDD32CCC144BDEA9CF7128B5C62F6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for a claim removed to Federal court that is alleged to be a covered claim, 60 days after the date of removal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H073598BACF004F9586934DDAC92FE769"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Stay of proceedings</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H6DF7D4FFDACA45298AD5F218DF119B58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), upon the filing of a special motion to dismiss under this chapter with respect to a claim, all other proceedings between the moving party and responding party that are related to the claim, including discovery proceedings and any pending hearing or motions, shall be stayed until notice of entry of an order disposing of the special motion to dismiss.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4828651350574C41AC1145E53C917823"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD5DE4740AD8640E9A9997052DD0600C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Good cause</header><text>Upon motion by either party, the court may allow limited and specified discovery related to a special motion to dismiss under this chapter, as determined by the court, for good cause.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF820FABD937E4EBD902D2F96114B7B34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Motion for remand</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proceedings relating to a motion to remand filed pursuant to section 1447 may proceed pending consideration by the court of the special motion to dismiss.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H887BF2E6B210473E899945B06B7635B8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expedited ruling</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a special motion to dismiss under this chapter is filed with respect to a claim, the court shall rule on the motion.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0fe46d3dcbec416fb4cd45f3a130449e"><enum>4203.</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This chapter shall not apply to any claim that is brought—</text><paragraph id="idfeb4b99a6c5f4449825554c64eccf616"><enum>(1)</enum><text>against a person primarily engaged in the business of selling or leasing commercial goods or services if the communication on which the claim is based arises out of the person's sale or lease of commercial goods or services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8715763e24d24ce980a6fc00e7fb7891"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by an official, agent, or entity of the United States Government acting in an official capacity or under color of law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e36931e50ee462e9589161d259c998d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for recovery for bodily injury, wrongful death, or survival damages.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87147a9a76d24cb5934db3e7aed8f826"><enum>4204.</enum><header>Interlocutory appeal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a court denies a special motion to dismiss under this chapter with respect to a claim, the party that filed the special motion to dismiss may take an immediate interlocutory appeal from the order denying the special motion to dismiss.</text></section><section id="H2B2013F021E1497DA727053773038D2B"><enum>4205.</enum><header>Attorneys' fees and costs; punitive damages</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97cca0aa013b493482d696747402034c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the moving party prevails on a special motion to dismiss under this chapter, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the moving party is entitled to an award of reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbb20d1fdee174f67bde9435964b34073"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Punitive damages</header><text>If the moving party prevails on a special motion to dismiss under this chapter and the court determines that the claim was presented to harass, cause unnecessary delay, or needlessly increase the cost of litigation, the court may impose an award of punitive damages. Any award of punitive damages under this subsection shall be limited to what suffices to deter repetition of the conduct or comparable conduct by others similarly situated.</text></subsection><subsection id="id19262d942e4d4890bfb46cd596d0f958"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No foreign-State immunity</header><text>A foreign state shall not be immune from fees, costs, or punitive damages imposed under this chapter.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H375D3DF2F7A64323863DA577C88D01A0"><enum>4206.</enum><header>No limit on other remedies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to reduce or limit any substantive claim, remedy, or defense to a claim based on, or in response to, covered protected speech or political activity by a party under any other Federal law or under the laws of any State or local government.</text></section><section id="id211051fdd84544749982cd667f74d12e"><enum>4207.</enum><header>Removal and remand</header><subsection id="id80e5ce3f201549a4b5f2265b86aa80d6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to removal allowed under section 1441, a defendant filing a colorable special motion to dismiss under section 4202 may remove the case to the district court of the United States for the district and division within which such action is pending, without regard to whether the party is a citizen of the State in which the action is brought or whether the defense under this chapter appears upon the face of the well-pleaded complaint, after filing a notice of removal signed pursuant to rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb1b9cc1bca0a48dfbdfc291faf9c31d2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Denial</header><text>If an action is removed under this section and the district court to which the action is removed has denied in whole a special motion to dismiss under section 4202, the court shall remand the action to the State court from which the action had been removed.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2C46C987A3F74E37B0552B9F322634A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4d5c35f8ca74712a2ed97d35957877f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 1292(a) of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="ide92d5e35e1c44f93938938c93e605591"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting a period;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a32ef2725b7442e8592d660a6d9ea48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7797b2786554bb59e930940baad9854"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41d4b9c5fcee4c5b9c47c58329f25a1f"><paragraph id="id2f44aa7d91b04d29b7291ab5d69cba13"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Interlocutory orders denying in whole or in part special motions to dismiss under section 4202.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36d635e621ff4645830442917835e689"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of chapters for title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 181 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBB7DCEE9B00B41FB95941EDD5B8EB8CC"><toc><multi-column-toc-entry bold="on" level="section"><toc-enum>182.</toc-enum><level-header level="section">Procedure to dismiss strategic lawsuits against public participation brought by certain foreign actors</level-header><target>4201</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAFEE499C538B4A0CAC340722CB5D9019"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0ccb538369a49869b9ce2c3414636b9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2bc158a8a2c415eb24a762838f1387d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apply to any claim filed on or after the date of the enactment of this Act regardless of whether the conduct at issue occurred prior to the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

