<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H40286B7CD27D447AAFA92FD37D7B6416" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6817 IH: Home-Based Telemental Health Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6817</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a home-based telemental health care grant program for purposes of increasing mental health and substance use services in rural medically underserved populations and for individuals in farming, fishing, and forestry occupations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C478E01F379403E8799E604B1ACCFFB" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HAAE2782449B4484BA1D2F603305D5F51"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Home-Based Telemental Health Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA44F2FBA5A3946B8BF7C90D8D8532619"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mental health and substance use services delivered to rural underserved populations via telemental health care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 330K (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c-16">42 U.S.C. 254c–16</external-xref>) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6467931C4CF449ED946C3CDAAA6764D1">
<section id="HF9B2ACBB78A4484A8740554E5675703B"><enum>330K–1.</enum><header>Mental health and substance use services delivered to rural underserved populations via telemental health care</header>
<subsection id="H253F28E0D150461094D8E0D9075A6BB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H5828AE344BDC4FF68DCB8AD6486B92D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered populations</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H59128B87A51C4473967BA37D4392EC6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health professional shortage areas (as defined in section 332(a)(1)) in rural areas; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC552B19722FB4963A07948817B8B480F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>populations engaged in a farming, fishing, or forestry industry;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H795DA76C9AAB46288DE842991EB7270C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible entity</term> means a public or nonprofit private telemental health provider network that offers services that include mental health and substance use services provided by professionals trained in mental health and substance use;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31B67F8BE3AB428C89453014995D7F55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>farming, fishing, or forestry industry</term> means an occupation defined as a farming, fishing, or forestry occupation by the Department of Labor in accordance with the Standard Occupational Classification System;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9473D7EF8A084AB78C70C42C0F2F9F7E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>home-based telemental</term> means the use of telemental health services where the patient is in his or her own home or other place of comfort;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F01CE480C714607BCF801EB23F29BD2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>professional trained in mental health</term> means a psychiatrist, a qualified mental health professional (as defined in section 330K), or another mental health professional acting under the direction of a psychiatrist;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H06AF08FE54E94214A40D0559CDCDE3E1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>rural</term> has the meaning given such term by the Office of Rural Health Policy of the Health Resources and Services Administration; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB16C52FD6DE8407B969C53C871758C31"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>telemental health</term> means the use of electronic information and telecommunications technologies to support long distance clinical health care, patient and professional health-related education, public health, and health administration.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD8270D2C456A40F9A6BA3960B06C5F4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Rural Health Liaison of the Department of Agriculture, shall award grants to eligible entities to expand and enhance access to mental health and substance use services for covered populations in their homes or other places of comfort, as delivered remotely by professionals trained in mental health and substance use using telemental health care.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA764028EC7DA4509ABCFB318E7D07B26"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Recipients of a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to—</text>
<paragraph id="H38CAFCD378CD482CB0477997C5FF5C0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deliver home-based telemental health services to covered populations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H325B1A7F8DEB4262A12A467D493B8BA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop comprehensive metrics to measure the quality and impact of home-based telemental health services compared to traditional in-person mental health and substance use care; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA4CF2F506F947C0B82D96BF6FB7AEF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support infrastructure that enhances the capacity of health care providers to deliver telemental health services in patients’ homes or other places of comfort, including by—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA587BF4153454D3E9A1CE6DCBE69048F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding broadband access;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H550BE3433C5B48FD92D643D9C746F457"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing devices for patients to access telemental health services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87F8A130C692449399B1DD3028396DDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offsetting costs of technology necessary for health care providers to deliver high quality care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB8FAF40B3F284D3A8068B99BAB85D137"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, not later than 3 years after the date on which the program under this section commences, and 2 years thereafter, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees reports on the impact and quality of care of home-based telemental health care services for covered populations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC7FCA18F16FD4DC292A559D512EC7363"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorized use of funds</header><text>Out of any amounts made available to the Secretary, up to $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029 may be allocated to carrying out the program under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

