<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN26372-H3N-YW-7VX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 805 ATS: Celebrating the historic significance of the 2026 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) World Cup and welcoming the international community to North America for the first tournament hosted by 3 nations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 805</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating the historic significance of the 2026 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) World Cup and welcoming the international community to North America for the first tournament hosted by 3 nations.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas soccer is widely recognized as one of the most popular sports in the world, with billions of fans across every continent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 1994 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (referred to in this preamble as <quote>FIFA</quote>) World Cup, hosted by the United States, was the most attended in history, having drawn nearly 3,600,000 spectators;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the legacy of the 1994 FIFA World Cup fundamentally changed the trajectory of soccer in the United States, fueling the 1996 launch of Major League Soccer and the creation of new professional pathways for players from the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2026 FIFA World Cup is a milestone in sports history as the first tournament to feature an expanded field of 48 national teams and a record 104 matches;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the first time in the history of the competition, the 2026 FIFA World Cup is being jointly hosted by 3 nations: the United States, Canada, and Mexico; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the <quote>United Bid</quote> of our 3 nations exemplifies the spirit of continental unity and cooperation among our great neighbors, with matches scheduled across 16 iconic host cities, including 11 in the United States, 3 in Mexico, and 2 in Canada: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide5e6de3348a542c09c65e12666a5f1e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>welcomes fans and players from around the world to the United States for the 2026 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (referred to in this resolution as <quote>FIFA</quote>) World Cup;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide71e6e192cbb4be1b8aae557c771e170"><enum>(2)</enum><text>thanks our neighbors and partners, Canada and Mexico, for their historic collaboration in bringing the FIFA World Cup back to North America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b754419d21c46ef9defe0a5cf126d77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the 16 host cities for their dedication to fans and players from all 48 participating nations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60b1db143148461ca69de7e545174783"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the continued use of sports as a banner of peace, friendship, and fair competition to unite the global public.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

