<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6B1BE53D1FE54029AC2CA44A4458E891" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6744 IH: Military Air Traffic Control Transition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6744</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 with respect to the activities of the joint aviation employment training working group, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDBA9A23767214F45AA147D5A3F4C1344" style="OLC">
<section id="H91A167DB427E40EC81498B5178F66EA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Air Traffic Control Transition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA65035FAB20949D6B545E804581DC9A6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Joint aviation employment training working group</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 425 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/63">Public Law 118–63</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD0441C57D9EB4DE4ABD2E7B7F8D6709B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A4ADF47EB4648F790D55E911154AFFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB26BC94EB874E3C8485DB5448BB20A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F834B7CB1044DF3BC20D212935E4B84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC0D8850142024A9889573A4A36BDF83E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H6204F5BBF5634B739414D480B616156E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop recommendations in consultation with the exclusive bargaining representatives of air traffic control specialists of the Federal Aviation Administration certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, to improve the transition of civilian air traffic control specialists under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense into the Department of Transportation in air traffic control occupations, including as controllers, air traffic managers, and supervisors. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2285B129E514556A970EA268FF39ABF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD174D6C3F7F341E3B965CDADA554B149"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A72716F83AE42668CE228BF15E8FBBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H848DDCA21D424E759CBDB3C88E2BA736"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE30EB49C18C943058793A42A6E742B63" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H7CFC8921F5BA486DA6F186A1B5ACB31D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations to improve the transition of civilian air traffic control specialists under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense into the Department of Transportation in air traffic control occupations, including as controllers, air traffic managers, and supervisors, as required pursuant to subsection (c)(6).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2FF53598DE848209695DA0937B94B24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e), (f), and (g) as subsections (f), (g), and (h), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACD32633C6444135875E6747756BAC87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7C6F5E9C1BB843F8A7EB95D7F7E30A97" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HA887420A16ED487C8DD1048D71E04AA3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (c), the working group shall identify any barriers—</text> <paragraph id="H6FA8884BC51E4C348407EC4032A252C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in training, phraseology, systems, or technology that would prevent the Federal Aviation Administration from hiring certified series 2152 air traffic control specialists from the Department of Defense to fill vacant Administration positions, including frontline manager roles;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2818341DCCEF47839EB8400867A00A96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improving the ability of the Secretary to determine and communicate how the credentials, experience, and training of a air traffic control specialist separating from the Armed Forces translate to credentialed civilian employment in the Air Traffic Organization of the Federal Aviation Administration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95D439F4F3AB4A44A7097792B17E54AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that exist to the standardization among the Armed Forces of series 2152 controller credentials, experience, and training and the alignment of such credentials, experience, and training to credentialed civilian employment in the Air Traffic Organization; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1B74CA6743B48CC8A217EB25AC5CAD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that exist to ensuring members of the Armed Forces with series 2152 controller credentials, experience, and training have earned the equivalent Federal Aviation Administration credential prior to separation from the Armed Forces in addition to receiving their military credentials.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

