<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H14F1C95A0EC2484A8D78FAFF478FEAA6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 950 IH: Commemorating the 25th anniversary of the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 950</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 25th anniversary of the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, December 11, 2025, marks the 25th anniversary of the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan (CERP);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CERP is the landmark bipartisan blueprint for restoration of America’s Everglades and a multigenerational State-Federal partnership to restore and better regulate the natural southerly flow of water from Lake Okeechobee to Florida Bay;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CERP, one of the most ambitious ecosystem restoration efforts in history, was authorized by Congress in the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 as a framework to restore, preserve, and protect the South Florida ecosystem while also providing for other essential water-related needs, including water supply and flood protection;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas WRDA remains the central legislative vehicle through which CERP and related Everglades restoration efforts receive Federal authorization for construction, reinforcing the importance of sustained congressional engagement to advance individual projects;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CERP’s implementation has been advanced through multiple administrations, including those of Presidents Bill Clinton, George W. Bush, Barack Obama, Donald Trump, and Joe Biden, reflecting an enduring national commitment to restoring and protecting America’s Everglades;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Florida’s partnership in CERP has likewise been sustained across successive gubernatorial administrations, including those of Governors Jeb Bush, Charlie Crist, Rick Scott, and Ron DeSantis, underscoring the longstanding State commitment to Everglades restoration and water quality;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas restoring the Everglades protects drinking water for millions of Floridians, supports a vast regional clean water economy, and helps address the harmful impacts of altered freshwater flows affecting connected waters and estuaries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas restoring and protecting the Everglades also strengthens Florida’s resilience to saltwater intrusion, extreme storms, and flooding, thereby safeguarding homes, schools, businesses, and critical infrastructure;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Everglades environmental and economic importance is nationally significant, and The Everglades Foundation has estimated that the Everglades provides approximately $1,000,000,000,000 in value to the State of Florida and the Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas measurable progress during the first quarter century of restoration includes major advances such as the Kissimmee River restoration, Herbert Hoover Dike improvements, and Tamiami Trail bridging, and continued work, including the Everglades Agricultural Area Reservoir, is central to achieving CERP’s long-term goals; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas continued, timely Federal and State investments in planning, construction, science, and monitoring are necessary to keep CERP projects on schedule, meet milestones and deadlines, and fully realize the promise of the plan: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H86DE49A86B84469DB214A9FCA6D5267E"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H93E42A9B3AE44C588E3B71C80ED9892D"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H10E1E3D44ADD4FF2AC25BABB76EC9428"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates the 25th anniversary of the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0031BFE11BB44CAFA6B0B9914C0631C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 established the modern framework for CERP and that subsequent water resources development actions remain essential to authorizing and advancing individual restoration projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68608E38B3E946B5A810E6E9C87566EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the enduring bipartisan leadership that has sustained momentum for Everglades restoration across the administrations of Presidents Bill Clinton, George W. Bush, Barack Obama, Donald Trump, and Joe Biden and the Administrations of Governors Jeb Bush, Charlie Crist, Rick Scott, and Ron DeSantis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H776EF14F43CB4471AFFD9DC6F9892E6C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirms the importance of continued bipartisan commitment to completing authorized CERP projects that improve water quality, strengthen ecosystem resilience, and protect the health, safety, and economic vitality of communities across Florida.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

