<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73F2FCBB0313484E8ACB518CBA025812" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8687 IH: Eliminating Nefarious Distribution of Smuggled Chinese Vapes Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8687</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide for escalating civil penalties for fraudulent or negligent importation of unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery systems.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9BF0756963C441B8A0D1FDE4B3463FD3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA6372F86788E4594B76D264FE936B221" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminating Nefarious Distribution of Smuggled Chinese Vapes Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ENDS Chinese Vapes Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC28AB780725F416E9BB1DE4B881197D6"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increased civil penalties for fraudulent, grossly negligent, or negligent entry of unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery systems</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9B3F9D914FD4AB8979909193A947919"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1304">19 U.S.C. 1304 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 592A the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C782B045F7A42C8AFFF8E0F6150A9D5">
<section id="H6E3991CB7B904DE6B0BB234496D05DB9"><enum>592B.</enum><header>Civil penalties for fraudulent, grossly negligent, or negligent entry of unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery systems</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7252D738DC434D099E69CE23C19E3B2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to enter, introduce, or attempt to enter or introduce an unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system into the customs territory of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41C2B36D105742658A683DEDF55A21A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H722E80F4D0784A388071B46C1B619356"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who violates subsection (a), whether through fraud, gross negligence, or negligence, shall be subject (subject to paragraph (2)) to the following penalties:</text>
<subparagraph id="H4DE333F85904470E8833604596B81A03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For a violation involving fraud, not to exceed $5,000 per unit of unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB23228E48A734D09AE3399E7D2F3DF46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For a violation involving gross negligence, not to exceed $1,000 per unit of unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFAF1007B28E247539081C769EB73AB38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For a violation involving negligence, not to exceed $500 per unit of unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBDA910346044B74A7FEE17A2084159D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>If the shipment containing the unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system involved transshipment through a third country for purposes of evading applicable duties, falsifying or concealing the country of origin, or any other scheme designed to evade applicable customs laws, an amount not to exceed twice the amount of the penalty otherwise applicable to the violation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB4A7514A03C64CA2B1C4C4821D96176F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>If the violation is the second or subsequent violation of section (a) by the person during a 3-year period, an amount not to exceed 3 times the amount of the penalty otherwise applicable to the violation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H484F224451444DC0B695B9D50BB32510"><enum>(F)</enum><text>If a violation is described in both subparagraphs (D) and (E), an amount not to exceed 5 times the amount of the penalty otherwise applicable to the violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC1C614AB14AA4941880DA1F1ED7AABC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum penalty</header><text>The penalties imposed under paragraph (1) with respect to a shipment containing an unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system may not exceed an amount that is 1,000 percent of the estimated retail value in the United States of the shipment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA288C537D724724AC3E19134FE16599" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Calculation of entries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each entry or attempted entry in violation of subsection (a) shall constitute a single violation, regardless of the number of units contained in the entry.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAF7D9630D231497496215181DDD7F674"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The procedures set forth in section 592 for the assessment, mitigation, collection, and judicial review of penalties shall apply to penalties imposed under this section, except as otherwise provided in this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFED03CBA2B4A42819107554109A3E650"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Food and Drug Administration, the Department of Justice, or any other Federal agency to pursue any civil, criminal, or administrative remedy otherwise available under law with respect to unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery systems.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5D72DD7CE7B4459980D9BB69731D1DB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD3377129BAAB4B9FB250E6CE8F26FBE9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Estimated retail value</header><text>The term <term>estimated retail value in the United States</term>, with respect to a shipment, means the aggregate price at which the unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery systems in the shipment would be sold to end consumers in the ordinary course of trade in the United States, as determined by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection by regulation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10F371FAB2CC420992DDA069AF2A8D99" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Person</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29577A0034614600AEE9865B69C827B3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>person</term> includes any individual, corporation, partnership, limited liability company, trust, or other entity.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B56D2FAD5B748028857E2BF567C48AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Common ownership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (b)(1)(E), 2 or more persons shall be treated as a single person if those persons are under common ownership of 25 percent or more, share a majority of officers or directors, or are otherwise under common control, as determined by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection by regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE28DF621B5A14FE69651E7330AC1B481" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system</header><text>The term <term>unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system</term> means an electronic nicotine delivery system that is not authorized under section 910 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/387j">21 U.S.C. 387j</external-xref>), or any other provision of that Act, for introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C4EFD4663D14348811F0E90E8DA6D2B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unit</header><text>The term <term>unit</term> means each individual electronic nicotine delivery system device, cartridge, pod, or other discrete article intended for separate consumer use.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HD8F2325A7F39401EA396464453AAFC2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Section 592B of the Tariff Act of 1930 applies to the entry or introduction of, or attempt to enter or introduce, an unauthorized electronic nicotine delivery system into the customs territory of the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

