<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26366-7CN-21-FTX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4916 IS: Aging with Artificial Intelligence Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4916</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To address the effects of artificial intelligence-enabled systems, including artificial intelligence chatbots, on older adults, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aging with Artificial Intelligence Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id655e0e523e414049b54932480b7a8763"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on the effects of artificial intelligence-enabled systems on older adults</header><subsection id="id54dfe5c1706540e5ae3616e83f0667b3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institute on Aging, shall seek to enter into a contract with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a consensus study on the effects of artificial intelligence-enabled systems on older adults, including artificial intelligence chatbots.</text></subsection><subsection id="id22c63882c14f4ea483e43cd484657aa0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The study under subsection (a) shall analyze—</text><paragraph id="id8243498a432d4a858e123f0ac65b3c88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>patterns and contexts of use of artificial intelligence-enabled systems among older adults, including use for communication, caregiving, companionship to reduce social isolation, health-related information, cognitive engagement, and activities of daily living, and associated benefits and functional outcomes, including cognitive, behavioral, and social outcomes, improved access to information and services, support for caregivers, assistance with everyday functioning, and aging in place, taking into account differences such as cognitive impairment, disability, digital literacy, social isolation, and other factors affecting use and outcomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4083f2875ca48cfb86727f9243c4c7d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the potential risks and adverse outcomes associated with the use of artificial intelligence-enabled systems by older adults, including scams, fraud, financial exploitation, misleading or inaccurate health-related information, overreliance on such systems, reinforcement of harmful or distorted beliefs or behaviors, including delusions, paranoia, or engagement in self-harm, crisis situations, and prolonged or excessive use;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e66141181b344e8a8254b6d7a3df656"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the safety, accessibility, privacy practices, and fraud-prevention safeguards associated with artificial intelligence-enabled systems used by older adults, including safeguards relating to crisis response, informed consent and data-use practices, accessibility for older adults with disabilities, and the role of human oversight in shaping reliance on such systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd66d7430c5042398ca91a32679914d4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the effects of artificial intelligence-enabled systems on family members, caregivers, clinician interactions, and caregiving-related decision-making, including the degree to which such systems supplement or substitute for human interaction or support; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2d6e47c2fbd4153baca29c78976f924"><enum>(5)</enum><text>research gaps, best practices, areas for future study, and opportunities for coordination relating to the use of artificial intelligence-enabled systems by older adults, including considerations relevant to Federal research and aging-related programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfb7893e7cf4f456286706e0214b67253"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall consult with the National Institute on Aging, the National Institute on Mental Health, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Federal Trade Commission, licensed medical professionals (including physicians, geriatricians, and psychologists), researchers with expertise in aging and technology, fraud and scam prevention experts, disability and accessibility experts, caregivers, health care organizations, and representatives from industry.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide7d88a2ca5f142a39ae6967e61db39d9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that describes the results of the study under subsection (a), including findings and recommendations regarding the use of artificial intelligence-enabled systems by older adults and associated outcomes.</text></subsection><subsection id="id91c7f727b0af49a69a1af5e1eccda3b0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id5b057488f55e40b5a6f88baef35afdf0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence chatbot</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence chatbot</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id31c8a9eb7a2a4f03b649df1ce3778eee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any interactive computer service or software application that—</text><clause id="id0cd1f496be7b410191cb2b00099b1512"><enum>(i)</enum><text>produces new expressive content or responses not fully predetermined by the developer or operator of the service or application; and</text></clause><clause id="id8a9daf66105f48a18756a001693a2b1c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>accepts open-ended natural-language or multimodal user input and produces adaptive or context-responsive output; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id412791038d5246b3bdccd0459fdeb324"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an interactive computer service or software application—</text><clause id="id6c80b2b0ce4b446fb4dbdd7f0ceff836"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the responses of which are limited to contextualized replies; and</text></clause><clause id="id0bfd238912eb4a95ba414467e4f1324b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is unable to respond on a range of topics outside of a narrow purpose.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf1b333acdd747629386090335820d43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence-enabled system</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence-enabled system</term> means any system that uses artificial intelligence, machine learning, or automated decisionmaking to perform tasks, provide recommendations, or interact with users, including—</text><subparagraph id="idb436fb01751e412da77cfc85f2b2645a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>artificial intelligence chatbots;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd98fdaafb47648c685b7075e2bcb8029"><enum>(B)</enum><text>voice-activated assistants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c0510ad7deb4c76a30cf8ef79f20caa"><enum>(C)</enum><text>automated health monitoring systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id140eb64be85542fc8d5d6080100f5220"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">robotic assistive devices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7f087523f3d48ada193f2a8b6358875"><enum>(E)</enum><text>generative or large language model-based tools, including decision support tools, used in health care, financial services, caregiving, or daily-living activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd97bdf30e8bf4f35a1ff1148a81220c8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Older adult</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>older adult</term> means an individual age 65 or older.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95fa0f7748ee45398a3c18a5b288183c"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Out of amounts otherwise appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary shall use to carry out this section not more than $2,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2027 and 2028.</text></subsection></section><section id="id8dd1a0d89fb144218e4076d9a83c7d4d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Aging research to improve care and health outcomes for older adults</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 5 of part C of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285e">42 U.S.C. 285e et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fbe118e768b46cfb0faf056a8d3e9a2"><section id="idf61dfa8155e54742834b546f46f8ce6a"><enum>445J.</enum><header>Aging research to improve care and health outcomes for older adults</header><subsection id="idc18af2d160e5414f99ea1d3707b6cda6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Institute shall facilitate multidisciplinary research, stakeholder coordination, and dissemination of best practices relating to the use of artificial intelligence-enabled systems by older adults.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8dfffe1ece0a4e22a522d56ebcd123f2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Director shall submit to Congress a report that describes activities carried out under this section, including emerging research findings and areas for future study relating to artificial intelligence-enabled systems and older adults.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaba7c5763561460ab088396c9ba40cc0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id256ce0364c2c444dbe41072aa91ee3b4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence-enabled system</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence-enabled system</term> means any system that uses artificial intelligence, machine learning, or automated decisionmaking to perform tasks, provide recommendations, or interact with users, including—</text><subparagraph id="idfcda2856cd9b456c88d90202a8c21969"><enum>(A)</enum><text>artificial intelligence chatbots;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccf553424d2e4bc491fb56247b0d37f9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>voice-activated assistants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf82cfc06648467d96f2e6106cc31cb3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>automated health monitoring systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe6aa0854d8d4b368c4ccca90fc29ef7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">robotic assistive devices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9a48c7ada134d0c894c4548e2789cbf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>generative or large language model-based tools, including decision support tools, used in health care, financial services, caregiving, or daily-living activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ideb9a2f034c0c419f823cd579e7ab7721" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Older adult</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>older adult</term> means an individual age 65 or older.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

