<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC87DEEBD34A454A8C99FE7040001EA0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7119 IH: DHS Use of Force Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require a policy on use of force and deescalation by law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBB69FB1B0CE14CE2AFCB37C27362DFAD" style="OLC"><section id="H9132487B9AF34493A510C0EA27188D02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Use of Force Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6A73E597E5E7478D979DD91A1BBB27D5"><enum>2.</enum><header>DHS policy on use of force</header><subsection id="HE7BBFECF0811456BACE3369CA6911EE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle H of Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H4CF79F068687400D9D4829012FA73C69"><section id="HB03672040D6C4C2789E1EF314878AE3C"><enum>890E.</enum><header>Use of force policy</header><subsection id="H2092F200A92B451EBC7FE162E143C98E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall implement a Department-wide policy on the use of force by law enforcement officers and agents of the Department to ensure such officers and agents—</text><paragraph id="H87BF18FC51574E57BAFE0CAF8C9E8D41" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use only the amount of force that is objectively reasonable in light of the totality of the circumstances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H638B6E6F735C4D80875FE43F028EA138" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when feasible, prior to the application of force, attempt to identify themselves and issue a verbal warning to comply with such officer or agent’s instructions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97CD70AFC6D2446296C854012AFF521C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek to employ tactics and techniques that—</text><subparagraph id="HDB6E1A4BE52A4E358E7DD0EB58B729F8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>effectively bring an incident under control, while promoting the safety of such officers or agents and the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE2C0B2EFB134A6BBD756B9AA227FE3E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>minimize the risk of unintended injury or serious property damage; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9D336DD8AC745C8B31E820EA58D415B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>are prohibited from using chokeholds and carotid restraints as a means to control non-compliant persons resisting arrest.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H292C726D5AA04DBBBECDF06D77C07AA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Department-wide policy under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HD918C836EDDA4ABFA6A84CC85959D041"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specify in a clear and consistent manner that deescalation is preferred;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F6B325D3B5C4EB986C15D3D9A65847C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require law enforcement officers or agents of the Department to complete initial and recurrent training in the full range of use of force tactics and techniques, including deescalation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D2A37B915A74C93A334E88352388185"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require the head of each component of the Department with such officers or agents to—</text><subparagraph id="H3531184C2C30417F911C8B74566CA2A3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate an individual, having subject matter expertise relating to the use of force, training, and the application of use of force tactics and techniques, including deescalation, to be responsible for ensuring compliance with such policy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EC969AD0D8348A2B2C7E5A8B531E792" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain a use of force review council or committee, the members of which shall have subject matter expertise described in subparagraph (A) to perform internal analysis of use of force incidents to—</text><clause id="H9E0373528C71403399F8D7E891BE6327" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform training, tactics, and techniques, and develop recommendations for improvements to such policy; and</text></clause><clause id="H106B293EDE3C4F10A3F7F5063A6368F8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify trends and lessons learned to be shared within each such component and across the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE2B2E2DA67E4B08A628A43B219C8754"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H3A534FABA2084643B447184C34C4B6E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1A5F5984321F421E9C5682A9CFC4204C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Issue requirements for the head of each component of the Department to collect and maintain consistent data relating to the use of force within each such component necessary to publish the reports required under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA748FB3849044436AB11AC2145FD5247"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Publish, every six months, a report on the website of the Department that includes data relating to each incident during the previous six-month period in which force was used by a law enforcement officer or agent of the Department in any of the following circumstances:</text><clause id="HE9C42DC38AAA4992B133A1EADFF0A9F5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Such use of force caused any injury or death to—</text><subclause id="H7E7E11C609D54F318E918FB5155AF427"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such an officer or agent; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H9AAC2683D35D4FFFBB4E3B1D2A394197"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a person.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3F887BCCBADB4687A21EC746DD02C3BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Such use of force included deadly force against a person, including when a firearm is discharged at a person.</text></clause><clause id="HCA471DFD64DF47808285B92AF935D071" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such use of force included a less-than-lethal device or canine that was intentionally deployed against a person.</text></clause><clause id="H0777C96F04E949CF92F1A2D439E72E6F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Such use of force involved a vehicle, weapon, or physical tactic or technique that delivers a kinetic impact to a person.</text></clause><clause id="HD3B879FAAE894DEF8822D8969AD5A100"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Such use of force included disabling fire against a maritime vessel or aircraft.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H42C41215E30F45C998448D054BE6856B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional elements</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1)(B) shall also include—</text><subparagraph id="H4A174D7F19F24473AA66DDC2A1B73785"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data that—</text><clause id="H561590E70940416E94560B679BA61F8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is disaggregated by Department component; and</text></clause><clause id="HD34C9059538B4A7FB31B86D6FD5909A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>describes—</text><subclause id="HF763CBBE3B6F4C78B9085CF540AEC55C" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>specific information on the region or jurisdiction in which each use of force incident included in such report occurred; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7194136B9C0D4B6C817ADA64EA9E0AB3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the circumstances surrounding each such incident; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CE6FBE05A17468992F14BB1023EBE44" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a specification of whether a law enforcement officer or agent of the Department or other person was injured or killed in each such incident.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78CBDDC897764D7D9E74DAFC0BC5558E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Summaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conjunction with each report required under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall publish a summary of any analyses under subsection (b)(3)(B) with respect to which, during the previous six-month period, final action was taken, including a summary of any findings resulting from any such analyses, including any findings relating to whether the uses of force contemplated by any such analyses complied with Federal law and Department-wide policy under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51CCF5BC446B44E682A7E97EBC7428A3" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Not later than 24 hours after any use of force incident by a law enforcement officer or agent of the Department that results in the hospitalization or death of such an officer or agent or a person, the Secretary shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and inform the public with respect to the facts ascertained relating to such incident.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EAA8FA3C0DB4995A37BDA9B0FF84D35"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Privacy protection</header><text>Any information published or made available pursuant to this subsection shall be published or made available in a manner that protects individual privacy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD01797587434766ADE80593AAA29F29"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Office of Inspector General</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department shall, on an ongoing basis, review compliance with subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1D62D872D6174DD882C4FFA9BF2894A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 890D the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H29B218C28BF449C1BEA52FAF5A9D4837" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 890E. Use of force policy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

