<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H70013C77FB5841E7B4E3FA7B499DDA87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6221 IH: Fostering the Future for American Children and Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6221</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify certain directives in the Executive order entitled <quote>Fostering the Future for American Children and Families</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H058CACC106B1481B9F9B8D4E32E667AF" style="OLC"><section id="H1CAD2B3181C6493DB7219690CAA58B49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fostering the Future for American Children and Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5F89DFBA4A4D4CD3A1FBF785D6C87874"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study of Federal, State, and private sector programs that support technical job training, on-the-job training, and apprenticeships for current and former foster youth</header><subsection id="HCF745351AF9B4C7EA3DEE0108BF2E699"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, shall conduct a comprehensive study of the Federal, State, and private sector programs that support technical job training, on-the-job training, and apprenticeships for current and former foster youth. The study shall evaluate the effectiveness of the programs, gaps in services provided under the programs, the barriers to accessing the programs, and the opportunities to expand career pathways for youth transitioning out of the child welfare system.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE92C4DC50DF4F7A893F4A65763DB2D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries shall submit to the Congress a report containing findings and recommendations of the study required by subsection (a) for improving alignment of the matters referred to in subsection (a), the need for additional funding to do so, and the modernization of the relevant programs.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5CFE8E503255411E8922EAFB712607B5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fostering the Future Pipeline Program</header><subsection id="H7212B93BA7BD43E68956800FC8A51C23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After completing the study required by section 2, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall establish in the Department of Health and Human Services a program, which shall be known as the <quote>Fostering the Future Pipeline Program</quote>, under which grants are made to States, academic institutions, private-sector employers, and nonprofit or faith-based organizations, on a competitive basis, to expand access to industry-aligned technical job training and apprenticeships for current and former foster youth, including through training or apprenticeships in high-demand fields such as skilled trades, manufacturing, health care, information technology, and agriculture.</text></subsection><subsection id="H072C45F617974C6E8E5F601E841F3AE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations on authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services not more than $50,000,000 for each fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="H11AD216532FB47109CACC4C960A430BA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authority to use education and training vouchers provided pursuant to the John H. Chafee Foster Care Program for Successful Transition to Adulthood to increase flexibility for youth exiting foster care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 477(i)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(i)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE93BCB42686146079BDC09D3147A12C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E71637C3DA42FA88F134EC402EE1A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) and subparagraph (C) and inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4A4A9E91E5944AA2B5DE934F6AE7D4A3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD132299E0ED049F1831E1C2F5F94FA5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be available for short-term, career-focused, credential-granting programs, including registered apprenticeships, certificate programs, and other rapid-employment pathways; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H44E5C68D13E6436B9090EA212C3D9DD2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

