<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDE0C96029C9643188896A914F1E6F69B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8881 RH: SBA Artificial Intelligence Utilization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 594</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8881</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–681]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to report on the use of artificial intelligence and machine learning by the Administration, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HD78ABB820290457E9BB9327D7989E259" style="OLC"><section id="H352CEC8BE6AE400CA5CB537505970B43" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SBA Artificial Intelligence Utilization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H74591F637C3241C39F112DEC39F549AB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports regarding artificial intelligence and machine learning use by the Small Business Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10(c) of the Small Business Act is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H540AF91AF63B45F7963199FBADEDA2E0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H03728E2D451E4EC0AB4839F222F4F520"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence and machine learning use reports</header><paragraph id="H3D0D9F9A81FB485F9D4622A865DD065B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report on—</text><subparagraph id="H8F6CFBE0FF7441669CA3E09DEB562FE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of artificial intelligence and machine learning by the Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B4AFC3156C6465892A1C2B4DB0DCC7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the benefits and risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence and machine learning in the work of the Administration, including in impeding the operations of the Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA1C5E0FAB434519B59B77A2A90D21E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>measures that the Administrator can take to effectively identify, evaluate, and manage such benefits and risks, including explanations of how the Administrator can—</text><clause id="HAE3AFAFDBFC64C94844D03E56DDA17EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain human involvement in important decisions informed by recommendations made by artificial intelligence or machine learning;</text></clause><clause id="H4C626621A33449798A63F90186A1DD6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify tasks and functions that artificial intelligence or machine learning can and cannot reliably and effectively perform, including whether artificial intelligence and machine learning can improve operations, productivity, or customer service;</text></clause><clause id="H719859D572084BD79C9065738183BF95"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine which specific artificial intelligence or machine learning tools are appropriate for a particular task or function, if such task or function is determined to have the potential to be reliably and effectively performed by artificial intelligence or machine learning; and</text></clause><clause id="H9BD17CF2D9D74B59B0BE43B49116BE48"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether an artificial intelligence or machine learning tool adequately fills a need of the Administration and is worth adopting to fulfill such need.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BABEAD397874B8DA9E2320A0318F710" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator submits each report required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall provide to the committees described in such paragraph a briefing on such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35CEBD5B37AB45388295BBA7A4B9874C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the terms <term>artificial intelligence</term> and <term>machine learning</term> have the meanings given, respectively, in section 5002 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

