<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA294B18EF5CC49BDBFBB2344A9155EEE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9752 IH: Protecting Home-Based Care for Rural Veterans Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9752</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure fair reimbursement rates for home and community-based services furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFBCE0BA45E8D4EEDB837EA56852D4161" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1119C31EDA744A29AF2A3860822E733F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Home-Based Care for Rural Veterans Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H05FB86AA3D1447D2ACDEB572BA928D3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reimbursement rates for home and community-based services</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB72D4027750F4D7E9702CEFC11FD0DD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Homemaker and Home Health Aide program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1720L(c) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E2AACA368894F35A8B2D3264AC53E95">
<paragraph id="HBCC99438AD154DF78225CA4ABF5B847B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On and after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Protecting Home-Based Care for Rural Veterans Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB4C86893FE54802BF8935B0DAB850AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any reimbursement rates for services furnished under the Homemaker and Home Health Aide program that were reduced after December 31, 2025, shall reinstate the rates in effect on such date; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2B0AD6D5A424019BF62E0285D74862B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not reduce the reimbursement rates for such services to an amount that is less than the rates in effect on such date, unless the Secretary notifies Congress of such reduction not later than 90 days before such reduction takes effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B3D3E49A0334A658CF94FF97F466039" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Protecting Home-Based Care for Rural Veterans Act of 2026</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2E756B0B2D54172B3132595D12DEA17"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifying whether the number of providers furnishing services under the Homemaker and Home Health Aide program is adequate to meet veteran demand for such services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H597B4704A89644899B32BB4768EFF15F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying any regions where provider participation in furnishing such services is inadequate to meet such demand; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H881F0494633D4C038AF84A8618B9CC6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying how the Secretary plans to ensure adequate provider participation in furnishing such services to ensure the needs of veterans for such care are met.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H59E121C639BE4F2497113270AB997E0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on reimbursement rates</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text>
<paragraph id="H820BF76AC939499198A15E5F9D84B812"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the data sources used to establish reimbursement rates for services under subsections (c) and (e) of section 1720L of title 38, United States Code, including any use of data from the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>), the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), or the private market;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H784519983BCA42D08829C6FAE7E98E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the weighting and adjustment factors applied to such data;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B72B91917A24EE0BFD533E171F52490"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the role of any contractors or third-party administrators in determining such rates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9F5B10A8F564D1CB07D5A9E70113655"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of any consultation with providers of home and community-based services in establishing such rates, including how such input was solicited, considered, and incorporated; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H05D093F8E375484FB5B8671EA02984CD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of any formulas, models, or analytical methods used to establish such rates, including any variables, assumptions, weighting, and any additional data sources or factors considered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

