<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E81F5E5F95D4444B707BFFA2542FA8C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8952 IH: Elder Pride Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8952</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to establish a LGBTQI rural outreach grant program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA5F7B32FBE5944A1890E357BF46E341A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3EA897C7A193456FA05275DD11D9B76B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Elder Pride Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H22CD3E361AAB4D619D43856D1E336538"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rural outreach grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3031">42 U.S.C. 3031 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC9BC1A1DE07046A1A00E58645FBD01A1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBB71813C31154CD38CFBB03B86EF0E40"><enum>423.</enum><header>Rural outreach grant program</header> 
<subsection id="H28D317C0230F41AB9821BBCC1B049C73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H36D9BE3F16774BC6B66C21746E690DB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means an entity that submits an application to the Assistant Secretary in accordance with subsection (c) and is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0BF9CA99B26545AF92326661FC57FCC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98451523DC3C425ABEA7C46004838E96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FE23DF004C74FC1B292D2A9D22D8053"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an agency, nonprofit organization, or institution that—</text> <clause id="HEFB20CA175FE4179BEB2AD7707601B04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>focuses on serving the needs of older individuals, LGBTQI individuals, older LGBTQI individuals, or individuals of another protected class; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2B49EE50B60E412793CBD96F5C8921DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>focuses on providing sexual health services to all older individuals, including services for individuals with HIV; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B20A89867E943F2BA512B910E7A0666"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may include an area agency on aging for a rural area or a multipurpose senior center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDCCD01AE3B542B19DAC22C1220FEE22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>LGBTQI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>LGBTQI</quote>, used with respect to an individual, means a lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, or intersex individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0125628D94B844E88CC57AC670CFDB19"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Protected class</header><text>The term <quote>protected class</quote> means a group of individuals sharing a common characteristic or identity who are legally protected against discrimination.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC48C3B9C8F8D436484D8A1B4F7922A3A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <quote>rural area</quote> means an area that is not designated by the United States Census Bureau as an urbanized area or urban cluster.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5EA2774DEE7149D88731CC1C6E7D8ED4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority for grants</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may make grants to eligible entities to carry out activities described in subsection (d) that are designed—</text> 
<paragraph id="H34A194216F12455192ACB8C9FD66366A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to create a cooperative and lasting partnership between LGBTQI older individuals, or older individuals of a protected class, residing in rural areas and the eligible entity receiving the grant;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3133575FF3B40C7B5895292091E2C07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to meet the needs of the individuals described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3F5B881A064412D9E84AA6878B2248B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide comprehensive sexual health services to all older individuals residing in rural areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA1C81C90FC844A328B9EF2949FA2F334"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header> <paragraph id="HB6342CF12E0649A68DCF49CF90E1BAA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Assistant Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Assistant Secretary may reasonably require, including the contents described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC2472DFA61E48BBA2375F7D642DC10B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application for a grant under this section shall contain—</text> <subparagraph id="HE31AF2C74BAA49E3A51C5B8688A4D549"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the proposed activities to be supported by the grant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H07A6312BAC08495A9F6BB34626E28BC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the size and characteristics of the population in a rural area to be served by such proposed activities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3DBE8AE34F740AA95F982C3FA35092A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the public and private resources expected to be made available in connection with such activities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9922557461434C0AB504593008BF29CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a demonstrated intent to partner with local organizations in rural areas in carrying out such activities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H842104D955A64B07B93CF3349D5362A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evidence in a form acceptable to the Assistant Secretary that such activities will meet urgent needs that are not met by available public and private sources; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B483F99AA894C9C911E41D00B20568C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other information or certifications that the Assistant Secretary determines necessary to achieve the purposes described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA3AFEE3876CE4D0CA9CD7BFB165ABD34"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity may use funds made available by a grant under this section to carry out activities that include initiatives that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD73B5828FDB342B383C0E23C6C016638"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engage in education and training relating to community outreach to LGBTQI older individuals, or older individuals of a protected class, residing in rural areas;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33641C9DBB5B44528193E69B145F1BEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce isolation and improve access to care for LGBTQI older individuals, or older individuals of a protected class, residing in rural areas by building relationships between such individuals and the local community;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H280B8CA0052A4E548391D0C5F2C08BA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>foster relationships between local service providers and LGBTQI older individuals, or older individuals of a protected class, residing in rural areas;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9DD4E6349EF4FBCBF349EF725FF1E98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve cultural competency with respect to LGBTQI individuals, and older individuals of a protected class, among organizations and personnel providing services to older individuals residing in rural areas;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8CA629ABAA8490FB6B87D9D805C132B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expand the use of nondiscrimination policies that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7E09EDA667104F2BAE2B0068BB81A613"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation, gender identity, and sex characteristics (including intersex traits); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23A99E224F4B4A5BA816B8D0823699E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create community spaces that are inclusive to LGBTQI older individuals and older individuals of a protected class; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9103951545B84C6689ED9675B88A6426"><enum>(6)</enum><text>focus on providing sexual health services to older individuals residing in rural areas, including services for individuals with HIV.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC847E19617D24A61BA3C4DABFC0B435D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>As a condition of receiving funds under this section, an eligible entity shall use such funds received under this section only to supplement the level of state or local funds that would, in the absence of the receipt of funds under this section, be made available for related LGBTQI services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H65E85A6B0FBF40E49F76C8D5504ED9AB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Standards and guidelines</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall establish standards and guidelines for activities supported by grants under this section. Such standards and guidelines shall permit an eligible entity receiving such grant to refine or adapt the standards and guidelines for an individual project if the refinement or adaptation is made necessary by a local circumstance.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HACAD4885890D4DD2982FFC75BA35C0B3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Coordination with local entities</header> 
<paragraph id="H675888F8725C4D02B511627A8520CE11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall, in carrying out activities supported by the grant, agree to cooperate and coordinate with—</text> <subparagraph id="H2C2C41E10FC14609ABE5BCB11A9278A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agencies of the relevant State and local governments responsible for providing services to LGBTQI older individuals, or older individuals of a protected class, in the area served by such activities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B9B63BA3C4443E6910C5656130F9540"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other public and private organizations and agencies providing services to LGBTQI older individuals, or older individuals of a protected class, in such area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07EC14CC54D94EBA8B02FEF1F74E937F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall prioritize cooperating and coordinating with public and private organizations and agencies that primarily serve populations of older individuals with the greatest social need.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98E3696F321640A69D26FF78A6CA7285"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the effective date of this section, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to the Congress and make available to the public a report describing the activities carried out under this section during the then preceding 2-year period.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H385B9DC1BE8C4026B34244FF9069B192"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is to be authorized for rural outreach grant activities under section 423, $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

