<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H02069EAD4150475E8ACADB522E73760D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6151 IH: Global Respect Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to foreign persons responsible for violations of the human rights of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex (LGBTQI) individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H47752B507BF54E3EA69133A1C71C175F" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC2EDFCD039004C0F9069CD312ADD14DD"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Respect Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8D0BD5698059403C810505001497CC67"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6108F40B8A9F45C6A5583C5FF3074D59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The dignity, freedom, and equality of all human beings are fundamental to a thriving global community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDF188E70C4543CFA3A32FA71E43DA9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The rights to life, liberty, and security of the person, the right to privacy, and the right to freedom of expression and association are fundamental human rights.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E8E4A2393174383B958B61D85793BC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Many countries are making positive developments in the protection of the basic human rights of LGBQTI individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8972ECBDC30C4C5F82F16EE813BDABCB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The alarming trend of increasing violence directed at LGBTQI individuals around the world continues.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A159217486940029A454E9C172E3F29"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately <fraction>1/3</fraction> of all countries have laws criminalizing consensual same-sex relations, and 12 countries carry the possibility of the death penalty.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FFD56A608764DF1A9EC92C36BFFABFC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Laws criminalizing consensual same-sex relations severely hinder access to HIV/AIDS treatment, information, and preventive measures for LGBTQI individuals and families.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96AD07CFC504440E8B5E1011665E985C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Celebrations of LGBTQI individuals and communities, such as film festivals, Pride events, and demonstrations, are often forced underground due to inaction on the part of, or harassment by, local law enforcement and government officials, in violation of freedoms of assembly and expression.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF199DFA8FDE6426491DC4AC5DFCB5A1F"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every year, countless individuals around the world are targeted for discrimination, harassment, arbitrary arrest and detention, physical attack, and murder on the basis of their actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4B3F94B10794D35918D561A96E123AD"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Those who commit crimes against LGBTQI individuals often do so with impunity, and are not held accountable for their crimes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AC5389D45A74E30A1C99C727D4BACB6"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Homophobic and transphobic statements by government officials in many countries in every region of the world promote negative public attitudes and can lead to increased discrimination and violence toward LGBTQI individuals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CDFF81218EA4B048CE0AF19FB59E4CE"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In many instances, police, prison, military, and civilian government authorities have been directly complicit in abuses aimed at LGBTQI citizens, including arbitrary arrest, extortion, cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment, torture, and sexual abuse.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA6325D6CFB8244538E285A8109F31A6D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sanctions on individuals responsible for violations of humanrights against LGBTQI people</header> <subsection id="H633342F1BDF044DBBCE5143B4C4BF21D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and biannually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of each foreign person the President determines, based on credible information, including information obtained by other countries or by nongovernmental organizations that monitor violations of human rights—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9DB302A549E418D8C4E2B0A77C27401"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is responsible for, or complicit in, with respect to persons based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics—</text> <subparagraph id="H23CD12D487CD45419A0134B882C57CE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">torture or cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02C2B5369E0B44EEACA341AF9856F16D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prolonged detention without charges and a trial;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5D9B703A17B4ADB99220973DCECBB1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>causing the disappearance of such persons by the abduction and clandestine detention of such persons; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5E77C5734424D03B9544B13930ED85A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other flagrant denial of the right to life, liberty, or the security of such persons; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9577C1CACD26400DB641C8FDCE37EA60"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acted as an agent of or on behalf of a foreign person in a matter relating to an activity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F9288B417AD4BE2831A7271B229EE3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form; updates; removal</header> 
<paragraph id="H032DB1592DBD4644B9D0EAC2E7ECE15C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The list required by subsection (a) shall be transmitted in unclassified form and published in the Federal Register, except that the President may include a foreign person in a classified, unpublished annex to such list if the President—</text> <subparagraph id="H220A6F4B996041C2A4631D2067DDC5EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that—</text> 
<clause id="HA6ACC28856624DA3BD750D37C7A8E8E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it is vital for the national security interests of the United States to do so; and</text></clause> <clause id="H05323FAAF28A43A09AC6699212AF239C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of such annex, and the inclusion of such person in such annex, would not undermine the overall purpose of this section to publicly identify foreign persons engaging in the conduct described in subsection (a) in order to increase accountability for such conduct; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0615B7002B2340AF85308A228E081619"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 15 days before including such person in a classified annex, provides to the appropriate congressional committees notice of, and a justification for, including or continuing to include each foreign person in such annex despite the existence of any publicly available credible information indicating that each such foreign person engaged in an activity described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94070CB8491B432789D3239EC97A6279"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees an update of the list required by subsection (a) as new information becomes available.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98DF057B66924CD89DCD60A308885D56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foreign person may be removed from the list required by subsection (a) if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees, not later than 15 days before the removal of such person from such list, that—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB923083D7D24DE5A5D7078A0B34942D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">new, credible information is discovered confirming that such person did not in fact engage in the activity for which the person was included in such list;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECAACDC6335240FCA62B1DDB1C0B0388"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such person has been prosecuted appropriately for the activity in which such person engaged;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4982CFE5B9F43419CC9C7E375E46D08"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such person has credibly demonstrated a significant change in behavior, has paid an appropriate consequence for the activities in which such person engaged, and has credibly committed to not engage in an activity described in subsection (a); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB76D93F597AD4DC0B871869B322511ED"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">removal of such sanctions is in the vital national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H813C04589A3C4647BB0E53509AB48B18"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public submission of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall issue public guidance, including through United States diplomatic and consular posts, setting forth the manner by which the names of foreign persons that may meet the criteria to be included on the list required by subsection (a) may be submitted to the Department of State for evaluation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2687A5EDFEBC43C6B3881EE4CFFAF22A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requests from chair and ranking member of appropriate congressional committees</header> 
<paragraph id="H52A834E9C6794242A60F258984AC304A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consideration of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the guidance issued pursuant to subsection (c), the President shall also consider information provided by the Chair or Ranking Member of each of the appropriate congressional committees in determining whether to include a foreign person in the list required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC51D240CCD6B4A05B82D87A17A76FDF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after receiving a written request from the Chair or Ranking Member of one of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a foreign person meets the criteria for being included in the list required by subsection (a), the President shall transmit a response to such Chair or Ranking Member, as the case may be, with respect to the President's determination relating to such foreign person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF71DDACFDC643F8BAA8E2ED515E9041"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President removes from the list required by subsection (a) a foreign person that had been included in such list pursuant to a request under paragraph (2), the President shall provide to the relevant Chair or Ranking Member of the appropriate congressional committees any information that contributed to such decision.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E7AC919B84B4A028CC93234EB5C43B5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may transmit a response required by paragraph (2) or paragraph (3) in classified form if the President determines that it is necessary for the national security interests of the United States to do so.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H084E192B80E04D6CBC908552F7508D6A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain individuals</header> 
<paragraph id="H9A9E367334AA4D0ABD47BE876F302ACA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, is described in subsection (a) is—</text> <subparagraph id="H09B8E27794014C7D8D6B8071AB68F2AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E45BF2102744D67AA2EC6FFBA4201CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C18C51622954F8FB98E36CEE802AD94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC519F48BCA184C5F9EAAAA7B499A67C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header> 
<subparagraph id="H52D202AF3AE74814B223DBE618229A8A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBD0031B82F441A6892C77D363C863E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text> 
<clause id="HE7CED3ED495D41D381F87CA2E5D8C0AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text></clause> <clause id="H40F1CCA97EA146D78A8B23899FE4A057"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F1099B1F9DC4051A66182E1A3F20573"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sense of Congress with respect to additional sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the President should impose additional targeted sanctions with respect to foreign persons on the list required by subsection (a) to push for accountability for flagrant denials of the right to life, liberty, or the security of the person, through the use of designations and targeted sanctions provided for such conduct under other existing authorities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H642D67B8D9C64A0884657FA137B04FF4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> <subparagraph id="HBCA7B865B65141948DF2E8BE89FF3982"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exception with respect to national security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply with respect to—</text> 
<clause id="H5CB4CE1F39CB4F39A13D1ACFE6124A79"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause> <clause id="H9D7BF7C9C1C0482BAD444F183A237D2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any authorized intelligence or law enforcement activities of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C7129CC4EE14B69A693FDD67F4E254B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply with respect to a person if admitting or paroling the person into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States or other applicable international obligations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H702DDAD7DE914B47A11379B61D598946"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception for certain immediate family members</header> <clause id="HA5306E9F36B54997A28F1981C3ECA6E1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual shall not be subject to sanctions under this section if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees, in accordance with clause (ii), that such individual has a reasonable fear of persecution based on—</text> 
<subclause id="H84E70F1B943448B19C4A24A53F1FC370"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1C68611438C345AAA2F01B9ECB6B0A9A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">race, religion, or nationality; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H209C932D452D4E998E5C728517B1AD74"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">political opinion or membership in a particular social group.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5C2FCB3EECC94F81A1F93885FCEDF953"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination and certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification under clause (i) shall be made not later than 30 days after the date of the determination required by such clause. Any proceedings relating to such determination shall not be publicly available.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF4CC5941CBF34E8D9CD07FAE1434FEEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means an individual who is an immediate family member of foreign person on the list required by subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9D2AE79D38E45A7B0B51F6740AC017B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the application of sanctions or restrictions imposed with respect to a foreign person under this section if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees, not later than 15 days before such waiver is to take effect, that the waiver is vital to the national interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H078469F9A79D4EA4997AB5EE0626A4B8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President, acting through the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text> <paragraph id="HFC59DD9B98A8461E80A02BF3A0923417"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the actions taken to carry out this section, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF8CCDA82FBEA4D8E9B42002E20B04025"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of foreign persons added to or removed from the list required by subsection (a) during the year preceding each such report, the dates on which such persons were so added or removed, and the reasons for so adding or removing such persons; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H094DC46EC7714E20A955B31A2B00BD4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis that compares increases or decreases in the number of such persons added or removed year-over-year and the reasons therefor;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D6FE5A8F92D43CFBD50431CB0C1920C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any efforts by the President to coordinate with the governments of other countries, as appropriate, to impose sanctions that are similar to the sanctions imposed under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94F0318176A44146AA9A79FB4E858B00"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the sanctions imposed under this section with respect to altering the behavior of each of the foreign persons included, as of the date of submission of the report, in the list required by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB22861C17B70442C9D109B33FA0DD4E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">steps the Department can take to improve coordination with foreign governments, civil society groups, and the private sector, to prevent the commission of the human rights violations described in section 3(a)(1) against persons based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAB377E5D196F426E9E91FEAAD987E1FF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Form; publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (f) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex. The unclassified portion of such report shall be published on a publicly available website of the Department of State.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F18971AD7744A2B9E8B243675E15083"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7F44BF884125492D9AF12A92EB6354BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H75EA10A3FF504FA68A1B591772133A87"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE0BC0E43A04499F8BCAD57625C05F9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D05DBD45E244991876D298D16C141DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>immediate family member</quote> has the meaning given such term for purposes of section 7031(c) of division K of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H639FAFC9B1F740F29207E8C1FD457631"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to allow the imposition of sanctions with respect to, or otherwise authorize any other action against, any foreign person based solely upon religious belief.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF900B111D74E4A78BFE5F06FBFE8D75A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Discrimination related to sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics</header> 
<subsection id="H6794BF63EBFE47B28B4FEB3E66D33A9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tracking violence or criminalization related to sexual orientation or gender identity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor shall designate 1 or more bureau-based senior officer or officers, who shall be responsible for tracking violence, criminalization, and restrictions on the enjoyment of fundamental freedoms in foreign countries based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H07189FF2DEB1401F80CD71F53A3FB1DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual country reports on human rights practices</header><text>The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7674FCEDD0D46EF907AA27070C6C6CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 116(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H582C0D9075EF4EB088905995C181251E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (11)(C), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB84491AD41854B75A866AA98CB3FB97A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)—</text> <clause id="H3622C864FB174A2085D2B77AD9B9C26F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA77F8BF2C2E84739BE0F636A19DA8618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28779A2505744880AD6F1B2AB8902B48"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB51584A1DD4B43FAB2374A9974B8B4E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HB157BC158E0B4736A9AC33FCD91F3BB7"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherever applicable, information relating to violence or discrimination that affects fundamental freedoms, including widespread or systematic violation of the freedoms of expression, association, or assembly, of individuals in foreign countries that is based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H390E5DEC11864A469512559765560671"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 502B(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(b)</external-xref>), by inserting after the ninth sentence the following new sentence: <quote>Wherever applicable, such report shall also include information relating to violence or discrimination that affects the fundamental freedoms, including widespread or systematic violation of the freedoms of expression, association, or assembly, of individuals in foreign countries that is based on actual or perceived sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


