<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H03011115254A4F3F9A1CC076DA587D20" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9331 IH: Strengthening Transaction Oversight and Preventing Payments Fraud Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9331</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Expedited Funds Availability Act to provide exceptions in the case of fraudulent checks or wire transfers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H99C2451602B64C13B1AFAA1368195A42" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7AEB5F0CD43C4FDEB264F67FBC3E1B70" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Transaction Oversight and Preventing Payments Fraud Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Payments Fraud Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H929CF524C4C64D10995E511B7245784C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Parity of availability for certain checks</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Expedited Funds Availability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4001">12 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subsection id="H897BA05295A648CD999EB6C4D0A9D61A"><enum>(a)</enum><text>in section 603 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4002">12 U.S.C. 4002</external-xref>)—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA70EF8B673924FCE910EA3D4CB350C4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA98A7427D5944BC899E3B1BC40D2BFAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (A) and (F);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FB55EDF3CC349758E06DD7C7550A80B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (E) as subparagraphs (A) through (D), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H680B68FD24474811A052A3D0B9329D82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), as so redesignated, by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H572993155C8C4A569B1CA928DE6EF78C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking paragraph (1) and the heading to paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE70F6A57AF8B4B91ADB70E1DD5E31231"><enum>(b)</enum><text>in section 604(a)(1)(D), by striking <quote>subparagraph (A), (B), or (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H439AE063BEA844B99BCD81799751FBD1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exception to funds availability requirements in the case of fraud</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 604(c) of the Expedited Funds Availability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4003">12 U.S.C. 4003(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFA103A6FD83B489987CF8FAC4F270A5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the heading of the paragraph, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Collectability</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FCC5C5EF42D4D7797B9C57904B6535A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (4) as paragraphs (3) through (5), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC02390DAD54647BB920010DE587BC23E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0C090248D54C4158995DC8C89061A2D3" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H3CC72E2165294EBB843F2F73B6B6422A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fraud</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3ED1972293084BD88C51B49AF5D5F0E9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with regulations which the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, shall prescribe, subsections (a)(2), (b), (c), and (e) of section 603 shall not apply with respect to any check deposited in an account at a depository institution if the receiving depository institution has reasonable suspicion to believe that the check is false, unauthorized, or otherwise involves fraud. For purposes of the preceding sentence, reasonable suspicion to believe that a check is false, unauthorized, or otherwise involves fraud requires the existence of indicators that would lead a reasonable person to suspect that the check involves fraud. Such reasons shall be included in the notice required under subsection (f).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2AEFFDBF623A40A093F7666FD74F1EE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A receiving depository institution that has reasonable suspicion to believe that a check is false, unauthorized, or otherwise involves fraud, as described in subparagraph (A), may also have reasonable cause to believe that such check is uncollectible from the originating depository institution, as described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC4540213108478182D76B386D20CC83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1) or (2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H2AD23BB5EE2245D5ACA480DB19481256"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exception to funds availability requirements in the case of new accounts and fraudulent wire transfers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 604 of the Expedited Funds Availability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4003">12 U.S.C. 4003</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H683FF14D39CA4D969F7C5B8FE87DDA5C" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HD32442F8D8FC45C4BC495F41510545C8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application of certain exceptions in circumstances with greater fraud risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an account established at a depository institution, and without regard to whether the account was established by a new depositor, upon the occurrence of circumstances identified by rule by the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, as associated with greater fraud risk, the provisions of paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any deposit in such account for a period of time determined by rule by the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, but not to exceed 60 days for each such occurrence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC78C121CD5914DC390B0751706E6F4C3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reasonable suspicion exception for wire transfers</header> <paragraph id="HC370603C20474C0C862F5DC742B51C71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with regulations which the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, shall prescribe, section 603(a)(1)(B) shall not apply with respect to funds received by a depository institution by wire transfer if the receiving depository institution has reasonable suspicion to believe that the wire transfer is false, unauthorized, or otherwise involves fraud. For purposes of the preceding sentence, reasonable suspicion to believe that a wire transfer is false, unauthorized, or otherwise involves fraud requires the existence of indicators that would lead a reasonable person to suspect that the wire transfer involves fraud. Such reasons shall be included in the notice required under subsection (f).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC44C696BD2F44780AD0AABB9B50329E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basis for determination</header><text>No determination under this subsection may be based on any class of wire transfers or persons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19FB76EE9F6E4B708286BC648AA65645"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Overdraft fees</header><text>If the receiving depository institution determines that a wire transfer for credit to an account is a wire transfer described in paragraph (1), the receiving depository institution shall not assess any fee for any subsequent overdraft with respect to such account, if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H727311D7E76D42C99E400B85291D1CD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the depositor was not provided with the written notice required under subsection (f) (with respect to such determination) at the time the wire transfer was delayed for credit; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A09002F5B8342BF982DE9FFDD240735"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the overdraft would not have occurred but for the fact that the funds so transferred are not available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADAE98563B2D46249C32A3E22293063A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Each agency referred to in section 610(a) shall monitor compliance with the requirements of this subsection in each regular examination of a depository institution. For the purpose of this paragraph, each depository institution shall retain a record of each notice provided under subsection (f) as a result of the application of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8736DE193A9E4F37A1B24A45DA6FDD5C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to restrict or prohibit a depository institution involved with a deposit by check or wire transfer from communicating to any other depository institution also involved with the deposit that a depository institution has invoked an exception under this section to some or all of the requirements of section 603 with respect to the deposit.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

