<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25H43-44W-18-4NK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3515 IS: To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly select a joint uniform credentialing and privileging system for medical providers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3515</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly select a joint uniform credentialing and privileging system for medical providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H11CAEF5AF14E43A5946B07D0D7C9634F"><section id="HB4666C4E0A78462A80B8A8763034EBD2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Joint uniform credentialing and privileging system for medical providers at the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H7FEB9B5062B845A2AF091D42A1D8D429"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2812df446aa54a15b7a90f3cb9b54782"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Domestic Policy Council, shall jointly submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the medical provider credentialing and privileging systems in use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida824a6b574b7422ba6f4701d84ff5a32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall include each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA100E7EC953B4E11BA82AA245E97A072"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the scope and scale of the medical provider credentialing and privileging systems in use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D293B9EFED34BC5B05BC9D70AF37B1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the type of data stored on each system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85868BB71F3D4E8DB1F2A63457B9A871"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the portability of provider credentialing and privileging information under each system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC2FFE517C1D4C668FF6A36D455CA954"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the interoperability between provider credentialing systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA23A1CA668554A9787D6ADD440A4CEB4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of the risk management system, adverse actions, and governance of each system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F4277B5F3F2437DB4489477FFF77A77"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of the limitations and gaps in the interoperability and administration of each system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7EE24501884474990DCBC3CF6F5C92A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Recommendations for scaling each system and addressing gaps in the interoperability and administration of each system, with the goal of achieving a single, uniform system to be used by both the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73BF6899453A4C21B3CABB266E4D3CB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Domestic Policy Council, shall jointly select one system from the systems in use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to serve as the joint uniform credentialing and privileging system for both the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H05E33DBB25AF4E5EAD5C0B9D93D3BABF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capability of system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that the joint uniform credentialing and privileging system selected under subsection (b) has the capability to import and share provider credentialing and privileging information.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3E6A933C05DF4F0E8BD065A124D8E38E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification of implementation</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2028, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written certification that the joint uniform credentialing and privileging system selected under subsection (b) has been implemented and is operational.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3a68b7034f5f4bb5a9235eb8450cd705"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba84c6683a8749249b8593a07c51cdd0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca80eb6a3b0d48928315c2f58fbe49f6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

