<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB3557849436A4D5AAEDBBE47ACFAF178" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7839 IH: Safe Standards for Personal E-bike and E-moto Device Specifications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7839</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Consumer Product Safety Commission to promulgate a consumer product safety standard for the uniform classification and labeling of certain electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5CE2268AA77B4C2FBC1A42228E9C634F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDB648E02227746B89F9CB0492A68C2F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Standards for Personal E-bike and E-moto Device Specifications Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Safe SPEEDS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE77F0F11EA7A4B7282E7CB536D046CF2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer product safety standard for low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices</header> 
<subsection id="H95D35AF4F24D402583D317DA249040E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, a final consumer product safety standard for the uniform classification and labeling of low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices that are manufactured in, offered for sale to a consumer in, or imported into the United States.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H84F6AA83B1A74B93A54B0D2EF37B17E1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Analysis; consultation; evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2E230340B3A845F3AD6E2B1FDF33D70B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent feasible, conduct and publish an analysis with respect to any crash, injury, and fatality associated with the use of a low-speed electric bicycle or any other off-road electric device reported during the 5-year period that precedes the date of the enactment of this Act, disaggregated by—</text> <subparagraph id="H15B8491D8071412688A4D3612CAA2A58" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the age of the user of the bicycle or device; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H951046354FA2472CBCA8FFF06A91BFBF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the type of bicycle or device, including—</text> <clause id="HE37C4012DC0B4137B3539C4B97CC29BA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the bicycle or device involved in the crash, injury, or fatality is a low-speed electric bicycle, any other off-road electric device described in subsection (h)(7)(A), or another bicycle or device; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7896D2EB60664D6096AED103EA1E1EC8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the bicycle or device is a low-speed electric bicycle, the classification of the bicycle as a class 1 electric bicycle, class 2 electric bicycle, class 3 electric bicycle (as defined in section 217(j)(2) of title 23, United States Code), or as none of such classifications.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD84714C57D3E493EB39D130914C1C4C5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluate the efficacy of Federal, State, and local laws, regulatory guidance, industry best practices, and international standards related to classifying, labeling, and establishing age restrictions for low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices (including the classifications of class 1 electric bicycle, class 2 electric bicycle, or class 3 electric bicycle as defined in section 217(j)(2) of title 23, United States Code) to determine whether the Commission should consider any such law, regulatory guidance, or best practice in carrying out the requirements described in subsection (c).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA25B1052A31C4B57A09D39CA5B09B547" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent feasible and appropriate, consult with the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H37467DE0D4CD4C9B847C4C5889CA0611"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Manufacturers, importers, and sellers of low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H465B774DCCAF4066B2F7BF643D55FBA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Independent product safety engineers and experts.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFC55C99A8CF4F2C9A1EC1D3BF64D7EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Representatives of consumer and transportation safety advocacy groups.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD7A4FE12B9648738D26ADE4C00F08EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69DBFED21A2A4752A704EED70A548EAF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other entity as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5B924C338CDE4AFD8873C00893AB5265" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on the analysis, evaluation, and consultation required under subsection (b), the Commission shall ensure the standard promulgated under subsection (a) includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="HB8B64F2177EF438AA612CF0EC709150E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions of distinct classifications for low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H236D66AA73454E44B4DCA7C6788E859D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Minimum age recommendations for the use of low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices with respect to each classification defined pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8886B401096F4F3F8E836159B3443226" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that a low-speed electric bicycle or any other off-road electric device—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6B86F6B77184B829430A420B020B020" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>satisfies a classification defined pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H874543F7236F4168B71A7D6073249D84" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes, at the time a low-speed electric bicycle or any other off-road electric device is offered for sale, a permanent, clearly visible, and consistently placed label on such bicycle or device that specifies—</text> 
<clause id="HC24BC34BC3624FD5814111C75EA67D48" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the classification satisfied;</text></clause> <clause id="HE7BB01BC149449F4B897CC607EF9885C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the motor power of the bicycle or device;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H19D33299F2E34E46A4DF7F7538E23ECB" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the maximum speed of the bicycle or device when powered solely by a motor;</text></clause> <clause id="H656192D9773D45B8AF87AF987B4E0133" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the relevant minimum age recommendation described in paragraph (2); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2C4F4CFA515D40BC803BD31E87386E81" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any other off-road electric device described in subsection (h)(7)(A), any such device—</text> <subclause id="H4C6BCD41BE264EA09723CA168E8E680A" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is not intended for on-road use; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H810C7F0C5F0F4C318818F1998F547A32" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not satisfy any motor vehicle safety standard prescribed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37981F552E9A476F8242BFF5E94A5ECE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A prohibition on the sale, offer for sale to a consumer, or display of a consumer product labeled as a low-speed electric bicycle that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H06BF947D6CCA44728704FDF50B7FD565" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not satisfy the definition of a low-speed electric bicycle;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8F6CA77CCA94B7F96CDED6A3D0DCF4F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designed, manufactured, or displayed by the manufacturer, importer, or seller of the consumer product to have the capacity to be configured or modified to increase the maximum speed or motor power of the consumer product such that the consumer product would no longer satisfy such definition; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05509FE805324B729405F6B48369BCDD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designed, manufactured, or displayed by the manufacturer, importer, or seller for off-road use and does not have operable pedals.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H2818CAF112844AFA8C3810A00512EE81"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text>At any time after the promulgation of the standard under subsection (a), the Commission may, through a rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, modify the requirements of the standard.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA742553C5BC14E8DB975045F96A311BA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of standard</header><text>A standard promulgated under this section, including a modification of such standard, shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule promulgated under section 9 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2058">15 U.S.C. 2058</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9CA1A07EAC0D49B3877A2B7CFFE5E6FB" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Analysis on crashes, injuries, and fatalities</header> <paragraph id="H318D0C3C144C473EAB9BEC9FD195EA83" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the promulgation of the standard under subsection (a), and periodically thereafter at regular intervals, the Commission shall conduct an analysis of any crash, injury, and fatality associated with the use of a low-speed electric bicycle or any other off-road electric device reported beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act or on the date of the publication of the most recent analysis conducted under this paragraph, whichever date is later, disaggregated by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFCB1724DB6B84FBC83279029A9C9DC56" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the age of the user of the bicycle or device; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E6C92B6ADA543BC9395914EBBBF6809"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type of bicycle or device, including—</text> 
<clause id="HF484A969D9844FA8A2F8E5424D4D6425"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the bicycle or device involved in the crash, injury, or fatality is—</text> <subclause id="H592BEB5A3F664E2CAC5C23C6F89A3BD5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a low-speed electric bicycle;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HEC949A58249846E298E9C28518FA3551" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other off-road electric device described in subsection (h)(7)(A); or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3103387A35774016A2373052AE10E7C2"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a bicycle or device that—</text> 
<item id="HD4DC965503394ADD91BC0710BB1D44DE" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>does not satisfy—</text> <subitem id="H59A481B0DCBE452583E388FFC25C7361" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>a classification defined pursuant to subsection (c)(1); or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H8BCDF8A448DD4D7394F3142A240B2914" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a requirement described in subsection (c)(3); or</text></subitem></item> <item id="H529325CDE8244FF7B9E86C19FA218933"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>violates the prohibition described in subsection (c)(4); and</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFD671BEB387E4E628BD0E1E2B5089BF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the classification defined pursuant to subsection (c)(1) that each such bicycle or device satisfies.</text> </clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H32C4B844E85843FBB62747549DB8B45E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Commission shall consult with a relevant entity and any other entity as the Commission determines feasible and appropriate to conduct any study required by paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9CA4DE5713A48C9BAF21469B44EBE27" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Redundancy</header><text>In conducting any study required by paragraph (1), the Commission shall avoid duplicating information to the fullest extent practicable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD46CBA3A54FD4741864C64A2305FA415" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report; publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which any study required by paragraph (1) is completed, the Commission shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A8F02ED52EB47ECBACB9F7E4AF2BBE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report on the findings of the study; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H518390F6EB094935A2C6C043ECF8AC7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish the study on a website of the Commission in a publicly accessible format.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF11D0B1963AE41888997F16CD4C2FAF9" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Grants; training module</header> 
<paragraph id="H0BC15712D9CB42FEACA23342F6C540C5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="H750CB04A06F541E28494851907CFC50A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031, the Commission shall award grants to relevant entities to carry out the following:</text> <clause id="HF7A9160BA241409898C3E9795E678494" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Hire and train personnel to ensure sufficient capacity and expertise for data collection, reporting, and recordkeeping related to any crash, injury, or fatality associated with low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices, including for the identification and classification of such bicycles pursuant to the classifications defined pursuant to subsection (c)(1).</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H250A63CC4BB0435EB4411F4AC4FA3BDE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Develop and implement—</text> <subclause id="HCC4314EA79CE4A83B9E33DD066E0738C" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policies, guidance, or best practices to assist with the compliance or enforcement of this Act in relation to other applicable Federal, State, and local laws, including policies, guidance, or best practices for manufacturers, importers, or sellers of low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5281DB91865841B88F7DA6C4A384FCC6" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>data collection and reporting protocols to enable the standardization, accuracy, and comprehensiveness of data on any crash, injury, or fatality associated with low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H220BB366E98B40C2A9DE805E21A08E80"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public education and safety initiatives to improve awareness of safety risks associated with the use of low-speed electric bicycles and other off-road electric devices, including education and initiatives related the standard promulgated under subsection (a) and the requirements described in subsection (c).</text></subclause> </clause> 
<clause id="H209B452A7C51464681A3190D07892E23" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other purpose the Commission determines necessary to support any study required by subsection (f)(1).</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27AA5268ADCD4E2B8F41BB9F5E730270" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission $2,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to award grants under this subsection.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0327EF82813A4E00ABE213ACDE283492" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training Module</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall develop a publicly accessible training module to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD538BEAECC764571A5D3DE553A620B1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instruct relevant entities on how to identify and classify a low-speed electric bicycle and any other off-road electric device based on the standard promulgated under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB0779483A4E46D88B678CBFDF7DB897"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve the standardization, accuracy, and comprehensiveness of data collection and reporting with respect to any crash, injury, or fatality associated with such bicycles and devices.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H9BC30CE0F09940B89EF767E3C711356A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H06FDF8D2FC754EADA8B499C53B24B9FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60DCABCFEF6F4EE98E259020985A2ECA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consumer product</header><text>The term <quote>consumer product</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2052">15 U.S.C. 2052</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B046DC1DE9447D1A4517676A3F1A777" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1C69F4534334E3795C05EC5CE72ADA3" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <quote>local government</quote> means any unit of government within a State, including the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9C6F2C3B0A8447DE93E47917A20ED7EB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A city.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H679B46457BCB49BCB5FD5E5BA5731B1B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A town.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A1F86BE2D324C709169BBF7FE678D6C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A county.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E84A9876A164A819C82867C8EB6C679" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A municipality.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5AD5008D4944BD89A15C5573172C03E" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A special district.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F963F94474D47F8A96F0F49A5E26A79" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A school district.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2BEA3880829840DBA50214C968576C64" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other agency or instrumentality of a State or local government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E255B23EFD24DCC8E6D0E2A6D8DFDF9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Low-speed electric bicycle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>low-speed electric bicycle</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 38 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2085">15 U.S.C. 2085</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EE5137A25134724A0FAF2E444AD99BA" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Native Hawaiian organization</header><text>The term <quote>Native Hawaiian organization</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C2CD7D885F94DBB84B02ECB11BA029F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an organization that—</text> 
<clause id="H511F2AEBCF004209AFDEF3480BB3032C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serves and represents the interests of Native Hawaiians;</text></clause> <clause id="H0A5B1E50D8F54FABAD0AE3DA878C91C6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides services to Native Hawaiians; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE72ED08B02AE4D87A03E97D8297800F9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has expertise in Native Hawaiian affairs; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10DA4A63E4384158B0426A382D241C2A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes Native Hawaiian organizations registered with Office of Native Hawaiian Relations of the Department of the Interior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9771A7B35518489483D4CEB67E51FFD9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Other off-road electric device</header><text>The term <quote>other off-road electric device</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB8C2911C3E14F76BE5B2D4360DCED77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a consumer product that—</text> 
<clause id="H18D5812423364D148BB08ABB4607F4B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is designed, manufactured, or recommended by the manufacturer, importer, or seller for off-road use;</text></clause> <clause id="HA919702CDA9D4566A73D7FE1E2E8F1C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is powered by an electric motor;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3876BA799DBD410B98257A2B2DD2427E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may or may not have operable pedals; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HBFD2CAB02EFB48D48574753AE2E3441C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is equipped with—</text> 
<subclause id="HD05BA40B99E849C19FADC9D9B733090D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fewer than 4 wheels;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H98DC2779972741A8821AAE1D0C373A76"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a seat or saddle designed to be straddled by the user of the consumer product; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1185DDF80C044818A37ECC4DF901D71E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>handlebars for steering control of the user; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1A7A85E61BA432A8434841DE21F4ACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other consumer product as determined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65D8019D14B84F809732A3431C8727AA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Relevant entity</header><text>The term <quote>relevant entity</quote> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H91E2F8E17F254E8D8E0D24FF1F6729FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A law enforcement agency.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A3F7A8BEF314F16BA18FEF074927A74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An emergency management service agency that is—</text> <clause id="H3D7932ECC0B5432D898C9CA08A5416D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>operated by a State, local, or Tribal government or Native Hawaiian organization; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H87FAE46B231340299E91093A587FAE4E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>described in section 501(c) of title 26, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4E7CFD29E1B4F56B0F5CA9F7F16063B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A State.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8CAE91C218DE4A31ADC86559976E293A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A local government.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE3239C2F0F14272937230F6B90CA6C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A Tribal government.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F20AF50F9E0409787B77683CFEFE293"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A Native Hawaiian organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7951FD90EB747438F81EE6B0A53BFAD"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F35CF4206124330A9A2A43817DE721F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <quote>Tribal government</quote> means the recognized governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

