<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H27F3D91E581445389E35D71C68D5B08B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1097 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States, and directing the Secretaries of the Treasury and Homeland Security, to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the implementation and enforcement of the “Memorandum of Understanding for the Exchange of Information for Nontax Criminal Enforcement” between the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Homeland Security.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1097</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States, and directing the Secretaries of the Treasury and Homeland Security, to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the implementation and enforcement of the <quote>Memorandum of Understanding for the Exchange of Information for Nontax Criminal Enforcement</quote> between the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Homeland Security.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3F774263613C4F30A79FF4632D2F61FD"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF8EE0462277D4C18B26FCE1A8F63D661" commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President of the United States is requested, and the Secretaries of the Treasury and Homeland Security are directed, to furnish to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days following the adoption of this resolution, copies, with appropriate redactions to the extent necessary to comply with Federal law, of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), audit trail, audit log, written agreement, or other communication, or any portion of any of the foregoing, in the possession of the President or the Secretaries, that refers or relates to the implementation or enforcement of the <quote>Memorandum of Understanding for the Exchange of Information for Nontax Criminal Enforcement</quote> (hereinafter the <quote>Memorandum of Understanding</quote>) between the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Homeland Security, including (but not limited to) the following:</text> <paragraph id="H536146F150BC4594B698A5927EE69DDB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any request by, or disclosure or provision of access to, the Department of Homeland Security with respect to any return information (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(b)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of any taxpayer, including (but not limited to) information from any of the following Systems of Records:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF34A620CBEED459D9D7EF35F43A942BD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Treasury/IRS 22.060 - Automated Non-Master File, 80 FR 54064 (Sept. 8, 2015).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32CA8CB8D23E4E7484783EC839ECF5C3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Treasury/IRS 22.061 - Information Return Master File, 80 FR 54064 (Sept. 8, 2015).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE00D79F6FA4B43D7A18FCCF4870A076A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Treasury/IRS 24.030 - Customer Account Data Engine Individual Master File, 80 FR 54064 (Sept. 8, 2015).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H118035175D574EA5A19DF999C88E9A8C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Treasury/IRS 24.046 - Customer Account Data Engine Business Master File, 80 FR 54064 (Sept. 8, 2015).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB79FD7289064C9DAF31DF83D68C6302" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Treasury/IRS 34.037 - Audit Trail and Security Records, 80 FR 54064 (Sept. 8, 2015).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8C9B8CAD3BA4EF085CA07B9D71A563C" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Treasury/IRS 42.008 - Audit Information Management System, 80 FR 54064 (Sept. 8, 2015).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF40FD4EEA87E43D98CF53CF07513AF10" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any policy, procedure, standard, or guideline of the Department of the Treasury or the Department of Homeland Security that refers or relates to the handling of any information described in paragraph (1) pursuant to the Memorandum of Understanding.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D53DCDB0D22495BBE9D77905A6E579E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information that refers or relates to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HADF91750F5124ED6A9B3385CFF391C92"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the implementation or enforcement of, or compliance with, any policy, procedure, standard, or guideline described in paragraph (2),</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3917BC449E8047DA98734333400F6149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any request by, or disclosure or provision of access to, the Department of Homeland Security with respect to any information described in paragraph (1) in violation of—</text> 
<clause id="H50D49AF5F1CD4B1C8FD7A2A39924239F"><enum>(i)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or</text></clause> <clause id="H4A327EA9789E4FECAB72002896412D5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any policy, procedure, standard, or guideline described in paragraph (2), and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H154E820D2ACD4C6E93416665C7B81FDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the discovery of, and all subsequent action (both taken and considered) with respect to, any violation described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body></resolution>

