<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25968-DP1-8N-GM0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3112 IS: Fairness for Fruits and Vegetables Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3112</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251105">November 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to establish an interagency seasonal and perishable fruits and vegetables working group, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fairness for Fruits and Vegetables Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id256199c3985545cc90664a1b99ff4aec" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency seasonal and perishable fruits and vegetable working group</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle B of title IV of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5671">7 U.S.C. 5671 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id0F2B35CEA0194D2097A3176D75207F88" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id5fb1fd99854848bfba35932081617e86"><enum>418.</enum><header>Interagency seasonal and perishable fruits and vegetables working group</header><subsection id="id181fa206f0c34b7c837281f1e8511d64" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs, the United States Trade Representative, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other Federal agencies or entities, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary, shall jointly establish an interagency working group (referred to in this section as the <term>working group</term>) composed of representatives from each agency to monitor and assess, on an ongoing basis, seasonal and perishable fruits and vegetables trade data and related information.</text></subsection><subsection id="iddcb67d6649104619a6c48e41183a1dec" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trade actions and investigations</header><text>The working group shall coordinate as appropriate regarding potential additional trade actions and investigations with respect to any seasonal or perishable agricultural products, as determined to be advisable by the working group.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb66cd4f8a0d74ab7a5bcd6bfed938942" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The working group shall consult with the Agricultural Trade Advisory Committee, relevant seasonal or perishable agricultural producers, and other relevant trade associations to identify threats that imports pose to domestic producers of seasonal and perishable fruits and vegetables.</text></subsection><subsection id="id41066f16638545f69bedb7e5a707c6c6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recommendations to Secretary</header><text>The working group shall recommend programs or assistance that the Secretary could provide to producers of seasonal and perishable fruits and vegetables to address market impacts.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

