<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT25426-NP1-MP-095"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3475 IS: To authorize, ratify, and confirm the Agreement of Settlement and Compromise to Resolve the Akwesasne Mohawk Land Claim in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251215">December 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize, ratify, and confirm the Agreement of Settlement and Compromise to Resolve the Akwesasne Mohawk Land Claim in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H37CDEB6F73FD4E4A850A2F679165B69F"><section id="id730fd7cecb36459fb6f80088f1b417cf" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Agreement and transfers authorized, ratified and confirmed</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following are hereby authorized, ratified, and confirmed:</text><paragraph id="id04d08db8f48f44b2922ccf2a3de460eb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Agreement of Settlement and Compromise to Resolve the Akwesasne Mohawk Land Claim in the State of New York (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Settlement Agreement</quote>), entered into by the Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe, the Mohawk Council of Akwesasne, the State of New York, the Counties of Franklin and Saint Lawrence, New York, the Towns of Fort Covington and Bombay, New York, and the New York Power Authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2267ca0b11084654a3b1a960fded7778"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>Any transfer of land, right-of-way, or easement that is the subject of the claims in the Canadian Saint Regis Band of Mohawk Indians v. New York et al. (82–CV–783); the Canadian Saint Regis Band of Mohawk Indians v. New York et al. (82–CV–1114); and the Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe, by the Saint Regis Mohawk Tribal Counciland the People of the Longhouse at Akwesasne, by Mohawk Nation Council of Chiefs v. The State of New York, et al. (89–CV–829).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id34bfc8bdf3484d3a9910c50a7b0f4f5e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Lands owned by Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe within settlement acquisition areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following shall be Indian Country as defined in section 1151(a) of title 18, United States Code, subject to the terms, conditions, and limitations of the Settlement Agreement:</text><paragraph id="id4ff4e2bdb1bd450aba4865d2925e5215"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Land owned on the effective date of the Settlement Agreement by the Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe within the Settlement Acquisition Areas, as defined in the Settlement Agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58c785c065c84a1a83c8ce2ca9d5d216" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Land acquired by the Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe within the Settlement Acquisition Areas after the effective date of the Settlement Agreement.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

