<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H724B08E5A0BB4E38AF0F4E924F7686C1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8171 IH: Facilitating Accelerated Supply of Targeted Housing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8171</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260402">April 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a demonstration program to develop workforce housing and affordable housing in areas where the workforce is expanding significantly, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA5A74BDDF2274CD98291C3CDC0434BE8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9010B25B8C3A4C108680CE5247710874" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Facilitating Accelerated Supply of Targeted Housing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAST Housing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA675DE668EBE444189D2559147C12362" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration program for the development of workforce and affordable housing</header> <subsection id="H2CA2B1B2B4614EFC9147852492EA6534" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish a demonstration program to award not more than 15 grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to develop workforce housing and affordable housing in areas within the jurisdiction of such entity where such entity has determined that the workforce is expanding significantly.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H807F7540BEFA492F816B41845A490008"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="H1EF24AB45CAB4FC0BE2BC6439F01A577"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA2A498B7ECD4D5C8899B966B4698558"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required inclusions</header> <subparagraph id="H80FC0C7C934240A4AFF324CF7F2B2753"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In an application for a grant under this subsection, an eligible entity shall include—</text> 
<clause id="HDED15E1638C24038A2BF48BA215749ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of existing laws, regulations, and policies effective in the jurisdiction of such entity that facilitate the development of workforce housing; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1F834325D1964311A6AEC05105BF7050"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of proposed laws, regulations, or policies that such entity intends to adopt that will reform zoning and facilitate the development of workforce housing, and a timeline for the adoption and implementation of such law, regulations, or policies.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF619188D6E9D43A789629A1FFAA8904D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Types of reforms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Types of laws, regulations, or policies that reform zoning and facilitate the development of workforce housing and affordable housing include—</text> <clause id="HEE37B53F7EE946D187E6631CFA93BCAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upzoning, including by-right development of mixed use, higher density, and accessory dwelling units;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA469CC53E7374F3E85EC36C899A6C1A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expedited permitting with set, shortened review timelines;</text></clause> <clause id="HBCEF3FC2AAD24E77A9ECE4FF2BF876F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by-right zoning for multifamily residential development near public transit;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4A3695BF97AB4750B82C3C1836DD12D2" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities that reduce barriers to placing manufactured and modular housing;</text></clause> <clause id="H1E1585A3DB4F4C74842E7DC1F79D2B65"><enum>(v)</enum><text>removal of parking minimums; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCAF82EEFB1C445199C2F0732D08AB6E9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>reductions of minimum lot size requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H65AFD218D34D436D95580DBB9B0E1F6F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities whose removal or streamlining of regulatory barriers has, as determined by the Secretary, most increased the amount of workforce housing and affordable housing in the jurisdiction of such eligible entity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4778BD6A11A04B05A4B7AF36DA9EFF76"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Variety of geographic areas</header><text>When selecting eligible entities to receive amounts under this section, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, to the extent practicable based on the eligible entities that apply, strive to provide amounts to eligible entities in a variety of geographic areas, so that the impact of the demonstration program can be evaluated in urban, suburban, and rural areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC1A924BE8E884705B4F421F0E2D83767"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header> <paragraph id="H9B7E5DD4ED8844E18A5F791F33CBF966"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity shall use any amounts provided under this section to finance—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8AEE7DD8E9384F64A19838F4D49A6403" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>costs associated with converting commercial space into workforce housing and affordable housing though private-public partnerships, including physical improvements, rehabilitation and development of such space;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C16499E4869422FB25D2E0685485F8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>costs associated with developing, rehabilitating, and physically improving workforce housing and affordable housing though private-public partnerships;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38F70BE353DF4C80AAB19E8B9C8C94E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technical assistance for housing developers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E9FCCEEA5474BA784517D6586E1178A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the identification and acquisition of properties that can be used to develop new and rehabilitated workforce housing and affordable housing in high-opportunity, mixed-income neighborhoods.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6D4437A4E294E3D83F8EFA3EECF6EAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>30 percent used for affordable housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity shall ensure that not less than 30 percent of the workforce housing units created, rehabilitated or improved by such eligible entity using amounts provided under this section are affordable housing units.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5FB5ABDC19634854B61F872195570906"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity shall ensure that each workforce housing unit or affordable housing unit created, rehabilitated or improved by such eligible entity using amounts provided under this section remains a workforce housing unit or affordable housing unit for not a period of not less than 5 years and after the conclusion of such period remains in compliance with any requirements established by the Secretary for workforce housing assisted under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9027D04E226A41788A8943715919C8C0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to eligible entities that are awarded a grant under this subsection with respect to using such grant amounts in conjunction with other Federally funded housing assistance programs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H734450F36F834D8B8C87F17C0BD47846"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than 18 months after the Secretary provides a grant under this section, and each year thereafter that the demonstration program is active, conduct a study to examine the effectiveness of the demonstration program that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9354EC21B65C42E199BED9EE4C4FE812" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the impact of the demonstration program on the timeline of approval, construction, and number of new workforce housing units; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF1B6970D9A445B7A1B9D4C7CCAF6A81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a comparison of such timelines in communities that participated in the demonstration program and communities that did not participate in the demonstration program.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3ABD1118DAA5424097BF8DAAA383EA4A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Use of unobligated COVID funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H0241D351A41C476A85AF85CCDDBA3BCD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury shall identify all Covid funds and transfer 10 percent of such amounts to the Secretary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F87EC4731C34E76BA468792C745D3C9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability and use</header><text>Amounts transferred under this section shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H32948E3561B24CB1AE0F8209CAB398E4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE630B19EBB824A05981AC9DA81B74BDF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affordable housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>affordable housing</term> means housing for which the total monthly housing cost payment is not more than 30 percent of the monthly household income for a household earning not more than 80 percent of the area median income.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H736F0E716FE54620AE878ACA67414AC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covid funds</header><text>The term <term>Covid funds</term> means amounts made available under—</text> <subparagraph id="HA63608E15E764DC38720E687FBB182C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Coronavirus Preparedness and Response Supplemental Appropriations Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1AD83BC4195B4C0D9C2B7FA14BB7C2E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Families First Coronavirus Response Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15AF39825F484607AA791B628FB1340C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the CARES Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB64CDB9F779407086E3576D1E1401DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Paycheck Protection Program and Health Care Enhancement Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB2FFFBEDA7C4DA5B517CF211DA5C001"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D2973DD96EB4AE6BBEAA6BB1499805A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the American Rescue Plan Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE28E4E4F2E144A718CB484E763AB01D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a unit of local government or a public housing agency that has can demonstrate that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBC4FA6E7D60D4E918A8F57B6F1020C0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the workforce in its area of jurisdiction has expanded as a result of Federal investments made through the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act or the CHIPS and Science Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A7644A6465D43C09998FEDE85CC5DC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can demonstrate that there is a housing supply shortage in its area of jurisdiction, including by showing low vacancy rates, rapid price increases, or high housing cost burdens.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9484A72B29E54F8390D944F71D61FF71"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public housing agency</header><text>The term <term>public housing agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCE3EBA2779648D081FDFC2D9D80F5C1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BF276C7ED6A49BE89239227063D0056" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Workforce housing</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAC7936AC42024587AADF5026D55D7DED" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>workforce housing</term> means—</text> <clause id="HCEBE3890CA5D4BE8A3401B1EAC105EC5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>housing for which the total monthly housing cost payment does not exceed 30 percent of the amount equal to 120 percent of the median income in the area, as determined by the Secretary, with appropriate adjustments for the size of the household; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC6DA239768464AC69D68D644FF561E4D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing made available for purchase at a rate that does not exceed 110 percent of the median price in the area for a comparable housing unit, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F3E08645B324E2081B6E8CD502A6D54" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>The Secretary may adjust the amounts described in subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that such adjustments are appropriate because of unusually high or low incomes in the area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

