<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN26282-XSC-MR-SW8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>109 S4280 PCS: Security And Freedom Enhancement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 371</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4280</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260413">April 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to reauthorize and reform certain authorities and to provide greater transparency and oversight.</official-title></form><legis-body><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf94e15c538f74d9985cb354e2afe5143"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Security And Freedom Enhancement Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2da0c42378644f3883f39500e5102e91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id585eaa655b634330a6328573f19236f2">TITLE I—Protections for United States persons whose communications are collected under section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4219F90A5B54477BA5EBC3297C369E90">Sec. 101. Query procedure reform.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide107e31b107d42f5981544baa525f184">Sec. 102. Annual reports.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id2ab3d178c75f4ebfa690e5546704453b">Sec. 103. Accountability and reporting procedures for compliance violations relating to queries conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id917381f5222846e6a48e4dbd19706e9e">Sec. 104. Prohibition on reverse targeting of United States persons and persons located in the United States.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id74b1eb29f9ea4ce2a7571e0f06f744cf">Sec. 105. FISA court review of targeting decisions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida787449dce6d418893304e2a50e6793b">Sec. 106. Sunset of changes to definition of electronic communication service provider.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idd8a7ae0b7a414544bb47731ef03d2401">Sec. 107. Limitation on directives under Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 relating to certain electronic communication service providers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idcd0055fa7a9b42f485a3636bbb262b2f">Sec. 108. Extension of title VII of FISA; expiration of FISA authorities; effective dates.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id16d47639b3d04921a3c61d540cc44fd8">TITLE II—Additional reforms relating to activities under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id8922be92db73442a9ee81c1889983dee">Sec. 201. Required disclosure of information and limits on use of certain information and on issuance of orders.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0529396acafd4e7bbc8b1957081e097d">Sec. 202. Criminal penalties for violations of FISA.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idd678c10555c54bd58f8e7e476b37d2bf">Sec. 203. Agency procedures To ensure compliance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id97D531366F3F4109BD21B95B8AA1C93A">Sec. 204. Limit on civil immunity for providing information, facilities, or technical assistance to the Government absent a court order.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id234912ab26dd464cbb82ad5b624bcaa7">Sec. 205. Prohibition on avoiding disclosure obligations through parallel construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id578b3b528ccb47c88d90efd1a168626c">Sec. 206. Sunset on grandfather clause of FISA’s business records provision.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="ide096ba32717041f68e28b8de3a304357">TITLE III—Reforms relating to proceedings before the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court and other courts</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6355e91d0f2a4efc907314178ec4f3ac">Sec. 301. Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court reform.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc62f7a7638e749e5b8140b8a86f21e4e">Sec. 302. Public disclosure and declassification of certain documents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida5ce82174f414413a54da889d110f8d2">Sec. 303. Technical amendment to contempt power of FISC and FISC-R.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="ide4bda9fd9bca4c479ca1707096d380f2">TITLE IV—Independent executive branch oversight</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id38e487c8db3941dbb375e0b7e36fd8b8">Sec. 401. Periodic audit of FISA compliance by Inspector General.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id40ca36f68f7a4ab78dee72b6313b1aac">TITLE V—Protections for United States persons whose sensitive information is purchased by intelligence and law enforcement agencies</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idedc959f7e7384fd1b8bb384e8b8150bb">Sec. 501. Limitation on intelligence acquisition of United States person data.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id61615acbc11b424fa0bed408638c52f1">Sec. 502. Limitation on law enforcement purchase of personal data from data brokers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idbde1866b68674116bcc0762519c8ee20">Sec. 503. Consistent protections for demands for data held by interactive computing services.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6a6f03e54b49407497fab496e2f10200">Sec. 504. Consistent privacy protections for data held by data brokers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9219ee40dece42e3a0633723940d366e">Sec. 505. Protection of data entrusted to intermediary or ancillary service providers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idc9f00f7466ca40f58c02700ce71c9332">TITLE VI—Transparency</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idde54c258021f432093c9e1c596bcd177">Sec. 601. Enhanced reports by Director of National Intelligence.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb2cc630b48504666a9d09aa7510fbd94">Sec. 602. Notification to Congress of certain unauthorized disclosures.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idb06a326cb10b4d69bcb4830d06b98b63">TITLE VII—Limited delays in implementation</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idbf41a31b1ecc484dbaa4ee562f728e01">Sec. 701. Limited delays in implementation.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="id585eaa655b634330a6328573f19236f2" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Protections for United States persons whose communications are collected under section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978</header><section id="id4219F90A5B54477BA5EBC3297C369E90"><enum>101.</enum><header>Query procedure reform</header><subsection id="idEC251092054C430B975652BA29B51F69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory audits of United States person queries conducted by Federal Bureau of Investigation</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idEC3F7C368D864109BAFBD84BF0CF8F17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Department of Justice shall conduct an audit that reviews each covered query, as defined in paragraph (8) of section 702(f) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(f)</external-xref>), as redesignated and amended by subsection (b) of this section, conducted during the 180-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, and during each 180-day period thereafter.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38AC785328B74C65A6FE7962797C9DA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Completion of audit</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4402feada58d432a86cf734e677f9fab"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of each 180-day period described in paragraph (1), the Department of Justice shall complete the audit described in such paragraph with respect to such 180-day period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddff9c703474d40779a4e7f3905be0f1e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after completing each audit required under paragraph (1), the Department of Justice shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress the complete and unredacted results of the audit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf176406a40a410ca7d5819e00f8259f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Briefing regarding untimely audits</header><text>If the Department of Justice fails to complete and send the results of an audit required under paragraph (1) to the appropriate committees of Congress on or before the date that 120 days after the end of the 180-day period to which the audit relates, not later than 127 days after the end of such 180-day period, the Department of Justice shall conduct an in-person briefing with the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50b8a03088b445c68f90c2d9a8dfb167"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><clause id="id9f760b282c204fa9bac9e8647c979fc2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the congressional intelligence committees (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="id2fb73e2c11cd423ab980f096b40a035e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="id017354bda3d84116b0e60b0439f107cf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c92b789304a4d76bd15aaa87c206e2b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Repeal of superseded audit requirement</header><text>Section 2(c) of the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref> note) is repealed. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id22612CF0575C470E94D37B5CC9B40B6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restrictions relating to conduct of certain queries by federal bureau of investigation</header><text>Section 702(f) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(f)</external-xref>) is amended— </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a4b80c2548c470b98678abfb51beb84"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (8); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC06A9E9390084DFCBA58BA0DC44E8AA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting before paragraph (8), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC84B0F32587443209B7C5AC976802864"><paragraph id="idD2AB1C1522184AA4A6722FF54643573E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Querying procedures applicable to Federal Bureau of Investigation</header><text>For any procedures adopted under paragraph (1) applicable to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall include the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="id1DA7FBBCC56B438E99EBFF9D34175C0F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Training</header><text>A requirement that, prior to conducting any query, and on an annual basis thereafter as a prerequisite for continuing to conduct queries, personnel of the Federal Bureau of Investigation successfully complete training on the querying procedures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id371932C1F7E2483681809F2133F21B97"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional prior approvals for sensitive queries</header><text>A requirement that, absent exigent circumstances, prior to conducting certain queries, personnel of the Federal Bureau of Investigation receive approval, at minimum, as follows:</text><clause id="id7C501DECCFE5499787454B635906148E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Approval from an attorney at the Federal Bureau of Investigation if the query uses a query term reasonably believed to identify a United States elected official, a governor of a State, an appointee of the President or the governor of a State, a United States political candidate, a United States political organization or a United States person prominent in such organization, a United States media organization or a United States person who is a member of such organization, a justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge of the United States, or a judge or justice of the highest court of a State.</text></clause><clause id="id854E3335B75C4D34B842929BBDFFE068"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Approval from an attorney of the Federal Bureau of Investigation if the query uses a query term reasonably believed to identify a United States religious organization or a United States person who is prominent in such organization.</text></clause><clause id="id4B4ECE9151A74DADB3D29474E1D3CAE1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Approval from an attorney of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for 2 or more queries conducted together, including through the use of batch job technology, any successor tool, or any other batch query method.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1E2F439B341E44F38E0DA823ABC63C4E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prior written justification</header><text>A requirement that—</text><clause id="idC2435DB12272453DA596FC848DAA6677"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prior to conducting a covered query, personnel of the Federal Bureau of Investigation generate a written statement of the specific factual basis to support the reasonable belief that such query meets the standards required by the procedures adopted under paragraph (1), which shall, for each covered query relating to the same United States person or persons, explain and support each individual query; and</text></clause><clause id="idDCA0EE6DC6A146E081EA1D9557FFAD68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each covered query, the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall keep a record of the query term or terms, the date of the query, the identifier of the personnel conducting the query, and the written statement of the specific factual basis required under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBBF2513480084A52AABCF20DB3BF8F5E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Affirmative election to include section 702 information in queries</header><text>Any system of the Federal Bureau of Investigation that stores unminimized contents or noncontents obtained through acquisitions authorized under subsection (a) together with contents or noncontents obtained through other lawful means shall be configured in a manner that requires personnel of the Federal Bureau of Investigation who are in compliance with the training requirement under subparagraph (A) to conduct such a query to affirmatively elect to include such unminimized contents or noncontents obtained through acquisitions authorized under subsection (a) when running a query.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBCA165506BA6412897B3C001018F3F09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAFCDE9BF4C364E5E97D89D50733DB12F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC5A16E9DA57947A6BB6DBD6FAE9FECB8"><subparagraph id="id4bc95c80cc8b4c748f2e3558ed7550ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3e3ec5a5b1e4d969f04df09a3aa2086"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a United States person; or </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31c00c8ff9db449495bc432f93cbe301"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person reasonably believed to be located in the United States— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id597e9d5a9d4b4318b3e80aa73684fcf4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the time of the applicable query; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb82664da29de438889cf0b7258f8846f"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the time of the communication or creation of the information subject to the applicable query.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06D498686CC14DCCB46EC645E3838DC1"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id013798cc884d40fd9b418ebdb239164c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <term>covered query</term> means a query that—</text><subclause id="id109661a30c904a0b9b7477805cf579db" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is conducted using 1 or more terms associated with 1 or more covered persons, including but not limited to personally identifiable information;</text></subclause><subclause id="id88facd94113545a1b894b0353f05b9dc" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is conducted in whole or in part for the purpose of detecting or retrieving information of or concerning 1 or more covered persons; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idec8b01a05a4b4e519c49f6306137df79" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is conducted with specific reason to believe the query will detect or retrieve information of or concerning 1 or more covered persons.</text></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id717c36c8b9424cc2a3dd7d0667191301"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Whether a query is a covered query shall be determined without regard to whether the information subject to the query has already been detected or retrieved using a method other than a query described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc0c3d19df4d6483c80524f5a2c639cdc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>query</term>— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7dbb5e41d97d4787914cf39ff1811489"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the use of any technique, whether manual or automated, to detect or retrieve information obtained through acquisitions authorized under subsection (a) from within a system, collection, or assortment of information, or a subset thereof; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf76b218d6e1f46f5b808369e6e4b20b3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include the manual observation of retrieved information.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id808600002D444A0D91F29BFF9813D195"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on warrantless access to the communications and other information of United States persons and persons located in the United States</header><text>Section 702(f) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id69D49A2A13544B7189B3BDB13697BD75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A) by inserting <quote>and the limitations and requirements in paragraph (2)</quote> after <quote>Constitution of the United States</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd59aa9b4a5a349c4b58c0c7d7799c4be"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD484C62497F34F7DB12DBA9955E875DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08d787362d804dd18d8e4fb6142bb12a"><paragraph id="ide3afd6905b4b46938f1dd38ac81c96ab"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on warrantless access to the communications and other information of United States persons and persons located in the United States</header><subparagraph id="id18bf2aa7946649e58008b321b61b971f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no officer or employee of any agency that has access to unminimized communications or information obtained through an acquisition under this section may access communications content, or information the compelled disclosure of which would require a probable cause warrant if sought for law enforcement purposes inside the United States, acquired under subsection (a) and returned in response to a covered query.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae0d8e2929804bde9d7a811084ff99cf"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions for concurrent authorization, exigent circumstances, consent, and certain defensive cybersecurity queries</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideca8e6efda87403a90abf6819d058cfa"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if—</text><subclause id="id3ce5208f9ca94b7f909323837a3ac190"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the person to whom the covered query relates is the subject of an order authorizing electronic surveillance, a physical search, or an acquisition under section 105, section 304, section 703, or section 704 of this Act or a warrant issued pursuant to the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure by a court of competent jurisdiction;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida7b518338480481ca728e4273298c1f4"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id905516fd1117481eae4bf42ab9846ace"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the person to whom the covered query relates is the subject of an emergency authorization authorizing electronic surveillance, a physical search, or an acquisition under section 105, section 304, section 703, or section 704 of this Act; </text></item><item id="id3376565c108c4398bdcf754a04e4d8a9" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the results of the covered query are accessed, a description of the circumstances justifying the accessing of the results of the covered query is provided to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></item><item id="id003cabf10f014c819bfe37d567c84eb5" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Attorney General makes or has made an application to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court in accordance with section 105(e)(1)(D), section 304(e)(1)(D), section 703(d)(1), or section 704(d)(1) of this Act; and</text></item><item id="id58a033eb86084a6f9e879479aacd17a8" indent="up1"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in the event such application is denied, the requirements of section 105(e)(5), 304(e)(5), section 703(d)(4), or section 704(d)(4), as applicable, are followed;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id6eefa2fe1af04f8b9948aea019f09724"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such person or, if such person is incapable of providing consent, a third party legally authorized to consent on behalf of such person, has provided consent for the access on a case-by-case basis; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id92adb1e47a804618b4f3733170147082"><enum>(IV)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id732dd988796040d5a68b55070cd7e0c8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the communications content or information is accessed and used for the sole purpose of identifying a potential victim or unwitting conduit of malicious cyber activity who is not a potential perpetrator of such activity;</text></item><item id="idcd955b7b4333415a805f12dca6682a25" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>other than for the purposes described in item (aa), no communications content or other information described in subparagraph (A) are accessed or reviewed; and</text></item><item id="id4164a8e0299d427c999d48db9660e998" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the accessing of query results is reported to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="ide807e089ed1d4f2e8e33ad0208f532c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>No communications content or information accessed under clause (i)(II) or information derived from such access may be used, received in evidence, or otherwise disseminated in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, office, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or political subdivision thereof, except in a proceeding that arises from the circumstances to which the applicable emergency authorization relates.</text></clause><clause id="id771b266ce8e749249ed7f93f51e394c3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Assessment of compliance</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Attorney General shall assess— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf00aef0139de4f1bb024942b5be647ad"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compliance with the requirements under clause (i)(II)(cc); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13708493864a4002b11ecf10db363b40"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compliance with the requirements under clause (ii).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5169237eaded438b8e8a3e7e8ad6915f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Foreign intelligence purpose</header><clause id="idaf91ebe6f7354006a91d147591dbaa2c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii) of this subparagraph, no officer or employee of any agency that has access to unminimized communications or information obtained through an acquisition under this section may conduct a covered query of information acquired under subsection (a) unless the query is reasonably likely to retrieve foreign intelligence information.</text></clause><clause id="id675761d11b304050a1a15d42df6ae7d8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>An officer or employee of an agency that has access to unminimized communications or information obtained through an acquisition under this section may conduct a covered query of information acquired under this section if—</text><subclause id="id32a9ee23b0a44529bf01c0fbebc0d76a"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ide43cb7c4b368404fb7adcf4bde088e4a"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the officer or employee conducting the query has a reasonable belief that— </text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd832592dc4c94c0e91ca9f4409a9410a" indent="up1"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an emergency exists involving an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm; and </text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id72d2ed46657244409d748032ce63ff7e"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the query could reasonably be expected to assist in mitigating or eliminating that threat to life or serious bodily harm; and</text></subitem></item><item id="idae9f2d4eaa3c45fca2b5399c152e180b" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the query is conducted, a description of the query is provided to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court, the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id72d57845eadb4085a9091a5acf694a65"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the query is necessary to identify information that must be produced or preserved in connection with a litigation matter or to fulfill discovery obligations in a criminal matter under the laws of the United States or any State thereof.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50B6AF16EE6E4908B882131DEC8FD4F2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification and consent requirements</header><clause id="HEA74180FF1674A38B190AF1DF42C74CD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional leadership defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>appropriate congressional leadership</term> means the following:</text><subclause id="HA879A633F43A41EB9E0272761A7D1AAF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The chairs and ranking minority members of the congressional intelligence committees.</text></subclause><subclause id="id521f43a90ba849bf8ded750bd443b0f7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the chair and ranking minority member of Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause><subclause id="H9BE0687A047A4B23BEFDAEB9A7B85A1B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause><subclause id="H4369851819A649C3A316E39909B5216E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The majority and minority leaders of the Senate.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ba0e9f7f4ed4642ae411901c773b46e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification requirement for certain FBI queries</header><subclause id="HEC6155FEAAEB4848ADAFBA7ED958E7FA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall promptly notify appropriate congressional leadership of any query conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation using a query term that is reasonably believed to be the name or other personally identifying information of a Member of Congress, and shall also notify the Member who is the subject of such query.</text></subclause><subclause id="H81F810D567DB441F917E2BE2C02462D2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><header>National security considerations</header><text>In submitting a notification under subclause (I), the Director shall give due regard to the protection of classified information, sources and methods, and national security.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6097765C85B74C06A1175D2430648C46" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Waiver</header><item id="H578AC9C6333147C1A3DDD4AF2DF7A27F"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director may waive a notification required under subclause (I) if the Director determines such notification would impede an ongoing national security or law enforcement investigation.</text></item><item id="H9B1BE804AA164DC59153DAA214720C47"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>A waiver under item (aa) shall terminate on the date the Director determines the relevant notification would not impede the relevant national security or law enforcement investigation or on the date that such investigation ends, whichever is earlier.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H1A94E6B22DA44A96A35217274EBCD538" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consent required for FBI to conduct certain queries for purpose of defensive briefing</header><subclause id="HBA961F73B47B4BF0BF42E98EA6E78098" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Consent required</header><text>The Federal Bureau of Investigation may not, for the purpose of supplementing the contents of a briefing on the defense against a counterintelligence threat to a Member of Congress, conduct a query using a query term that is the name or restricted personal information (as such term is defined in section 119 of title 18, United States Code) of that Member unless—</text><item id="HE118249856554F03B6C75F8534A1DEA7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Member provides consent to the use of the query term; or</text></item><item id="H43EA5B5EBFED42F79ABEEF84809BDD6F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Deputy Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation determines that exigent circumstances exist sufficient to justify the conduct of such query.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HF7471E91A3F24845964252176450D28D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notification</header><item id="HF73F1138ADCF4DACAA779384F1E44139"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Notification of consent sought</header><text>Not later than 3 business days after submitting a request for consent from a Member of Congress under subclause (I), the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall notify the appropriate congressional leadership, regardless of whether the Member provided such consent.</text></item><item id="H6D13F5343BC844E3981EE925BACE584E"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Notification of exception used</header><text>Not later than 3 business days after the conduct of a query under subclause (I) without consent on the basis of the existence of exigent circumstances determined under item (bb) of such subclause, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall notify the appropriate congressional leadership.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H86211944AA984CFA89BE7E70679BDE43" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this clause may be construed as—</text><item id="HEADF7C67E1614E8A8CFC7B966B773045"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>applying to matters outside of the scope of the briefing on the defense against a counterintelligence threat to be provided or supplemented under subclause (I); or</text></item><item id="HB854DF391FFA4C9E90068C60A5CABF4B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>limiting the lawful investigative activities of the Federal Bureau of Investigation other than supplementing the contents of a briefing on the defense against a counterintelligence threat to a Member of Congress.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c799f09957743928d3cd7ca72581e95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>No officer or employee of any agency that has access to unminimized communications or information obtained through an acquisition under this section may access communications content, or information the compelled disclosure of which would require a probable cause warrant if sought for law enforcement purposes inside the United States, returned in response to a covered query unless an electronic record is created that includes a statement of facts showing that the access is authorized pursuant to an exception specified in paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d431646e49d4892af466a7b73e92fb9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Query record system</header><text>The head of each agency that has access to unminimized communications or information obtained through an acquisition under this section shall ensure that a system, mechanism, or business practice is in place to maintain the records described in paragraph (3). Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>SAFE Act</short-title>, the head of each agency that has access to unminimized communications or information obtained through an acquisition under this section shall report to Congress on its compliance with this procedure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDFBD80B2306042E4AB298929C4FE5637"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3CE68679486248D0B20BCC5381A98768"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 603(b)(2) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1873">50 U.S.C. 1873(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>, including pursuant to subsection (f)(2) of such section,</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCE138F24579041A9AC5ECE3052F221AC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 706(a)(2)(A)(i) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881e">50 U.S.C. 1881e(a)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>obtained an order of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court to access such information pursuant to section 702(f)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>accessed such information in accordance with section 702(b)(2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide107e31b107d42f5981544baa525f184"><enum>102.</enum><header>Annual reports</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf018d3b47f56409191ef16ea03586047"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 707 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881f">50 U.S.C. 1881f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba0e9c3fa4eb4239a84a4c2eeb459abc"><subsection id="id3c9afd20a1fc47339e627932aa021b94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id575a2573e955468d99b0bdbeca11db85"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives an annual report, which shall include, for that year, disaggregated by each agency that conducts queries of information acquired under section 702, the following information:</text><subparagraph id="idd0ad57c293d34d7e838863261ef33cc9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The total number of covered queries (as defined in section 702(f)(8)) conducted of information acquired under section 702. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98756a9caf294907bbfd4812559d24e9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of times an officer or employee of the United States accessed communications contents (as defined in section 2510(8) of title 18, United States Code) or information the compelled disclosure of which would require a probable cause warrant if sought for law enforcement purposes in the United States, returned in response to such queries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e26c4ebe4d84b738d46856bae471361"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of applications for orders described in subclause (I) of section 702(f)(2)(B)(i) with respect to a person for which communications contents or information relating to such person were accessed under such subclause and the number of such orders granted. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3993088b1fd04591b0119ad222ae5bd1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of times an exception under subclause (II), (III), or (IV) of section 702(f)(2)(B)(i) was asserted, disaggregated by the subclause under which an exception was asserted.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50ce66d69cde4d7a956e51830e27e07a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The number of times that 2 or more approved queries were conducted together, through the use of batch job technology, any successor tool, or any other batch query method.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1c4993b53f5431b90fcdbcfb1fe5e0c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The number of queries run by an agency with access to unminimized communications or information obtained through an acquisition under section 702 run at the request of or on behalf of 1 or more other agencies that do not have such access, broken down by the agency that ran the query, the agency for whom the query was run, and the date of the query.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6161A378284745549C45A2D0ADB73C09" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to declassification review by the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence, each annual report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be made publicly available during April of each year and include information relating to the previous calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7861155630b04e9ca26dbcdb375b2369"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of superseded reporting requirement</header><text>Section 603 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1873">50 U.S.C. 1873</external-xref>) is amended— </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a5e82d7c70348c8919bc24e8f72cb8d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fc1e5bad5b64e399aa561c7514a43e5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2ab3d178c75f4ebfa690e5546704453b"><enum>103.</enum><header>Accountability and reporting procedures for compliance violations relating to queries conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation</header><subsection id="id785a2c98444a4881a7d416d3dba811c4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881">50 U.S.C. 1881 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28cfb805e9004cf9ae3c663261d98d14"><section id="iddf9c423d0e7349b5b8ba00a538133487"><enum>710.</enum><header>Accountability procedures for incidents relating to queries conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation</header><subsection id="ideecb3e14d62f420f8301233e96cf7054"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall establish procedures to hold employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation accountable for violations of law, guidance, and procedure governing queries of information acquired pursuant to section 702.</text></subsection><subsection id="id864601871e464652bb30bea53405547b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The procedures established under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id7bae885d8b9741f3a359d1e78aedf10c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Centralized tracking of individual employee performance incidents involving violations of law, guidance, and procedure described in subsection (a), over time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a540813f681434d8b6262eab9789d79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Escalating consequences for such incidents, including—</text><subparagraph id="id3d279d6cff3348658e24df01aaa9661a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consequences for initial incidents, including, at a minimum—</text><clause id="idad53f5b298a947bfbf89dff2af1d202b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>suspension of access to information acquired under this Act pending remedial action; and</text></clause><clause id="idd0aefed90c3843f4b7961cd4d0614685"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>documentation of the incident in the personnel file of each employee responsible for the violation; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc6f61fe496d42cd8ef68059dad1b620"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consequences for subsequent incidents, including, at a minimum—</text><clause id="id9308f759fbb747b78f6914d2f78efd97"><enum>(i)</enum><text>possible indefinite suspension of access to information acquired under this Act;</text></clause><clause id="idb3bdcbaf30d54087a684c661f2aa2806"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reassignment of each employee responsible for the violation; and</text></clause><clause id="idc041e8e14a8c4f9da92d7585cafd4eef"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>referral of the incident to the Inspection Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for review of potentially reckless conduct.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b634b7b8a934f9fb6a9bd048cf69278"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Clarification of requirements for referring intentional misconduct and reckless conduct to the Inspection Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for investigation and disciplinary action by the Office of Professional Responsibility of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idf382a30fee2b4ac39e037e08b50693de"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 709 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id608A1D9F4E374DEE85973C7F6B245409"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 710. Accountability procedures for incidents relating to queries conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id4349eff7be67468fa4e353a0f76ac5e9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><paragraph id="iddf538cc54bbf42f89023992cfe13b3ec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the congressional intelligence committees (as such term is defined in section 801 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1885">50 U.S.C. 1885</external-xref>)) a report detailing the procedures established under section 710 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9d8775a76af403ea65e05c7f86bfaf6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the congressional intelligence committees (as such term is defined in section 801 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1885">50 U.S.C. 1885</external-xref>)) a report on any disciplinary actions taken pursuant to the procedures established under section 710 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as added by subsection (a), including a description of the circumstances surrounding each such disciplinary action, and the results of each such disciplinary action.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb49c0ca883be4cf583e56cd98919c0bb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The reports required under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex to the extent necessary to protect sources and methods.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e592e9bf8744270bbd044850d8e6ed6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Paragraph (5) of section 702(f) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(f)</external-xref>), as redesignated by section 101(c)(2) of this Act, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id933dbbc1128b4ec2b5d05a4288dd9f7b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) as clauses (i), (ii), and (iii), respectively, and adjusting the margin accordingly; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id991792c7fa4d4cbcbac54e24134a9ed6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Director</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9ee8b52ada34c389b417c521745dc3f"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id344d126178c94c829d91a965720c96be"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3470143b7ca84d52a2cbfb22bf25fe7d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbe34b7be8714af9b591509053e279b0"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c1b0214300842a0b3570a32324b820e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives an annual report on the actions taken under the minimum accountability standards issued under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8dd3e861f73a47c6bb7d17f1964d9253"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Restriction on certain information available to the Federal Bureau of Investigation</header><text>Section 702(n)(2) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(n)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives,</quote> after <quote>the congressional intelligence committees,</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="id917381f5222846e6a48e4dbd19706e9e"><enum>104.</enum><header>Prohibition on reverse targeting of United States persons and persons located in the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idcd07c4b4731543a78341f14c28c37b49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>if the purpose of such acquisition is to target a particular, known person reasonably believed to be in the United States;</quote> and inserting <quote>if a purpose of such acquisition is to target 1 or more United States persons or persons reasonably believed to be located in the United States at the time of acquisition or communication;</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59c423f6a9aa40628222d940156df911"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd1ad0f298f24b5fb71dc344f408c1c4"><subparagraph id="id70e99404a76e4489afa80c29dbe2fbf6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that—</text><clause id="id294695b2527e4f419ef3c131a422d563"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any acquisition authorized under subsection (a) is limited to targeting persons reasonably believed to be non-United States persons located outside the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="idcec6b73a4f4644438da5219bffe5a929"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>targeting 1 or more United States persons or persons reasonably believed to be in the United States at the time of acquisition or communication is not a purpose of an acquisition; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id818e522039cb466fa93dee4fec239c40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2)(A)(i), by amending subclause (I) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f489424fc874c65af667d148a6ef940"><subclause id="idf6981c5ee3df46489014175d1a9378e3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensure that—</text><item id="idf75ee41251a54a98b24854e1085ca060"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an acquisition authorized under subsection (a) is limited to targeting persons reasonably believed to be non-United States persons located outside the United States; and</text></item><item id="id6382f8bdf7c742a5bea6ad6be1592126"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a purpose of an acquisition is not to target 1 or more United States persons or persons reasonably believed to be in the United States at the time of acquisition or communication; and</text></item></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id42e88094639d457bb9dc2e4dcda7273a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(2)(B), by amending clause (i) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26e92233eb954544ae55a57e518c7e2e"><clause id="id84cbfefeb17f4a2d82f4d8f0111322be"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that—</text><subclause id="id79a678f39dd845018d3628fed87ac084"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an acquisition authorized under subsection (a) is limited to targeting persons reasonably believed to be non-United States persons located outside the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc444937e79d4e4c9d441dc90febd3ac"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a purpose of an acquisition is not to target 1 or more United States persons or persons reasonably believed to be in the United States at the time of acquisition or communication; and</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id74b1eb29f9ea4ce2a7571e0f06f744cf"><enum>105.</enum><header>FISA court review of targeting decisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id81d0c1aaf07f4814bd0ecde6710e59ce"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="id342286862bfe40d68c9d14e1d3b87c1a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebb840f165ba41f9ab4b842425276c1d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc4b9b6d4a5f45059321faf7004df388"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a59ce2f61284826a0c474bd2a54aaf6"><subparagraph id="idcaf3ac70ca1942479c4a5aca6eb1e16f"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include a random sample of targeting decisions and supporting written justifications from the prior year, using a sample size and methodology that has been approved by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9feb0b4d9f6408e9c9f0f62004a4f13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idcfd0ada1c22548fba9db89c0b1c25737"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (g)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (h)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b29acf07d754bcdb17cb09478abffdb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as amended by subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, by inserting <quote>, including reviewing the random sample of targeting decisions and written justifications submitted under subsection (h)(2)(F),</quote> after <quote>subsection (h)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ida787449dce6d418893304e2a50e6793b"><enum>106.</enum><header>Sunset of changes to definition of electronic communication service provider</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on December 31, 2026, the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64259d326a5d496280becab538a05b8c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 701(b)(4) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881">50 U.S.C. 1881(b)(4)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69f8aea0e4304459b5dc815463900345"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc72cecaaff64fd59dd45d70c4588aa2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (E); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29330058bfd045098ad1efc89f1b2780"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (E); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5adf6bc74bfa491a87ef5385ad9f8aec"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), as so redesignated—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbef139743c64d4592c1b5b00f4ab32f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>custodian,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id935af84a240446b4a146860d884b2c22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(D), or (E)</quote> and inserting <quote>or (D)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ff66d6adb724babb95387037f9ec32f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 801(6) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1885">50 U.S.C. 1885(6)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39ef89b6a7eb426a9480f97d73befb41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (E); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcda32fc229c446f28d04fe19e0f1b107"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (F) and (G) as subparagraphs (E) and (F), respectively; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5012bf3dd9f04b38909dde6bf8f1a312"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), as so redesignated, by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9738622288fd439f974fb3b655508e4c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), as so redesignated—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf63606d3231c47819916020b15d3e8e1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>custodian,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99cab77c04644a768936e268da08f802"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(E), or (F)</quote> and inserting <quote>or (E)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8a7ae0b7a414544bb47731ef03d2401"><enum>107.</enum><header>Limitation on directives under Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 relating to certain electronic communication service providers</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9159f6db3a5941b8b980332ae2982afb"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 702(i) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id8ECDE3BB591248DC8FB2198FD73A5EC9" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2839ec32569f4a088bb242cbfe4bc263"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Limitation relating to certain electronic communication service providers</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bf34757eac944a5b72df5e32ef23b40"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5efa9c32e6af4606b8ed0d0e02bc1bc1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb222e90ec05b4672bbc6f067f5199c96"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the congressional intelligence committees;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id616b2f2e3a004b9caa656b3468d8a1df"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7def75e3b1bc45f7981cf4e35b30ac70"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67d24f8e12e94d228ab6f6a43ca926b5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered electronic communication service provider</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id976c8ec417604681b1479e10b0c92a20"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subclause (II), the term <term>covered electronic communication service provider</term> means—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide769ad89f1cc4459a3a5e5a07c11bffc"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a service provider described in section 701(b)(4)(E);</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42751093a2864982a5af835eafaaceb6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a custodian of an entity as defined in section 701(b)(4)(F); or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id944fcc2b39f246838e4bc43b81226520"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>an officer, employee, or agent of a service provider described in section 701(b)(4)(E).</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c07085a7bdc482e91ee68e8f2841970"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <quote>covered electronic communication service provider</quote> does not include— </text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id808ffb5e5f4f4eba985cb4f1b35f1013"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an electronic communication service provider described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of section 701(b)(4); or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f87cbd2792843738e930a73851b4a55"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an officer, employee, or agent of an electronic communication service provider described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of section 701(b)(4), </text></item><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subclause">to the extent that the electronic communication service provider is providing the United States Government with information, facilities, or assistance pursuant to such subparagraphs. </continuation-text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38447525591b46d5b77e34a3e6e58faf"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Covered opinions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered opinions</term> means the opinions of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court and the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review authorized for public release on August 23, 2023 (Opinion and Order, In re Petition to Set Aside or Modify Directive Issued to [REDACTED], No. [REDACTED], (FISA Ct. [REDACTED] 2022) (Contreras J.); Opinion, In re Petition to Set Aside or Modify Directive Issued to [REDACTED], No. [REDACTED], (FISA Ct. Rev. [REDACTED] 2023) (Sentelle, J.; Higginson, J.; Miller J.)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfbded61eb13244b49b97f650b1120651"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A directive may not be issued under paragraph (1) to a covered electronic communication service provider unless the covered electronic communication service provider is a provider of the type of service at issue in the covered opinions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb75dca7d49db44f28ebef376292f5e18"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Declassification review required</header><clause id="id0b68c8facc6c40bbbe5ca43044e86e29"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>SAFE Act</short-title>, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall complete a declassification review in accordance with section 3 of Executive Order 13526 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3161">50 U.S.C. 3161</external-xref> note; relating to classified national security information), or any successor order, (in this subparagraph referred to as <quote>Executive Order 13526</quote>) and, consistent with that review, make publicly available to the greatest extent practicable the type of service provider and services at issue in the covered opinions.</text></clause><clause id="id9060a01e84bc4e4b80cdc1468c2fc404"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Specific inquiry</header><text>In conducting the review required under clause (i), the Director of National Intelligence and the Attorney General shall determine—</text><subclause id="id110a80b8f72647a5b2ec0f8f51eea49f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the information described in clause (i) continues to meet the requirements for classification set forth in Executive Order 13526; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id15694d34eb4343e8b61816b00e9d8281"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the information described in clause (i) continues to meet the requirements for classification set forth in Executive Order 13526, whether the information should nonetheless be declassified pursuant to section 3.1(d) of Executive Order 13526.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb160f604ddaa445b97f56800f23fa94d"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In making a determination under subclause (II) of clause (ii), the Director of National Intelligence and the Attorney General shall consider—</text><subclause id="ida12ed20b9c37408081efde4f8208406a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the public interest served by ensuring that laws are public and transparent; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id65076674db92431080bfa7d03ad07b7e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the fact that the type of service provider or services at issue in the covered opinions have been the subject of public disclosures.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24fc9ac6719b44d4b6dad50ffbb9d55f"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements for directives to covered electronic communication service providers</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb667e93442b4479c904a8a5b00210a64"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), any directive issued under paragraph (1) on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>SAFE Act</short-title> to a covered electronic communication service provider that is not prohibited by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall include a summary description of the services at issue in the covered opinions.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id459441f862024beb8d65f8c4079344a9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Duplicate summaries not required</header><text>A directive need not include a summary description of the services at issue in the covered opinions if such summary was included in a prior directive issued to the covered electronic communication service provider and the summary has not materially changed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c53f6b2407147928300ca6351b0eee5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court notification and review</header><clause id="idb00252e9a2ec4e83829f90fec2edb9eb"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notification</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide72c3a8555464c34a033ba5042742e8c"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subclause (II), on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>SAFE Act</short-title>, each time the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence serve a directive under paragraph (1) to a covered electronic communication service provider that is not prohibited by subparagraph (B) and each time the Attorney General and the Director materially change a directive under paragraph (1) served on a covered electronic communication service provider that is not prohibited by subparagraph (B), the Attorney General shall provide the directive to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court on or before the date that is 7 days after the date on which the Attorney General and the Director served the directive, along with a description of the covered electronic communication service provider to whom the directive is issued and the services at issue.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5b88204b34c48929ca0036d5e228bde"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Duplication not required</header><text>The Attorney General does not need to provide a directive or description to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court under subclause (I) if a directive and description concerning the covered electronic communication service provider was previously provided to the Court and the directive or description has not materially changed.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idca8dde2f6c6a478d8dd1d1d1418b260c"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>As soon as feasible and not later than the initiation of collection, the Attorney General shall, for each directive described in clause (i), provide the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court a summary description of the type of equipment to be accessed, the nature of the access, and the form of assistance required pursuant to the directive.</text></clause><clause id="id74f827480abb4f7fa644dcd3a52bca72"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Review</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide12a9a7fd93645b994a9f902eab9e687"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court may review a directive received by the Court under clause (i) to determine whether the directive is consistent with subparagraph (B) and affirm, modify, or set aside the directive.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcfedc9f8691a40738cbee4ba1c069345"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notice of intent to review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 7 days after the date on which the Court receives information under clause (ii) with respect to a directive, the Court shall provide notice to the Attorney General and cleared counsel for the covered electronic communication service provider indicating whether the Court intends to undertake a review under subclause (I) of this clause.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88c96532354c46bcb4a6b4be55f3ba0e"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Completion of reviews</header><text>In a case in which the Court provides notice under subclause (II) indicating that the Court intends to review a directive under subclause (I), the Court shall, not later than 30 days after the date on which the Court provides notice under subclause (II) with respect to the directive, complete the review.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0e856405a0540fbbded98ab472aa790"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Congressional oversight</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc305d648c34c4decae8781a141163162"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf883e0e5af74fbbaecb6c35a7a6251b"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subclause (II), on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>SAFE Act</short-title>, each time the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence serve a directive under paragraph (1) on a covered electronic communication service provider that is not prohibited by subparagraph (B) and each time the Attorney General and the Director materially change a directive under paragraph (1) served on a covered electronic communication service provider that is not prohibited by subparagraph (B), the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress the directive on or before the date that is 7 days after the date on which the Attorney General and the Director serve the directive, along with a description of the covered electronic communication service provider to whom the directive is issued and the services at issue.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idceec9d1dba9646ef8b85b036f2ae2920"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Duplication not required</header><text>The Attorney General does not need to submit a directive or description to the appropriate committees of Congress under subclause (I) if a directive and description concerning the covered electronic communication service provider was previously submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress and the directive or description has not materially changed.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3A146A493CEC404CA66A4182ADCE55E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>As soon as feasible and not later than the initiation of collection, the Attorney General shall, for each directive described in clause (i), provide the appropriate committees of Congress a summary description of the type of equipment to be accessed, the nature of the access, and the form of assistance required pursuant to the directive.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2f691c91dd8409fa2541b65596cd6e8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Reporting</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8ca4ff06824411885e5e31b175be889"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quarterly reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>SAFE Act</short-title> and not less frequently than once each quarter thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the number of directives served, during the period covered by the report, under paragraph (1) to a covered electronic communication service provider and the number of directives provided during the same period to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court under subparagraph (E)(i).</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd133da862ca486fb2bf2433e90973fe"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Form of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted pursuant to subclause (I) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subclause><subclause id="id2f360facb81648b0902eeab79867f028" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Submission of court opinions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 45 days after the date on which the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review issues an opinion relating to a directive issued to a covered electronic communication service provider under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a copy of the opinion.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id225fa022503f4084becba73744fea3cc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Effective on December 31, 2026, section 702(i) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(i)</external-xref>), as amended by this section, is amended by striking paragraph (7).</text></subsection></section><section id="idcd0055fa7a9b42f485a3636bbb262b2f"><enum>108.</enum><header>Extension of title VII of FISA; expiration of FISA authorities; effective dates</header><subsection id="idebf79325f60340d7a520df32b4f35de6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text>Section 403(b) of the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/261">Public Law 110–261</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 2474) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idae4e7b56db104f2da4c99a633e87ad94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881">50 U.S.C. 1881</external-xref> note)—</text><subparagraph id="id41b6c2d2ef9f49febc725960320b48a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>two years after the date of enactment of the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</quote> and inserting <quote>on April 20, 2028</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8363a79fb084dfa9695a812dc74cb65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, as amended by section 101(a) and by the FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017 and the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act,</quote> and inserting <quote>, as most recently amended,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc02380e668934f37b0d6607fc3b375b7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2511">18 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref> note), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>two years after the date of enactment of the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</quote> and inserting <quote>on April 20, 2028</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4ee49afa89104a3e99de85e1e24b7b0c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 404(b) of the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/261">Public Law 110–261</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 2476), is amended—</text><paragraph id="id3551811c023a4a4ba41cb1a2216b6f0e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="id1a1bee15ec4048aea24bf01eb7940cca"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">two years after the date of enactment of the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">April 20, 2028</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd8130aa7687b43d28215eb5d39c0c8a1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, as amended by section 101(a) and by the FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017 and the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act,</quote> and inserting <quote>, as most recently amended,</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id85eb0e7f4270449a9a44ce0c33264b0b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>, as amended by section 101(a) and by the FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017 and the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act,</quote> and inserting <quote>, as most recently amended,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e9c8da07bf5474785df4192dc7bff50"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="id83dd085bd5fc45a0b456e09843d8df7d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, as added by section 101(a) and amended by the FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017 and the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act,</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>, as added by section 101(a) and as most recently amended,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a308313cd71468e98b89535b0a91fd2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, as amended by section 101(a) and by the FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017 and the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act,</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>, as most recently amended,</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="id16d47639b3d04921a3c61d540cc44fd8" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Additional reforms relating to activities under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978</header><section id="id8922be92db73442a9ee81c1889983dee"><enum>201.</enum><header>Required disclosure of information and limits on use of certain information and on issuance of orders</header><subsection id="id5bf8a7002e334b27b79bfe890532428a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required disclosure of relevant information in Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 applications</header><paragraph id="id8ce2269c944f4a3da6b27ebc592e6e3b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc67445f3b34420e81c5cf35105783ff"><title id="id8e97ada4c7b245bf9b482710cb017f77"><enum>IX</enum><header>Required disclosure of relevant information</header><section id="id558dde0dd6d1475c93533a4c79f88048"><enum>901.</enum><header>Disclosure of relevant information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General or any other Federal officer or employee making an application for a court order under this Act shall provide the court with all information in the possession of the Government that is material to determining whether the application satisfies the applicable requirements under this Act, including any exculpatory information.</text></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idc6c55f9ec36549fb8f2e575fd7da2eee"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collection of communications under section 702</header><text>Section 702(h)(2) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(h)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id733a2474a2c5420bb77d9ee65f564aea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda78b0129db94492a543a9a0ea718c34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id302cbacd7c794d21959a979ff0ebb018"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ccad75d601b47b6ae7e8c08005a625d"><subparagraph id="id7ee9318fc7e64ef7a60c24f522a8f78b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>attest that, to the best of the knowledge of the person making the certification, the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence have been apprised of all information in the possession of the Government that might reasonably—</text><clause id="idd86107bef68f466eac06f64dc7997582"><enum>(i)</enum><text>call into question the accuracy of the certification or the reasonableness of any assessment in the certification conducted by the department or agency on whose behalf the application is made; or</text></clause><clause id="id05816e591b534b62af533e27c216c08d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise raise doubts with respect to the findings that are required to be made under subsection (j).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc693ac341e914ac89169f853f72e5dd4"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clerical amendments</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc350068970be4d4b89aea82c357071b2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The table of contents for the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id5ad87fc9-6f60-49ec-b4a6-c2bd566c1a53"><toc><toc-entry level="title" idref="id8e97ada4c7b245bf9b482710cb017f77">TITLE IX—Required disclosure of relevant information </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id558dde0dd6d1475c93533a4c79f88048">Sec. 901. Disclosure of relevant information.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad70c342946e4f089d686d370143c3c3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 104(a)(13) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1804">50 U.S.C. 1804(a)(13)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47c0124ad9e7410a92cd69bb517c5c81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 10(a)(7) of the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1804">50 U.S.C. 1804</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfc6ba1d9193d4f398855905ce4263f90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification regarding accuracy procedures</header><paragraph id="id28ddc968f4f64c408909fe41ed023fd7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification regarding accuracy procedures</header><text>Title IX of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as added by subsection (a) of this section, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc298062510ce49b49c07a5fb70f1ee8d"><section id="id068d3433482a4784a542ad51f5b63dbd"><enum>902.</enum><header>Certification regarding accuracy procedures</header><subsection id="idb66e5d3df19244e2814560c092152dfa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of accuracy procedures</header><text>In this section, the term <term>accuracy procedures</term> means specific procedures, adopted by the Attorney General, to ensure that an application for a court order under this Act, including any application for renewal of an existing order, is accurate and complete, including procedures that ensure, at a minimum, that—</text><paragraph id="id334dc49b2b5b4341a5b945fda3933456"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the application reflects all information that might reasonably call into question the accuracy of the information or the reasonableness of any assessment in the application, or otherwise raises doubts about or contradicts the requested findings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id77a61b92bf81436c85a2cdf02edc386c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the application reflects all material information that might reasonably call into question the reliability and reporting of any information from a confidential human source that is used in the application;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01df22feee8943b1b4d0b78d0c88a244"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a complete file documenting each factual assertion in an application is maintained;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52deb71ad9544e6898b8f1dff7c8244e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the applicant coordinates with the appropriate elements of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>)), concerning any prior or existing relationship with the target of any surveillance, search, or other means of investigation, and discloses any such relationship in the application;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id501f9d865c814645b61bdf3a5668f9dc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>before any application targeting a United States person (as defined in section 101) is made, the applicant Federal officer shall document that the officer has collected and reviewed for accuracy and completeness supporting documentation for each factual assertion in the application; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9aa500d6d037499aa0081ebfc3590fb1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the applicant Federal agency establish compliance and auditing mechanisms to address, on an annual basis, the efficacy of the accuracy procedures that have been adopted and report such findings to the Attorney General.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcbb7fd57ddf841719ca2233b082de1fd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement and certification of accuracy procedures</header><text>Any Federal officer making an application for a court order under this Act shall include with the application—</text><paragraph id="id0ea525dce799419ca3ab0a4eddca4000"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the accuracy procedures employed by the officer or the officer's designee; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddac32da067344547949ae3f4f91441d7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a certification that the officer or the officer's designee has collected and reviewed for accuracy and completeness—</text><subparagraph id="id951502486c0947918290e68d99b8f107"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting documentation for each factual assertion contained in the application;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2b9cdc16cba44a28ce3948c0486b52b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all information that might reasonably call into question the accuracy of the information or the reasonableness of any assessment in the application, or otherwise raises doubts about the requested findings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1334388e30164043aea047d7882c927b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all material information that might reasonably call into question the reliability and reporting of any information from any confidential human source that is used in the application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id03298d3657fa44e390a8649d4712d9a2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Necessary finding for court orders</header><text>A judge may not enter an order under this Act unless the judge finds, in addition to any other findings required under this Act, that the accuracy procedures described in the application for the order, as required under subsection (b)(1), are actually accuracy procedures as defined in this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id33e50d1cd1c34e56a9f58d3d19b8af74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as amended by subsection (a) of this section, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id269A46C3D6744C75B310BE12517073EC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 902. Certification regarding accuracy procedures.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc50b42468d024fa399bca012cef333d9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of certain information</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide59c6f76c6fa47c0b15ac9be131480bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1804">50 U.S.C. 1804</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc506b6f709c448db97454915f3992a3"><subsection id="idafef0c62a688499e80475c0945c7c5e2"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The statement of facts and circumstances under subsection (a)(3) may only include information obtained from the content of a media source or information gathered by a political campaign if—</text><paragraph id="id8f74ec60adc74c2d9bd604e79ab6cbd4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such information is disclosed in the application as having been so obtained or gathered;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19fef379b246401c92aea7da40643f66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with regard to information gathered from the content of a media source, the application includes an explanation of the investigative techniques used to corroborate the information; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69d2c3011c9e4b63baa4e12dc2d4ee15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with regard to information gathered by a political campaign, such information is not the sole source of the information used to justify the applicant’s belief described in subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id387e0e241e5d4e76b65168039e99d4bd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id856fc3de7c2b43dd8439780683a26834"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 104(a)(6) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1804">50 U.S.C. 1804(a)(6)</external-xref>)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc28b7f5c02544851aecd085eef0a27bb"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7043b4a3b9b4425886f7c98865713264"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a82a53848534713b2437b6b2d0b1946"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraphs (F) and (G); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id041a64505be541159a60b3fb034d4b1a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 303(a)(6) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1823">50 U.S.C. 1823(a)(6)</external-xref>)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf41cf11c3f6d4721ac83d3a7612b78d8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; </text></clause><clause id="id76be25a23f39463a986249765fe2b180" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida396ee2928b34988a0b7cd506a41d53a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraphs (F) and (G).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5b7076ccd67a4988bc31bcc657c63b4a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on issuance of order</header><text>Section 105(a) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1805">50 U.S.C. 1805(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idb5f3e38f02fd4ef391a9f7974cdff6f5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideccbae892ae9401891c6dfdda1ced3c1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide25379d923394aa0ab84d2cd001d9640"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce7eb0cd2c9f4566899400dd209563fa"><paragraph id="id6c63dcb297254c1dbefb00c39dbec910"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for an application that is based, in any part, on information obtained from the content of a media source, on information gathered by a political campaign, or on information relating to activity protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="idb4f828ae0e814cfe904503a7d271b1bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such information is disclosed in the application as having been so obtained or gathered, or as being so related; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id947e0eac8d7f4a68b000210297a50a77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with regard to information gathered from the content of a media source, the application includes an explanation of the investigative techniques used to corroborate the information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id451e2c436ca545e6951e44526757498b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with regard to information gathered by a political campaign, such information is not the sole source of the information used to justify the applicant’s belief described in section 104(a)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83fd9ccfac6147c68b4499b4fb4bc180"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming repeal of RISAA exculpatory information requirements</header><text>The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4918167a1404e8cbbec2fa604863337"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 104(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1804">50 U.S.C. 1804(a)</external-xref>), by striking paragraph (13); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8661b739c6f44a089e4751a09f2c57a0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 303(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1823">50 U.S.C. 1823(a)</external-xref>), by striking paragraph (11); </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id332d78c9256f4074b90e5390fb86d792"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 402(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1842">50 U.S.C. 1842(c)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fa4eb5b1cdd4671bef212dffa1371dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id255cc367c845440c8dbc454e19d98d17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id598af1f8302040388555762a7cf50d16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5); </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd81ba9c5ea19495eab93bc69e624c8c2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 502(b)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1862">50 U.S.C. 1862(b)(2)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3211f41cafe1452b875376dc8977cc6f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide728ac69df7e490aadeec3d0e9e7190f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (C);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90adbff27919469b84efcdd9209b9ac8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id106d080c61394277946e3ac1b4a2c73d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F); </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida77b2e169a9f4dec853b4a2ef8fe5f7a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 703(b)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881b">50 U.S.C. 1881b(b)(1)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fdc3dbad8b44ce698358d5071a78fbd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (J), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc3a8eb3bdcd484eaa20513012c4eb45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (K)(ii), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82af5963a4194999bd2465767a9c5cbb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (L); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd554652d1bf44e59e812e77507b2e19"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 704(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881c">50 U.S.C. 1881c(b)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36965efd67ad45579445316636e53dba"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (7), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c9acf68c5bc49ac8df8f02118811637"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)(B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd7662b6ade24db9abd7d6e07cb67905"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (9).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0529396acafd4e7bbc8b1957081e097d"><enum>202.</enum><header>Criminal penalties for violations of FISA</header><subsection id="ide0704873ff2a4dadbd793f40f2c5dea3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 109(a) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1809">50 U.S.C. 1809(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd4e2072675554d42ae5274200b0c2c69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97d839e40e5e41a7a3f52bdfb2b31431"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd922c7c0699459ab5702ebe046a3a24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6b5acdd0e114525acc64586fb9e3686"><paragraph id="id3afb6d2f90cf420e996dcc3332cffbc9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>knowingly submits any document to or makes any statement before the court established under section 103(a) or the court established under section 103(b), knowing such document or statement to contain—</text><subparagraph id="id666a01b633e2453a9120634446d191bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a false material declaration; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06b3a7b510054630814d889af0dc649d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a material omission; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9fcaed9a3df24cdca7744f8893e50e35"><enum>(5)</enum><text>knowingly discloses the existence of an application for an order authorizing surveillance under this title, or any information contained therein, to any person not authorized to receive such information, except insofar as such disclosure is authorized by statute or executive order setting forth permissible disclosures by whistleblowers.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id63d4d3bae9ef487e80c777f91c4ead3b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section may not be construed to interfere with the enforcement of section 798 of title 18, United States Code, or any other provision of law regarding the unlawful disclosure of classified information.</text></subsection></section><section id="idd678c10555c54bd58f8e7e476b37d2bf"><enum>203.</enum><header>Agency procedures To ensure compliance</header><subsection id="id98b272a29ddd4406a06b3002b5a3ac03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agency procedures to ensure compliance</header><text>Title VI of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1871">50 U.S.C. 1871 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id214481780b504e79b8c34dd9cecf8726"><section id="id27699b8d143641b7b8b49e231c2179bb"><enum>605.</enum><header>Agency procedures to ensure compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The head of each Federal department or agency authorized to acquire foreign intelligence information under this Act shall establish procedures—</text><paragraph id="idb6f2072d95244c5fb6b177610371cbe9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>setting forth clear rules on what constitutes a violation of this Act by an officer or employee of that department or agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16a5d0c6ed4f463e9d137d72894e3562"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for taking appropriate adverse personnel action against any officer or employee of the department or agency who engages in a violation described in paragraph (1), including more severe adverse personnel actions for any subsequent violation by such officer or employee.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id665b2d41f92c41638d221218832321e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 604 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7E27044FF2C246369DA9DC1E99A2BAB3"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 605. Agency procedures to ensure compliance.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8068df66d5e4b749faa685179000456"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal department or agency that is required to establish procedures under section 605 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as added by subsection (a) of this section, shall report to Congress on the implementation of such procedures. </text></subsection></section><section id="id97D531366F3F4109BD21B95B8AA1C93A"><enum>204.</enum><header>Limit on civil immunity for providing information, facilities, or technical assistance to the Government absent a court order</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2511(2)(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idEF08AD47D5624E1AAD19F9CA1E47191B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (ii), by striking clause (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6BE870D989384F7B98B632FD32E884BD"><subparagraph id="id5D4B7A70EFC3411A81C862AE7F44DF9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a certification in writing—</text><clause id="id044706ce5c8242848b7eb14273d5bd5f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by a person specified in section 2518(7) or the Attorney General of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id20c6ee5bde344f0285a47d42dfb27911"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that the requirements for an emergency authorization to intercept a wire, oral, or electronic communication under section 2518(7) have been met; and</text></clause><clause id="idbbb8606373a7495a8584ad555e2a01c1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>that the specified assistance is required,</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idC86B84D6E8DE4542806F5D2ECDAA6EE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (iii) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA04DFEC0C9D0490B8079DFA7917A6998"><clause id="id8AC9E4C9B28E4A238C118AF481258AFA" indent="up2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For assistance provided pursuant to a certification under subparagraph (ii)(B), the limitation on causes of action under the last sentence of the matter following that subparagraph shall only apply to the extent that the assistance ceased at the earliest of the time the application for a court order was denied, the time the communication sought was obtained, or 48 hours after the interception began.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id234912ab26dd464cbb82ad5b624bcaa7"><enum>205.</enum><header>Prohibition on avoiding disclosure obligations through parallel construction</header><subsection id="id3e62fb8648ed4266a30658eb2925b201"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Derived defined</header><paragraph id="idde4f28bdb4ec4fc497c1f9fd94ef304e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9709bb6e1e94c3cb875bee406ef23eb"><subsection id="id075ec75034e04a109237028ebd094bf3"><enum>(q)</enum><text><quote>Derived from</quote>, with respect to an electronic surveillance, physical search, use of a pen register or trap and trace device, production of tangible things, or acquisition under this Act or pursuant to executive authority, means the Government would not have originally possessed the information or evidence but for that electronic surveillance, physical search, use of a pen register or trap and trace device, production of tangible things, or acquisition, which shall be determined without regard to any claim that the information or evidence is attenuated from the surveillance, search, use, production, or acquisition, would inevitably have been discovered, or was subsequently reobtained through other means.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id7da0fc1031474e8fbbe3870401579b47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming addition to other titles</header><text>The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida71e38bcd40d418eb4787663a43600ea"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 301(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1821">50 U.S.C. 1821(1)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote><term>derived from</term>,</quote> after <quote>destruction’,</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id065b32b7fe154eb0b83ca00056c9ea93"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 401(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1841">50 U.S.C. 1841(1)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote><term>derived from</term>,</quote> after <quote>person’,</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd1ad6d0588d43ccb4a50b8f4fa7f779"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 501(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1861">50 U.S.C. 1861(1)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote><term>derived from</term>,</quote> after <quote>terrorism’,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06137d0d9dce4beba0ba5c29a87c3c7d"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 701(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881">50 U.S.C. 1881(a)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote><term>derived from</term>,</quote> after <quote>United States’,</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf01fc82093b1472a87b3857bebe2ad84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policies and guidance</header><paragraph id="id8ebcf9346e20491e8c583931d674ae2e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence shall publish—</text><subparagraph id="id74a5e7e0529b43b68146bba10e4ea604"><enum>(A)</enum><text>policies concerning the application of subsection (q) of section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as added by subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d667df4ef9345b1bd3314bd5b6f9c2c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance for all members of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>)) and all Federal agencies with law enforcement responsibilities concerning the application of subsection (q) of section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as added by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ce6c38b7e9a4917816fcd37634828ff"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text>Whenever the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence modify a policy or guidance published under paragraph (1), the Attorney General and the Director shall publish the modifications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf80c852c30ee426f82a29eee1cd3f661"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of information acquired under title VII</header><text>Section 706 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881e">50 U.S.C. 1881e</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="ide9f77169b47f4439b01aeb02e79acaa5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>, except for the purposes of subsection (j) of such section</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26e608ee69294fa798d88152f248f335"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98649465c0ba4b4a832d4c70d6cf3ecd"><subsection id="id748e75499e994555b39f21f0aab9f8db"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information acquired under sections 703, 704, or 705</header><text>Information acquired under section 703, 704, or 705 shall be deemed to be information acquired from an electronic surveillance pursuant to title I for the purposes of section 106.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id578b3b528ccb47c88d90efd1a168626c"><enum>206.</enum><header>Sunset on grandfather clause of FISA’s business records provision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(b)(2) of the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/177">Public Law 109–177</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1805">50 U.S.C. 1805</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting <quote>, except that title V of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as in effect on March 14, 2020, shall cease to be in effect with respect to such an investigation, offense, or potential offense on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>SAFE Act</short-title></quote> after <quote>continue in effect</quote>.</text></section></title><title id="ide096ba32717041f68e28b8de3a304357" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Reforms relating to proceedings before the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court and other courts</header><section id="id6355e91d0f2a4efc907314178ec4f3ac"><enum>301.</enum><header>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court reform</header><subsection id="ida0d61c301eaf42feb56cd65d96eee8ed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of appointment authority</header><paragraph id="id987e4d6e80ca4ac8b81d0fc8a89eee5a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 103(i)(2) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803(i)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8860a389a5dc46248dc7314ca82e6999"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc57f807b087e445eb86ed5784a657254"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking clause (i) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8901f595494c434eb0b458343164ae01"><clause id="idd280293727ae44bd859578b4b4c240d5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall, unless the court issues a finding that appointment is not appropriate, appoint one or more individuals who have been designated under paragraph (1), not fewer than one of whom possesses privacy and civil liberties expertise, unless the court finds that such a qualification is inappropriate, to serve as amicus curiae to assist the court in the consideration of any application or motion for an order or review that, in the opinion of the court—</text><subclause id="id75bca6cdfaa24a1291c3326f80a2e140"><enum>(I)</enum><text>presents a novel or significant interpretation of the law;</text></subclause><subclause id="idda6921a8c2f94cac9068df288e9608ed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>presents significant concerns with respect to the activities of a United States person that are protected by the first amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida86b983158ca471c9e60d806ae6251c9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>presents or involves a sensitive investigative matter;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf78cffeefa494431803ec96c057d7ac6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>presents a request for approval of a new program, a new technology, or a new use of existing technology;</text></subclause><subclause id="id9edccaf6fe624888b9f4f96adb96892e"><enum>(V)</enum><text>presents a request for reauthorization of programmatic surveillance; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id7b48319920334ab7ac09ac693dee2f3c"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>otherwise presents novel or significant civil liberties issues;</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfbba2d847dcf43b1a1151ef7596b6e17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>, unless the court issues a finding that such appointment is not appropriate or is likely to result in undue delay</quote>; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id044cf22e2ad24ead8cdb226b401a9e1b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6e8133cc199499bacd59bf32fea56d9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f6ec94f269e4896acd892a599bfd902"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of sensitive investigative matter</header><text>Section 103(i) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c074007118d47b6bb3604de26c289fd"><paragraph id="id50fe0baa8d49407694f1ffefd09e5095"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>sensitive investigative matter</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idb64aa32ad1d84fc1b13febccbdd105c1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an investigative matter involving the activities of—</text><clause id="id09103249355346b1998b7b369fa54703"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a domestic public official or political candidate, or an individual serving on the staff of such an official or candidate;</text></clause><clause id="ide8aaabb5f94f4b57ad34efba60aeb689"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a domestic religious or political organization, or a known or suspected United States person prominent in such an organization; or</text></clause><clause id="ide03e53ac2916411ba2c5690c456de101"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the domestic news media; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97c0650f2f144b9c9e5449f7a56367df"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other investigative matter involving a domestic entity or a known or suspected United States person that, in the judgment of the applicable court established under subsection (a) or (b), is as sensitive as an investigative matter described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida8ee2b580e1741a48947e006a219018c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority to seek review</header><text>Section 103(i) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803(i)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id80b3a2e87a6e4ca18e548c0bde526de2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="idd7e28bd572cf403e9dbecad473cbb063"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">; authority</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Duties</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc76c5cc0b86c4c96ad09d726898738ec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>shall</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8096c5ffe254cdf80e970903efe2f27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00d1838525104e00baf7f019434bb9fa"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4157b80ed704a8fa99be5cb986e6cdf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as so redesignated—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76371b638b234502bbcb7ec025f29245"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>shall</quote> before <quote>provide</quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67c58eae1c164c0fb32cf1f67a8b6d14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, including legal arguments regarding any privacy or civil liberties interest of any United States person that would be significantly impacted by the application or motion</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id331bbf4d983847b282b5c5733bf8e9e3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbaaf287a15a48d2b4d189fa108d1b7b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id944f78ea8ad94155b553c0a453fb300d"><subparagraph id="id3aefb601e2ba47ffac55970ed51628cc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may seek leave to raise any novel or significant privacy or civil liberties issue relevant to the application or motion or other issue directly impacting the legality of the proposed electronic surveillance with the court, regardless of whether the court has requested assistance on that issue.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id12ddeb735ac7447dbdaca976a7215b9a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (7) through (12) as paragraphs (8) through (13), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id39eff990b6f94b2aa4bbf4fa5feb4186"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43872ae542854304ad2d28125c677c23"><paragraph id="id39f75add15a144499c3270383e278d23"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authority to seek review of decisions</header><subparagraph id="id3d802b99406b41e3871a92bd037401da"><enum>(A)</enum><header>FISA court decisions</header><clause id="id4bd0e277e5a14754938ebabcb260ed9b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Petition</header><text>Following issuance of an order under this Act by the court established under subsection (a), an amicus curiae appointed under paragraph (2) may petition the court to certify for review to the court established under subsection (b) a question of law pursuant to subsection (j).</text></clause><clause id="iddcd0384dda794562afb8688a484d4e1a"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Written statement of reasons</header><text>If the court established under subsection (a) denies a petition under this subparagraph, the court shall provide for the record a written statement of the reasons for the denial.</text></clause><clause id="ida64c4261b8be4355985af5da1ba79fc0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Upon certification of any question of law pursuant to this subparagraph, the court established under subsection (b) shall appoint the amicus curiae to assist the court in its consideration of the certified question, unless the court issues a finding that such appointment is not appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id896830be3d744d849d9964837194e700"><enum>(B)</enum><header>FISA court of review decisions</header><text>An amicus curiae appointed under paragraph (2) may petition the court established under subsection (b) to certify for review to the Supreme Court of the United States any question of law pursuant to section 1254(2) of title 28, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95acd2dc8d014fd088b7dbbb0fe5fd38"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Declassification of referrals</header><text>For purposes of section 602, a petition filed under subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph and all of its content shall be considered a decision, order, or opinion issued by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review described in section 602(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id81c56997cca448ce98fa5d7eede99341"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access to information</header><paragraph id="idda16f3eb61944bc2800a3e85764546d5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application and materials</header><text>Section 103(i)(6) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803(i)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1a410919d924b90835b8114c5447779"><subparagraph id="id2ca2a4a9a86449caae5988df4f4720e9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause id="id99aa64650cd8446b8f55f23f67415b7a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Right of amicus</header><text>If a court established under subsection (a) or (b) appoints an amicus curiae under paragraph (2), the amicus curiae—</text><subclause id="id118b9f97de134e389d8d38d859584692"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall have access, to the extent such information is available to the Government, to—</text><item id="ide3c1966a4e0f4690bca490ca58a6e6cb"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the application, certification, petition, motion, and other information and supporting materials, including any information described in section 901, submitted to the court established under subsection (a) in connection with the matter in which the amicus curiae has been appointed, including access to any relevant legal precedent (including any such precedent that is cited by the Government, including in such an application);</text></item><item id="id8baf71ab430540a5825dd0b9a0764947"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>an unredacted copy of each relevant decision made by the court established under subsection (a) or the court established under subsection (b) in which the court decides a question of law, without regard to whether the decision is classified; and</text></item><item id="idf286a5a3afb3451bbef66352c5f9ae40"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any other information or materials that the court determines are relevant to the duties of the amicus curiae; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id401c187ea28b4a5392e56d88dff0d4e0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may make a submission to the court requesting access to any other particular materials or information (or category of materials or information) that the amicus curiae believes to be relevant to the duties of the amicus curiae.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id083ce906047d4e418f4bb252f2bf839e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supporting documentation regarding accuracy</header><text>The court established under subsection (a), upon the motion of an amicus curiae appointed under paragraph (2) or upon its own motion, may require the Government to make available the supporting documentation described in section 902.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id37e5c5723851467e8fb6e0d97ad6f012"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification of access to certain information</header><text>Section 103(i)(6) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803(i)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id94f150fd745840808337f77948a0acaa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>may</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id857fe0ac34d24833baa71447a5f82bb8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f3e1d698b3943159c29f73a80a23d2e"><subparagraph id="id6e5822aa77ae42bbb4ef14b798dab33c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text>An amicus curiae designated or appointed by the court shall have access, to the extent such information is available to the Government, to unredacted copies of each opinion, order, transcript, pleading, or other document of the court established under subsection (a) and the court established under subsection (b), including, if the individual is eligible for access to classified information, any classified documents, information, and other materials or proceedings.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7628c9563bc84f24aaf01397530f4439"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation among amici curiae</header><text>Section 103(i)(6) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803(i)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id7bd9d0c24f07434abd6197f414a58420"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc384806630b74017a207c83294a0ce8a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b2ea4a4c63249798332965356231b42"><subparagraph id="id10b83081d0364eba80c0388279bb6185"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Consultation among amici curiae</header><text>An amicus curiae appointed under paragraph (2) by the court established under subsection (a) or the court established under subsection (b) may consult with 1 or more of the other individuals designated by the court to serve as amicus curiae pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection regarding any of the information relevant to any assigned proceeding.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id88d540b4dcce42bbbeb0bcbaedea462a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to proceedings under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) that take place on or after, or are pending on, that date.</text></subsection></section><section id="idc62f7a7638e749e5b8140b8a86f21e4e"><enum>302.</enum><header>Public disclosure and declassification of certain documents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 602(a) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1872">50 U.S.C. 1872(a)</external-xref>) is amended— </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8f43e695e2140a0b491bdce462823db"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>, to be concluded as soon as practicable, but not later than 180 days after the commencement of such review,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id485a0f43ab5243fbbb00a4322cdfab27"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>to be concluded as soon as practicable, but not later than 180 days after the issuance of such decision, order, or opinion,</quote> before <quote>and, consistent with that review</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida5ce82174f414413a54da889d110f8d2"><enum>303.</enum><header>Technical amendment to contempt power of FISC and FISC-R</header><subsection id="ide01526e746944b56b21af058ef6afc8d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/21">Chapter 21</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id5f566772227f44449ce00488c4819de6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 402, by striking <quote>, including the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review established by section 103 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803</external-xref>),</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>, the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court, the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review,</quote> ; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb69234ca5cb24850b80eeb20662c1f9d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41BFC6601441436B929D0873406B8586"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ad558a78cc84dfca503892992bd5fd2"><enum>404.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this chapter—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="ida129520daba14d05907f108c2f945652"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>court of the United States</term> includes the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idef8bfdbe02e747498767d5e982e80dd5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the terms <term>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court</term> and <term>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 601(e) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1871">50 U.S.C. 1871(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb63da45086a94609b702c006926d972a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5F925174D636448CBAE942A77C071C42"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">404. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="ide4bda9fd9bca4c479ca1707096d380f2" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Independent executive branch oversight</header><section id="id38e487c8db3941dbb375e0b7e36fd8b8"><enum>401.</enum><header>Periodic audit of FISA compliance by Inspector General</header><subsection id="id73e36b195286419b9283a7f228430abe"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Title VI of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1871">50 U.S.C. 1871 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 203 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68e35128ba2a4b06a5d5ae59563d407d"><section id="id037f5024d306438d917cf671dfe82289"><enum>606.</enum><header>Periodic audit of FISA compliance by Inspector General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than June 30 of the first calendar year that begins after the date of enactment of this section, and every 3 years thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall—</text><paragraph id="id7366a0c4a6264e3eb569d4b0287cd201"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an audit of alleged or potential violations and failures to comply with the requirements of this Act, and any procedures established pursuant to this Act, which shall include an analysis of the accuracy and completeness of applications and certifications for orders submitted under each of sections 105, 303, 402, 502, 702, 703, and 704; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8771d0e153dc4e3caa1035389cc317b3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the audit required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id17eec011a4c04335bf153d53ae05c9c5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, as amended by section 203 of this Act, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 605 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA472E447E1C247D083CBD7BF464C2C8F"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 606. Periodic audit of FISA compliance by Inspector General.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="id40ca36f68f7a4ab78dee72b6313b1aac" style="OLC"><enum>V</enum><header>Protections for United States persons whose sensitive information is purchased by intelligence and law enforcement agencies</header><section id="idedc959f7e7384fd1b8bb384e8b8150bb"><enum>501.</enum><header>Limitation on intelligence acquisition of United States person data</header><subsection id="id5e5f7f970cba46b99e2bff0283790006"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id61a15608a4b747b5880d990afa98a26d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idf8efc7eef65a42beae3efd13eac60978"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the congressional intelligence committees (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb61ca81bc7943bda038ca0827f344b8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f300e2a1a52488dabe1630431f0a9fe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id33eac9fd861d43379c1454ce09056973"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered data</header><text>The term <term>covered data</term> means data, derived data, or any unique identifier that—</text><subparagraph id="id074011d575054c8b84ec65db1c7bccf3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is linked to or is reasonably linkable to a covered person; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bda6c62580c4f1cb37012e80dff5fcc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf36ba8f05f924243a81e5bc6be75027f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data that—</text><subclause id="id32d9cef6121c41f8bd255574b348afdc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is lawfully available to the public through Federal, State, or local government records or through widely distributed media;</text></subclause><subclause id="id347854d3398f4d6088dfb6f9317839f5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is reasonably believed to have been voluntarily made available to the general public by the covered person; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idb3642bee947a472b8d8d89561228c274"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is a specific communication or transaction with a targeted individual who is not a covered person; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf1298be8426542a09265b4e5cacb0532"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>human intelligence other than data transfers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide025dbf40d4c44dea418e37b24c19588"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="id8d68592e4c254a43b0d87a3b58fa6729"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is reasonably believed to be located in the United States at the time of the creation or acquisition of the covered data; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4bbae4d9811c4c05bf0c248f839ed511"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a United States person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2f4e4c9d1c6491daceb274729a87874"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaaf8a22e829848e5895d9135f84af86c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State, United States, United States person</header><text>The terms <term>State</term>, <term>United States</term>, and <term>United States person</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb014fe73e7b24ddeb1b141971f5356b4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="ida8e7284dbd354b1c9a586034ec70e6cb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) through (7), an element of the intelligence community may not acquire covered data, which shall include acquiring covered data directly or indirectly, such as by acquiring covered data from another entity that directly acquired the covered data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b9c3487a22f4f499446cd4c6f7fb427"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization pursuant to court order</header><text>An element of the intelligence community may acquire covered data if the collection has been authorized by an order issued pursuant to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) or title 18, United States Code, by a court of competent jurisdiction covering the period of the acquisition, subject to the use, dissemination, querying, retention, and other minimization limitations required by such authorization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23be1e6c9d094b7cafc24be6b7d5ff39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization for employment-related use</header><text>An element of the intelligence community may acquire covered data about an employee of, or applicant for employment by, an element of the intelligence community for employment-related purposes, but only if—</text><subparagraph id="idcc277c4e09844e59adb221a1f2b8bd32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>access to and use of the covered data is limited to such purposes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc755088c6c44c72bef94a64084ec0d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered data is destroyed at such time as it is no longer necessary for such purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d24a877f4c54abfb710990344aafceb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception for compliance purposes</header><text>An element of the intelligence community may acquire covered data for the purpose of supporting compliance with collection limitations and minimization requirements imposed by statute, guidelines, procedures, or the Constitution of the United States, but only if—</text><subparagraph id="id6772604f80134cb082fbf9be89eb2cfb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>access to and use of the covered data is limited to such purpose; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4333107915134cb79aa63f38179d7434"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered data is destroyed at such time as it is no longer necessary for such purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida84bbd56037644999d75a123cd35b5ce"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exception for life or safety</header><text>An element of the intelligence community may acquire covered data if there is a reasonable belief that an emergency exists involving an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm and the covered data is necessary to mitigate that threat, but only if—</text><subparagraph id="idc30d4665f8a540b89b179f33a46f1a25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>access to and use of the covered data is limited to addressing the threat; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fdf0af2e7d849c68f685452ed60e265"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered data is destroyed at such time as it is no longer necessary for such purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6e16f6d937f439da8132581276c4999"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exception for consent</header><text>An element of the intelligence community may acquire covered data if—</text><subparagraph id="idccadaee6a9364734a8f496cc28125ec9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each covered person linked or reasonably linkable to the covered data, or, if such person is incapable of providing consent, a third party legally authorized to consent on behalf of the person, has provided consent to the acquisition and use of the data on a case-by-case basis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb010292b88841b8bddf4e2ec4a798fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>access to and use of the covered data is limited to the purposes for which the consent was provided; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e0d6ad3357b442fa2203d909c70d0a4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the covered data is destroyed at such time as it is no longer necessary for such purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id54c098ed685f43519cd261a2abaf24c4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Exception for nonsegregable data</header><text>An element of the intelligence community may acquire a dataset that includes covered data if the covered data is not reasonably segregable prior to acquisition, but only if the element of the intelligence community complies with the minimization procedures in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idadddf035586f417b9e787b670b5ed7a6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Minimization procedures</header><paragraph id="idb202924db5ae4b668690a2e9ccd0235c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall adopt specific procedures that are reasonably designed to minimize the acquisition and retention, and to restrict the querying, of covered data that is not subject to 1 or more of the exceptions set forth in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7612fd19680d4162b458341f296b75da"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acquisition and retention</header><text>The procedures adopted under paragraph (1) shall require elements of the intelligence community to exhaust all reasonable means—</text><subparagraph id="iddd47a563e1b34ce3897468e0ee0d23eb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to exclude covered data not subject to 1 or more exceptions set forth in subsection (b) from datasets prior to acquisition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4917122280564f53ac91131a6cfe2fad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to remove and delete covered data not subject to 1 or more exceptions set forth in subsection (b) prior to the operational use of the acquired dataset or the inclusion of the dataset in a database intended for operational use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idddbc727d6ab24f8eb549becc4059b076"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Destruction</header><text>The procedures adopted under paragraph (1) shall require that if an element of the intelligence community identifies covered data not subject to 1 or more exceptions set forth in paragraphs (2) through (6) of subsection (b), such covered data shall be promptly destroyed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd90ac27ada96435eb599b3115ef36417"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Querying</header><subparagraph id="id3482e8f67c414964a8392083949e0862"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), no officer or employee of an element of the intelligence community may conduct a query of covered data, including covered data already subjected to minimization, in an effort to find records of or about a particular covered person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id567efdb1d2cb4233802ba088d1a35c96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a query related to a particular covered person if—</text><clause id="ida7dcc5136afe4e09a8879d472adaa8c0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such covered person is the subject of a court order issued under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) or title 18, United States Code, that would authorize the element of the intelligence community to compel the production of the covered data, during the effective period of that order;</text></clause><clause id="id42810039518c491281efee563beb8736"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the purpose of the query is to retrieve information about an employee of, or applicant for employment by, an element of the intelligence community, provided that any covered data accessed through such query is used only for such purpose;</text></clause><clause id="idf1064b5c0b144d4189b4e85e92fc98bb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the query is conducted for the purpose of supporting compliance with collection limitations and minimization requirements imposed by statute, guidelines, procedures, or the Constitution of the United States, provided that any covered data accessed through such query is used only for such purpose; </text></clause><clause id="id8f83bdeb0a67441ea1bb41b3233c72c3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the officer or employee of an element of the intelligence community carrying out the query has a reasonable belief that an emergency exists involving an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm, and that in order to prevent or mitigate such threat, the query must be conducted before a court order can, with due diligence, be obtained, provided that any covered data accessed through such query is used only for such purpose; or</text></clause><clause id="idb5104aae842c4a3280c0baa675fa3163"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such covered person or, if such person is incapable of providing consent, a third party legally authorized to consent on behalf of the person has consented to the query, provided that any use of covered data accessed through such query is limited to the purposes for which the consent was provided.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43cbfda8fd4f47eba6c7a61a91f16093"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule for nonsegregable datasets</header><text>For a query of a dataset acquired under subsection (b)(7)—</text><clause id="ide3553dc5241e41f59bc1e766c37b8242"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each query shall be reasonably designed to exclude personal data of covered persons, unless the query is subject to an exception set forth in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="id0fec52c4aa3a406198d2db95dc102113"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any personal data of covered persons returned pursuant to a query that is not subject to an exception set forth in paragraphs (2) through (7) of subsection (b) shall not be reviewed and shall immediately be destroyed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc0f542bf3bb548eaa7634df907bdc38b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of data obtained in violation of this Section</header><text>Covered data acquired by an element of the intelligence community in violation of subsection (b), and any evidence derived therefrom, may not be used, received in evidence, or otherwise disseminated in any investigation by or in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, office, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or political subdivision thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc2299c76f5d946f68aa1f2fd66624015"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><paragraph id="id236f4dc4b7844f51aad1cb8c8539befd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board a report on the acquisition of datasets that the Director anticipates will contain information of covered persons that is significant in volume, proportion, or sensitivity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5497f4ed682a4bcb9f5cb999460984c6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="idc06f54db10c844eeb9106671ca5337d9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the covered person information in each dataset.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3dcf1098cb66450bb58cd05f856380d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An estimate of the amount of covered person information in each dataset.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2399e41a70a498ba5818ec67799364c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notifications</header><text>After submitting the report required by paragraph (1), the Director shall, in coordination with the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence and Security, notify the appropriate committees of Congress of any changes to the information contained in such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1cd61d99480347dfb8ee5a4030413e98"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability to the public</header><text>The Director shall make available to the public on the website of the Director—</text><subparagraph id="id17993451885d407b857304f00b72ae5a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the unclassified portion of the report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb82f3fc3cbf346839f93c9741e98afc9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any notifications submitted pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfa684df4554444b5bbcf8cfa115bcde2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall authorize an acquisition otherwise prohibited by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) or title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="id61615acbc11b424fa0bed408638c52f1"><enum>502.</enum><header>Limitation on law enforcement purchase of personal data from data brokers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2702 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87cf600894884137a9438a6b9416a286"><subsection id="id1dd672901eb44a2685e195a948021772"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on obtaining in exchange for anything of value personal data by law enforcement agencies</header><paragraph id="id45333969fe6e4dd6a8e87449dceaeda0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection and subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph id="id1b623012dee94dccaf77952a1a2a84f6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered governmental entity</term> means a law enforcement agency of a governmental entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6403688188d946f8a4892dc1a5ac6fcd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>covered organization</term> means a person who—</text><clause id="ide43e7f304f544b4f82db688f9c8643d3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not a governmental entity; and</text></clause><clause id="id94fe2357287a49c48d1d9a56e56cf3c4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not an individual;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8dd14b934f5a4195856e4e078c35c5c4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>covered person</term> means an individual who—</text><clause id="id7dac04203c694d40bcf3fba4a1723f18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is reasonably believed to be located inside the United States at the time of the creation of the covered personal data; or</text></clause><clause id="id07d76ee03e7c428baa18c49a8213b695"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a United States person, as defined in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f38f5b0eaab4136af1db836693d2985"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>covered personal data</term> means personal data relating to a covered person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e2e9d8f073c4f9ca2c03e1ec9c3611d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>electronic device</term> has the meaning given the term <term>computer</term> in section 1030(e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46fb657837fb42a59ae0937251ac30d5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the term <term>lawfully obtained public data</term> means personal data obtained by a particular covered organization that the covered organization—</text><clause id="id87b242c3542d48a195eef34f6d3c9dd3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reasonably understood to have been voluntarily made available to the general public by the covered person; and</text></clause><clause id="id751d9b6b69ce435cb588a387a2a408ab"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>obtained in compliance with all applicable laws, regulations, contracts, privacy policies, and terms of service;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc81d96489936475db9766df7bb80dbf6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the term <term>obtain in exchange for anything of value</term> means to obtain by purchasing, to receive in connection with services being provided for monetary or nonmonetary consideration, or to otherwise obtain in exchange for consideration, including an access fee, service fee, maintenance fee, or licensing fee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida2e02e4863424ced99a5dc6f805a9449"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the term <term>personal data</term>—</text><clause id="idd5e11c3057cb4ac0924b1fb263adab00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means data, derived data, or any unique identifier that is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to, an individual or to an electronic device that is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to, 1 or more individuals in a household;</text></clause><clause id="idbe3f69fa9157464197dc74fc744a4c36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes anonymized data that, if combined with other data, can be linked to, or is reasonably linkable to, an individual or to an electronic device that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to 1 or more individuals in a household; and</text></clause><clause id="id4948422bccd94b9ea43ef32029365dbd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1052b845827649d281f77ecc40e02dee"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data that is lawfully available through Federal, State, or local government records or through widely distributed media; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id63722e5b615c4f4a878ebc2b77543d2c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a specific communication or transaction with a targeted individual who is not a covered person.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c0c0d7f5ef846fdb35a3adc11ff69ab"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><subparagraph id="id20955e69570148e8870f5937a58733cc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause id="idc7ba57749f6b45af8ceb0ed1433e26ec"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Subject to clauses (ii) through (x), a covered governmental entity may not obtain in exchange for anything of value covered personal data if—</text><subclause id="id4d9fc5d600944d6b8900bf60e38f4bde"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the covered personal data is directly or indirectly obtained from a covered organization; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idc783b1cedf71462cbf98e4d8c8225c8c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the covered personal data is derived from covered personal data that was directly or indirectly obtained from a covered organization.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf26556eb62204d3bb6e9b2aba06402de"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for certain compilations of data</header><text>A covered governmental entity may obtain in exchange for something of value covered personal data as part of a larger compilation of data which includes personal data about persons who are not covered persons, if—</text><subclause id="id0a69e5afa93549f18e5b6e0ec534a723"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the covered governmental entity is unable through reasonable means to exclude covered personal data from the larger compilation obtained; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb2962ee057504784bb2195669be0e60b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the covered governmental entity minimizes any covered personal data from the larger compilation, in accordance with subsection (f).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb9af286ee95d485ba8b1dab46a979f46"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception for whistleblower disclosures to law enforcement</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data that is obtained by a covered governmental entity under a program established by an Act of Congress under which a portion of a penalty or a similar payment or bounty is paid to an individual who discloses information about an unlawful activity to the Government, such as the program authorized under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7623">section 7623</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to awards to whistleblowers in cases of underpayments or fraud).</text></clause><clause id="id71673feb26354a08ae140c5584deb471"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Exception for cost reimbursement under compulsory legal process</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data that is obtained by<pagebreak></pagebreak>a covered governmental entity from a covered organization in accordance with compulsory legal process that—</text><subclause id="ide5620049d862419487106a563ed90009"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is established by a Federal or State statute; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id598067cb080d456f9737cc22c44cd792"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides for the reimbursement of costs of the covered organization that are incurred in connection with providing the record or information to the covered governmental entity, such as the reimbursement of costs under section 2706.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7c0a33973f0f47a9aac8288477bebc18"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Exception for employment-related use</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data about an employee of, or applicant for employment by, a covered governmental entity that is—</text><subclause id="id1658e3df9f3f42d89761a9a5c6d24acc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>obtained by the covered governmental entity for employment-related purposes;</text></subclause><subclause id="id9970c0c3c48043fe93d838fc495f7231"><enum>(II)</enum><text>accessed and used by the covered governmental entity only for employment-related purposes; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id174bc951b2c04c798d37ec46f6d10446"><enum>(III)</enum><text>destroyed at such time as the covered personal data is no longer needed for employment-related purposes.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3b66abe2d7594ab19f8e0409f9818a5b"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Exception for use in background checks</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data about a covered person that is—</text><subclause id="id927fff76f37d4c1aa8d6383783ed1ddd"><enum>(I)</enum><text>obtained by a covered governmental entity for purposes of conducting a background check of the covered person with the written consent of the covered person;</text></subclause><subclause id="id911f9970124d41ea87f267995f6745e7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>accessed and used by the covered governmental entity only for background check-related purposes; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id558c7df92c3d4efa930507c9134b248e"><enum>(III)</enum><text>destroyed at such time as the covered personal data is no longer needed for background check-related purposes.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id127728a0c790404fbd4ca1c50e7770f7"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Exception for lawfully obtained public data</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data that is obtained by a covered governmental entity if—</text><subclause id="ide49332c39ea542399f21045aa3e0414e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the covered personal data is lawfully obtained public data; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id00618cb1d3a841018dc63c3f643a6c73"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the covered personal data is derived from covered personal data that solely consists of lawfully obtained public data.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idde92a58cb9c946fea5761c3e80af74d2"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Exception for life or safety</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data that is obtained by a covered governmental entity if there is a reasonable belief than an emergency exists involving an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm to a covered person and the covered data is necessary to mitigate that threat, provided that—</text><subclause id="id7c3e9d48b0d9450ca2932644a7e6575d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>access to and use of the covered personal data is limited to addressing the threat; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide5cf8afa9080425a92275a05dbc621bc"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the covered personal data is destroyed at such time as it is no longer necessary for such purpose.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id143124df37664cb88a092286c34e7f9d"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Exception for compliance purposes</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data that is obtained by a covered governmental entity for the purpose of supporting compliance with collection limitations and minimization requirements imposed by statute, guidelines, procedures, or the Constitution of the United States, provided that—</text><subclause id="idf6bb2bba626849ceb6516ac4c452a36e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>access to and use of the covered personal data is limited to such purpose; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb981b8b765174d81a4a030601ce65e4c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the covered personal data is destroyed at such time as it is no longer necessary for such purpose.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf62127eee33f42579e6443647d683271"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Exception for consent</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to covered personal data that is obtained by a covered governmental entity if—</text><subclause id="idd5c1329c8c0640d0bc4e5c12aba112d1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>each covered person linked or reasonably linkable to the covered personal data, or, if such covered person is incapable of providing consent, a third party legally authorized to consent on behalf of the covered person, has provided consent to the acquisition and use of the data on a case-by-case basis;</text></subclause><subclause id="id723f79f46586414ea3debe6d409601df"><enum>(II)</enum><text>access to and use of the covered personal data is limited to the purposes for which the consent was provided; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id037256db6de54ba8a0c7d090581bf507"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the covered personal data is destroyed at such time as it is no longer necessary for such purposes.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0bd72b39dede42a59a3ccc0f2024eaea"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Indirectly acquired records and information</header><text>The limitation under subparagraph (A) shall apply without regard to whether the covered organization possessing the covered personal data is the covered organization that initially obtained or collected, or is the covered organization that initially received the disclosure of, the covered personal data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id04a734f9526649479b0f4031ea7a628e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limit on sharing between agencies</header><text>An agency of a governmental entity that is not a covered governmental entity may not provide to a covered governmental entity covered personal data that was obtained in a manner that would violate paragraph (2) if the agency of a governmental entity were a covered governmental entity, unless the covered governmental entity would have been permitted to obtain the covered personal data under an exception set forth in paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id54d243cf2d54475ebf6c21b39b12869f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of data obtained in violation of this section</header><subparagraph id="id171c076d2a134efd92c04770a806b8ee"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Covered personal data obtained by or provided to a covered governmental entity in violation of paragraph (2) or (3), and any evidence derived therefrom, may not be used, received in evidence, or otherwise disseminated by, on behalf of, or upon a motion or other action by a covered governmental entity in any investigation by or in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, officer, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id034e3f89892b4999ba5b6cc1304f65a1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use by aggrieved parties</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to limit the use of covered personal data by a covered person aggrieved of a violation of paragraph (2) or (3) in connection with any action relating to such a violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a5a8a03990b441a921044084bd264d9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Minimization procedures</header><paragraph id="id10bbd3009cea4deb83dc18348767b7d9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall adopt specific procedures that are reasonably designed to minimize the acquisition and retention, and to restrict the querying, of covered personal data, and prohibit the dissemination of information derived from covered personal data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id024391cfef9143d08c02fbdcd146e01e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acquisition and retention</header><text>The procedures adopted under paragraph (1) shall require covered governmental entities to exhaust all reasonable means—</text><subparagraph id="id57ffd0a326e6432aaa7a68306d68f85f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to exclude covered personal data that is not subject to 1 or more of the exceptions set forth in clauses (iii) through (x) of subsection (e)(2)(A) from the data obtained; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id595377e7aadd4438876d172fc6ff4b01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to remove and delete covered personal data described in subparagraph (A) not subject to 1 or more exceptions set forth in clauses (iii) through (x) of subsection (e)(2)(A) after a compilation is obtained and before operational use of the compilation or inclusion of the compilation in a dataset intended for operational use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d39cef2c3bf4d62ad6c96fc62abcbb8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Destruction</header><text>The procedures adopted under paragraph (1) shall require that, if a covered governmental entity identifies covered personal data in a compilation described in clause (ii) of subsection (e)(2)(A) not subject to 1 or more exceptions set forth in clauses (iii) through (x) of such subsection, the covered governmental entity shall promptly destroy the covered personal data and any dissemination of information derived from the covered personal data shall be prohibited.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd353bdaad63d4b918d7e9fb75b70fa62"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Querying</header><subparagraph id="id5b57590d7ed645428ffe3fe43d97e7bb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), no officer or employee of a covered governmental entity may conduct a query of personal data, including personal data already subjected to minimization, in an effort to find records of or about a particular covered person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1071c0eccaef4d4e86041bc89faaaf7e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a query related to a particular covered person if—</text><clause id="idf9ba9fa5a5ff49bcb9226c81821d5532"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such covered person is the subject of a court order issued under this title that would authorize the covered governmental entity to compel the production of the covered personal data, during the effective period of that order;</text></clause><clause id="id081b801034db4aebb57671f450732aed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the purpose of the query is to retrieve information obtained by a covered governmental entity under a program established by an Act of Congress under which a portion of a penalty or a similar payment or bounty is paid to an individual who discloses information about an unlawful activity to the Government, such as the program authorized under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7623">section 7623</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to awards to whistleblowers in cases of underpayments or fraud), provided that any covered personal data accessed through such query is used only for such purpose;</text></clause><clause id="id886f37cdc57c462ba952b049334c6c82"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the purpose of the query is to retrieve information about an employee of, or applicant for employment by, a covered governmental entity that has been obtained by the covered governmental entity for employment-related purposes, provided that any covered personal data accessed through such query is used only for such purposes;</text></clause><clause id="id9bf98264f5b34936a047dabdeda8e063"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the purpose of the query is to retrieve information obtained by a covered governmental entity for purposes of conducting a background check of the covered person with the written consent of the covered person, provided that any covered personal data accessed through such query is used only for such purposes;</text></clause><clause id="ide4cd2f0a744344f8a5a460e2e10347c0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the purpose of the query is to retrieve, and the query is reasonably designed to retrieve, only lawfully obtained public data, and only lawfully obtained public data is accessed and used as a result of the query;</text></clause><clause id="idc522f1ac9cbd4cfd9a285902d8a9d31a"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the officer or employee of a covered governmental entity carrying out the query has a reasonable belief that an emergency exists involving an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm, and in order to prevent or mitigate that threat, the query must be conducted before a court order can, with due diligence, be obtained, provided that any covered personal data accessed through such query is used only for such purpose;</text></clause><clause id="idab0233f8dee641ccb53ff8b08416af1e"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the query is conducted for the purpose of supporting compliance with collection limitations and minimization requirements imposed by statute, guidelines, procedures, or the Constitution of the United States, provided that any covered personal data accessed through such query is used only for such purpose; or</text></clause><clause id="id7190ce044e63406d833adb3c19cc6224"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>such covered person or, if such covered person is incapable of providing consent, a third party legally authorized to consent on behalf of the covered person has consented to the query, provided that any use of covered personal data accessed through such query is limited to the purposes for which the consent was provided.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef30f40a39f64ccfb8f82fc2d79aba5e"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule for compilations of data</header><text>For a query of a compilation of data obtained under subsection (e)(2)(A)(ii)—</text><clause id="id657b7f7ceaa14e0bb323aff3796769fd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each query shall be reasonably designed to exclude personal data of covered persons, unless the query is subject to an exception set forth in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc311255a3e842118a33698bb61edbba"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any personal data of covered persons returned pursuant to a query that is not subject to an exception set forth in clauses (ii) through (x) of subsection (e)(2)(A) shall not be reviewed and shall immediately be destroyed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idbde1866b68674116bcc0762519c8ee20"><enum>503.</enum><header>Consistent protections for demands for data held by interactive computing services</header><subsection id="id40f3cd3a808349b9804c3a9f44590309"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 2711 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd823fa1964ea449cb2ab6443e35a2753"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65fa5a5bdaac4225946fea3cccdd5470"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73eee48352374a11a8b571368dde5b1b"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf71bdda2a94a4a36b20edfc11ee8fd15"><paragraph id="id74ed03ce4e054becb92b14901bc8acf9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>online service provider</term> means a provider of electronic communication service, a provider of remote computing service, any information service, system, or access software provider that provides or enables computer access by multiple users to a computer server, including specifically a service or system that provides access to the Internet and such systems operated or services offered by libraries or educational institutions; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id16709315e4ec455292bc54c75cffec4b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required disclosure</header><text>Section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id83ef37f9d16e486d9abc8fd2a6479ea5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>a provider of electronic communication service</quote> and inserting <quote>an online service provider</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f0384645d7148c889ba85452fcbaeee"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="idf0d854a4c8a34a38aa7a0ddaa3aded91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service</quote> and inserting <quote>an online service provider</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d12446f27f04ded99183d39ebba096f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>A provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service</quote> and inserting <quote>An online service provider</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id52522fb7544643f4823e59290f96d249"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>a provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service</quote> and inserting <quote>an online service provider</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad25b115d4574726bb73c56377f5543d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on voluntary disclosure</header><text>Section 2702(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended— </text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e4ac427f8ba473f8db4d86ded014ad1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a person or entity providing an electronic communication service to the public</quote> and inserting <quote>an online service provider</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80ff27b66c204acc9c79b67b2af99e2b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>a person or entity providing remote computing service to the public</quote> and inserting <quote>an online service provider</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e7a2959880f40b49dbdfec86af5e124"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>a provider of remote computing service or electronic communication service to the public</quote> and inserting <quote>an online service provider</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6a6f03e54b49407497fab496e2f10200"><enum>504.</enum><header>Consistent privacy protections for data held by data brokers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2703 of title 18, United States Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id035f354abfe14e5c801393c665229c26"><subsection id="id337553d15c6849ad966c6f591bd1d5a1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered personal data</header><paragraph id="id7f09aaea91384a7ab8c27236fb996901"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>covered personal data</term> and <term>covered organization</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 2702(e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53b64c2934034e3ca770cc4793f0d7ba"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Unless a governmental entity obtains an order in accordance with paragraph (3), the governmental entity may not require a covered organization that is not an online service provider to disclose covered personal data if a court order would be required for the governmental entity to require an online service provider to disclose such covered personal data that is a record of a customer or subscriber of the online service provider.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddba04049d3774e50a621c5d9ab00ea80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Orders</header><subparagraph id="id7fadddafc1a1489f8774954b0435dc9e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A court may only issue an order requiring a covered organization that is not an online service provider to disclose covered personal data on the same basis and subject to the same limitations as would apply to a court order to require disclosure by an online service provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99e498ad86074299851584bd57f1de48"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standard</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a court shall apply the most stringent standard under Federal statute or the Constitution of the United States that would be applicable to a request for a court order to require a comparable disclosure by an online service provider of a customer or subscriber of the online service provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id9219ee40dece42e3a0633723940d366e"><enum>505.</enum><header>Protection of data entrusted to intermediary or ancillary service providers</header><subsection id="id987c4d15aa6d4f638d8aa81b7a9d35e4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 2711 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 503 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08ac8f18f5774b86a438a7352d7362e9"><paragraph id="id7ea21adf69bb4de3a1d80e0ff4a75e67"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>intermediary or ancillary service provider</term> means an entity or facilities owner or operator that directly or indirectly delivers, transmits, stores, or processes communications or any other covered personal data (as defined in section 2702(e) of this title) for, or on behalf of, an online service provider.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idc58ebefad3b54649837ab2c7d724f769"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Section 2702(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id3f45ad42f84344c2a438e878797e7f59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fd91117e8f74274bea184f112fc5930"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaae271a0794e40be8ceef7582ddae947"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida69daff578164d78a86b043a55b4f334"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45fff57e86c443a1b366923b9f6e5f27"><paragraph id="idbae32a7fe4684b018ac586300971301e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an intermediary or ancillary service provider may not knowingly disclose—</text><subparagraph id="idefd2222e13864585b38940cd64a9e225"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to any person or entity the contents of a communication while in electronic storage by that intermediary or ancillary service provider; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3fea13c05d744a481131b3ff1e66183"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to any governmental entity a record or other information pertaining to a subscriber to or customer of, a recipient of a communication from a subscriber to or customer of, or the sender of a communication to a subscriber to or customer of, the online service provider for, or on behalf of, which the intermediary or ancillary service provider directly or indirectly delivers, transmits, stores, or processes communications or any other covered personal data (as defined in subsection (e)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="idc9f00f7466ca40f58c02700ce71c9332" style="OLC"><enum>VI</enum><header>Transparency</header><section id="idde54c258021f432093c9e1c596bcd177"><enum>601.</enum><header>Enhanced reports by Director of National Intelligence</header><subsection id="ide72fa13c1c754cd2ae9ac8657ed5f24e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 603(b) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1873">50 U.S.C. 1873(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd63e7c5ede2641459eaab79e293799e3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(C), by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0dc36b8f43bc40cc87bc8bccb6b0e15d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (7) as paragraphs (6) through (10), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72d260b8804d44e680ff4b12389de2e8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bb4f12c4b7f46ada8bec94baf066bcc"><paragraph id="id725ce3b10c5c420d9f4d05a0cc207257"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the subject matter of each of the certifications provided under section 702(h);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bba6236aaa0463daf32189d5dbca0be"><enum>(4)</enum><text>statistics revealing the number of persons targeted and the number of selectors used under section 702(a), disaggregated by the certification under which the person was targeted;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f55d1f655bd4df1a53c93fee4df2dd7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the total number of directives issued pursuant to section 702(i)(1), disaggregated by each type of electronic communication service provider described in section 701(b)(4);</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idfacdddc253fe446e91e1548a2556def3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id706b516538244001817384c4f0bda528"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), as so redesignated, by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ef66fd324f647cc88894adc9bd61fd1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9fb64a7bf9647abb43b9670e653c81b"><paragraph id="id608bbf4c2e7542c68064750aed928013"><enum>(11)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="iddb4047af733c4d05aca5af985e82d58d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of disseminated intelligence reports derived from collection pursuant to section 702 containing the identities of United States persons, regardless of whether the identities of the United States persons were openly included or masked;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id97e9440f06bd4c85ba32735b164aa7e1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of disseminated intelligence reports derived from collection not authorized by this Act and conducted under procedures approved by the Attorney General containing the identities of United States persons, regardless of whether the identities of the United States persons were openly included or masked;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id92ee686a0c7b40eb9af048e247588d11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number of disseminated intelligence reports derived from collection pursuant to section 702 containing the identities of United States persons in which the identities of the United States persons were masked;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id6569813d307b431db7e04c2c47fd2bd0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the total number of disseminated intelligence reports derived from collection not authorized by this Act and conducted under procedures approved by the Attorney General containing the identities of United States persons in which the identities of the United States persons were masked;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idd07264b9643f400a9f2caceb7eb1161e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total number of disseminated intelligence reports derived from collection pursuant to section 702 containing the identities of United States persons in which the identities of the United States persons were openly included; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id816b642457bc4951be50e2b2b9903e0e"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the total number of disseminated intelligence reports derived from collection not authorized by this Act and conducted under procedures approved by the Attorney General containing the identities of United States persons in which the identities of the United States persons were openly included;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide59e48c2d9ef423b9e36579660688ed7"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the number of queries conducted in an effort to find communications or information of or about 1 or more United States persons or persons reasonably believed to be located in the United States at the time of the query or the time of the communication or creation of the information, where such communications or information were obtained under procedures approved by the Attorney General and without a court order, subpoena, or other legal process established by statute;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc930aae7d4ca49ddb40e05594fd2c9fa"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the number of criminal proceedings in which the Federal Government or a government of a State or political subdivision thereof entered into evidence or otherwise used or disclosed in a criminal proceeding any information obtained or derived from an acquisition conducted under procedures approved by the Attorney General and without a court order, subpoena, or other legal process established by statute; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id314be7c51a4542879a8f178a41e2a848"><enum>(14)</enum><text>a good faith estimate of what percentage of the communications that are subject to the procedures described in section 309(b)(3) of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1813">50 U.S.C. 1813(b)(3)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="id6785d65a280d431c8b81444a2b4b2c25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are retained for more than 5 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id789dd4abd7fe4fad857725ef28e3370c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are retained for more than 5 years because, in whole or in part, the communications are encrypted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc560284622be4eccb2ce792da545387b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of nonapplicability to Federal Bureau of Investigation of certain requirements</header><text>Section 603(d) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1873">50 U.S.C. 1873(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id97b4285a85c04f6a893d5d144f7fbd5e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id179532c4cff94fe4a8331e7aa080ce56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb87e56bf5002465d90f0e903eba01151" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 603(d)(1) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1873">50 U.S.C. 1873(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>paragraphs (3), (5), or (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (6), (8), or (9)</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2cc630b48504666a9d09aa7510fbd94"><enum>602.</enum><header>Notification to Congress of certain unauthorized disclosures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 18(a) of the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>congressional intelligence committees</quote> and inserting <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote>.</text></section></title><title id="idb06a326cb10b4d69bcb4830d06b98b63" style="OLC"><enum>VII</enum><header>Limited delays in implementation</header><section id="idbf41a31b1ecc484dbaa4ee562f728e01"><enum>701.</enum><header>Limited delays in implementation</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2c6a6852b4741e8b0de6f2c40a9abd1"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id0effed52facd48a8879e96d21f6e1085"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the congressional intelligence committees (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb632ac22b699430daf13144b8491d9fc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb4e9c62b17b40829bbf8f4df04d62d0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideac3cd0ccfc94814891b18ba483ca183"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence as may be appropriate, delay implementation of a provision of this Act or an amendment made by this Act for a period of not more than 180 days upon a showing to the appropriate committees of Congress that the delay is necessary—</text><paragraph id="id91c38bd295534bd3aee73cdb8f204319"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop and implement technical systems needed to comply with the provision or amendment; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcd9bfc0e8034e74b8cf367c37d01e15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to hire or train personnel needed to comply with the provision or amendment. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

