<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDEF95082E4804567803D52E91DD7A945" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9157 IH: American White-Collar Worker Jobs Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9157</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reform the H–1B process, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H67B559CFF7AA4179877E4B0D836FB5D7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA87ACEA5F4964FFEB6849BDBD7B29D9D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American White-Collar Worker Jobs Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD3319B71AD54404FA110EB8AF88D6DC6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reasserting congress’s constitutional authority over immigration</header> <subsection id="H57827492E9D446449AAA9A4EC9FEB432"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The power to authorize employment for classes of aliens is reserved to Congress.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAFC3CC6AC2F346788EB5E48999D2A4AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unauthorized alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 274A(h)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>pursuant to statute</quote> after <quote>Attorney General</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAC4E61D2DB654EFCB006B4815554F9A0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act applies to an alien’s entry and entire stay in the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H05A8C6B8E7A545C18F42D866A505FA50"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 214(a)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>The authority to prescribe regulations under this section is limited to those necessary to set the duration of admission and to insure that at upon failure to maintain the status under which an alien was admitted, or to maintain any status subsequently acquired under section 248, the alien with will leave the country.</quote> after the first sentence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4F87631389D84780B71D47B2494FF54B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall update rules regarding nonimmigrants to be consistent with this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A6CFFADAF5949A29163521074011EFC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nonimmigrant classification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 248 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1258">8 U.S.C. 1258</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF0DA9C888CEC4201913447AD53C58760" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H316E96FB77F54003B0F7091710F4A07A"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any adjustment of status under this section requires complying with the admission and ongoing requirements of the new nonimmigrant status acquired.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFBC942CDE73149418672586430DC6DB5"><enum>3.</enum><header>H–1B reform</header> 
<subsection id="HE30751B5D0424DAD91CDC2AE45A5CA30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header> 
<paragraph id="HB4B7753BD7B746CABE04F359DE867D29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nonimmigrant requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(a)(15)(H) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>having a residence in a foreign country which he has no intention of abandoning</quote> before <quote>who is coming</quote> the first place it appears.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5F2154845C44504AE8404F97F807D74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immigrant presumption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 214(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>(other than a nonimmigrant described in subparagraph (L) or (V) of section 101(a)(15), and other than a nonimmigrant described in any provision of section 101(a)(15)(H)(i) except subclause (b1) of such section)</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32DC3BBE9AAD4BE8BCEE1353E7244006"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special provisions for lengthy adjudications</header><text>Section 106 of American Competitiveness Act in the Twenty-first Century Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/313">Public Law 106–313</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB80FF5D34BB4F3BB8429A839EE10A7E"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Admission of nonimmigrants</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 214(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(h)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H88E40691BC6D475ABEBD4773B1792832"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Labor condition application</header> 
<paragraph id="H35A6713E55614AAFA04F623F0B9A6B09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inadmissibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(n)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H6AE40FE232C1424D8A0257C9F77DD820" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2AC42779B2A5494F83B0E51AD4DAB9A0"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph id="HA0D2C8BFF9864A56BF00BDB84D89AF88" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No alien may be admitted or provided status as an H–1B nonimmigrant in an occupational classification unless the employer has filed with the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Labor has approved an application that—</text> 
<clause id="H7B3E529F362F44F2A135B38C0C5430B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>uniquely identifies the potential nonimmigrant to whom the application applies, including a photograph;</text></clause> <clause id="HFF159690A6114DDF9213E3C164E19097"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specifies the occupational classification of employment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4FA547111D0147A9875FE0EA55748098"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>specifies the address where the nonimmigrant will be employed;</text></clause> <clause id="H5D92500C8B98494EBD299F27BEA4B29B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>specifies the wage to be paid to the nonimmigrant;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H719E78C6BF4043E3967A87C4AD2E479B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>specifies the nationality of the nonimmigrant;</text></clause> <clause id="H11B20334F92C45F38086064A621AC2D3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>includes any other information the Secretary of Labor determines is necessary; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3391A1A101644C26A9CBEF07B665D1CA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>certifies the following:</text> <subclause id="H1921DFDC32C14682BBDC487CA49B6888"><enum>(I)</enum><text>That the employer will pay the nonimmigrant full-time wages for the entire period of employment that are the higher of—</text> 
<item id="HC6C8ACB73B804107A1487E26B828693B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the actual wage level paid by the employer to all other individuals with similar experience and qualifications for the specific employment in question; or</text></item> <item id="HFA8DB4946A39437BAE7AC82AB6EBE71D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the wage determined by the Secretary of Labor to be at the 75th percentile for workers in the same location and occupation.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCBDDB0A894F94767B617EE42C3ACBAD9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>There are not sufficient workers who are able, willing, and qualified, and who will be available at the time and place needed, to perform the labor or services involved in the petition.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6F930EDA9D84415E8DEA162C83E6AC77"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The employment of the alien in such labor or services will not adversely affect the wages and working conditions of workers in the United States similarly employed.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE0384F8DEBCA4104950AA9BCE74D113E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>There is not a strike or lockout in the course of a labor dispute in the occupational classification at the place of employment.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H30B92FF7C36F427788F481FA07B73F87"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The employer, at the time of filing the application—</text> 
<item id="H7DEFC4867762435BACBF8F987A12FE11"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>has provided notice of the filing under this paragraph to the bargaining representative (if any) of the employer’s employees in the occupational classification and area for which aliens are sought; or</text></item> <item id="H5005EA0E5DEC48F6AF716736569608DA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if there is no such bargaining representative, has provided notice of filing in the occupational classification through such methods as physical posting in conspicuous locations at the place of employment or electronic notification to employees in the occupational classification for which an H–1B nonimmigrant is sought.</text> </item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H434B195D6860447890A9536F0894F2C0"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The H–1B nonimmigrant has not and will not displace any United States workers either directly employed by the employer or indirectly by a third-party employer.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD2A5020806E048A583974E93105D934A"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The employer has not and will not lay off any United States workers in the same employment classification within one year of making the application.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H99A9AB67F902456F8D66AD114D012C0A"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>An employer, prior to filing the application—</text> <item id="H1CBBED27B95146D9840F1FC7CC6D8381"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>has advertised the job on an internet website maintained by the Secretary of Labor for the purpose of such advertising;</text>
                                        </item> 
<item id="HB5440DA14D074F6795B1DEE73126793F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>has offered the job to any United States worker who applies and is equally or better qualified for the job for which the nonimmigrant is sought; and</text></item> <item id="H3CCC2AC2BCFF43BC9BAE8B11F67156CF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>has taken good faith steps to recruit, in the United States using procedures that meet industry-wide standards and offering compensation that is at least as great as that required to be offered to H–1B nonimmigrants under subclause (III), United States workers for the job for which the nonimmigrant or nonimmigrants is or are sought.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1054B5DB54F947508F3F2A5235A7FB37">
                                        <enum>(IX)</enum>
 <text>The employer has not placed any advertisements specifically seeking to hire nonimmigrants either directly or through a third party within the past year.</text>
                                    </subclause> 
<subclause id="HD00989CCFA064D8E85360DA7918F9CDB"><enum>(X)</enum><text>The percentage of the employer’s employees within the United States who are nonimmigrants does not exceed 5 percent.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC9C8EDD2D60541BC94A6EE1793524C7C"> <enum>(XI)</enum> <text>The nonimmigrant is fully qualified to perform the occupation of intended employment, including possessing a bachelor’s degree or higher from a university determined to be equivalent to a degree from a United States university by recognized educational credential evaluation service in a field that is related to the occupation and possessing any licenses required for that occupation. The Secretary of Labor shall determine which educational credential evaluation services are recognized.</text>
                                    </subclause> 
<subclause id="H36C3B3350A304EB7812B7AAD93ECD954"><enum>(XII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nonimmigrant has not and will not be required to pay any part of the fees or expenses for obtaining the visa.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9924B173CADB4A29A499B908B8B393B5"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nonimmigrant has not and will not be required to pay for any services provided by the employer, such as housing.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDFD75465059D476C9D0DB54D6F762C15"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nonimmigrant has not and will not be charged any fee, bond, damages or similar for ceasing employment with the employer.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H868CB4AF482846228D3E20058830DD2F"><enum>(XV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The employer does not restrict employment opportunities, such as using a preferred vendor list, for either temporary or permanent employment to those supplied by or referred by specific third parties.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE50DF57DF754BA9BBE83F63AE74B9E8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor shall review the contents of the application before approval. The Secretary of Labor shall not approve an application for an occupational classification where the unemployment rate exceeds 2 percent.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B2C94E6EF7C4B45BCC84EA56363555D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor shall make available to the public information received in applications, less any personal identifying information.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85946A75C0CB453FA719547062879562" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish and maintain a website for employers to post jobs prior to seeking foreign labor.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F5CCF69E81E410BBA85DB03F3E5368F" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The application shall be valid for making a petition for a visa under section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b) for 90 days after approval.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B2F5C92E8DE42B79B9B62E0B40B1D16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prevailing wage</header><text>Section 212(p) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(p)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H55C99424F96740D18FC9094248ABF89A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) and (4); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD757A411953B49118ACF866B356C1B19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8A91C9E4544465E8180228119B7A92F"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Occupational classification</header> <text>Section 212(t)(2)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(t)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by striking all that follows after <quote>subsection</quote> and inserting a period.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC53BF4E697624292B5833832972F4630"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Section 212(n)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBB3ABC197F2647A29309A323F3386391" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HA26AB5EB926F49A9BA7160AA462CADF5"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph id="HA6E74D3875DE4BCE9DBA3609183D4151" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor has the power to enforce the provisions of this paragraph, including the power to investigate, review documents submitted as part of the visa process, subpoena, and audit.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6960077692454B078F87907D8159217D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall establish a process for receiving complaints of violations of this paragraph. The Secretary may act on any such complaint received within 1 year of the alleged violation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD5B18F41E4D4B5CBA877533B9E19127" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor may charge an employer that violates the terms of this paragraph. An employer charged shall have the right to request a hearing. The Secretary of Labor may sanction an employer up to $100,000 (inflation adjusted) for each violation of the terms of this paragraph. The Secretary of Labor may also ban an employer from employing H–1B nonimmigrants, both directly and indirectly through a third party, for up to 10 years. A party may appeal such a judgment of the Secretary of Labor to the court of appeals having geographic jurisdiction where the violations were found to have occurred.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED29A7B082254D41BC1DC4AF65C0DB0E" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States workers have the right not to be displaced by nonimmigrant workers. Any United States worker who is displaced by a nonimmigrant shall have a cause of action in tort in the Federal courts against those employers causing the displacement, whether directly or indirectly.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF8E7347476034497B526D294626724E5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions repeal</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 212(n) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF7778C552E684EB5A0DE5A84EC2138A1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Displacement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(n)(4)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)(4)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, and is located in the same area of employment as the other job</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0743657B7BB84C52A3D2D94D44CFA51B"> <enum>(f)</enum> <header>Lay offs</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(n)(4)(D)(i)(II) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)(4)(D)(i)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>(or, in the case of a placement of a worker with another employer under paragraph (1)(F), with either employer described in such paragraph)</quote> and inserting <quote>in the same area of employment</quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H437EA806A09F466C9DE8A3CEB879E109"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Manner of issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 214(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD6B97DB50E6848F788AA776DCCF229E5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA68C863795D7429EABA77F8AD154A1F7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HDBBB0ECD79964AB3874BABB0053A937B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b), may not exceed 65,000.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6978D7B10A9434CB168AC0A40C41C18"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>in the order in which petitions are filed for such visas or status</quote> and inserting <quote>, with priority given to petitions with higher salaries</quote>;</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5E99E4A3DBD405E93C0EC0835349DA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>6 years.</quote> and inserting <quote>2 calendar years. This duration starts with the date that is the earlier of the date of admission or date of change of status to that of a nonimmigrant under section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b), or 90 days after the visa is issued.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5C9A5F48E81417EB75187B35C36DB1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraphs (5) through (7) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE91EFEC369D043C28E0E8076509097B8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H1A161F1B1A194436BB5149D8AB180859"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of nonimmigrants admitted under section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b) from any one country may not exceed 7 percent of the number allotted under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B58C18E4A164359960AD91B4D03CA75"> <enum>(h)</enum> <header>New employment repeal</header> <text>Section 214(n) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(n)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
            </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

