<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E9E0E0153CE4FACAAC1E1DC11BA343D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6868 IH: Advancing Consumer Choice, Equity, Safety, and Self-Care Through OTC Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6868</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to apply the least burdensome appropriate means for supporting certain administrative order requests with respect to over-the-counter monograph drugs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3DF72530758349868C824FF3D9A65828" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2E12FF13A17047BF94FE538B23DC8691" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Consumer Choice, Equity, Safety, and Self-Care Through OTC Innovation Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ACCESS Through OTC Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H07D1AD4A3297459C8ED8C76CD1C33966"><enum>2.</enum><header>Least burdensome means for supporting certain administrative order requests with respect to over-the-counter monograph drugs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 505G of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355h">21 U.S.C. 355h</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD387A39B2498478386BFC32680D388BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (q) as subsection (r); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H459A6537D7D8459E86ADC0AE43BF843A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (p) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H265B6B3F34B245D7955A699802F49C9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H8682F42F0F374706A035F8BA6B3C90DC"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Least burdensome means for supporting requests for certain administrative orders</header> <paragraph id="HA6021EEC3A3746D88031E78282E9239E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining whether a drug is generally recognized as safe and effective under section 201(p)(1) when evaluating a request submitted under subsection (b)(5), the Secretary shall apply the least burdensome appropriate means for supporting such a request and satisfying the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A29E699DE3C4C7B816D7B799F06A4CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Meeting requests</header> 
<subparagraph id="H00109743D0E848F380D64648CD53F236"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an order requested under subsection (b)(5), and if published reports are insufficient to support the requested findings, the Secretary shall meet with the requestor, if the requestor makes a reasonable written request for the meeting, for the purpose of providing recommendations on the types of evidence necessary, including, if appropriate, the potential design and size of any studies to support a demonstration that the drug is generally recognized as safe and effective.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDA1E20C4A324B8798B8258D611EE86D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preparation and availability of meeting minutes</header><text>The Secretary shall prepare, and make available to the requestor, the minutes of any such meeting.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9A509CDC3FC479A8B137D13E6A81BBC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administrative record</header><text>In the case of any such meeting, the Secretary shall reduce to writing and make a part of the administrative record—</text> <clause id="HC786E8E6F5E040C7A0DFCF0B1A25363D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any recommendations regarding the parameters of studies under this paragraph that the Secretary provides to the requestor; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5E842DD5E3024273A2DA6DEC56B356C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary of the meeting discussion.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A1F5CAE50CE4707A7C1A3D75C6CAEB5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to alter, supersede, or limit the criteria—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1082E5F805424CFAAF53B39F8E6353CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for determining under subsection (b)(5)(A) whether a request is sufficiently complete and formatted to permit a substantive review; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4B40C21F97F4FBF8A39A6CD8C59BA0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for determining whether a drug is generally recognized as safe and effective under section 201(p)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

