<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25L13-GRV-TX-0DK">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3052 IS: To promote recruiter access to secondary schools.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3052</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251023">October 23, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on
                    Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To promote recruiter access to secondary schools.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="id5b5c54d6087541b2b618a8b10234006f" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Recruiter access to secondary schools</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 503(c)(1)(A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="ide3c040e27eaa40b4b0ef4bfae25c3670">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>by amending clause (i) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="idFAF8B4950078432097612A9DF4764CFF" style="OLC" act-name=""> <clause indent="up2" id="idE7C31D1BB473420F9991B5AE926690F9"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>shall provide military recruiters the same access to the campus of each secondary school served by the local educational agency for the purpose of recruiting students who are at least 17 years of age that is provided to any prospective employer, institution of higher education, or other recruiter;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idab745316691c476585f7db983c335d2c">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>provide to military recruiters access to</quote> and inserting <quote>facilitate upon request made by military recruiters for military recruiting purposes not fewer than four in-person recruitment events per academic year, across different grading periods, which may include</quote>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c3ac6055c904438923d952c44e00f72">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending clause (iii) to read as follows:</text>
                <quoted-block id="id3CCC64BA245F4E97B45E9EA884181905" style="OLC" act-name="">
                    <clause indent="up2" id="id9864793F3108424BA54FEEC765D07CE4">
                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>shall provide to military recruiters within 60 days of the commencement of the academic year, and thereafter within 30 days of a recruiter request, access to secondary school student names, academic grade, addresses, electronic mail addresses (which shall be the electronic mail addresses provided by the school, if available), and telephone and mobile phone listings, notwithstanding subsection (a)(5) of section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>).</text>
                    </clause>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

