<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BA4C9AB32F04B5085208EB291C0EE5D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7404 IH: Fair Repair Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7404</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require original equipment manufacturers of digital electronic equipment to make available certain documentation, diagnostic, and repair information to independent repair providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H48236C2BB1DE4AB5BDD99CFD32FB103B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H08C6A1BE92B9411DA5A825C78E9605D3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Repair Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H0EE6F4F429EB469892827645108A85CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements for original equipment manufacturers</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4219B960DBF7461694000CA33AAC803C"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of digital electronic equipment manufactured by or on behalf of, sold, or otherwise supplied by an original equipment manufacturer, the original equipment manufacturer shall make available, for the purposes of diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of such equipment, to independent repair providers and owners of such equipment on fair and reasonable terms, documentation, parts, and tools, inclusive of any updates.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87DC3368CB92416888A3E825A91BDCBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of certain parts</header><text>An original equipment manufacturer shall not use parts pairing or any other mechanism to—</text> <paragraph id="H35A42171E5EC457B9A379B67F5F09683"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent the installation or functioning of any otherwise-functional part, including a non-manufacturer approved replacement part or component;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4A478ED400AE42E884F639BF8CDB0283"><enum>(2)</enum><text>inhibit or reduce the functioning of any part, such that replacement by an independent repair provider or the device owner would cause the device to operate with reduced functionality or performance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB15F5DA48EFF4A35BE3B3D753C161803"><enum>(3)</enum><text>create false, misleading, deceptive, or non-dismissible alerts or warnings about parts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3590F40AD5B8487F9979B5E0EF5BBADC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>charge additional fees or increased prices for future repairs; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61C9AD0314184DAC8DAF60F43E7DBF95"><enum>(5)</enum><text>limit who can purchase parts or perform repair services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H838B43122ACE4BC0A8C9BDCADEA1B739"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
<subsection id="HE39B7A9151E2470AB59BCD1F499218C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission</header>
<paragraph id="H088EEB19FE9A4ADE907B250B3444E0A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of section 2 shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7722A90D577E41F8AD5082DA731CA9E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> <subparagraph id="H05AD67C938AC4767B4BF94AF369C25D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this Act and any regulations promulgated under this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act, and any person who violates this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HD5CF6EE622F44196A926FB77B5FDC91B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, prescribe any regulations it determines necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B17130187B3471581B13D1C29D9B29A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H96E57B8ADC854010A250B42BAE167BCE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by State attorneys general</header>
<paragraph id="HC2F0FC6CA70149B9A798CC8DEFFB45E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the chief law enforcement officer of a State, or an official or agency designated by a State, has reason to believe that any person has violated or is violating section 2, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State, in addition to any authority it may have to bring an action in State court under State law, may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court or in any other court of competent jurisdiction, including a State court, to—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4607692BAB44AF98CCD01E6343B9CAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin further such violation by such person;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAC00E4352F234F31930399D720ECACB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9204F7A9908E4CB8B46B4AD544E2C645"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain civil penalties; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB139E90E258F4C9C9FD10F60567734A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E3441F31F1E4321A25886D159DD59C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice and intervention by the FTC</header><text>The attorney general (or other such officer) of a State shall provide prior written notice of any action under paragraph (1) to the Commission and provide the Commission with a copy of the complaint in the action, except in any case in which such prior notice is not feasible, in which case the attorney general shall serve such notice immediately upon instituting such action. The Commission shall have the right—</text>
<subparagraph id="H66D3525D140741ADBAB40FC3B58EE938"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intervene in the action;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72AF401501AF4A659F5C120F8906F480"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H28B3851838A14E28B1DF2C8CCF5E4746"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF783DA82A2094AF8BB4BB2B418BBF104"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text>If the Commission has instituted a civil action for violation of this Act, no State attorney general, or official or agency of a State, may bring an action under this paragraph during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for any violation of this Act alleged in the complaint.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H359223194549427F9AF3721842BD85E7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship with State law claims</header><text>If the attorney general of a State has authority to bring an action under State law directed at acts or practices that also violate this Act, the attorney general may assert the State law claim and a claim under this Act in the same civil action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H199648D19DFC4917BBCE90311150032B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rules of construction, limitations, and non-application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following rules of construction, limitations, and non-application provisions apply to this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H81F66D2EC5E84A9F9475C3A2D1CD2744"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Security-related functions not excluded</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For digital electronic equipment that contains an electronic security lock or other security-related function, the original equipment manufacturer shall make available to the owner and to independent repair providers, on fair and reasonable terms, any special documentation, tools, and parts needed to disable the lock or function, and to reset it when disabled in the course of diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of the equipment, to restore full functionality of the equipment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA8770038245B4618B5B62848088E486F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of trade secrets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require an original equipment manufacturer to divulge a trade secret, as defined in section 1839 of title 18, United States Code, to an owner or an independent repair provider except as necessary to provide documentation, parts, and tools on fair and reasonable terms.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3472A53EA54445F9C1D4BBF2A0B81B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms of agreement with authorized repair providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No provision in this Act shall be construed to abrogate, interfere with, contradict, or alter the terms of any arrangement described in section 6(1)(A), including the performance or provision of warranty or recall repair work by an authorized repair provider on behalf of an original equipment manufacturer pursuant to such arrangement, except that any provision in such terms that purports to waive, avoid, restrict, or limit an OEM's obligations to comply with this Act shall be void and unenforceable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB6CF959B2564C0284E97118BF7C58FB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-application to motor vehicle or motor vehicle equipment manufacturers</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall apply to a motor vehicle manufacturer, a manufacturer of motor vehicle equipment, or a motor vehicle dealer, acting in that capacity. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5F247102F7C470B941B7E178F827BC1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-application to manufacturers of medical devices</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall apply to a manufacturer of a medical device, acting in that capacity. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H395F157D24B24A7A88F677410E05F198"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Non-application to manufacturers of off-road or non-road vehicles</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall apply to any manufacturer, distributor, importer, or dealer of an off-road or non-road vehicle, acting in that capacity, including without limitation, aircraft, motorcycles, marine vessels, all terrain sports vehicles, utility terrain vehicles, recreational vehicles, and racing vehicles.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFDFEBAD07222453297896EF0E4C421A0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Non-application to manufacturers of safety communications equipment</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall apply to any manufacturer of safety communications equipment, the intended use of which is for emergency response or prevention purposes by an emergency services organization, such as police, fire, or medical and emergency rescue services agencies, acting in that capacity.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66DE5B7CF697442CBC5C8F9B83187B78"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header> <subsection id="H496C7BF502184EE4AA087F4A1B935D25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Damage resulting from repair</header><text>No original equipment manufacturer or authorized repair provider shall be liable for any damage or injury to any digital electronic equipment, person, or property that occurs as a result of repair, diagnosis, maintenance, or modification performed by an independent repair provider or owner, or any other use by an independent repair provider or owner of parts, tools, or documentation provided by an original equipment manufacturer, including with respect to any—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01A2BE84BC8E4CB3BD6953E77B22CAC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indirect, incidental, special, or consequential damages; </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84BC208435AB40048ABB69A2751E17D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">loss of data, privacy, or profits; or </text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43B57F88ADE24894A5657BC2EDC89161"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inability to use, or reduced functionality of, the digital electronic equipment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H20021CF980734A0193DB23E7E68FCDC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No warranty for independent repair providers or owners</header><text>An original equipment manufacturer shall not be required to warrant any repairs provided by independent repair providers or owners.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3F7A9E9BE8CA47CC8119341ED6CA072C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Improper use of personal data</header><text>No original equipment manufacturer shall be liable for improper use of personal data or any data privacy or security breach in connection with repair, diagnosis, maintenance, or modification performed by an independent repair provider or owner.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9E751B4DBE8D4F67982BF2ABD0F3E3AF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text>
<paragraph id="H4C3B35B5097E42E08BEB56F764933E99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorized repair provider</header>
<subparagraph id="HE0365B9AE90A4421BA4E55C06D5E740F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>authorized repair provider</term> means with respect to an OEM, a person that—</text> <clause id="HD801AA63144B4EE7AFA66B2A149CC36B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has an arrangement with the OEM in which the OEM grants to the person license to use a trade name, service mark, or other proprietary identifier for the purposes of offering the services of diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of digital electronic equipment under the name of the OEM; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H5E488677B4AD4A6B9D441D02C2A1BD07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise has an arrangement with the OEM to offer such services on behalf of or under contract with the OEM.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDABF2AC0CCC446889019274049B5D52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An OEM that offers the services of diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of digital electronic equipment manufactured by it or on its behalf, or sold or otherwise supplied by the OEM, shall be considered an authorized repair provider with respect to such equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA6C55D4F71C4299AE4930FA110FE446"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital electronic equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>digital electronic equipment</term> means any product that depends for its functioning, in whole or in part, on digital electronics embedded in or attached to the product. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H734AC2E486804C8FA7EC96724664517A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>documentation</term> means any manuals, diagrams, reporting output, service code descriptions, schematic, security code or password, or other information used in effecting the services of diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of digital electronic equipment.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H711926D11E8047F883171B0A99555E7A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fair and reasonable terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fair and reasonable terms</term>, with respect to a part, tool, or documentation, means at costs and terms that are equivalent to the most favorable costs and terms under which an OEM offers the part, tool, or documentation to an authorized repair provider—</text> <subparagraph id="HC967A5BFD0754083AECB97362EA71265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accounting for any discount, rebate, convenient and timely means of delivery, means of enabling fully restored and updated functionality, rights of use, or other incentive or preference the OEM offers to an authorized repair provider, and for any additional cost, burden, or impediment the OEM imposes on an owner or independent repair provider;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7EE6702852C74A728FC2252A143E71D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not conditioned on or imposing a substantial obligation or restriction that is not reasonably necessary for enabling the owner or independent repair provider to engage in the diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of digital electronic equipment made by or on behalf of the OEM; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BB9609C90F348869D4896730F5309B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not conditioned on an arrangement described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3FC3713D1DAB409CB95EF589717A062E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Independent repair provider</header>
<subparagraph id="HAA09E7E765014B7AA56930C1CEFB60C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>independent repair provider</term> means with respect to an OEM, a person that is not affiliated with the OEM or with an authorized repair provider of the OEM, when such person is engaged in the diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of digital electronic equipment manufactured by or on behalf of, sold, or otherwise supplied by the OEM.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A7EA514256C4D5C9A27743CE68C4556"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An OEM or, with respect to that OEM, a person who has an arrangement described in paragraph (1)(A) with that OEM, or who is affiliated with a person who has such an arrangement with that OEM, shall be considered an independent repair provider for the purposes of those instances when such OEM or person engages in the diagnosis, service, maintenance, or repair of digital equipment that is not manufactured by or on behalf of, sold, or otherwise supplied by that OEM.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF5C048FCA980468B9894AA3BF3C8F7FF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Medical device</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medical device</term> has the meaning given the term <term>device</term> under section 201(h) of the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(h)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFFBCB9A1DE0401BBF0A1AC7DACF5D89"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle</term> means a vehicle that is designed for transporting persons or property on a street or highway and is certified by the manufacturer under all applicable Federal safety and emissions standards and requirements for distribution and sale in the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6D805AB8033141229FE0BA0719B81A0C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Motor vehicle dealer</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle dealer</term> means a person who—</text> <subparagraph id="HABF6DDD2CBDF43F58866D8B38CC86D0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is engaged in the business of selling or leasing new motor vehicles to another person pursuant to a franchise agreement;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H16932A2E0B9C481F9F93892650D7DBB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has obtained a license to engage in such business under the applicable State law; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CDA8DF573C74E64AF0777E2EF622B1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is engaged in the services of diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of motor vehicles or motor vehicle engines pursuant to such franchise agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE5A3BC5BF5848F1AE6D67BB01BBE195"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Motor vehicle manufacturer</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle manufacturer</term> means a person engaged in the business of manufacturing or assembling new motor vehicles. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5F3218AB3AEC4E5E8344C2E2FD9F0EF4"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Original equipment manufacturer; OEM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>original equipment manufacturer</term> or <term>OEM</term> means a person who is engaged in the business of selling, leasing, or otherwise supplying new digital electronic equipment or parts of equipment manufactured by or on behalf of itself, to any person. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H352DB8CBA6AF4FB39E546A597DFCA4E0"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Owner</header><text>The term <term>owner</term> means a person who owns or leases digital electronic equipment. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9404BF2C416D491CA8534A4455512BB4"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Part</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>part</term> means any replacement part, either new or used, made available by or to an OEM for purposes of effecting the services of maintenance or repair of digital electronic equipment manufactured by or on behalf of, sold, or otherwise supplied by the OEM. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62C3776B3A3F4BBFAEC594B0B0F6EA62"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Parts pairing</header><text>The term <term>parts pairing</term> means, with respect to a part, the practice of employing software to identify component parts through the use of a unique identifier.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A94709D47164474957DA8D1D738BA41"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Tool</header><text>The term <term>tool</term> means any software program, hardware implement, or other apparatus used for diagnosis, maintenance, or repair of digital electronic equipment, including software or other mechanisms that provision, program, or pair a part, calibrate functionality, or perform any other function required to bring the equipment back to fully functional condition.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H28AE793D1CF149A780D7CE801B000A0E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to equipment sold or in use on or after the effective date of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

