<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H269281723C4746B09E9F888FC1866E12" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9567 IH: Preserving Our Constitution Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect individual liberties guaranteed under the constitution of the United States of America and laws made pursuant thereto.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD578630E996F4D25A9AB5A32B1F4F2F2" style="OLC">
<section id="HD8429A0488D74BC8AB8ECFD934A6DA52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Our Constitution Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H787575A1889A458A9833A9D6375765A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="H27165570E5264A609C19FC5AD32D0ED8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEBEF7FD1BA7444CEB12C49D2898893BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Constitution of the United States of America and the laws made pursuant thereto are the supreme law of the United States of America.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1D9EC74AB55434D94794BEE4EE4641A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The individual rights and liberties guaranteed and protected by the Constitution of the United States of America are the envy of the world.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19E31DA8F5E74176A69EA495806E00C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such liberties have encouraged individual genius to flourish in this Nation to the mutual benefit of all Americans and the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACB59DD4685A44419084C927921525A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The principle of individual liberty is not simply a slogan for outside consumption but a reality for all Americans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H454412D88B564AD3B63366881E2280C4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The role of elected officials of the United States is to secure and protect for its citizens as well as subsequent generations the liberties provided to us by our Founders.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DE785B0A6064E1BBE0E188B0ADB83C7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The existence of such liberties has been a beacon to draw immigrants from around the world yearning to live free.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81F67113434745FAB3CEB4489839F14B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>There are other legal and political systems in the world whose principles and laws diminish or destroy individual liberty and lead to individual subservience to governing authorities to the dread and misfortune of the people so governed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7D0AA3010784836BCD8A262EE12F710"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The people of the United States of America desire to preserve the blessings of liberty and the rule of law for themselves and their posterity and ensure that no foreign legal or political systems in conflict or incompatible with our laws, traditions, and individual liberties are applied in the United States courts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD23EA9385754DCCA4573AA94C84FF3F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>It is the Congress of the United States which possesses the authority to establish and regulate the jurisdiction of Federal courts and other adjudicative bodies.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H371F59C4E2CE4C039DE88A0756D5F0A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of Congress to protect and promote for ourselves and our posterity the individual rights and privileges granted by our Founders under the Constitution of the United States of America and the laws made pursuant thereto.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8490C8417F93467987DBDB08C29B126D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition of laws incompatible with the constitution of the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States, its territories, possessions, and any Federal adjudicative bodies, including courts, judges, magistrates, administrative bodies, and all other instrumentalities thererof, may not recognize or enforce any foreign law, religious law, custom, or practice that is in conflict or incompatible with the Constitution of the United States of America and the laws, rules, and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.</text></section> <section id="H9C06A495F2BC4C6B9527D49FD5BBA3D2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H50B2CDB6E9954A31B1DFAAC0CC899068"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>foreign law</term> includes any law, rule, or regulation of jurisdictions outside the United States of America and its territories and possessions and/or which does not recognize and protect the same or equivalent individual rights and liberties guaranteed under the Constitution of the United States of America.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA43E672E33CE4799988D032F87FADA79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>religious law, custom, or practice</term> means any law, rule, or regulation constituting, implementing, or enforcing a religious system, belief, code, or ethnic or tribal custom or practice.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC34EAD6041A4D8A84C643A91BA40868"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>laws, customs, and practices</term> includes those laws, customs, and practices, which permit, enforce, or implement any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HADA634F4E91A465C9D49AE180EC5FF81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Prejudicial treatment of women or persons of a particular race, religion, ethnicity, social class, or caste before the law.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1FA2BA664294708ABA7EDF924D34B0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Prohibition of the right to leave, change, or renounce one’s religion or belief.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3924BC6D0A0E42F09165C80819FF1D7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Prohibition of otherwise protected speech or assembly.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B1E61AEDEF94EB1A148B6C0A7FF5022"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Plural marriages.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4A4743E68C04DD59B96D6B8A6B7111D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Marriages of convenience or contracts for sexual services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7ACFADDFC10C4BCEAC7A55EFD6167176"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Forced or underage marriages.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE962EA923A54826A820C3AA9AE0767A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Violence against women and children, excluding reasonable parental discipline of children.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0ADE3F22CF54A6CB6545FC67685BD15">
          <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>Politically or religiously motivated physical violence or homicide.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA920715B47744A7C8CBDB1B9D1D75985"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>Cruel and unusual punishments as prohibited by the 8th Amendment to the United States Constitution, including, but not limited to, punishments such as amputation, lashing, flogging, stoning, branding, or piercing.</text>
                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A534804F9FC42178E617C8E284C00A9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Female genital mutilation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53A2EE0CCCF943F6A00170EB96B2EEE0"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Human sacrifice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H46414FAEAF3B4594984881EFA4FAC793"><enum>5.</enum><header>Ways in which incompatible laws may not be applied or enforced</header> 
<subsection id="HE1881BB41F2A409FAFDA6820A2D122F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contractual enforcement</header><text>The courts, judges, magistrates, administrative agencies, or other adjudicative entities of the United States may not enforce contractual provisions or agreements that provide for the choice of law described in section 2 to govern its interpretation, performance, or implementation, or to resolve any claim or dispute.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H695605E05612434E89E81C3825796744"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Choice of law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The courts, judges, magistrates, administrative agencies, or other adjudicative entities of the United States shall not enforce contractual provisions or agreements that provide for forums in which courts, judges, magistrates, or other adjudicative entities are governed by or apply laws described in section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD54FBB092F6447095138E3A69A10362"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The courts, judges, magistrates, administrative agencies, or other adjudicative entities of the United States shall not recognize or enforce any other motion, petition, or similar request for relief which violates section 2.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H02E98A7F0ADF47439C41275A06B7B5A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Foreign decisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The courts, judges, magistrates, administrative agencies, or other adjudicative entities of the United States shall not recognize or enforce a decision rendered by any foreign court, administrative agency, or other adjudicative entity if that decision was governed by or applied laws described in section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F3E2BDC2B9B4BAB985897197D53BF4C">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Venue</header>
 <text>A court shall not dismiss an action on grounds of forum non conveniens if the court determines that any alternative forum does not provide procedures and substantive protections sufficient to ensure that each litigant’s constitutional rights, including equal protection and due process, will not be denied.</text>
            </subsection></section> 
<section id="H7580257C9D4D4B2BBCBDF4043B58A2B5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that section 4 sets forth the strong public policy of the United States.</text></section> <section id="HA651D3C0C0E74926845719F030679AEC"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability clause</header> <subsection id="HF1F498D6BB0D4557A74F095B1CCD42F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If any provision of this Act is found to be unconstitutional, all other provisions shall remain in full force and effect.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8305D3CBB0114036B65A2BC0812BB44B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Arbitration</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to impair the enforcement of arbitration agreements or awards pursuant to the Federal Arbitration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/9/1">9 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, et seq.), except to the extent enforcement would violate rights guaranteed by the Constitution of the United States.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HBCFADA4A932E46C18B92EC74F8D78AE3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="HCE44B71460F847FBB00C7D77B96E383C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Failure to comply with this Act shall constitute reversible error on appeal.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H500B170E076448E5977157A03087339C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to create a cause of action for injunctive relief or compensatory damages.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

