<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF67C5EA9FB324985B06C12DE3B1DCD0B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1425 IH: Original Resolution Honoring Transportation Security Officers for their Sacrifice and Dedication to Public Service During Federal Government Shutdowns</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1425</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring Transportation Security Officers for their sacrifice and dedication to public service during Federal Government shutdowns.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Government experienced a partial shutdown from February 14, 2026, through April 30, 2026, constituting the longest partial Government shutdown in the Nation’s history;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Transportation Security Officers (TSOs) continued reporting to work without pay, placing them under significant financial strain, causing many to have to choose between, or forgo, basic necessities such as transportation, child care, and housing;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many TSOs and other Transportation Security Administration (TSA) personnel live paycheck to paycheck and were forced to miss shifts to work second jobs or leave the workforce entirely to support themselves and their families;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many TSOs had not yet fully recovered financially from a previous 43-day Federal Government shutdown, which concluded in November 2025;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas TSOs serve a vital role in safeguarding the Nation by keeping airports in the United States running smoothly and protecting travelers from potential threats entering and leaving the country;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas requiring Federal employees to work without compensation is unjust, immoral, and inconsistent with the principles of liberty, justice, and fairness for all;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas TSOs’ dedication, professionalism, and sacrifice are indispensable to the security of the Nation, and as such, deserve recognition by Congress and the American people; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas forcing TSA personnel to endure financial hardship during Federal Government shutdowns, despite having no role in budgetary negotiations, is shameful, immoral, unprincipled, and must end: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H3287C6B8970C4B79A0E6A347C7FF39D9">
        <section id="H0226650D6D2A47079956C3D90672754C" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Original Resolution Honoring Transportation Security Officers for their Sacrifice and Dedication to Public Service During Federal Government Shutdowns</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HA7F4C2C3D2C74036BEAEB6ECA12C2C0C">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Sense of the House of Representatives</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H028D83EDAAD8450793389FFEEEDD3E15"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stands in solidarity with Transportation Security Officers (TSOs) and all Transportation Security Administration (TSA) personnel;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HF973FA3B3B7A491A8C3F1378E8F0C9CB">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>thanks TSOs for their sacrifice and dedication to public service during Federal Government shutdowns;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H82FFF21E29B841CDA91F14BD2E721A95">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>recognizes and affirms the critical importance of their work in protecting the American people; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H16A5E8E442C1456C8BD0DB7727D1095D">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>remains committed to ending the unjust withholding of TSA employee compensation during Federal Government shutdowns.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body></resolution>

