<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0E94C91AB6F40DFA20299401DF13DE5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9654 IH: National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 Technical Corrections Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9654</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government
            Improvement Act of 1997 to treat domestic partnerships as marriage for purposes of the
            program of benefits paid by the Federal Government for survivors of a District of
            Columbia police officer, firefighter, or teacher in the same manner and to the same
            extent that domestic partnerships are treated as marriage for purposes of such benefits
            which are paid by the District of Columbia, to conform the age limit after which a
            surviving spouse of a police officer, firefighter, or teacher may remarry without losing
            survivor benefits under such program to the age limit established with respect to
            survivor benefits of Federal employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H14D8A5D6810D4BB7B6C6B2A42A4DA763" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H773482B93588416197E8A6E2B59EF4D7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 Technical Corrections Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HAEFCCFE14F5C40478C67BFEB2069F266" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of program of benefits paid by Federal Government for survivors of District of Columbia police officers, firefighters, and teachers</header> 
<subsection id="HDAE0643A63E8425A952464A1DB5B044B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage of surviving domestic partners under same terms and conditions for benefits paid under District of Columbia Retirement Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11012 of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 (sec. 1–803.02, D.C. Official Code) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H90FE863A7F2D4D73B365420E9022C98F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HF909BC55728A43F085BA2BC60BF1EB19"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Coverage of domestic partners</header> <paragraph id="HA64619D9EC6A433ABDF5A1C7F3AFD727"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the determination of the entitlement of an individual to a benefit payment under a District Retirement Program shall be made as if the amendments made by section 32 of the Omnibus Domestic Partnership Equality Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Law 17–231) and the amendments made by section 2 of the Teachers, Police, and Firefighters Retirement Benefits Amendment Act of 2018 (D.C. Law 22–215) had taken effect prior to the freeze date.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C222192EBD14E1EB3D1EC688E17B05F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion of unrelated provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) does not apply to the amendments made by subsections (b) and (e) of section 2 of the Teachers, Police, and Firefighters Retirement Benefits Amendment Act of 2018.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9E33FEE1CE8C46B4BAC4C41D2689E9F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of same age limit for termination of benefits by reason of remarriage under Federal employee retirement programs</header> <paragraph id="H37EB768B20EB44C5B6C2A2074B02DE43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals covered by District Retirement Program</header><text>Section 11012 of such Act (sec. 1–803.02, D.C. Official Code), as amended by subsection (a), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8C0A6EBC837D4DD79FC3C9EBA8AD49A8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HA508B3DFCEA8404D889E8A8F85EA1A9C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application of age limit under Federal employee retirement programs for termination of survivor benefit by reason of remarriage</header> 
<paragraph id="H6A16BFD984234F53B1E88C8088F08762"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation on termination of benefit on grounds of remarriage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), for purposes of subsection (a), the entitlement of an individual to a benefit payment under a District Retirement Program shall be determined as if, prior to the freeze date, the entitlement to the benefit payment under the Program did not terminate by reason of the remarriage of the individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6422769E4CB64CB48569AE7B55A12B0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for survivors remarried before becoming 55 years of age</header><text>Paragraph (1) does not apply if the individual remarried before becoming 55 years of age, unless the individual was married for at least 30 years to the individual on whose service the benefit payment is based.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H547D551866D54042A31E2B27301F47EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for survivors of judges</header><text>Section 11–1568(c), District of Columbia Official Code, is amended in the matter following paragraph (3) by striking <quote>fifty-five years of age</quote> and inserting <quote>fifty-five years of age, unless the widow or widower was married to the judge for at least 30 years</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD87A496A360A44648F3F98A96D84F833"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 11003(6) of such Act (sec. 1–801.02(6), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>section 11012(e) and (f)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 11012(e), (f), (g), and (h)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H04425CBE2D8F47429AD93DD02CF3E490" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annuity deposit for certain service under District of Columbia retirement system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1905(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8332">5 U.S.C. 8332</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB75A6E38FE53408EA7BD3F88D044AFDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>Qualifying</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (4), qualifying</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H867D49AF4E564E0BB36BB9EA7A3070DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H382C9111E5E2444BB5F58A1FFD5A0FB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H824F5E3ED03B47CEBBC1BA19A00E5AA8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Service deposit</header> <subparagraph id="H566F787E33834F4E98197DADD2A08580"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (3), the qualifying District of Columbia service of any individual who makes a deposit under this paragraph shall be taken into account for purposes of computing the amount of any benefit payable out of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund under section 8348 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE767FF7D95748E494433981081B07EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any individual—</text> <clause id="H29890BFF29D84AD498087EBFF5D19F6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who, pursuant to this section, has qualifying District of Columbia service included in calculating the individual’s creditable service under section 8332, of title 5, United States Code, may deposit an amount equal to the product of the basic pay received for that qualifying service multiplied by the applicable percentage, or percentages, in section 8334(c) of such title, plus interest (computed in accordance with section 8334(e) of such title); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H24C321FCF72C4BFABC3526D91C63DDAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who, pursuant to this section, has qualifying District of Columbia service included in calculating the individual’s creditable service under section 8411 of such title may deposit an amount equal to 1.3 percent of basic pay received for that qualifying service, plus interest (computed in accordance with section 8334(e) of such title).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6630FC0252BE4FB6B4ECCE8343E81B19"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of survivor annuities, deposits authorized by this paragraph may be made by a survivor of an individual described in subparagraph (B)(i) or (B)(ii).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53C121BDBB3B43CEA5F0F98D67568B1E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any deposit made under this paragraph shall be credited to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34FD0DD918F1480CB045FEE842D4A6EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Personnel Management shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this paragraph. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

