<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM25L70-FH2-0F-8TF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 539 ATS: Recognizing the 80th anniversary of the commencement of continuous operations of Stars and Stripes in the Pacific and the invaluable service of the Stars and Stripes as the “hometown newspaper” for members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees, and family members stationed around the world.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 539</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 80th anniversary of the commencement of continuous operations of <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> in the Pacific and the invaluable service of the <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> as the <quote>hometown newspaper</quote> for members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees, and family members stationed around the world.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas May 14, 2025, marked the 80th anniversary of the commencement of continuous operations, in service to the military community of the United States, of <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> in the Pacific, a military newspaper established in Honolulu to provide an independent, uncensored news source for members of the Armed Forces fighting in World War II;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> was heralded for indispensable service when it was initially established during the Civil War and again during World War I, when General John J. Pershing reestablished <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> to provide news and information as an important morale-building force for soldiers serving in the American Expeditionary Forces;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas after its permanent formation during World War II, <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> excelled in its mission across every theater of war, leading President Harry S. Truman to state, <quote>In Africa, Europe, and the Pacific, <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> has established itself as a cherished and important soldier's institution.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> commenced printing in Tokyo on October 3, 1945, working in requisitioned space formally occupied by the <italic>Japan Times</italic>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> has continuously covered news, not only for military service members and Department of Defense civilian employees, but to United States veterans, families of veterans, current service members, and contractor personnel, particularly those serving overseas, in conflicts since World War II, including conflicts taking place in Korea, Vietnam, Bosnia, Kosovo, Iraq, and Afghanistan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas while readership of print newspapers has declined in recent years as technology has evolved, <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> has innovated in finding new ways and products to deliver the <quote>hometown news</quote> to the broadest portion of military community; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas through internet versions of the newspaper, social media, and other media products, <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> is now reaching 1,400,000 readers every day: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate, on the occasion of the 80th anniversary of the commencement of continuous operations of <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic> in the Pacific—</text><paragraph id="idc95580b8de2c44e69e78140b5d7f2994"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates this important milestone in the history of an important institution of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2252217cdeb64232a0919a1ea2c4938f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates and honors the men and women of <italic>Stars and Stripes</italic>, past and present, who have so diligently served the United States military community.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

