<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD9D5BE1201384F338CE6020CF9F57D8C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7617 IH: To provide funding for administrative expenses of the Department of Homeland Security during any lapse in appropriations during fiscal year 2026, to require that the Department be responsive to congressional offices during such a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7617</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide funding for administrative expenses of the Department of Homeland Security during any lapse in appropriations during fiscal year 2026, to require that the Department be responsive to congressional offices during such a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9520A9DE4A1A4EF6AD47641AB62A4688" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDB73D51099224EF482DC1D9C928C75FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Continued operations of the Department of Homeland Security</header> 
<subsection id="H049403E4F6064E1BB595623B0CE93448"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>In the case of a lapse in appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security there are appropriated such amounts as may be necessary for administrative expenses necessary for the operation of the Department for the duration of the lapse in appropriations, including the Department’s Office of Legislative Affairs and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement’s Office of Congressional Relations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC9EE8F1A6BD84401993D49412F228D92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continued operation</header><text>With respect to any lapse in appropriations occurring during fiscal year 2026, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, using amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a), ensure that the Department performs all functions that the Department would perform in the absence of such a lapse, including responding to communications transmitted to the Department during such lapse by congressional offices.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

