<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H93AB1962AC994E16B2CD73C1DE638056" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8615 IH: Facilitating Leadership and Expertise through Exchange and Training in Shipbuilding Now Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8615</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To combat China’s unfair and non-market-oriented trade practices related to the shipbuilding industry, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H5CE77A7FFC4C40BB8E74B50A691D050C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDBBBADA2BAD34F1096001B23D3641407" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HA5E519D12CEA46649781209F5F582B89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Facilitating Leadership and Expertise through Exchange and Training in Shipbuilding Now Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FLEETS Now Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9856F3D27BB44D47BCC4B5D2F2E35714"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HDBBBADA2BAD34F1096001B23D3641407" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H456B7C3117E34502AF782A3C6F35F1AB" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5060084DA8684DAAA92C9825B7D89076" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5D1AD32523424668AA73BF9AF29F78F3" level="title">Title I—Matters relating to shipbuilding and the People’s Republic of China</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD97C368BF6BE48A3958F9D1CE42F3907" level="section">Sec. 101. Strategic ports; United States International Development Finance Corporation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE897886F0401485B8BDD42D3E75B3BEA" level="section">Sec. 102. Briefing and report on China Ocean Shipping Company Shipping Heavy Industry and China State Shipbuilding Corporation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD033BAFC6CD743F7A38DF860BCC64DB4" level="title">Title II—Matters relating to shipbuilding and the United States, its allies and partners, and the international community</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9A68406D3160430084A95AD3C26027E8" level="section">Sec. 201. Statement of policy to counter shipbuilding practices of the People’s Republic of China.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB547337E82FF49FB97C7E6C2338FF6C2" level="section">Sec. 202. International shipbuilding coordination responsibility.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H293F060008B040068F5532F590D196A8" level="section">Sec. 203. Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0BEA90044E6B468281003673F244897A" level="section">Sec. 204. Exchange program for shipbuilding industry experts.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF0D99994D8904CA4ABFCF0473DA5CE71" level="section">Sec. 205. Maritime investigators.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC78F23926A874FCBAD1E23855ABA7CAF" level="section">Sec. 206. Allied maritime framework.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H750F75045A1F4759BC17CF41E531D0EA" level="section">Sec. 207. Maritime group of nations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9425E528E6864D66B5DFA89B48222D2C" level="section">Sec. 208. International Maritime Organization.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H456B7C3117E34502AF782A3C6F35F1AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H0104EA6E3AA744A791338BA3CA4D1B58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People’s Republic of China (hereafter in this section referred to as the <quote>PRC</quote>) has deployed unfair and non-market-oriented practices in the maritime, logistics, and shipbuilding sectors to achieve a long-term dominant position in the shipbuilding ecosystem. In response, the United States Trade Representative launched an investigation under title III of the Trade Act of 1974 in April 2024, and reaffirmed its allegations in a notice of proposed actions in February 2025.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0215B6720F96414C95D77571FCFA6249"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The PRC’s Military-Civil Fusion strategy uses the opacity of China’s business ecosystem to channel commercial activities—including foreign shipbuilding orders—into upgrading its naval industrial base. By integrating commercial and military production at shared shipyards, the PRC enables the transfer of capital, technology, personnel, and supply chains to China’s defense industrial base, strengthening military capabilities through civilian contracts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1DA7D21AD254F73BC8F37A4E1C45544"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The PRC frames its shipbuilding and maritime sectors as strategic industries that must be targeted to build economic, technological and military power. This targeting necessarily means the displacement of foreign firms from existing markets, and taking new markets as they present, which diminishes competition. The United States has not taken sufficient action to counter the PRC and protect United States enterprises.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EF7027C463142E18D8BF70E3C6B47C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>By achieving dominant market positions, the PRC exercises increasing influence over global supply, pricing, and access to goods and services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF703C9F7FBE491BB38F1632F9B47B0E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The PRC’s targeting of the maritime, logistics, and shipbuilding sectors creates dependencies on China, increasing risk and reducing supply chain resilience. The PRC seeks to displace foreign competitors throughout the maritime value chain in domestic and foreign markets, increasing the world’s dependence on the PRC for products, services, and technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4C43D39274D4049875A3F9989F42705"><enum>(6)</enum><text>International dependencies on the PRC increases risks (potential disruptions, whether natural, accidental, or politically motivated) for individual firms and their workers, for economic sectors, and supply chain resilience. The PRC has demonstrated its willingness to weaponize dependencies for the purpose of economic coercion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1587D957DB3C400B96D4C01320969FB6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The PRC’s control over Chinese economic actors in the maritime, logistics, and shipbuilding sectors enables China to direct and influence commercial behavior in pursuit of market dominance in ways that run counter to fair competition and market-oriented principles.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE95D400BA57342C18D6C77BC8BF49635"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The PRC’s industrial plans identify a matrix of mechanisms that are used to achieve market dominance, including government financial support, barriers for foreign firms, consolidation policies, measures associated with forced technology transfer and intellectual property theft, state-led investments, and government procurement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA64DABCAED144706A096C1F51901AE9A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>As a result of the PRC’s market distortion, Chinese maritime, logistics, and shipbuilding sectors accrue a wide range of non-market advantages, such as artificially low costs or preferential supply from China’s non-market excess capacity, including in steel, China’s lack of effective labor rights, and China’s control over digital logistics services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F71CEEABA0C45D9B3FECEA119A421BF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The PRC’s direct intervention in the shipbuilding market makes ships built in the United States and elsewhere commercially less competitive. Less than one percent of new commercial ships are built in the United States and domestic shipbuilding is almost exclusively for military use.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68B889D2A3004DDDBBBF2328F71A6A0A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 2024, the PRC accounted for 53.3 percent of the global shipbuilding industry and the China State Shipbuilding Corporation built more commercial ships by tonnage in 2024 than the entire United States shipbuilding industry has built since the end of World War II.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7A71A7A00C34DE9865901B82279C7DD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The state-owned shipbuilding conglomerates like China Ocean Shipping Company Shipping Heavy Industry and China State Shipbuilding Corporation are China’s largest commercial shipbuilding corporations and the primary entities responsible for the buildup of the People’s Liberation Army Navy into the world’s largest navy enabling the PRC to increase its capacity to undermine United States national security interests.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DD755EC34A64776B5334F040758FE70"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The shipbuilding capacity of the United States has been weakened by decades of neglect, leading to a contraction of a once vibrant domestic maritime workforce while simultaneously empowering our adversaries, eroding United States national security, and reducing American jobs in the maritime sector.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB20B26B7482447DF81A6E99F7789858F"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Increasing domestic shipbuilding capacity is essential to restoring America’s maritime strength and self-sufficiency. This will require coordinated action across procurement policy, capital investment, supplier resilience, and workforce development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC320DC20DDCC47A590B3748DF28024BE"><enum>(15)</enum><text>According to America’s Maritime Action Plan from February 2026, the United States does not have the capacity necessary to scale up the domestic shipbuilding industry to the rate required to meet national priorities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBEDD4418553441EB510FE4E67BF36F8"><enum>(16)</enum><text>For decades, the United States strategic position and shipbuilding industrial capacity have been weakened, in part, by cumbersome Government procurement processes, a lack of strategic support for construction of commercial vessels in domestic shipyards, and the degradation of Federal financial investment in the Maritime Industrial Base.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8C820C3962145C3BC52630DF8DDAFD6"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Strengthening the United States maritime sector requires leveraging international and industry partnerships to align trade policies to enhance investment in the United States maritime sector. By creating clear pathways for foreign direct investments in United States shipyards, suppliers, and maritime infrastructure, the United States can expand domestic capacity while reinforcing relationships abroad.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37698DA2C8214C8594C1F2BFB73C70CF"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Currently, foreign firms are severely disadvantaged in competing with the resources of the Chinese state, resulting in lost sales, under-investment in capacity, diminished ability to attract financing, and lost jobs and lower wages.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31CD6F9568A848298DDFA9BE8D3DDB39"> <enum>(19)</enum> <text>Foreign companies, including firms based in many United States-allied countries purchase 75 percent of the ships built at China’s dual-use shipyards, funneling billions of dollars in revenue and transferring key technologies into the People’s Liberation Army naval industrial base.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF576139AA014E74BAD8AAD66341C80C"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The United States does not have a single agency or department charged with designing and implementing industrial shipbuilding policy. As a result, there is no single official charged with protecting and expanding the domestic shipbuilding industry in the United States. This creates inefficiency in reinvigorating the United States shipbuilding industry and confusion when engaging international partners about joint strategies for diversifying shipbuilding supply chains.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE0264D6E53B451489164FC68ACF5CA8"><enum>(21)</enum><text>The President’s Maritime Action Plan outlines a strategy for reclaiming America’s maritime strength, ensuring the Nation can defend its interests and ferry its trade. In implementing the Maritime Action Plan, the United States will modernize its procurement processes and streamline regulations to accelerate shipbuilding and reduce costs.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5060084DA8684DAAA92C9825B7D89076"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD3DDF4BA7B59486FA9EE163A4A96424E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allied country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>allied country</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2350f(d) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E22CF1697DE4E85924A8BDC8104C330"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H56D22566BC2E4703B75BFD499DB7BEAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H202F8D6A8DAE41C1ADE6A06AA41AEAE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5D0A9B8013D4301B18C734C4B9F4C29"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deck-plate professional</header><text>The term <term>deck-plate professional</term> means a skilled worker who operates directly on the production floor as a skilled tradesperson with specialized expertise related to a ship’s systems and functionality.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1082D69A096B4287B018AF8B1FDFD694"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign country of concern</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30B517426A09459293F2C1846513D31C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unreasonable refusal to deal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unreasonable refusal to deal</term> has the meaning given that term for purposes of section 7(d) of the Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/46/41104">46 U.S.C. 41104</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></section> 
<title id="H5D1AD32523424668AA73BF9AF29F78F3"><enum>I</enum><header>Matters relating to shipbuilding and the People’s Republic of China</header> 
<section id="HD97C368BF6BE48A3958F9D1CE42F3907"><enum>101.</enum><header>Strategic ports; United States International Development Finance Corporation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HAFE94ED3EE3148E89D9EAEC2000BF25C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1402(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9601">22 U.S.C. 9601(3)</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H16A6D9E22F2347E5B3D515B7E6DE7A71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC74C8FF3D41E45C09E68D467B0AED7C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (G) as subparagraphs (A) through (F), respectively; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H751A9FC963174767848CBB706F7FDB72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1412(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9612">22 U.S.C. 9612(f)</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H86760958B9F44ECB8ABF1E2E4B0835CF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD8455CF7FCEF4AE0B4891FA572931A72"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>Harbors or ports (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>)) and related infrastructure.</text> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE897886F0401485B8BDD42D3E75B3BEA" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>102.</enum><header>Briefing and report on China Ocean Shipping Company Shipping Heavy Industry and China State Shipbuilding Corporation</header> 
<subsection id="HC1ADF7D2E7BD42679B5A98E569C53196"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other Federal agencies and departments the Secretary determines relevant, shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on—</text> <paragraph id="HC2B214F6DB874080BA7F852F4DEC6049"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">companies or entities with formal or informal financial relationships with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H298F6E7A5534447FA5EF1713C713F369"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the China Ocean Shipping Company Shipping Heavy Industry; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26501CF856AD46C49D038738780D31D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the China State Shipbuilding Corporation; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A4BFC932C0C4FEB83B4EB3FCB169C1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the business practices of such companies and entities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4E2714647882411E86CD94BD1EDAB6D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H269738F5E23E49E38E9066524269B26A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of each current and former subsidiary of the China Ocean Shipping Company Shipping Heavy Industry and the China State Shipbuilding Corporation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1381D54DE774653A2D55A286E9F2A10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any trading practices of any such entities that are subject to review by the United States Trade Representative for being unreasonable, discriminatory, or violating trade agreements.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44CC9851361F49D8A7675106BE38D015"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The degree and extent of direct involvement by the Government of the People’s Republic of China in the governance, strategic direction, planning, and commercial operations of—</text> <subparagraph id="H43D8EDE4110F447992E785A124C459D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the China Ocean Shipping Company Shipping Heavy Industry;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABE1A28404A04224BDC1CE5988CEB788"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the China State Shipbuilding Corporation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1204B04C25B8450B89EBE68D20AE1729"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the Chinese shipbuilding industry.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD94A4E609D984600962248F38E438670"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of each shipyard in China that is producing warships for the People’s Liberation Army Navy or producing dual-use commercial ships, including ferries and barges, that may be used by the People’s Liberation Army Navy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24F280B9D9524A2788463B9ED07AF079"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An indication of which such shipyards are conducting business with non-People’s Republic of China foreign entities and potentially thereby facilitating the modernization of the People’s Liberation Army Navy.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title> 
<title id="HD033BAFC6CD743F7A38DF860BCC64DB4"><enum>II</enum><header>Matters relating to shipbuilding and the United States, its allies and partners, and the international community</header> 
<section id="H9A68406D3160430084A95AD3C26027E8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>201.</enum><header>Statement of policy to counter shipbuilding practices of the People’s Republic of China</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to develop a domestic capacity to produce ships for both commercial and military application independent of supply chains that include materials sourced from the People’s Republic of China. Such policy shall be given effect, among other things, through a comprehensive effort, in coordination with allies and partners of the United States where appropriate, that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H19C103F8C60D491E9BC03F3653AA3163"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relevant knowledge transfer to and skillset development of a shipbuilding labor force in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75660CE27F56409FBBFDC40D702FD867"><enum>(2)</enum><text>securing direct investment in United States shipyards by allies and partners; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE4F03DD5F9B44E1BFF076EB7CB2A9FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development of a coherent long-term strategy to diversify shipbuilding supply chains and expand domestic shipbuilding capacity, incorporating all relevant Federal agencies and departments.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB547337E82FF49FB97C7E6C2338FF6C2" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>202.</enum><header>International shipbuilding coordination responsibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall designate an individual as the primary point of contact in the United States Government for purposes of—</text> <paragraph id="H150B1B9FBA4842D7BCB0EE2BAECC8CE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>attracting international shipbuilding investment opportunities in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8AA89433EF374477AC8AF46CF461349F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leading cooperation with the governments of foreign countries on international shipbuilding supply chain diversification; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB889EC65654D4D0089EC948CAB8931C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leading engagement on behalf of the United States Government for coordination of international shipbuilding industries in a manner that creates supply chain resilience and protects the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H293F060008B040068F5532F590D196A8"><enum>203.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Department of State Appropriations Authorization Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2655a">22 U.S.C. 2655a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4550D1F9D9A0423880BBDC8BB9CDDDC8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H42A585E28A284AB5A3BA7C5A96FAF4A4"><enum>9.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs</header> <subsection id="H3D3F5BD682634F66BCD8F6950CD56A1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be in the Department of State an Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs, who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs for matters pertaining to space, oceans and maritime diplomacy, polar affairs, environmental quality, freshwater, fisheries, wildlife and wildlife trafficking, conservation, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF27FE659A96B49B8BDD46F51D372F26B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs shall maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters pertaining to oceans and maritime diplomacy, fisheries, natural resource conservation, and outer space in the conduct of foreign policy, including, as appropriate, the following:</text> <paragraph id="H42F2A61E2D0C4A14BD00D8C907323F1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing United States policy on global environmental security issues with respect to oceans, fisheries, the Antarctic region, waste and global pollution, and water and other natural resource management and conservation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F31D01BD9954C15BABD7EA5F0D57959"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Representing the Department in bilateral and multilateral negotiations involving the law of the sea, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H60EF0867B45649A0923549751389F5E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>freedom of navigation, overflight, and other lawful uses of the ocean;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C7C19FD9EA148BE971C6BCA73017EFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maritime security;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD077A8E968745C383B86DE63B26550A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>United States maritime zones, including the United States extended continental shelf;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3D45377782F46F49EE46ECCED8AB347"><enum>(D)</enum><text>marine science;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68A353E79E484F94A2D5819FB62E670D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the sustainable management and protection of marine habitats and resources;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB9C23671205D488DAB8B6842BF1588A4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>marine pollution; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47C4832445E84B02A422CF78058DBCEC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>maritime claims and boundaries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C17AE41214945F88843FB7C57A5AFB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Leading United States engagement on Antarctica and in international oceans agreements and conventions with foreign governments and international organizations, to promote solutions that advance United States national security, economic, and environmental interests.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF8B280C8B7F47BA82B9A89063B4E4CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordinating the development of policies and programs to conserve and manage economically important ecosystems, including, forests, wetlands, drylands, and coral reefs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H343296FDA61340D58C9B919E3B674E1D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Developing policies and programs to address international threats to natural resources, such as illicit trade, illegal, unreported and unregulated fishing, wildlife trafficking, and illegal logging and associated trade.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB6E45A1F5A84494818E85B178ADF0B1"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>Developing and implementing United States foreign policy related to air, water and soil pollution and risks to human health and the environment caused by the transboundary movement of hazardous chemicals and waste and other forms of pollution to promote environmental security, with trade partners and in multilateral institutions.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC3C27A1CE7B4279AD37EA30D38AB29C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Representing the Department in bilateral and multilateral engagements including organizations, institutions, and negotiation of international agreements on related issues.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1133E2E5359B4782A95034F952482160"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Developing policies and programs, in coordination with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Department of Commerce, and other relevant Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, to support partnerships between the United States and international and private industry partners in the development of infrastructure and policies that expand economic growth in outer space, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1C20CCFEFF104FE7A2F18E8FDBC78D25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>countering malign efforts by foreign adversaries and other actors that threaten United States interests in civil and commercial space; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA623EE2693C6423E8417A1FB431E3F96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expanding access to foreign markets for United States commercial industry, including by encouraging reforms that reduce barriers to trade and cooperation with United States civil and commercial space actors.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2514133A58E249C18A96ECB77F68D8AD"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Leading bilateral and multilateral engagements related to civil and commercial space activities, resilient space services, burden sharing, and other matters related to international space law and diplomacy and other United States international obligations and commitments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB30115CDEEBB4B72A77D6054B4D43F7D"> <enum>(10)</enum> <text>Leading United States Government engagement with international Global Navigation Satellite Systems providers to ensure compatibility and encourage interoperability of civil global navigation satellite services on United States-based global positioning systems, including through the International Committee on Global Navigation Satellite Systems.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C566D5AEA644B85B8447A3862DDC165"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Leading Department efforts to implement international arrangements and promote cooperation on Earth observation satellite systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0468D8EE899B4C73861CBABB6642DA4A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Leading Department engagement in multilateral and bilateral forums on international space policy, space law, and commercial and civil treaties or agreements.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BD41D567E2A425D8A3B1A897213879B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Leading Department efforts on transparency in space by maintaining the official United States space object registry and promoting best practices for safe operations in space, preservation of the space environment, space traffic coordination, and space situational awareness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38B653C66F684593AEC3D18C65BD5CD1"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Leading Department efforts to align foreign space law, regulatory, and policy frameworks with United States-endorsed models, approaches, and best practices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5603AEDF0A046C5B605417AD9A123E9"><enum>(15)</enum><text>At the direction of the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs and the Secretary of State, represent the United States in international maritime diplomacy matters, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H060641ED165A4985872CFB08F81AF0F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the creation and operation of the Allied Maritime Framework under <internal-xref idref="HC78F23926A874FCBAD1E23855ABA7CAF" legis-path="206.">section 206 of the FLEETS Now Act</internal-xref>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H69B96FF6AE1348DFB35AAC3678156A93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the development of the report under section 103; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B20ED05AE3B4890BA58F9965E2F73BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>leading United States engagement in the Maritime Group of Nations under <internal-xref idref="H750F75045A1F4759BC17CF41E531D0EA" legis-path="207.">section 207</internal-xref> of the FLEETS Now Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H835B6841FF7F493A902A875CBC4613AC"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authoring any reports produced by the Department which examine the maritime claims and boundaries of coastal countries and assessing their consistency with international law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4B1AD19E777415D8A8A19C37B5001EE"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Performing such other duties as the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C6920767D6C49A4828D836A54AAC62C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appointment</header> 
<paragraph id="HC82D3F46E5C44D25876BA988CC39A95E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date of the enactment of the FLEETS Now Act, the individual serving as the Assistant Secretary for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs on the day before such date of enactment shall be the Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA4DCF64623543FB89EEE046B914B127"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent appointment</header><text>Any subsequent appointment of an individual to the position of Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs shall be subject to the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H25BA78691BB14B80B3A9B94B36CE0BEF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Establishment of Bureau of Water, Environment, and Space Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a Bureau of Water, Environment, and Space Affairs, which shall perform such functions related to space, oceans, environmental quality, fisheries, wildlife, wildlife trafficking, and conservation affairs as the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs may prescribe.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H93AFC20FFD50486C8C32AEDADC1C4361"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Water, Environment, and Space Affairs shall be the head of the Bureau of Water, Environment, and Space Affairs.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
<section id="H0BEA90044E6B468281003673F244897A"> <enum>204.</enum> <header>Exchange program for shipbuilding industry experts</header> 
<subsection id="H7423CDD577FE46929A6ECC5A0A7D8BB9"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Sense of Congress</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that the Secretary of State should initiate an exchange visitor program of technical shipbuilding expertise to increase shipbuilding knowledge, training, experience, and expertise in the American shipbuilding workforce.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HF3C2122587544FE987E0EBCBFE2AF80A"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Authorization To provide for exchanges</header> <text>Section 102(b) of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2452">22 U.S.C. 2452(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H88A4FE4907704D6782BCECFD021BC39D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in paragraph (11), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF46DCF81841441719264FC3B188CBB8D"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in paragraph (12), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3292916345F4A74849869EF33F54FDF"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>by inserting at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H4F333971332E4CBA9E1C2648FFEDFFB7" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H8B4585351715449D829011E9CB97AE06" indent="down1"> <enum>(13)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interchanges and visits between the United States and other countries of marine engineers, naval architects, electrical engineers, deck-plate professionals, marine surveyors, shipyard infrastructure analysts, quality assurance and quality control personnel, shipyard project managers, and other experts related to the shipbuilding industry until the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="HF0D99994D8904CA4ABFCF0473DA5CE71"><enum>205.</enum><header>Maritime investigators</header> 
<subsection id="H26C70112A5FE486E97999C9B1576B3AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Chair of the Federal Maritime Commission, detail to countries described in subsection (b) personnel from the Division for Trade Policy and Negotiations of the Bureau of Economic and Business Affairs for the purpose of investigating—</text> <paragraph id="H23B8886DBC34493986ECD5D6A87935B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unfair shipping practices, including price-fixing, market manipulation, or unreasonable refusal to deal;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E5100D65A534FF496D965124B8BF4FC"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>specific actions by foreign governments to deny port of entry to United States-flagged vessels;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H60F7CDB2A28C48FBADA1F2BBCAFF21B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>flags of convenience to determine if lower safety, labor, and environmental standards in foreign countries create unfavorable shipping conditions for United States trade;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6901D70AA38D4D5AAD0DFC902AC3818B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>anticompetitive agreements between ocean carriers and marine terminal operators for potential antitrust issues; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13A0F9A9F4C74F47A4CEAC4D3826F151"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mapping the financial relationships of shipping companies of the People’s Republic of China, including the Ocean Alliance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB61E46D6BB3D4EB5B9C8E19BC5428BC7"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Locations of investigators</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The personnel described in subsection (a) shall be detailed to diplomatic and consular posts in countries that meet each of the following criteria:</text> <paragraph id="HBC02D1F629274F9A8B3D1F7E35F8C7FF" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The country is among the top 5 countries globally by ship registry size and maintains an <quote>open registry</quote>, allowing foreign-owned vessels to register under the flag of such country without a residency requirement (also known as a <quote>flag of convenience</quote> policy).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1ED05180288944ADB97D32A6D79195C6" commented="no"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The country is among the top 15 countries globally with respect to not less than 2 of the following criteria:</text> <subparagraph id="HFA2678E3197347F3AE9B02EBA6985670" commented="no"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>Shipbuilding, as measured by tonnage as a percentage of global total.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF10EDB8AA18340EBAFC18ED37D682D04" commented="no"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Number of citizens or nationals who are merchant mariners.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD40F22EF3EC4494E8717B5BBF6173E37" commented="no"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>Number of commercially owned ships greater than 1,000 gross weight tonnage.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H02F34EE6CBAE4FECB3DCAF743F394F2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of findings in investment climate statement</header><text>Section 707(b) of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9903">22 U.S.C. 9903</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (11) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H2CF937835E8E459CAFFB12E40F1DBA65" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H5AF6B4AFF29C457F9F19B90E73E882D8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Information about unfair business practices in the maritime, logistics, and shipbuilding sectors in each applicable country or region, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBF443F76A72E433BA8E87303E83C9562"><enum>(A)</enum><text>price-fixing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09E2E912DFC34B79A49C88E8A45EBA7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>market manipulation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8612211969684FBB84EBDCC3E5F6349D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unreasonable refusal to deal (as such term is defined for purposes of section 7(d) of the Ocean Shipping Reform Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/46/41104">46 U.S.C. 41104</external-xref> note)); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FBF11A6AE8949878CD8A0610757B1BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>anticompetitive agreements between ocean carriers and marine terminal operators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2297451FBB4F4529ADBE855718B6D4DA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disclosure of certain investments by countries receiving aid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7031(b)(2) of division K of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/76">Public Law 113–76</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 510) is amended by inserting <quote>and investments in maritime, logistics, and shipbuilding sectors</quote> after <quote>allocation practices)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC78F23926A874FCBAD1E23855ABA7CAF"><enum>206.</enum><header>Allied maritime framework</header> <subsection id="H53A0E6B87C8A4E229C66FB4EE039E866"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, acting through the individual designated pursuant to section 202 and in coordination with other relevant agencies and departments, shall engage allied countries to develop a shared framework to enhance collective capacity to design, produce, and maintain military and civilian ships, through—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5331F46396E84DD09D2CDDAD0CD4139C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhancing information exchange between such countries regarding such design, production, and maintenance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE770EBC5FAD34EDFA14334D38631C26E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expanding procompetitive industrial collaboration with respect to such ships; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H102187E3394F49D6A8379E8679BE40E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strengthening the marine industries and the shipbuilding industries in allied countries.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H72ACF9F1CDC64CB69B3394D6C4836283"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The framework required in subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H873128905E1F49D38819277FCDB97D23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the establishment of a mechanism to—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7CF71261F2F43CF9B251F88D2969A7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure countries participating in the framework can access reciprocal ports and shipping support during crises and conflicts;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6347805F704C4CFB8AACE6FDF1F1CBCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>co-develop best-in-class design principles for the construction of ships;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD044C02E63464327A7AE886923CC2949"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collaborate, on a reciprocal basis, on the construction, repair, interoperability, and other capabilities of new ships to reduce costs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HADCB6AE7F08E4C9CB0D4184A4D95DB26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish guiding principles for production line sequencing and supply chain management;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H794389C6F7914ABA9F85657F68462501"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinate Cabinet or Minister-level recommendations to drive down the production costs of ships and accelerate the delivery of ships, consistent with relevant laws in the relevant countries;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D5A715DA6D3409493A6102A065EE42A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>establish a process for determining specific ship types or industry niches that are best suited for allied cooperation, including icebreakers, support ships, oilers, tankers, liquified natural gas carriers, undersea vessels, research vessels, and dual-fuel ships; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39F1B75321C94FDBB4E75E3B2842F76C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>develop a mechanism to incentivize financial investments from foreign sources and remove barriers to foreign direct investment in shipbuilding;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BDBD4213C1C47EA8928A061EFD942D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the establishment of a joint workforce-development program between participating shipyards and partner networks engaged in the production of ships for the purpose of training, information sharing, and the exchange of technical advisors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB13806403294DCFACE65137A71857EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the establishment of a mechanism to develop and share research and development and leverage innovation to promote sustainability and mutual benefit;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66FC0641852F4B37B1A91D90CE8DFFAB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an agreement among countries participating in the framework to procure ships and ship components from shipyards identified by the participants as shipyards with specialized capabilities and experience in ship production; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB69A86847294D52AEB8745353180EB4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an agreement among countries participating in the framework to prevent leakage of dual-use technologies to companies connected to the military of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H750F75045A1F4759BC17CF41E531D0EA" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>207.</enum><header>Maritime group of nations</header> 
<subsection id="H52BBC2855BAB4D6A9551D839EE0A7318"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall seek to establish a group, to be known as the <quote>Maritime Group of Nations</quote>, to coordinate regulatory and commerce policies to facilitate a new maritime multimodalism for commercial shipping.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H147202625C90435686B21379E88982EC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation</header> <paragraph id="HEC042A3A128C448D8840EFDCAC95D88A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State should invite to the Maritime Group of Nations appropriate counterparts from the governments of countries that meet each of the following criteria:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H25175960FFC24179BC430D111AE50886"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The country is of significant importance for the purposes of establishing and advancing the objectives of the Maritime Group of Nations, as determined by the Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C62298B41AF489E920B057779301237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The country additionally is among the top 15 countries globally with respect to at least two of the following criteria:</text> 
<clause id="H8E89AEF682804158BFCA1C8E57A87383"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Shipbuilding, as measured by tonnage as a percentage of global total.</text></clause> <clause id="H0F3BAD2C2CD249CFAC3E4BA7F91C7FDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Number of citizens or nationals who are merchant mariners.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5582558287004CBEA6C550F19B745D18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Number of commercially owned ships greater than 1,000 gross weight tonnage.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52601819A703487C8327842ECD775756"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The Maritime Group of Nations established under subsection (a) may not include a foreign country of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H90967A66DF454D1EBC53DBEE1F1BFC90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Maritime Group of Nations established under subsection (a) should consider the following:</text> <paragraph id="H8A7079CA0B8142F499CEEE8FD49C4992"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supporting the establishment of maritime prosperity zones across a diverse geography, including areas outside traditional coast shipbuilding and ship repair centers, to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE5B12DF9B1E94E6AA7EF5CCF31F780EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incentivize and leverage national private capital and investment by allied countries in the maritime industries and waterfront communities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A8775721B2E44CD9A92B1547E22EC7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthen industrial base capacity and readiness through shipbuilding, workforce development, and expanded manufacturing incentives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF188E5B03B994D23A2795DC0C5454455"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supporting the implementation of a coordinated, reciprocal fee on foreign-built vessels, to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF506B6394A29424E992247110D84CE7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide consistent funding to strengthen the merchant marine enterprise; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFEFD8979BEF648AB8A123C25943FBB14"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support investments in commercial shipbuilding, fleet expansion, industrial base resilience, and maritime workforce development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6673B464FC6D41D8833535D70C183900"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing standardized reciprocal trade agreements that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD1E79F3874AA43F3924DB6AFFFC9A6DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would ensure fair competition; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21EF8D9F3BF443A3AB368A5FB8AD9CE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce dependency on adversarial supply chains.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD21396E94BD1479A85E23B9062A049B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordinating a collective position with respect to regulations and guidelines issued by the International Maritime Organization that protects domestic shipbuilding industries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25CC36AD27F449F68D2DB8271394776C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementing and contributing to the exchange visitor program authorized by the amendments made by <internal-xref idref="H0BEA90044E6B468281003673F244897A" legis-path="204.">section 204</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H9425E528E6864D66B5DFA89B48222D2C"><enum>208.</enum><header>International Maritime Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall direct the United States Ambassador to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States mission to the United Nations to urge the International Maritime Organization of the United Nations, and the members of its Council, to—</text> <paragraph id="HE6A345FE365B44E4BEB1E2AF5E2C86C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revise the International Maritime Organization’s Net-Zero Framework, specifically to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8CFEBFC148D04C0EBA6DED95FA71C0BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exclude any limits on conventional crude or diesel, liquified natural gas, or any other type of marine propulsion technology and instead champion an <quote>energy all</quote> approach that does not restrict or constrain current or breakthrough fuel types;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H079A74ED729B42EEA1ED0D7DE6103F2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>remove any financial penalties, carbon taxes, or multilateral funds which are used to help nations decarbonize;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8559890B6E974D95ACFF7AE4115B1636" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eliminate penalties on liquified natural gas, recognize biofuels as viable marine fuels, and support industry-led advances in alternative fuels and other technologies without creating undue advantage or disadvantage to certain fuels or technologies through regulation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0992DD81323C476E8FD5145766954A21" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withdraw or phase out of any regional shipping emissions reduction schemes, including the Emissions Trading System of the European Union;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE599AB14DD6349D8A406C03DBCBB2D4F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support an <quote>opt-in</quote> model with respect to the rules of such organization; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF41A354D4E7147AFA5A2070A2BCE06E3"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remove any net-zero 2050 targets the President determines unreasonable;</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H696D0ABAF893404DB87E0B3088B5C435"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advance the candidacy of United States citizens into senior-level positions within the—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D047CAB53E34255B0D18BD316631B68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>International Maritime Organization Assembly;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2A01A209D38479B98165C1983EE0B95"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">International Maritime Organization Council; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F6F53D2FF3645C19F0175C5781054AF"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">main committees of the International Maritime Organization, including—</text> 
<clause id="H159BCCB852304F58A504B6B866E376CF"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>the Maritime Safety Committee;</text> </clause> <clause id="H4F68E5B4DD4F4EE8A5666402307BFA90"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the Marine Environment Protection Committee;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H4C29374CE1754C929436548CE8CCC947"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>the Legal Committee;</text> </clause> <clause id="HF9C0F16BD02647A78554A2E6BFC727E8"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>the Technical Cooperation Committee;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H182E4EA031B5461688EAD3D62B2A91B1"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>the Facilitation Committee; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H75B023EC8B1B4A7B940952284DBA0FF6"> <enum>(vi)</enum> <text>any Sub-Committee;</text> </clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F782A4BB16C496CA8F6198407998717"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advance the candidacy of a United States citizen to fill the position of Secretary-General of the International Maritime Organization;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D92A4FAFA75467DB342C0B39E4014FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">combat the anti-competitive practices of the People’s Republic of China by investigating and regulating the deliberate use of policies and practices to give domestic shipbuilding industries a competitive advantage over foreign rivals (also known as <quote>industrial targeting</quote>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H081D175D5DCB4348BFB7E3C8685A8999"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advocate for the consistent enforcement of existing safety and technical rules to ensure foreign-flagged vessels meet International Maritime Organization standards without requiring unilateral United States regulations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5ED1BE3FCF04B819FF2B4FD86988D6A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>de-link United States domestic environmental requirements from international certificates to reduce compliance friction for United States shipyards.</text></paragraph></section></title> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


