<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H667EA7629BE548FFA96705731F4AC71A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9652 IH: Northern Marianas VA Community-Based Outpatient Clinic Authorization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9652</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a minor medical facility project in Saipan, Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H863E19B5B8374E10AD9E3A9A1D1306B8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1694984261E8417496CBB5828280AB09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Northern Marianas VA Community-Based Outpatient Clinic Authorization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H95B8171427FC41FC9B117242A5B31F8C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of minor medical facility project for community-based outpatient clinic in Saipan, Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands</header> 
<subsection id="H90430BCFC33949CDBE6D757FC51B975A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may carry out a minor medical facility project in fiscal year 2027 in Saipan, Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, for the construction, lease, build-to-lease, renovation, alteration, repair, or retrofit of a community-based outpatient clinic in an amount not to exceed $3,696,000.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H7CC3017296634314AFC24F1599DF27BC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of existing structures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the project authorized under subsection (a), the Secretary may use amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (e) to conduct such construction activities as the Secretary determines appropriate for such project.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA2181029F6346F19B194562A28C62CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Flexibility in building standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the project authorized under subsection (a), the Secretary may apply such alternative building, design, space, resiliency, or construction standards as the Secretary determines appropriate for the unique geographic, logistical, and market conditions of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, if the Secretary determines such standards will ensure that the facility is safe, accessible, functional, and suitable for the delivery of outpatient care under laws administered by the Secretary to veterans.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2DC99013C172481FA1E03D5CF7CA9165"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Required considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the feasibility of the project under subsection (a) or in determining the type of facility at which to carry out the project under such subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the elevated costs and logistical challenges associated with construction, leasing, renovation, alteration, repair, and retrofit activities in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC54B4538562047CCA2A181E7CB7AAC37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the lack of a permanent Department of Veterans Affairs clinical presence in the Commonwealth;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A525534A8D84F988174C8FEDD4355C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the geographic distance of existing medical facilities from the Commonwealth;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F63B09E22664A949BA6AE914C2645BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the need to ship construction materials for such project by ocean transport;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7C9ED333BEE4CA5AADCA666A92DDE62"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the limited availability of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H748576450EEF49468E6DB6C70DCB6F3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construction contractors and subcontractors; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B9A993E4F2549B789D9833DCD940654"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>contractor housing; and</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45DC8A3E08DD4FD0BD986AD33517AAFA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the need to reduce the burden of traveling to medical facilities for veterans residing in the Commonwealth.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBDB0F308BCC44DA49988609659F8FA46"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for fiscal year 2027, for the project authorized under subsection (a), $3,696,000, to be deposited in the Construction, minor Projects account of the Department.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

