<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY26152-W4Y-PT-DHD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3913 IS: Self-Initiation Trade Enforcement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3913</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a task force to identify potential countervailable subsidies, dumping, and circumvention with respect to trade.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Self-Initiation Trade Enforcement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id8D7CAB2570C64B3B95E493D66C24F247"><enum>2.</enum><header>Task force to identify potential countervailable subsidies, dumping, and circumvention</header><subsection id="id3C228FEF99B34F0181DAAAF4EE27B88F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established, in the administering authority, a task force to be responsible for—</text><paragraph id="id19734CA5CCFC4A6CB620A92B4C47215D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conducting research to—</text><subparagraph id="id3C81A8F4F26A44D088BB886DCA95D58D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify potential countervailable subsidies and dumping that may be causing material injury or threatening to cause material injury to an industry in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6E02C7EF06AD4F48B00777CC2476EC82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify potential circumvention of existing antidumping or countervailing duty orders; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id93A3F2DE5FB34C3FB923FD9D05D24DA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>making recommendations, where appropriate, to the Under Secretary of Commerce for International Trade with respect to initiating investigations under sections 702(a) and 732(a) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1671a">19 U.S.C. 1671a(a)</external-xref> and 1673a(a)) and circumvention inquires under section 781 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1677j">19 U.S.C. 1677j</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id09F9381C11174C3184709CE5350F5F93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In carrying out the responsibilities of the task force under subsection (a), the task force shall—</text><paragraph id="id2107e7237a154e7fb2ee1cec4695fae2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitor trade flows, government and industry data, price fluctuations, domestic industry and market conditions, and other relevant available information to identify potential countervailable subsidies, dumping, or circumvention of existing antidumping or countervailing duty orders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideee3e0dae97341af8e0e82f194f22814"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct background research on—</text><subparagraph id="id8B6D4A8D0D9C45AB86FEB075F9B86D6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>production capabilities and pricing practices of foreign companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDAA1E2B185A14EDD98F527AA694A1AE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>foreign government subsidies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1FFF6A27159C4DF98999293AAE5EFDE8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other relevant information available to the task force;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f9c1499fc1f4bfe9fe8dcf192af81d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult with, or solicit information from, the United States International Trade Commission, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and such other Federal agencies as the task force considers appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7C177B0AA8FA404BAAA8068F110F4827"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prioritize cases that affect small and medium-sized businesses in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD7484742E14F4B05A7160D657E764EC3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In carrying out the responsibilities of the task force under subsection (a), the task force shall consult with industries in the United States with respect to potential countervailable subsidies, dumping, and circumvention.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1b8d666ac10b4a8a90462f14f205dcf4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nondisclosure of certain information</header><text>The administering authority shall not disclose information with regard to the activities of the task force under this section unless and until a determination is made to initiate an investigation under section 702(a) or 732(a) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1671a">19 U.S.C. 1671a(a)</external-xref> and 1673a(a)) or a circumvention inquiry under section 781 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1677j">19 U.S.C. 1677j</external-xref>), as the case may be.</text></subsection><subsection id="id717F19EB57DE40829EAD5AC3380C8D14"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>administering authority</term>, <term>countervailable subsidy</term>, <term>dumping</term>, <term>industry</term>, and <term>material injury</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 771 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1677">19 U.S.C. 1677</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

