<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H689E4D954D9B495A91ECD5DD468AF5E0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9430 IH: American Drone Manufacturing Dominance Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9430</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To condition certain grants on the discontinuation of use of any unmanned aircraft system manufactured by certain foreign countries, to strengthen domestic unmanned aircraft system manufacturing, enhance law enforcement security, and reduce reliance on unmanned aircraft systems produced by certain foreign countries by directing the use of certain tariff revenues, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCE801F758A7745FFAD25E7538D260619" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H13CAD361C61C4113BA9BCF7AA4FBC71F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Drone Manufacturing Dominance Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HD12F90DD2B5A4110AB20B73DD8D488D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certification requirement for eligibility</header> <subsection id="H4AEA35593E514C00A919DB13B68BE194"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning in fiscal year 2027, as a condition of receiving funds under a covered grant program, each law enforcement agency applying for a covered grant program shall certify to the Attorney General that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9F027A04398D415D802A27E0D79FA512"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the agency will not, after January 1, 2027, purchase, lease, or otherwise acquire any unmanned aircraft system manufactured in a covered foreign country; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A05A1186D4D483D90A95425B67DC835"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the agency will, not later than January 1, 2031, discontinue use of or discard any unmanned aircraft system manufactured in a covered foreign country that it currently owns or operates.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H861B701AEB5148EE8BA8F5B407C10A60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of certification</header><text>The Attorney General shall prescribe the form and manner of certification required under subsection (a), which may be included as part of any existing grant application or renewal process.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F487F5CA5664B4295ECE24A33D98A0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance and enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may conduct audits of recipients of covered grant program to ensure compliance with subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H645AF1F18D4048BEA48ECF1334172D30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties for noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any law enforcement agency found to be in violation of subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H33DE59BBBAE444F99C663F42839F0C37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be ineligible to receive funds under a covered grant program for the following fiscal year; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H535EAD0EE9584D5984E064E48F6F1103"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be required to repay any grant funds awarded under a covered grant program for that fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6A9B10071FCB4442B048375C25805652" commented="no"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Use of grant funds for secure unmanned aircraft system procurement</header> <paragraph id="H94FC22CBF0BE42CE8117DC8C4F1D19D4" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Authorized use</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts made available under a covered grant may be used by a State, unit of local government, or law enforcement agency to acquire, operate, and maintain an unmanned aircraft system that is not manufactured by, assembled by, or otherwise sourced from a covered foreign country.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC336EB3163F64319AF3A5B013D32D335" commented="no">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Priority consideration</header>
 <text>In awarding a covered grant program, the Attorney General may give priority to applicants seeking to replace or upgrade unmanned aircraft systems manufactured in a covered foreign country with secure systems manufactured in the United States or by allies and partners of the United States.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D749BCEB4384B4AA2EC11D721A448AA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall issue regulations to carry out this section, including establishing procedures for certification, auditing, and enforcement.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H99171D01F3744D9DAB1E16968847FEEF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of section 301 duty revenues</header> <subsection id="H9FAD92FA89DE44B5AA9522B924B6D6CD"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,500,000,000 to be derived from duties collected pursuant to any action taken by the United States Trade Representative under section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC2C722B19D55446EB218A1A3FC252C68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text>Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="HD725FE6818F74367880EB9BC514F17D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$150,000,000 is authorized to be made available to the Attorney General to carry out section 4;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A9714E425AD4ACC87573F574048459B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$150,000,000 is authorized to be made available to the Attorney General to carry out section 5; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF843C3007764E29A70D444751D18839"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,200,000,000 is authorized to be made available to the Secretary of Commerce to carry out section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3AAD0CAB17ED4BCABC1A9EC9CB804C84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability and rescission of funds for sections 4 and 5</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b)—</text> <paragraph id="H15FE20DAE3584C1C8FDDD41711804042"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall remain available for obligation for a period of 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68F48CC4A2BE401CAA3AF7F50830C6D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amounts not obligated at the end of such period shall be permanently rescinded and deposited into the general fund of the Treasury for the sole purpose of deficit reduction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF5C72BFD5E5B4E3BB01CE8B6E739E21B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Law enforcement unmanned aircraft system buyback program</header> <subsection id="HC0A2301CAD014F6CB82ABC7168902755"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish a program to provide payments to State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies to surrender to the Attorney General unmanned aircraft systems manufactured or assembled in a covered foreign country.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5CA27C8F09E445998B6E3FCB01BC07F6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible equipment</header><text>Equipment that is eligible to be surrendered to the Attorney General for payment under this section is—</text> <paragraph id="H0AA7118410AC4B56AFB55F620D8232EB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an unmanned aircraft system that was manufactured in, assembled in, or otherwise sourced from a covered foreign country; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A5B2DD2D134417FB50723090ED51A4D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an unmanned aircraft system that was not manufactured in, assembled in, or otherwise sourced from a covered foreign country, a critical component of such system that was manufactured in, assembled in, or otherwise sourced from a covered foreign country.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H661C84D929FC47AFA1E676F6F2CA0F00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds made available under this section may be used to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H086BEE2DAE554D6BB9B85A8D34A7D1F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compensate State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies for surrendered unmanned aircraft systems or critical components of such systems;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB489C6B8786E4C1C9D47A7E7758A23AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cover administrative costs of operating the program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D5BC2AB027A4B2FB1769B561DAFE5CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure secure destruction, decommissioning, or controlled storage of unmanned aircraft systems surrendered under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB033F544F6E94DE89EFCC13948F904C7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Attorney General shall give priority for payment under this section to law enforcement agencies that surrender unmanned aircraft systems that are actively deployed in public safety or critical infrastructure operations.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD71E1A5C96134389AD78D8AE0980CE43"><enum>5.</enum><header>DOJ grants for procurement of secure unmanned aircraft systems</header> 
<subsection id="HBFF78A632C814DC19003ADCE9E4FD2F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services and the Office of Justice Programs, shall award grants to State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies for the procurement of unmanned aircraft systems that are not manufactured or assembled in a covered foreign country.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60E9C58823014F81907229C35A678E8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>Grant funds may be used for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H657C4457CCEB49A8AD04886EF5EACD6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acquisition of unmanned aircraft systems not manufactured or assembled in a covered foreign country;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0F789DA20664593A7DBC80CAA1960FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training, certification, and licensing of operators of such systems;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1719BF1C3B344E199D700123DFA2A9CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintenance, software, and cybersecurity protections related to such systems; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4B78F6948794032A47797581D489695"><enum>(4)</enum><text>integration of such systems into public safety operations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7CA6E13B39024569811F50135CEB1192"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants, the Attorney General shall give preference to law enforcement agencies that will procure—</text> <paragraph id="HBDF15B3ADAF540988345C0E05EB9DA48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>systems manufactured in the United States; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC83EC7BF3D84FBAB9483F28EB10AF32"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">systems manufactured in Ukraine, a NATO ally, a major non-NATO ally, or a qualifying country (as defined in section 225.003 of the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation), that do not include components manufactured in a covered foreign country.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H01EE3621F58242B3A8AB6E568910D1D9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Domestic unmanned aircraft system manufacturing facility grants</header> <subsection id="HA0AEE50AF9354EAF935FD53BD77C5E73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program established</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall establish a competitive grant program to make grants to private entities to support the construction, expansion, or modernization of facilities in the United States for the manufacturing of unmanned aircraft systems and related components.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7205E5B6E30E484BA5E480927A1DF10F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A private entity shall be eligible to receive a grant under this section if the entity—</text> <paragraph id="H2B30E124559C421A88D65260579ADB04"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manufactures unmanned aircraft systems or unmanned aircraft system components;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A1C5A6F8B1D415C8C26372EE25C53B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposes to construct or substantially expand an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft system component manufacturing facility located in the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9840BA51BBF44E369F8A2D6F56A61CA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates that the unmanned aircraft systems or unmanned aircraft system components manufactured at such facility are capable of being readily adapted or repurposed for use by the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H498154744A1A4B36A8560F67852C7EB4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Defense repurposability requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (b)(3), an unmanned aircraft system shall be considered readily adaptable for use by the Department of Defense if it—</text> <paragraph id="H6CF9ABD51BDF43F88A2819229B068CB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is designed using modular or open-architecture systems;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F24E6B1054B46439691E11434C145BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is capable of supporting encrypted communications, secure navigation, or payload integration; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75A10262AD714447A062F191498FA95F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>can be modified for intelligence, surveillance, reconnaissance, logistics, or other defense missions without substantial redesign.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77CA1139A819432F9968790B04C22F43"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant under this section may be used for—</text> <paragraph id="H146D6179C248459CAAC8BDE102005A57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>site acquisition and preparation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64074E53C24B460DBD3263AF4C7B958A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>construction and equipment costs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D991DC7C5B249BFBEB9F65D9EC8BEB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>workforce training and development;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3087BAE3F5AB4979AE30B6075EABFF68"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advanced manufacturing tooling and supply chain localization; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1ACF6015CC2441D69F5CC0A90E869E4A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>research and development directly related to production readiness.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H58FCE52FDAC94B5DBDC57AA5B4458606"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination With Department of Defense</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall consult with the Secretary of Defense to ensure that recipients of grants under this section manufacture unmanned aircraft systems that are compatible with current or anticipated defense operational requirements.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H558379C956694EA0BCF6FCA59979CC92"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting and oversight</header> <subsection id="HBF5F73B27C584F56A57A7909E70F18B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of justice report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5F619223A07A484E9EDD2D93796B841A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and types of unmanned aircraft systems surrendered pursuant to section 4; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EA60479AB27466E9193AD4AC1CF76E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the distribution and use of grants under section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D921C8D898B4BAA8D5140001535418A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of commerce report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to Congress a report detailing—</text> <paragraph id="H00E7C5CD7FB54F42A3CE0D4040240FE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grants awarded under section 6;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD8DB5CEDB1E430089BADF0DCC368E76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>construction progress and operational status of facilities funded under such section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6511ED9DB4984E1A9EC18371BDDAAA78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which such facilities are producing systems with defense applications.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H07B5F50275C24036A70552E2E21A9F67"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H64AE46F590804C2DB34B5AB4A58D2A8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered foreign country</header><text>The term <term>covered foreign country</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4873 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8883372723534B53B4B6180505B72404">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Unmanned aircraft system</header>
 <text>The term <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> has the meaning given in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4850C2DFCDE24880ADE65C698A8DF143" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement agency</term> means any State, local, or Tribal police department, sheriff’s office, or other governmental entity with authority to enforce criminal laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H293D3E4D83E846B39760207EE0A732EC" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered grant program</header><text>The term <term>covered grant program</term> means any grant program administered by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5151204540E04BE084BA636A404A12C1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9AAF3FD37AD4A568D224F39975EEE50" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4ACF1366BF1242CBB7A998C551EDE145"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NATO Ally</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>NATO ally</term> means a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (other than the United States).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10E023D97C6E4375B36245D08A791FA7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Major non-NATO ally</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major non-NATO ally</term> has the meaning given such term in section 644(q) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2403">22 U.S.C. 2403(q)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

