<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26519-T5W-4L-FS3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4495 IS: Reactors at Risk Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4495</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require reports on the dangers posed by nuclear reactors in areas that might experience armed conflict.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reactors at Risk Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id55e835d5ab6b4049affbdc95a45fc232"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on dangers posed by nuclear reactors in areas that might experience armed conflict</header><subsection id="id690f512b39544e36bfdc1e4505da954a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Under Secretary of Energy for Nuclear Security shall jointly submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report assessing the following:</text><paragraph id="id845be63ff06247a6ab4545a399f8e9a8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The dangers posed to the national security of the United States, to the interests of allies and partners of the United States, and to the safety and security of civilian populations, by nuclear reactors in existence as of such date of enactment or scheduled to be completed during the 10-year period beginning on such date of enactment and located in the following areas:</text><subparagraph id="id2d8b9b1689294c58988ab4dde2f9a818"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Regions that have experienced armed conflict in the 25 years preceding such date of enactment, including the following conflicts:</text><clause id="id62904a653055448b8e96f30afa2c0dc9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Attacks by the Russian Federation on Ukraine.</text></clause><clause id="id61e0e0c105f0499ab31d8c7b8fe40114"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Conflict in the Middle East, including between Israel and Iran.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f5713de111d4ab5878cc3c51952000f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Areas that are contested or likely to experience armed conflict during the life span of those reactors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida570424958eb4a3fa36198c47f35ba7d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Areas that would be involved in any of the following possible conflicts:</text><clause id="ide30e17420b524043b30b88bac511dc6b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An attack by the Russian Federation on the eastern European countries of Estonia, Latvia, Belarus, Lithuania, or Poland.</text></clause><clause id="ide16458b4e2ae4875bc708c151babb202"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A conflict between India and Pakistan.</text></clause><clause id="id3ef18437b9774ea4a37b093da4030d60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A conflict over Taiwan.</text></clause><clause id="id63a595d16c644c639281f484042e8bee"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An attack by North Korea on South Korea.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idff92aaf5f41c424fbae9c992b18b4737"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Steps the United States or allies and partners of the United States can take to prevent, prepare for, and mitigate the risks to the national security of the United States, to the interests of allies and partners of the United States, and to the safety and security of civilian populations, posed by nuclear reactors in places that may experience armed conflict.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id37ae2bd8c8504834aa9ec2e095971989"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="id46ef95f4e0d24190bb22662a8a2a1a30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id919ed72aa6a64cf5983e1fd9b0a566a3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d7f5a5a80874c4292ff2ec53688ed98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

