<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8DCBDE169E414211A43F8716CB2DB4F5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1043 IH: Expressing support for the designation of February 2026 as “American Heart Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1043</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of February 2026 as <quote>American Heart Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas cardiovascular disease affects men, women, and children of every age and race in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas cardiovascular disease continues to be the leading cause of death in the United States, claiming the lives of over 940,000 individuals in the United States in 2022;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas heart disease and stroke claimed more lives in 2022 in the United States than all forms of cancer and chronic lower respiratory disease combined;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, from 2019 to 2020, deaths from heart disease increased by 4.8 percent, the largest increase in heart disease deaths since 2012;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas individuals in the United States have made great progress in reducing the death rate for cardiovascular disease, but this progress has been more modest with respect to the death rate for cardiovascular disease in communities of color;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas cardiovascular disease (CVD) results in tremendous health care costs and lost productivity, and if not addressed, the United States alone will spend over $1,000,000,000,000 by 2035 on costs relating to CVD;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas CVD accounted for $417,900,000,000 in health care expenditures and lost productivity between 2020 and 2021;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, approximately every 40 seconds, an American will have a heart attack;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2022, stroke accounted for approximately 1 in every 20 deaths in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2022, sudden cardiac arrest accounted for over 19,000 deaths;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas cardiovascular diseases are the leading causes of maternal death among women in the United States, accounting for more than a quarter of pregnancy-related deaths between 2017 and 2019;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas congenital heart defects are—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5767DA846AE442E391D4830367C2C920"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the most common types of birth defects in the United States; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H878F659F745946C8A52924E930DFE570"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the leading killer of infants with birth defects;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas extensive clinical and statistical studies have identified major and contributing factors that increase the risk of cardiovascular disease, including—</text> <paragraph id="HC5DFADF95B234BAF8E9B42320201E920"><enum>(1)</enum><text>high blood pressure;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4048832CC294AFCB83D5944BC84E5A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>high blood cholesterol;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FD0F0F3978D43F58DB8DF8FFF2EB475"><enum>(3)</enum><text>poor diet;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69CBBD72493F4CC68E71291C7A97EDFF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>exposure to nicotine;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B45F5E104F94F16B476BD74A24189E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>physical inactivity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H190DE3CC771342E5B7B314D5E6EEBD6F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>poor habitual sleep;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB77BDD7EE68E4EBE92F76DC6A38B90EE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>obesity; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B4F70F9291F4FA2A9C60DD40E34D469"><enum>(8)</enum><text>diabetes mellitus;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas an individual can greatly reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease through lifestyle modification coupled with medical treatment when necessary;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas greater awareness and early detection of risk factors for cardiovascular disease can improve and save the lives of thousands of individuals in the United States each year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, under section 101(1) of title 36, United States Code, the President is requested to issue an annual proclamation designating February as <quote>American Heart Month</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute of the National Institutes of Health, the American Heart Association, and many other organizations celebrate National Wear Red Day during February by <quote>going red</quote> to increase awareness about cardiovascular disease as the leading killer of women; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, every year since 1964, the President has issued a proclamation designating the month of February as <quote>American Heart Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCA2BE6082FB1487688A89AA4BD447036"> 
<section id="H7AA1B76EFD3F4DCE981F746D5ECF1F03" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HA5D07C8EC76C4B35BFE806E3DE3F74AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>American Heart Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EB693FA084040BE89049862C2D1CA51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of American Heart Month;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H830C6BE8EC3C426EB4FC22B3374B7A6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes and reaffirms the commitment of the United States to fighting cardiovascular disease—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H04AE735D80CE4F42B89ECC154D52C252"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by promoting awareness about the causes, risks, and prevention of cardiovascular disease;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9A0FE3661F14A4B8827F9005E900E92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by supporting research on cardiovascular disease; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82EC843F05EE4738AC93855AB3B8AF91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by improving access to affordable, quality care to reduce long-term disability and mortality;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE581C2EB9BE547ABA8C5412F1A80BD7D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends the efforts of States, territories, and possessions of the United States, localities, nonprofit organizations, businesses, and other entities, and the people of the United States who support American Heart Month; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A4F487BB1AB46CBABFE81AEBC409F4B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages every individual in the United States to learn about their risk for cardiovascular disease.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

