<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0A60B74D8A3746429DE8E2C5CAF3F7F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8303 IH: Revitalizing America’s Schoolyards Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8303</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to revitalize schoolyards.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E02E00E0C8743A2849B127C566A5D82" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB2738B7D52DC408883469E39057B49F8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Revitalizing America’s Schoolyards Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB691B791AA454294A344B6DE3FB4BEB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H9D178005FDCC48D597C5EC6744E3AC16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H684D5F5CB86644949D8D749E864E7949"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H496F4023BA994E4BBE0D4A82F477843B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an educational service agency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC796FED83B544C759B4264331483C410"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization that has expertise in outdoor learning, nature play, spaces, or outdoor education working in partnership with a local educational agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2C6AF39FF5C41249C0675BE75CC0291"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>educational service agency</term>, <term>elementary school</term>, <term>high school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B188D59CDB544D186E6C9FB88A3E198"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revitalized schoolyard</header><text>The term <term>revitalized schoolyard</term>—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEFA81FAA5D274C3B8B30111128344436"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a park-like outdoor environment at an elementary school or secondary school that has been updated to—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8E1DD2793FB4B399E427C1E6A3ADF99"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthen local ecological systems;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50D16327EE934448AC768F55FEC0FD78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a range of hands-on learning resources; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1D9DC5E24B446DC8DCD5E623AC13F7D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foster nature play and social opportunities while enhancing the health and well-being of children and adults; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD7C2983F315E441E8A4129A06DB1B81E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB570DAC460E64C5D970EB3BD9DA4456D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06F5FB22931B4B47A9395E9A7CF25C57"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trees and plants where children can access them;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83DE7FC64A2C4D6991CC0E103D24AAB6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cultivated gardens;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0E001D2C1704A06AEF3057619F775DC"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outdoor meeting and gathering areas; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H419A0153F8384BE7ABAEF93F43B35CF4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other elements designed by, and for, the students and the surrounding community; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17DBEC342C96498AB734798BDA31315A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serve as a facility for shared public use.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E5B8F5F78CD4300A64A0971B822878D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD79664209164B758E71D88B8EEF3C6D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Shared public use</header><text>The term <term>shared public use</term> means use as public facility that, to the extent feasible, is open and accessible to the public, outside of school hours, but during daylight hours.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H92D3499555314D3CA187EF0E95F70A8D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant cohort structure, duration, and amount</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED990912B1B246FEA5B96404E52E9585"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation for tribal educational agencies including the Bureau of Indian Education</header><text>From the amount appropriated to carry out this Act for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve 5 percent for the Secretary of the Interior to carry out this Act for schools operated by the Bureau of Indian Education or schools that are operated by an Indian Tribe, or an organization controlled or sanctioned by an Indian tribal government, for the children of that Tribe under a contract with, or grant from, the Department of the Interior under the Indian Self-Determination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5321">25 U.S.C. 5321 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2501">25 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2BA2F33F416F4860A05C11DA3DA57677"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cohort structure</header>
<paragraph id="H04C1E49E62A048FF996277DC1ADEF081"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Grants awarded under this Act shall be awarded in cohorts on a biennial cycle.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9835B4B4CF98422CBDB7789FC1229739"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Each cohort shall be eligible for—</text>
<subparagraph id="H03FB104E3A4343288BDBDFAAD235BEDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a planning grant described in section 4(a) in the first year; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7ED0E35F8A147AF9195A3BA7A17303A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to the availability of appropriated funds and a determination by the Secretary that the grantee has demonstrated the viability of the proposed project, an implementation grant described in section 4(b) in the second year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F45DDEE40D8409BA8A1F35F6E39A04D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria for viability</header><text>The Secretary shall establish criteria for determining viability under paragraph (2), which may include the adequacy of the concept plan described in section 4(a)(3)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFD5C1B25E32940558D50B01F4E75E142"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amounts and duration</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBFD5A47D550D45B7A5D2054353909BAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>From the amount remaining for a fiscal year after making the reservation under subsection (a), the Secretary shall use—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55B9355A6CBC4CF8B68701AC968B7858"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">30 percent of such amount to award planning grants under section 4(a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B7A4394A480485C824E7996919E2652"><enum>(B)</enum><text>70 percent of such amount to award implementation grants under section 4(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12DD087D382E4EEDBAD7196E6AAC9EB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may receive not more than $1,000,000 in grant awards for both a planning grant and implementation grant in total under section 4.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90E18637C0BC4DE8BDD9FE4CCC6A0DA9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Planning grants and implementation grants awarded under section 4 shall each be for a period of not more than 2 years, for a total of 4 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H043181831EF446F690800B4817B3841C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>The Secretary may authorize the reallocation of funds awarded under a planning grant to support implementation activities in a subsequent fiscal year, provided such reallocation does not exceed the total award cap established under this section and is consistent with the purposes of the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF6375A7F8A6A427AB9E111ABF6EDD929"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Surplus funds</header> <paragraph id="HFCC0709BC4C442B4A30E6FC7D5ABF50C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of surplus funds for additional grant awards</header><text>If, after awarding initial planning grants, the Secretary determines that remaining unobligated funds are available due to awardees requesting less than the maximum grant amount or due to denial of applications for failure to demonstrate concept plan viability under section 4(a)(3)(A), the Secretary may use such remaining funds to make additional grant awards to other eligible entities from the same application cycle, if—</text>
<subparagraph id="H365C3FDCDC544A8F8899A90E8D303B17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such applicants meet or exceed the minimum criteria for awards established in the notice inviting applications;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0F644A50406493AB2283A104E912796"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount awarded in a fiscal year does not exceed the amount appropriated for that year; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA55B00EACB8147D698329659C785D237"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such additional awards do not exceed the maximum grant amount specified under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32541FD18A5B433CB66BC0199CAA041F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making additional awards, the Secretary shall prioritize applicants that scored highly, but were not initially funded due to funding limitations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H949529B66BC446A9A7C8916A1C47557D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Planning grants and implementation grants</header>
<subsection id="H5FA65EEAE4B14E518EA6978975C59D8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Planning grants</header>
<paragraph id="H8776A6C1F5F244AD930D8A73677EADFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award planning grants to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to develop concept plans described in paragraph (3) to turn some or all of the outdoor spaces of the public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the eligible entities into revitalized schoolyards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD62F38B88370470D9558FB290D5A163E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity that desires to receive a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, including the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HBACA0517AFBD43BA9D637C3DACCBDE4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An initial scope of work briefly summarizing the project.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC97742BE87274AE1A5F79ECAA262DAE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A plan for educator professional development to support educators in using the revitalized schoolyard.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H86B6582F01E34C6B8CA79CC2D38195C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identification of State learning standards that may be addressed through student involvement in the revitalized schoolyard.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD7F8D6749A0450089AC37A9EA47947F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A plan for how the eligible entity will provide for maintenance and operation of the revitalized schoolyard after the grant period ends.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDF6C01DFB30F484FABC20CAF01530DE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
<subparagraph id="HD2C978D608174D45B9527FF3C2272427"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Concept plan</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall use the grant funds to develop a concept plan, including design and construction documents, to turn some or all of the outdoor spaces of the public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the eligible entity into revitalized schoolyards. Such concept plan shall comply with the following:</text> <clause id="HF0CBD053A2B843A39032FFC9FA2A7055"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Be developed with school and public input, including students, families, educators, school staff, and the public.</text></clause>
<clause id="H93128BC7E9B34965BD87CE443B6934DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Be developed with the goal of longevity and resilience of the revitalized schoolyard after the grant period under this subsection and subsection (b) has expired.</text></clause> <clause id="H8EF2F419FF3F4EF7BCC82E2327ED70EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Maximize investment in schools with low tree canopy and vulnerability to extreme heat or flooding.</text></clause>
<clause id="H7013E7EED6AE4566B5D03A4DF1587A1E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Maximize investment in schools with a high percentage of students eligible for a free or reduced-price lunch under the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause> <clause id="H56712E2EA56245198B2CC9B66B1E3073"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Include—</text>
<subclause id="H07AEE39E3D52465491066EEE279E4343"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ecological, climate, and biodiversity goals;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBBEBC0E0FC0D4A578DE9F988DB864744"><enum>(II)</enum><text>learning and education goals;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F3C1143B9024DB9BD1C60E33EF079D7"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">physical and mental health goals;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H370C3EFCBAE04016890C1424D3A3345D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a description of how the entity will provide accessibility in compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H2B143D01922E4962828989F51CE2386E"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the number of students to be served at each school served under the grant, the total size of each such school property in acres, and the size of the proposed revitalized schoolyard at each site in acres;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H03F908A334E940D09C177E154C9B3EE1"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a concept plan drawing of the design proposed for each school served under the grant;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7AA18E4CB674F448495D54111E165FD"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>an estimate of the probable cost based on the scope of work identified in the concept plan;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBE7FD219801944E2B8A47A53AA2DB3C2"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>an identification of community partners, including nonprofit organizations or design professionals, that have expertise in outdoor learning spaces or outdoor education, if applicable;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HA9545BA5977F417C8AB5D5BC693D0DC9"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>a long-term management plan describing how the eligible entity proposes to maintain the revitalized schoolyard over time and how the concept plan relates to other district plans; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HD314E0E0ABEA40AF8D1463D2D74EB709"><enum>(X)</enum><text>how components of the site design may address—</text>
<item commented="no" id="H1EE5B9B350BB48839CBBB1A33D1D68A5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>growing food, planting pollinator plants, creating habitat for wildlife, and creating amenities to support students in observing nature and participating in school gardens;</text></item> <item commented="no" id="HBAEFC6470F9A4BAFA6D3F231B5B2E4D6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>conserving water and managing stormwater;</text></item>
<item commented="no" id="HA000E90AEC7B4C9A905A2096269000A1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>supporting hands-on learning activities and programs across subject areas and grade levels, such as conducting experiments regarding soil, wind, water, and other elements;</text></item> <item commented="no" id="HF069825D0247494B880F877D0FF76A44"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>using the arts, such as preparing skits, plays, murals, drawings, and sculptures that celebrate nature, including its animals, plants, patterns, and behaviors, to strengthen learning objectives;</text></item>
<item commented="no" id="HA687B6A82C744D29BB5EF2836ED00C95"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>planting, to the extent practicable, native and nonnative species, which—</text> <subitem commented="no" id="H544E40BE61E3432A83C68903FB89C023"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>directly protect students from the effects of extreme heat due to climate change; and</text></subitem>
<subitem commented="no" id="H1877B4C59B70418DA0588810F9FF9211"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>cast shade on adjacent classroom windows in the school building to help reduce temperatures indoors and save cooling costs during the warmest parts of the school year; and</text></subitem></item> <item commented="no" id="H4B6D94CCC804461A995E7F4504459FB3"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>the use of natural playgrounds, which include natural and nature-based elements, such as rock gardens, sand boxes, log stumps, streams, living plants, or innovative playground elements, that encourage gross motor play and integrated with the outdoor landscape and vegetation, and which—</text>
<subitem commented="no" id="HACC3268D8BC449B9961A91A9FEF9994A"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>will absorb less heat from the sun and air than traditional playgrounds and equipment;</text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="HE9F28900A2CA48D2A17BEAB078A59424"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>are inclusive and accessible for children of all abilities;</text></subitem>
<subitem commented="no" id="H973C43C6514F4F39B8A050A779ADF45C"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>allow children to learn about nature; and</text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="H3CC6D8F6B22F47C087FD58BE159BEEE5"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>use non-petroleum-based materials.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8A38010AAB084EE6BF8F46FC7317EB44"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E9B07C909CE4CA9B89963E77EB0D6C1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection may use grant funds to hire or contract a qualified grant writer or consultant as an allowable administrative cost to assist the eligible entity in preparing and submitting an application for an implementation grant under subsection (b).</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H822A777E048A487C8F59C2089E20BF6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may use not more than 10 percent of the total grant award to hire or contract a qualified grant writer or consultant as described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8BCFBE3CE30E460A95921EEAA9C99D2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header>
<paragraph id="H70132C52216D45ACA60CD2F58F03919A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award implementation grants to eligible entities that received a planning grant under subsection (a) and developed a concept plan in accordance with subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16CE0C0AD7E049F3A8700F9F71F0BC9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA293E3283C84698AF7A0F8303334FF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that desires to receive a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A5DE0B908C349438C9F0AE84A727805"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Multiple grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may apply for more than 1 grant under this subsection in order to complete individual schools in separate phases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB088083398749419EF974E9B39D7897"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <subparagraph id="HE9BC71BBD88E4F0C9CF6D0F6D22379DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall use the grant funds to implement some or all of the concept plan developed in accordance with subsection (a) by turning some or all of the outdoor spaces of the public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the eligible entity into revitalized schoolyards.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF0079BE01EA94B228437090A5FF7527D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Permissible uses</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection may use not more than 25 percent of the grant funds—</text> <clause id="HE7061E158E0A4A35AFFA47CEBC3198DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for professional development for school leadership, educators, and paraprofessionals related to outdoor teaching and bringing students outside for learning; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1E5A0AE247DA4264B0A70FCA6CF4D911"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to support an educator or other school staff member or school partner to establish, maintain, and steward the revitalized schoolyard of the elementary schools and secondary schools served by the eligible entity and provide professional development described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0443EF7340064B3B95C44CF2F3775BC1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Match</header> <subparagraph id="H2275DD43894E433BAAE1F436ADBCEF41"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall provide matching funds from non-Federal sources in an amount equal to 20 percent of the grant award.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6DBDB0AE15AD4EDE815F8B1C0A284B96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive the matching requirement under subparagraph (A) for an eligible entity that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89E57A6DBF134899BBE0EAD0FF6F3E87"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives a grant under this subsection and serves students not less than 40 percent of whom are eligible for a free or reduced-price lunch under the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), which calculation, in the case of high schools served by the eligible entity, may be completed using comparable data from the schools that feed into the high schools; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC077485304B540549C54F8B45EB48050"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receives a grant under this subsection and serves a school described in section 3(a).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H5BDB66DA2BFB47259C6A0E81F2A67731"><enum>5.</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In awarding grants under this Act, the Secretary shall give competitive priority to an eligible entity—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15C9C3D0391C4D6581FD35908814B5A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that serves students not less than 75 percent of whom are eligible for a free or reduced-price lunch under the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), which calculation, in the case of high schools served by the eligible entity, may be completed using comparable data from the schools that feed into the high schools; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8495FB3B0EA24CCDA429134E589DAD8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that serves a school—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78B51D5B28EE4410AE62BA89FCCE3388"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that serves students not less than 75 percent of whom are eligible for a free or reduced-price lunch under the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), which calculation, in the case of high schools served by the eligible entity, may be completed using comparable data from the schools that feed into the high schools; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63ECEF3994DD4AE88102E8CBFA60EA60"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where the proposed revitalized schoolyard will be developed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="HD68130BDE26246089E42785E4B54B2B1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall maintain a clearinghouse of information that—</text> <paragraph id="HA0B3DD32D98441988CFF8A4987147EBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides examples of outdoor learning spaces, including successful models being used;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCB997A0F99E646359F2F7A0D1F370323"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes input from nonprofit organizations, professionals, and other community members with expertise in outdoor learning spaces and environmental education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8D0F630BB1A48A9BD94C1580CE2A322"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides links and information about State and local entities with expertise in outdoor learning spaces and environmental education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H072AD631739448E0B467935BD2FDAB58"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reflects best practices on designs for outdoor spaces relating to nature play, non-petroleum based materials, maintenance, stewardship resources, example partnership programs, green infrastructure in schools examples, outdoor learning resources, lesson plans, and planning tools; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H453667459C704D1E8CB39079A3712665"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is housed within the National Center on School Infrastructure, or other clearinghouse, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H9958346F166143EA9E9814DB31336B24"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

