<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE1DEE933BE7148CF9FE8285CF02A157D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6619 IH: Promoting Regional Opportunities for Sustainable Prosperity and Economic Resilience in the Pacific Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6619</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize preferential treatment for certain imports from the Pacific Islands.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H292133D3BD4741768EB9A981F5BF56B6" style="OLC"><section id="HDF31356B00354FF08A57F9F7F7044074" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Regional Opportunities for Sustainable Prosperity and Economic Resilience in the Pacific Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROSPER in the Pacific Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD8399CDFA854498BBF886043FE885D53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H3D4B3DD36B3F4F0EAC59021D994E0B9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States has longstanding and enduring cultural, historic, economic, strategic, and people-to-people connections with the Pacific Islands, based on shared values, cultural histories, common interests, and a commitment to fostering mutual understanding and cooperation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDF4EEA20601474AB26A1513C0D43B6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the economies of the Pacific Islands countries face significant challenges including geographic isolation, limited economic diversification, vulnerability to natural disasters, and underdeveloped infrastructure and trade capacity, that can make conventional economic indicators based on average national income poor measures of development progress and welfare outcomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFD1A99C4E9481BAD799F53411C179C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strengthening U.S.-Pacific Islands economic ties through a preferential trade program would promote inclusive economic development, create sustainable job opportunities, and improve standards of living in the region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99651E9088724F839BE69F598812F7C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a U.S.-led preferential trade program would also make Americans safer, stronger, and more prosperous by advancing a free and open Indo-Pacific, prioritizing sovereignty, economic independence, and the rule of law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2A7C6F0C86E34CAF9F86DB8608E4FC18"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><subsection id="H664A76BD91044E8F969F083F446BF8E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall authorize the provision of preferential treatment under section 4 to articles that are imported directly from a Pacific Islands country into the customs territory of the United States if the President determines that the country—</text><paragraph id="H83F4D8F0A6CE4AC799549A9A037202C3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>meets the requirements set forth in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 104 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3703">19 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED758D5E5FAA453FBC45DD86B53773F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not meet any of the bases for ineligibility under section 502(b)(2) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2462">19 U.S.C. 2462(b)(2)</external-xref>) and does not meet any of the additional bases for ineligibility under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E7253551F9C4B2180CEF614C5094027"><enum>(3)</enum><text>after taking into account the factors set forth in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (c) of section 502 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2462">19 U.S.C. 2462</external-xref>) and the additional factors set forth in subsection (d), the country meets the eligibility requirements of such section 502.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Any income threshold requirements applicable for purposes of determining whether a country is eligible to be designated as a beneficiary developing country or least-developed beneficiary developing country under title V of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2461">19 U.S.C. 2461 et seq.</external-xref>) shall not apply with respect to determining whether a Pacific Islands country is eligible for preferential treatment under section 4.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H9BF16CD2567F4688874999BD2693AC0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal, suspension, or limitation of preferential treatment; mandatory graduation</header><text>The provisions of subsection (d) of section 502 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2462">19 U.S.C. 2462</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to Pacific Island countries to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to beneficiary developing countries under title V of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2461">19 U.S.C. 2461 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF6BAE76019864059BEB4D13335F612FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional bases for ineligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not authorize the provision of preferential treatment under section 4 to articles that are imported directly from a Pacific Islands country into the customs territory of the United States if any of the following applies:</text><paragraph id="HE068D932CD154B36A01B8B986FD89374"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such country fails to effectively afford internationally recognized worker rights to workers in the country (including any designated zone in that country).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H642512CF8D3741C699C0B932F6904B8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such country engages in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights in that country (including any designated zone in that country).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA87C37DCFA5649F4AE56A58030B26C2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such country fails to effectively enforce its environmental laws, regulations, or other measures, or to fulfill its international environmental obligations, including as such obligations relate to public health and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1D2CC344FDC4849933F303CBC8DADA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional factors affecting country designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to authorize the provision of preferential treatment under section 4 to articles that are imported directly from a Pacific Islands country into the customs territory of the United States, the President shall take into account—</text><paragraph id="HD1E800006FAF40AB8BA0DD6A761E8A04"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether or not such country effectively affords to workers in that country (including any designated zone in that country) internationally recognized worker rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H501E24359FE74DA28264DD277E01A68F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which such country effectively enforces its environmental laws, regulations, and other measures, and fulfills its international environmental obligations, including as such obligations relates to public health and illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16BA27D8C1454A89A6C370965D320F09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which such country has established, or is making continual progress toward establishing—</text><subparagraph id="H96EB6C33C3634DE6B29B9D1A1013F538"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rule of law, political pluralism, and the right to due process, a fair trial, and equal protection under the law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB957E97B3F6A4755829F6B702741F23B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>economic policies to reduce poverty increase the availability of health care and educational opportunities, expand physical infrastructure, promote the development of private enterprise, and encourage the formation of capital markets through micro-credit or other programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H099A8D8AE8B5403189E29567CE5D0C95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a system to combat corruption and bribery, such as signing and implementing the Convention on Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials in International Business Transactions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB6AB4E1D205640E4B5C845DB781EDC7E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Eligibility for certain benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President is authorized to designate articles as eligible articles from a Pacific Islands country that is listed as eligible for benefits under section 3(a) to the same extent and in the same manner as the President is authorized to designate articles as eligible articles from least developed beneficiary developing countries under section 503 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2463">19 U.S.C. 2463</external-xref>), including subsections (a)(2) and (b) of such section.</text></section><section id="H08EA3E6104F5417881AE0203F6E10B66"><enum>5.</enum><header>Free trade agreements with Pacific Islands countries</header><subsection id="H091D9DD50E374286BA43FACDC49E075E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text>Congress declares that free trade agreements should be negotiated, where feasible, with interested countries in the Pacific Islands, in order to serve as the catalyst for increasing trade between the United States and the Pacific Islands and increasing private sector investment in the Pacific Islands.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB6F64EACA87642B28395E84F08A39A2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan requirement</header><paragraph id="H7265861F84944D10A4258DB706C16663"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, taking into account the willingness of the Governments of Pacific Islands countries to engage in negotiations to enter into free trade agreements, shall develop a plan for the purpose of negotiating and entering into one or more trade agreements with interested beneficiary Pacific Islands countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB570CCC02E7C4E5F8CA920ECFDE3EDA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of plan</header><text>The plan shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H399B54FAC01144D29173538A3D4B9BBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The specific objectives of the United States with respect to negotiations described in paragraph (1) and a suggested timetable for achieving those objectives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H738570BD9F4E4B0D84419F462048AFD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The benefits to both the United States and the relevant Pacific Islands countries with respect to the applicable free trade agreement or agreements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3395582AD1434AD4B5396DBB564B5604"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A mutually agreed-upon timetable for the negotiations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9F3A3783DF7417ABCF41D77BDAFA1F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The implications for and the role of regional and subregional organizations in the Pacific Islands with respect to such free trade agreement or agreements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACAE5BD714B54B519F3C575A81E3984E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Subject matter anticipated to be covered by the negotiations and United States laws, programs, and policies, as well as the laws of participating eligible Pacific Islands countries and existing bilateral and multilateral and economic cooperation and trade agreements, that may be affected by the agreement or agreements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE48621C0C64D5F8FC9FB2EE55F55FA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Procedures to ensure the following:</text><clause id="H47392D3850A8470992B90C487F405FE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Adequate consultation with the Congress and the private sector during the negotiations.</text></clause><clause id="H1A6517A983A54FF6B4F1DBD0E71524FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Consultation with the Congress regarding all matters relating to implementation of the agreement or agreements.</text></clause><clause id="HA3AB5474A03447F6A36EFCD5822E5B44"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Approval by the Congress of the agreement or agreements.</text></clause><clause id="H2F02FEF8574B4299A860F424F7DFD55B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Adequate consultations with the relevant Pacific Islands governments and Pacific Islands regional and subregional intergovernmental organizations during the negotiation of the agreement or agreements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1700DE3797F0449BB2CFA29159B07C77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall prepare and transmit to the Congress a report containing the plan developed pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="H874BF666D2C345CEAF7C5AD8C7E868BF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Trade facilitation and capacity building</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall, in consultation with the Governments of eligible Pacific Islands countries, establish a trade facilitation and capacity building program for the Pacific Islands—</text><paragraph id="HC29E63560A114E02B2B69952D38190E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enhance the Governments of eligible Pacific Islands countries to support successful exporters and to build awareness among potential exporters in eligible Pacific Islands countries about opportunities abroad and ways to manage trade documentation and regulations in the United States and other countries, including through outreach to civil society organizations, indigenous groups, and trade associations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H266748B594FE4BA889F4C9757AB08FFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide export finance training for financial institutions in eligible Pacific Islands countries and the Governments of eligible Pacific Islands countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEED9101B75649918336751B36D244F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to assist the Governments of eligible Pacific Islands countries in maintaining publication of all trade regulations, forms for exporters and importers, tax and tariff rates, and other documentation relating to exporting goods on the internet and developing a robust public-private dialogue for eligible Pacific Islands countries to identify timelines for implementation of key reforms and solutions, as provided for under the Agreement on Trade Facilitation of the World Trade Organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86D52629F8424716AC5EA4A9F3CD3748"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to increase access to guides for importers and exporters on the internet, including rules and documentation for United States tariff preference programs.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4E9FB81DDDE146ADB2673289F52CB139"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall submit to Congress, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter through 2036, a comprehensive report on the trade and investment policy of the United States for the Pacific Islands, and on the implementation of this Act.</text></section><section id="HE473C7D33C63490C9CDB5FD6AFA32D26"><enum>8.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No duty-free treatment provided under this Act shall remain in effect after December 31, 2036.</text></section><section id="H4F9821711DD64D739E7DA99C4643D47A"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA83C00FFD40649DCBC744E2512BAD1EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>internationally recognized worker rights</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HB48FEB58E7364E89B2026E8292E80465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the right of association;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44F78E27BEBA45B6A831F78A9909B94E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the right to organize and bargain collectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D8BE963D5AB48A0A1275733AEBD5F7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a prohibition on the use of any form of forced or compulsory labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H448AC68766E84CECB765A2A42EC853BE" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a minimum age for the employment of children, and a prohibition on the <quote>worst forms of child labor</quote>, as defined in section 507(6) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2467">19 U.S.C. 2467(6)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F821046A6424B3F86D27C1669F78921"><enum>(E)</enum><text>acceptable conditions of work with respect to minimum wages, hours of work, and occupational safety and health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35552B5ABB134C50833DD22020FF9E62"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the elimination of discrimination with respect to employment and occupation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE88C0025347248F39862EC2139BAE730"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the elimination of violence or threats of violence against workers, including violence related to gender-based violence or harassment in the workplace and violence related to workers exercising or attempting to exercise any of the rights described in subparagraphs (A) through (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46505FCC93E942719F8AF6DEC7EE35F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <term>Pacific Islands</term>, <term>Pacific Islands country</term>, <term>country in the Pacific Islands</term>, and <term>countries in the Pacific Islands</term> means the Cook Islands, the Republic of Fiji, the Republic of Kiribati, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of Nauru, Niue, the Republic of Palau, the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the Independent State of Samoa, the Solomon Islands, the Kingdom of Tonga, Tuvalu, and the Republic of Vanuatu.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

