<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3942837A389348F5AF17F670F087686A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7126 IH: Securing Essential and Critical U.S. Resources and Elements Minerals Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7126</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Strategic Resilience Reserve of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H92C5F68394EC46A7BE804D778144C76D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H60AB15AD88B340F19BA9A3AB17E4FC73"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA7E9E2491A24DF696E77F0E2B074A4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Essential and Critical U.S. Resources and Elements Minerals Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SECURE Minerals Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BBE034F636B40B384635BCB700DBF86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H60AB15AD88B340F19BA9A3AB17E4FC73">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC6F15592B889431595A64E2857B7F06D">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H95580D53D206456BA38DE1F6507BFB7D">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="HB7EBB1D73FAB48D9AC71AF4089EE952D">TITLE I—Establishment and Board of Governors</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA87796586ECC49DBB660A370A8C79614">Sec. 101. Establishment.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H1EA32CA0CCA2469DBC94B4AD685AA53D">Sec. 102. Board of governors.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H4EA1C1B26D884103A102DE3F87E93543">TITLE II—Duties and authorities of the Reserve</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H1DDD6F555CB143F9854A14B3CDF991D1">Sec. 201. General authorities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HEEA75148BD1F411791E541BF9F665787">Sec. 202. Identification of eligible critical minerals and materials.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA0C7DB334EDB49A69B66C04EED7BC69B">Sec. 203. Data collection.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC562BADF12A34E8C9CC957F18ADB3E15">Sec. 204. Critical mineral and material market risk and vulnerability assessment.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H9366FC23DBB648A5BC4E2F82A4B46330">Sec. 205. Production standards.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H9273624AF44B411B9510985ABAA09D3E">Sec. 206. Financing and acquisition of critical minerals or materials.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H6AFA3968623348738FB0E25AF42AB098">Sec. 207. Sale of critical minerals or materials.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H1EC9737FF7604362970DA814E4946D38">TITLE III—Administrative provisions</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HFC8EB1414F684B869461F7A46B3F8A2C">Sec. 301. Corporate powers.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H958C2888C6FE41639B5BFB2D19DBBCD8">Sec. 302. Records and accounts.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H34EE0646D0554A24BDA8F94944C6D99B">TITLE IV—Oversight and accountability</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H60329E84737D41408D030E27E9577B06">Sec. 401. Risk and audit committees.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H43985669E65A4EF9B90C5DF2614CFDDB">Sec. 402. Annual audit and comptroller review.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H94758199DC9D45A68F6AD8FDD4205C47">Sec. 403. Reporting and transparency.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HC6F15592B889431595A64E2857B7F06D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HAFC4C01D320C4E0EA6569A66F2BACCB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">critical minerals and materials are essential to the ongoing economic and national security of the United States, playing a vital role in the manufacturing, transportation, medical, technology, defense, and energy sectors;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FA825A7E00E482190E28436DFBD9365"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the global demand for critical minerals and materials has been rapidly increasing due to advancements in technology, whether defense, dual-use, or commercial, and the increasing adoption of renewable energy sources and next-generation automotive systems, all of which rely heavily on critical minerals and materials for the production of batteries, solar panels, wind turbines, high-speed computing, advanced magnetic systems, and other high-tech applications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF950CC8B92E74FEDA7984B8D45804A4C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the People’s Republic of China—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10E738439B6C4B5E8C23A55D4FE4A918"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">currently controls a significant portion of the global supply chain for critical minerals and materials through extensive mining, integrated midstream operations, significant domestic subsidies and incentives, and strategic investments in resource-rich countries, dominating the global market infrastructure for critical minerals and materials and enhancing the ability of the People’s Republic of China to manipulate pricing to the detriment of competitors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF2C45C7698F430C8F33AB927FC82549"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">centrally controls its dominant market share across multiple critical mineral vertical markets, preventing fair competition and hindering the ability of United States firms and firms in partner countries to innovate and scale production;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6290A81540A475ABB818538DDD8765F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">predatorily leverages its position as sponsor or consumer, as applicable, over mining projects globally, resulting in a dearth of feedstocks to the great detriment of downstream industries, regions, and countries, including the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BD0C3A1F8994517A2B5B9F556834004"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the integrated operations of which are subservient to the Chinese state, is calibrated to weaponize its influence over prices and volumes in the contest for access to critical minerals and materials, as well as the end-use components and applications produced from critical minerals and materials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D196293453240D28DB60872327D8D69"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acts to undercut efforts in the United States and partner countries to develop alternative sources of supply;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28C9539BBBDB466B81A3A0B9BE53D167"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">producers of critical minerals and materials in the United States often face artificially low prices set by supply chains controlled by the People’s Republic of China, discouraging private investment in domestic extraction and processing;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5F87E0523FB41DC9AC9905F58E9D732"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the lack of transparent, competitive, and market-driven pricing mechanisms for critical minerals and materials outside of the People’s Republic of China compounds market problems, creating systemic risk and limiting the viability of an independent supply chain for critical minerals and materials in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A7FD169114D4572B39E99173947AC48"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States is heavily reliant on imports for many of the most critical minerals and materials, including rare earth elements, making the United States vulnerable to supply disruptions, geopolitical tensions, and economic manipulation by countries that dominate the market, specifically the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A0288BC7DA94DE990421D093EF53FA7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the vulnerabilities to the United States defense industrial base posed by reliance on imports of critical minerals and materials are significant, and given the long lead times for investments in both mining and processing of critical minerals, domestic critical minerals production projects are particularly susceptible to price shocks induced by the People’s Republic of China, which can depress critical mineral prices for an extended period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3415A89734ED4583A1763CA375CD9110"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing domestic primary feedstock production, processing, conversion, recycling, reuse, and repurposing to advanced materials and products, as well as increasing alternative market supply in partner countries, are imperative to reduce the impact of market manipulation by foreign state actors, such as the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73EC211E876141F885365BE3D3ADA065"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States must ensure that a stable and secure supply chain of essential resources is available to our domestic innovation and manufacturing ecosystems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD475B2FACFBA4B80BCCD2C631CC7DF70"><enum>(10)</enum><text>sustainable and responsible corporate behavior in the direct operations of companies and across their global value chains is important to ensuring a resilient domestic critical minerals supply;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD28DBBF0C2024EEE80DD05198DF377A0"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investments in domestic extraction and processing infrastructure, as well as reuse, repurposing, and recycling, are necessary to build a resilient and diversified supply chain for critical minerals and materials, supporting the economic growth and national security interests of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28898B6B39FD4890B36E40EC730637FB"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">government support to develop and ensure the integrity of Western and partner country markets for critical minerals and materials as a countermeasure against the anti-competitive tactics of the People’s Republic of China and the supply chain co-collaborators of the People’s Republic of China will fill the most acute strategic gap, which cannot be otherwise achieved by private industry participants acting alone.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H95580D53D206456BA38DE1F6507BFB7D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC89C9CA7C6D492D8C75E4F25733B75D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6A5B76E5990442E93251EDC112C0E86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC60ECD1CE404B47B3A9A82C3BA091D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB8A1C0BD30D42BF8D44FA3DF84F17C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F86E641773F4D2EBE50EAE1BA8F1BAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5036D143014642EB93429DDF82D531AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE5B3305518043F19459B2A1EE0EE8C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB281C6240E9D46A1B4243AAAAA738FA7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFA3BD6F9B2E45AB8C2AE84710327E5B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAC9B27B567947DBA0E8DA979B0BFCBB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1C978F8FB00473E935C3AB18AF486BD"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC8CCBD793624CA3A8AD00FBDE6218C1"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A5E569C3AC4481BA4F581DFF9DACCD5"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D6C6B5CA89D448EBE376603187355EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized intermediary</header><text>The term <term>authorized intermediary</term> means an entity that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H578E5B7211034CDDA7B765C6061AE883"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a private entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7575B6F6B9B43258E9992F5BFA67449"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has expertise in more than 1 critical mineral or material;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EFBD7626E29403DB40082A82E4D4F18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has expertise in commodities trading, market making, capital management, or finance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8086428324A44CDA9168364E1A2B33A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>does not have any management influenced by a foreign entity of concern or a citizen of a covered country, including any entities affiliated with the private entity or the ownership of the private entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD43705FC87624BEE8C360A50026512E7"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not owned, controlled, directed, financed, or otherwise influenced, directly or indirectly, in whole or in any part greater than 25 percent, by a foreign entity of concern, a citizen of a covered country, or the government of a covered country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35EEE187A0A34FD48F117469C3A8DCA6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>has been approved to be an authorized intermediary by the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55BA793C55464E9DA20134023EFDF7E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the board of governors of the Reserve established by section 102(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E306338D57B4EC79C979233B6B3D106"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The term <term>Chairperson</term> means the Chairperson of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H917FB4E7A8214FE4B812FCAF48B91682"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered country</header><text>The term <term>covered country</term> means a country that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H972D62B9420A4B289884099F85ADE9C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a covered nation (as defined in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB28D309D20544BFE989F8AD2A92114C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the Director of National Intelligence, determines to be engaged in conduct that is detrimental to the national security or foreign policy of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H030A237E313943DAAD60C12D532F23C9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Critical mineral or material</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral or material</term> means mineral or material included in the list of eligible critical minerals and materials established by the Reserve under section 202(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA20CD1DB0CC49569487E37E8E36A4A9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Dependence rate</header><text>The term <term>dependence rate</term> means the percentage of domestic end-use consumption of a critical mineral or material that is supplied by production by a foreign entity of concern or in a covered country, in aggregate.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6363C42D8AAF473BBC1EEC2D253D28DA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> means a foreign entity that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67B8FBC0D2314FB088C074BFA0BACAFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the requirements described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (D), or (E) of section 10638(3) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19237">42 U.S.C. 19237(3)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H35BC0CD72F1C48BCBCBDEF6250A8E89C"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6DE692636AF84CFE98FFAD0FD6158FFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is owned, controlled, directed, financed, or otherwise influenced, directly or indirectly, in whole or in any part greater than 25 percent, by the government of a foreign country that is a covered country; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H02C8186433C94996A740C57FC06B91BF" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is otherwise subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a government of a covered country.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB629FE71CEF147E6A4508AE00A940784"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Partner country</header><text>The term <term>partner country</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H510225714A254B1BAF16E3AD341BD6F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA376C980EF0F4876BCE1DB29DDE57021"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a country that has been designated as a major non-NATO ally under section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321k">22 U.S.C. 2321k</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A09093EC90944BB909EEF1D60A45865"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a foreign country, including any market or any producer in a foreign country—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75928CCCD2D64B93969D1D4FF7C4BCC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with which the United States has entered into a mutual defense treaty or other mutual defense agreement, but not including Venezuela;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62FF100BFED2403D925FD7509B43D34E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is recognized by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense as a strategic partner due to an established bilateral agreement that emphasizes mutual interests in security, defense, and critical mineral supply chains, including countries designated under United States strategic frameworks and agreements;</text></clause><clause id="H90E4E658AE424F029A1970AF7A24FDEE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with which the United States has entered into a comprehensive economic and trade agreement that includes provisions for the collaboration on critical mineral resources and to safeguard supply chains critical to national security and economic stability;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA84B5E9F26F409A93996977DB89FB50"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with which the United States Geological Survey has in effect a memorandum of understanding concerning scientific and technical cooperation in earth sciences, unless that country is a covered country; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57A64E134A6B4D27B81F0B22E4A0D9CB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>with which the Department of State, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, or the United States Trade and Development Agency is working to advance an active critical mineral project.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2160B4736C6E4CA2982D0FCF1E021CAA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Production rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>production rate</term> means the percentage of domestic end-use consumption of a critical mineral or material that is supplied by domestic and partner country production in aggregate.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD358B8DBBFDA4C77813A6D7D28118822"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Purposes of the Reserve</header><text>The term <term>purposes of the Reserve</term> means the purposes of the Reserve described in section 101(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC45130A0D9E445E1AF87368196C576B8"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Recycle</header><text>The term <term>recycle</term> means an action or process to convert a critical mineral or material contained within a finished or semi-finished product into a form suitable for repurposing or reuse of the critical mineral or material.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31E35874DC4240F2AA34A560E21B5BCB"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Repurpose</header><text>The term <term>repurpose</term> means any operation that results, in whole or in part, in a critical mineral or material being used for a different purpose or application than the purpose or application for which the critical mineral or material, or the product into which the critical mineral or material is manufactured into, was originally intended.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BA85C731E3147848801E5837DC0A61A"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Reserve</header><text>The term <term>Reserve</term> means the Strategic Resilience Reserve Corporation of the United States established by section 101(a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF870A6C67CF24B4881D6771DACA0A53F"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Reuse</header><text>The term <term>reuse</term> means the complete or partial direct reuse of a critical mineral or material after use for the original purposes for which the critical mineral or material was intended.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9CBAEA0E40241A7BC6CAB0975E4138E"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Vice-chairperson</header><text>The term <term>Vice-chairperson</term> means the Vice-chairperson of the Board.</text></paragraph></section><title id="HB7EBB1D73FAB48D9AC71AF4089EE952D" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Establishment and Board of Governors</header><section id="HA87796586ECC49DBB660A370A8C79614"><enum>101.</enum><header>Establishment</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51024E19AB284B2BA3AD73457E100EC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Entity formation</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF69C17D0DC974DD7957470F1800CD9C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a wholly owned government corporation, to be known as the <quote>Strategic Resilience Reserve Corporation of the United States</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3953D94BF2894F038ACB435702B85B74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 9101(3) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D82F3B334F045C3B71795442A56F18A"><subparagraph id="H7B6F7335A6034DE88C885672A67B05D2"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>the Strategic Resilience Reserve Corporation of the United States.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F4407A050AD421F8B9E5BD228F34EC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Reserve are—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB655A18F172847518CF5AD9AEB6BF38D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support a free, fair, and competitive market for critical minerals and materials in which domestic and partner country producers and processors can compete and innovate;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4486407BB8E443499AC61364472973C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support domestic and partner country production, extraction, processing, refining, reuse, repurposing, and recycling of, and capabilities and infrastructure with respect to, critical minerals and materials;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB2130F4D90242B88FD6CF6B7B514006"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support and protect stable and economically sustainable prices of critical minerals and materials, including price levels consistent with competitive market economies and reliable supply;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB127A1A6D043489C925096AE8E21CDAE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support responsible production of critical minerals and materials with respect to standards for transparency, environmental, and labor practices, and to ensure a competitive market for producers meeting those standards;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B6424214B46485DA7D15BD45675F85B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to assist in maintaining balanced and adequate supplies of critical minerals and materials to the United States, as determined by the Board;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE608DA98D0834216B42D05EE20FB7ED4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, to ensure that, at each stage of the supply chain—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2105E96B206E421C924A81CA0F9FB25A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the production rate of each critical mineral or material is equal to or greater than a percentage determined to be reasonable by the Board, in coordination with appropriate Federal agencies, but not less than 25 percent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1246BFE5F0A04440A2C5642E2121CE8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the dependence rate for each critical mineral or material is equal to or less than a percentage determined to be reasonable by the Board, in coordination with appropriate Federal agencies, but not less than 75 percent;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C15B147B06E46C69E3DE00A12434E66"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to prioritize—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2E493694A064D468F3B4AB19E99045A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">domestic projects and supply chains, including processing capacity, for critical minerals and materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D74BAF856EE43DFBCBCB0914F3FC110"><enum>(B)</enum><text>projects that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58626691F212451088AA8DC787631596"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recycle, reuse, or repurpose critical minerals or materials; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B47591160164710B472B352F0C7A088"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>extract or produce critical minerals or materials from mine or industrial waste, including mining tailings, industrial waste, or non-conventional waste streams; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55A9009901BE4C5EAAFDDFA4F2850889"><enum>(C)</enum><text>projects for critical minerals or materials the dependence rate of which is 100 percent; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H653C772D387C44E89E27E59738BE1D66"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to ensure the efficient use of government funds to support critical mineral and material projects and, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure fair returns to taxpayers and investments made by the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H089D51E6FB2B4D7B8D7F590AD9938BB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Reserve to carry out the requirements of this Act $2,500,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1EA32CA0CCA2469DBC94B4AD685AA53D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Board of governors</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84EB176C48094C498130BB9766678550"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EDE3DACB1B448B8B20B9B07F987D134"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appointment</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6EDD497BB074F7394FB1A79A02654AF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Reserve shall have a board of governors consisting of 7 voting members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA89D1CBBA374824AA8D213714BEE4ED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chairperson and Vice-chairperson</header><text>The President shall designate, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25BEFA0942CB4D7D8192C059CB3EC3B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 member of the Board to serve as Chairperson, for a term of 4 years; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24738F4D50FD460794CB274598D04F2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 member of the Board to serve as Vice-chairperson, for a term of 4 years, and who shall serve as Chairperson in the absence or vacancy of the Chairperson.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF175D5CDAF142F4A6A03674D3E63ED5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Initial appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall appoint each of the 7 members of the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CB20146CAF443F6B008EFE841046E70"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The President shall carry out this paragraph with due regard for a fair representation of Tribal, labor, environmental, industrial, and commercial interests.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9674F82C8184049AF78323BFB383374"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>To be eligible to be appointed as a member of the Board under paragraph (1), an individual—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7C29AE61D7648AE8EDC91DA378C7252"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall have significant demonstrated expertise in—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE1035287B7D41A0B4C14A3C9F0ED69A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the business of commodities production, storage, or trade, or the financial sector as it relates to critical minerals or materials;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C0CDBEF60084268B6617D2E3B8265DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the financing, development, or operation of projects related to the manufacturing and commercialization of critical minerals or materials;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A697EA850504E08862C5A80862D8479"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demand for, and usage of, critical minerals or materials, including future demand or usage of critical minerals or materials for national security and economic purposes;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA05AA25426B44448D63FE4DDE7035D0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recycling, repurposing, or reuse of critical minerals; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8B422120FD44B01925950768FD76464"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other experience related to the production and usage of critical minerals and materials, including expertise in sustainable and responsible production practices, in the fields of engineering, logistics, law, academia, research, or policy; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4129C1C14C84527B5078AB6CDC74926"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF22627EB33484BCCB08C0C7E4D55028D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have a direct, or closely indirect, financial interest in an entity directly involved in the commodities industry or financial sector as it relates to critical minerals or materials; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1A595FEE8B24948AF4451EB477472E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have immediate family with a direct financial interest in an entity directly described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF15DC5527A7C4E6A9216B3911E9B4D27"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21939E92F9EB4AEBABBEFFA4EDD58EC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, each member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 14 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CC9D0066F314F0D92791B41745FB032"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial staggered terms</header><text>Of the members first appointed to the Board—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07D96754CBBC4E38A1D9FF8BF1DF066E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 member each shall be appointed to a term expiring in calendar year 2028, 2030, 2032, 2034, 2036, 2038, and 2040, respectively; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C3FF1FB6D474222BC1730B856DA2A4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each term shall expire on January 31 of the applicable calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4D2DA0CD9494E88AB45E117B9B99B17"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which a vacancy occurs on the Board before the expiration of the term for that member, the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint a new member of the Board to fill the vacancy and serve the remainder of that term.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H104B664C11794A55B5BB8FE9AB3C7C9D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Completion of term</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6360060AE56441B19A7B69F5035E976A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On expiration of a term for a Board member, the applicable Board member may continue to serve for 1 year or until a successor is appointed pursuant to this subsection, whichever is less.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CE1395007144A7B8DBDDA68CE8B533D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chairperson and Vice-chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is appointed to serve a term as the Chairperson or Vice-chairperson under paragraph (1)(B) shall, after such term ends—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94CDA2C276D5490DB24ED67A9D0F44E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as the Chairperson or Vice-chairperson, respectively, until a successor is appointed pursuant to this subsection; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0DB118842B948B8BA5ACE8513A9A62B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as a member of the Board for the remainder of the term of such individual in accordance with this paragraph.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H076356F0C2E740549BF452CC69B4FBB2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Each member of the Board shall be compensated at a rate equal to the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF08E7EAF885D49838AC9D035145E503B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5140AEE7E98E40559D1055AE43B985D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date on which the term of a member of the Board begins and ending on the date that is 2 years after the date on which the term of that member ends, the member may not hold any direct, or closely indirect, financial interest in, or hold any office, position, including in an advisory or consultant position, or other employment in or with, any entity receiving or pursuing financial support from the Reserve.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93208008D9F5486A8386C9C477F0892C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Opportunity to cure violation</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AEB033FCB664265B759BA984655D8AC"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>If the Comptroller General of the United States finds that an individual described in subparagraph (A) is in violation of that subparagraph, that individual shall cure the applicable violation by not later than 30 days after the date on which the violation is found.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H445E1F517ECE499F93473BEF31717485"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements to cure</header><text>To cure a violation of subparagraph (A), as required by clause (i), the applicable individual shall, at a minimum—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB62924378C7448B2A972C0C919C41085"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">renounce any pecuniary gain associated with the violation; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8588DC13CE140548BE42C82B1C31017"><enum>(II)</enum><text>terminate each relationship that is the subject of the violation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39CE396FFFF6402F84C196907619A51C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Penalty for uncured violation</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA20D2215343F41C98ED096541E5BA9F1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Comptroller General of the United States finds that an individual described in subparagraph (A) is in violation of that subparagraph and does not cure the violation in accordance with subparagraph (B) by the date described in clause (i) of that subparagraph or, as applicable, by the date established by the Board under subparagraph (D), that individual shall be removed from the Board.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C15BF9FE1964811A7B2459851630377"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicability of criminal liability</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H588E62BE21BC4947B228E469470F670F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Board shall be considered to be an officer or employee of the Executive Branch for purposes of section 207(a) of title 18, United States Code, and shall be subject to paragraph (2) of that section.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3D4A8A41E8D4951988F6D9117E19FA3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>If the Comptroller General of the United States makes a finding described in clause (i) with respect to an individual described in that clause, the Comptroller General of the United States may refer the matter to the Attorney General.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBFFC14F843E462E936DF3A231588EAD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Extension of cure period</header><text>The Board—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27C38360C93F4F8196C75C36C7097DBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may extend the time period provided under subparagraph (B)(i) for an individual described in subparagraph (A) to cure a violation of that subparagraph by not more than 90 days; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8328282E50C946ED88047D33794584F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall document the rationale behind any extension granted under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37083488C99749999113B34F91A4EFDE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph 5(C)(i), a member of the Board, Chairperson, and Vice-chairperson may not be removed from office except by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52F9BB47E03D4F74AE4567FAA5D82D31"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impeachment by Congress; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C95F44810C74C85A9336D7D31725B78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the action of the President for inefficiency, neglect of duty, malfeasance in office, or incapacity to perform the applicable duties described in this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1722DB9C6067423EABC0436F22E7B51C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF43E25BE391C458BBA2C90680A533668"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Open to the public; notice</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), all meetings of the Board shall be—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3497056159AD4070AB07B63237C870B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>open to the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB40AD828ED94904BA30AF68EF86470B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preceded by reasonable public notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2823C2BDFA7548B4A6EE6706CF5D6E27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Board shall meet—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34DC4907F6344098B90B4E456B779793"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date on which all members of the Board are first appointed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE336A5FB12B14AB38538C9CF3FFAE3A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less frequently than quarterly after the date described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD341AE57809B4193A48859DDB66512FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at the call of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H347E012E8F9841DBB30F0FECE689C3B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Chairperson; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34FFF3FB113F467E90CA1B869663FCE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>4 or more members of the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6744EB2674614CD2A81102FE22E03F8F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Closed meetings</header><text>The Board, by majority vote of the members, may close a meeting to the public if, during the meeting, there is likely to be disclosed proprietary or sensitive information regarding a project under consideration for assistance under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2263BF16FFDC468FBB3E2A2755860F54"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minutes</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H434BF847FEAD4D57A1982EF6962D900D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the minutes of each meeting of the Board shall be made publicly available as soon as practicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14ED2ABD0CCC4F0E8F42B1DD2B03F6BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Closed meeting minutes</header><text>The minutes for a closed meeting shall be made available—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H981AF53535E145BD9E359F4072DBBBA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 60 days after the date of the closed meeting; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8C6F0989456418AA44C4C1542C833DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the public not later than 3 years after the date of the closed meeting, with any necessary redactions to protect information that remains proprietary or sensitive at the time of publication.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H508BEB64306E4C0E939BE62937DF250D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exemptions from public transparency requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The closed meetings and minutes under this subsection shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C73FC4BA9F241CAB675B2A99E69E167"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be exempt from disclosure under—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C5A2CFDDABC4B8286EDB6D8D69C3513"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>), pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of that section; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2BB86AEA8594C6EAAA0BF616BE84168"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any provision of State, Tribal, or local freedom of information law, open government law, open meetings law, open records law, sunshine law, or similar law requiring disclosure of information or records; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8173AF00658C45DFA6E05E407F637041"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not be subject to section 552b of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Government in the Sunshine Act</quote>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36646EDD4E0543C7A6E3E7F0519C7268"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>5 members of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6D6FE3878E14054B70C1360FAE9DFE2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Voting</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49CB68F8C06446E7ACF4A30659A4C2B0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Board shall have an equal vote in all decisions of the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1143DB642244652984E1E78909BEB81"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Decisions</header><text>Unless otherwise specified, decisions of the Board shall be made by majority vote of the members constituting a quorum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEEBD214A46C47198E191A43B8A34AFD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Powers and duties of the Board</header><text>The Board shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EEC771A75E943849083DB4E19AE66EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date on which all members of the Board are appointed—</text><subparagraph id="H773EDD8B61F5436BA0F5E1545327F670"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and approve the bylaws of the Reserve, including bylaws for the regulation of the affairs and conduct of the business of the Reserve, consistent with the purpose, goals, objectives, and policies of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC52C2243A51E49A8B9708EBC4C27DABF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish dollar-value thresholds, not to exceed $2,500,000, above which transactions and loans made by the Reserve will require approval of the Board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H507D0592AF7A46A6AD26473E13A092E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish committees required by this Act composed solely of members of the Board, as the Board determines to be appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6004640EED85441E96161ECAD86EECC6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>develop and approve a conflict-of-interest policy for the Board and employees of the Reserve, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3574D1A9F2C64D399EA3CA5CDA6D80AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing compensation levels for employees of the Reserve, not to exceed $150,000 initially (but which may be adjusted for inflation), above which employees of the Reserve shall be limited with regard to future employment at and compensation from entities receiving financial support from the Reserve, for a period not to exceed the date that is 2 years after the date on which employment with the Reserve ends; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B18F7668A334AB98DA3BCF84565D001"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishing penalties for violations, including monetary penalties, that, for violations of the limitations described in clause (i), may be based on the higher of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD859FBDED4D3468BAE5C881C9FEC7FE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current compensation of the employee; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBA466F63C1E495FB7C4FBAC03284E5E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total compensation from entities receiving financial support from the Reserve;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75358530AF9040BDAAEB2E04A7743273"><enum>(E)</enum><text>approve or disapprove internal policies that the Chairperson shall submit to the Board, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB26BEC9F7E1437280ADD980691CD10D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>policies and procedures regarding the approval of authorized intermediaries;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D16ED3B698F4700913458DEEA951487"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policies and procedures regarding the project application and approval process;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C8DFF31525E42A88AB780287C659AEA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policies and procedures regarding the acquisition and sale of critical minerals and materials sufficient to ensure fair access to transactions with the Reserve and effective use of capital of the Reserve;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H852C8E64259E497DBF91627E209967D0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policies and procedures regarding financing, acquisition, and sale to raise global production standards for critical minerals and materials that minimize environmental damage, prevent forced labor use, and ensure a more competitive market for producers in countries with stronger standards; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H392659828C0440B69AFD7F17F84B7060"><enum>(v)</enum><text>operational guidelines; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H925E29BEF8DE4E54BA1785F77B89FF08"><enum>(F)</enum><text>approve or disapprove a 1-year business plan and budget for the Reserve;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H819E590C06784EDB82330BBF20B9CFF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the Reserve is operated in a manner that is consistent with this Act by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC4ED5B81F7E41DFA1347123906AEC53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitoring and assessing the effectiveness of the Reserve in achieving the purposes of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD594A3049744E37AAE5D0D1B4CBEA52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reviewing and approving internal policies, annual business plans, annual budgets, and long-term strategies submitted by the Chairperson;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51D8C9CBFDF5476F83B5F085301A9425"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reviewing and approving annual reports submitted by the Chairperson;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C866D056A7F453782E1D73AD6B696CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>engaging 1 or more external auditors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7F37D7747FF4D699F13CA461C824FF6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reviewing and approving all changes to the organization of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EE599F1B8354AA88B86E1214207E31D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>appoint and fix, by a vote of not fewer than 5 of the 7 members of the Board, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, the compensation and adjustments to compensation of all personnel of the Reserve, subject to the condition that in appointing and fixing any compensation or adjustments to compensation under this paragraph, the Board shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA052FCAE4784120B4140603E29ADF66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with, and seek to maintain comparability with, other comparable Federal personnel, as the Board may determine to be appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF27AEDE80B98482789FBD0421F12164A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with the Office of Personnel Management; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA45537BB8BF646E6A2344B31A6A8C272"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carry out those duties consistent with merit principles, where applicable, as well as the education, experience, level of responsibility, geographic differences, comparability to private sector positions, and retention and recruitment needs of the Reserve in determining compensation of personnel;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAA9C752A4684E2987F0C6091B7D6854"><enum>(4)</enum><text>approve by a vote of not fewer than 5 of the 7 members of the Board—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEEB0A63519C4190894EF1CADA1E3559"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any changes to the bylaws or internal policies of the Reserve; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FF139550D794E3CA30055C448EBD891"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any equity investments and accompanying documentation made under section 206(b)(4);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37E9850A27BE48B48605D5D9BAF84A16"><enum>(5)</enum><text>have the authority and responsibility—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB25B842E81874CA5A24C3EB6512FF349"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to oversee entering into and carrying out contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other transactions as are necessary to carry out this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H944B7C43D9A64B9ABEF3968D627467FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to approve of the acquisition, lease, pledge, exchange, and disposal of real and personal property by the Reserve and otherwise approve the exercise by the Reserve of all of the usual incidents of ownership of property, to the extent that the exercise of those powers is appropriate to and consistent with the purposes of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0550983FCAC34379987890607D264B08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to determine the character of, and the necessity for, the obligations and expenditures of the Reserve, and the manner in which the obligations and expenditures will be incurred, allowed, and paid, subject to this Act and Federal law specifically applicable to wholly owned government corporations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA929D005BDFA4432BAE9D18B4410B62E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to execute or approve, in accordance with applicable bylaws and regulations, appropriate financial instruments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H395F0C706D354F23926DD246BD3B3024"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to approve other forms of credit enhancement that the Reserve may provide to projects, subject to the condition that the forms of credit enhancements shall be consistent with the purposes of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47E17C2794DB4931ACE854C3E69C3DC8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to exercise all other lawful powers that are necessary or appropriate to carry out, and are consistent with, the purposes of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H422A8C2A38C943EBABF28AE3A6BE80E6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to sue or be sued in the corporate capacity of the Reserve in any court of competent jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE55761AF4A574DB58C96DA25BFA6AE23"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to indemnify and hold harmless the members of the Board for any liabilities arising out of the actions of the members acting in that capacity, in accordance with, and subject to the limitations under, this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83CAD5AF576E483A9A5BF395A98577D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to enter into binding commitments, as specified in approved financial assistance packages; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7184BB760581499A970127526058B296"><enum>(J)</enum><text>to determine whether—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64234513F9404EF192C78E64484B891A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to obtain a lien on the assets of an entity that receives assistance under this Act; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06A647B745714AFE86B6678AE84B6328"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to subordinate a lien under clause (i) to any other lien securing project obligations; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD807342810F44250ADB4D9657DBA2C31"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establish the risk and audit committees described in section 401.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H4EA1C1B26D884103A102DE3F87E93543" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Duties and authorities of the Reserve</header><section id="H1DDD6F555CB143F9854A14B3CDF991D1"><enum>201.</enum><header>General authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the extent necessary to develop, operate, or maintain the Reserve, the Reserve may—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B744F2DFB0A4750B63BA87F7FECD3DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue rules, regulations, or orders;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA091832D7C44B3F9BFC7EA560BAD1FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acquire by purchase land or interests in land for the location of storage and related facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF10E8E2B0E76464BA0322930B5ADF34C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>construct, purchase, lease, or otherwise acquire storage and related facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFE28644E22B412BBB58C694AA67E3A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>use, lease, maintain, sell, or otherwise dispose of land or interests in land, or of storage and related facilities acquired under this Act, under such terms and conditions as the Board considers necessary or appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF48C19F0D1346A9AB2BCB2F992AC569"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acquire, subject to the requirements of this Act, by purchase, exchange, or otherwise, critical minerals or materials for storage;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A52E93CC8D349F080A2F57369E169DE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>store critical minerals or materials in storage facilities owned and controlled by the United States or in storage facilities owned by authorized intermediaries if the Reserve has sufficient contractual certainty of access to the critical minerals and materials and those facilities are subject to audit by the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6E39075B3F941C68E7B21BEA56FA5F7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">execute contracts with private entities for the storage of critical minerals and materials at storage facilities owned by private entities if the Reserve has sufficient contractual certainty of access to those critical minerals and materials and those facilities are subject to audit by the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FDD4E2C9AA84BCE83FB48265DD5E140"><enum>(8)</enum><text>partner with private sector, academia, and Federal agencies to further the purposes of the Reserve, including to advance the development and commercialization of responsible reuse and recycling processes for critical minerals and materials; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE6AA3205EE5467AAE083D3087B733CF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>execute any contracts necessary to develop, operate, or maintain the Reserve.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEA75148BD1F411791E541BF9F665787"><enum>202.</enum><header>Identification of eligible critical minerals and materials</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39688BEB51184DE9AB8E2D17728F385E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligible critical minerals and materials list</header><text>Subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Reserve, in consultation with the heads of Federal departments and agencies described in section 203(6), shall establish, and thereafter maintain, a list of critical minerals and materials eligible for financing or acquisition support described in section 206.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2948EE7D1164E139384D7A01545FE49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDF10261A2A44D12B686FC76AA027DA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mineral or material may only be included on the list of eligible critical minerals and materials established under subsection (a) if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EA17F9422FD4951B53570CFA73B7CE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mineral or material is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H996F278B26754145B5AF7411DD5B5B6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">included on the list of critical minerals published by the United States Geological Survey pursuant to section 7002(c) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEF8400550134372A3401DBCEBEC729B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>included on the list of critical materials published by the Department of Energy pursuant to section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H674FBD82CB8846C8A35F543B0072D37A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a material of interest designated by the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70862A31B6384BDD8E2467EEBCE3BEDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Reserve determines that the mineral or material—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19F2907B15C644CBBDADD27EA3E5E853"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a non-fuel mineral or material;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88DFF18E5920425DA2277F400EF778E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a vulnerable or highly concentrated supply chain; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5D476B70439424B88ECA2D4863A4FC1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is necessary—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5A413A9CE6E4547BDE9BB878770A88D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for the national defense and national security requirements of the United States;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F051D5A0682470EAA13B9EAC8816FA3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for the energy infrastructure of the United States, including—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F73FA22048B4F0CAC36AC85167D3DFE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>pipelines;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F63E6454E7144E198C7B145AD72BB20"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>refining capacity;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD32D40B91AF473F8FCF2D3D8E8A3278"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>electrical power generation, storage, transmission, and distribution;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE6FE387641B44E7B366AB77CF6303B7"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>renewable energy production; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H573DB040A7E643CD888E7870705AD2A1"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>energy storage;</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58D3DA2EF6184F48AB44EF708E6C93EE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to support domestic manufacturing, agriculture, housing, telecommunications, health care, or transportation and transportation infrastructure; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47E76AB0051747339731D4D5E43E68B1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>for the economic security of the United States.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4E34A90C0AB433DAC73A3896D4353C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modifications</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E6A48D9700A44439C70BCD5D51D286A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Additions</header><text>After the list of eligible critical minerals and materials is established under paragraph (1), the Reserve may add a mineral or material to the list of eligible critical minerals and materials maintained under subsection (a) if, after the date that the most recent list is published under subsection (e)(1)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CEB60211E13478AA7326713604B1D49"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mineral or material—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DC097E10F734989BBCE859ED43D2ED5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is included on the most recently published list of critical minerals published by the United States Geological Survey pursuant to section 7002(c) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H614BAA8097FE4A7BBFF1CCFAD6EC9B06"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is included on the most recently published list of critical materials published by the Department of Energy pursuant to section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E882D43350A4C95A09765A27D09EFE1"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a material of interest designated by the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30E8E5641E834D01A22402EB2F80A2E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Reserve determines that the mineral or material meets the requirements described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2644F87C85FB4747A4DD2494E4B7F80E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the list of eligible critical minerals and materials is established under paragraph (1), the Reserve shall remove a mineral or material from the list of eligible critical minerals and materials maintained under subsection (a) if—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H550D5352557944349EF7376FFA423268"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the mineral or material, as of the date on which the list is published under subsection (e)(1)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57663BE7966B42BCA8A2FE4A340EDEBA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not been included on a list of critical minerals published by the United States Geological Survey pursuant to section 7002(c) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)</external-xref>) for a period of at least 3 years;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A08837D199D4AD7B677898243E35749"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has not been included on a list of critical materials published by the Department of Energy pursuant to section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>) for a period of at least 3 years; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC50270488D64487AE346BC02647D1FD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has not been designated as a material of interest by the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency for a period of at least 3 years; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7C0EC0B6B5D46908996D7C4BC40FA38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Reserve determines that the mineral or material no longer meets the requirements described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H05078ECC7194459791731ED06ED6C488"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In establishing and maintaining the list of eligible critical minerals and materials under subsection (a), the Reserve shall consider—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5ABFB2CE775F4E0DA56C89DAA7D33107"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of any assessments conducted under sections 204 and 205;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF9C344FA36A4A53A90FB363941CF88B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the existing market infrastructure and financial environment for a given critical mineral or material, especially domestically or in partner countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H637ABF421B4C43EAB4FA37ECC4C4613D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the substitutability of, and projected demand for, a given critical mineral or material; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7287F1FF98A246D1BF287462E17BE53D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other information the Reserve determines necessary to achieve the purposes of the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F10444A357D4373BA4FB7C2DAD3E0F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>A mineral or material may not be included on the list of eligible critical minerals and materials established and maintained under subsection (a) if the mineral or material is—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CA8C6F81A2940A7AB72C46AC441C00B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oil, oil shale, natural gas, coal, or uranium;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H124A03F966584666A09B4C7F7BC4EC56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>water, ice, or snow; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96962A0E43F44C3D9C231D7569AD852D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a common variety, as determined by the Board, of sand, gravel, stone, pumice, cinders, or clay.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EFC21C4DF8E4CCD956421C49C7A26EA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Update</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58FA3810E4D445BD85C886E862A1A31C"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Reserve shall publish and update not less frequently than annually the list of eligible critical minerals and materials established and maintained under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B396512FB224F349CA0078A35CAD3C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Reserve shall separately publish a list of minerals and materials—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1F6E1BF11E44C169EFE0B4167F75E12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>previously included on a list published under paragraph (1) but were removed within the previous 3 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB7B2E2401144F40AD51CA500A091877"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not included in the list published under paragraph (1) but with respect to which the Reserve has an active position, contract, or transaction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0C7DB334EDB49A69B66C04EED7BC69B"><enum>203.</enum><header>Data collection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established within the Reserve a division, to be known as the <quote>Division of Data Collection</quote>, which, to the extent practicable, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82D8D8B6F24B40299AC19083F7B3C8EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be led by a Director selected by the Board;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B7F44583F2541A9BF6BF62056DE39AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and maintain a proprietary dataset sufficient to ensure the thorough analysis of global critical minerals and materials markets;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4BB6D97BFAA42638C32E4D53BEF4E0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect and maintain sufficient datasets, including data comprising global, domestic, and partner country markets and, to the extent possible, data derived from individual critical mineral and material projects, to inform and estimate—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16793697E4CE48A4B1E44ADE98D2FF07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>production, extraction, infrastructure, repurposing, and recycling costs for critical minerals and materials supply chains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA5C8C0259244167907F8E66E2F30D4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collection and recycling rates for critical minerals and materials in domestic and partner country markets; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38C4124896F843E29600A1E03C47288F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the forecast of supply and demand of critical minerals and materials within domestic and partner country markets;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE55AB78256F8412EAEA800C664E9EB0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>collect and maintain—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F61637B8558471095A35C1EFD3AB2DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actual transaction price data for critical minerals and materials in the global market, including geographic data; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H463ADF4B1D9B4656A763DBC5812631B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other datasets necessary to effectuate such purpose, including modeled transaction data and datasets produced by or derivative of datasets produced by the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H884FD98E77474CB38DCC57574A188C0D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>using the most current data collected under paragraphs (3) and (4), support the activities described in sections 204 and 206;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B5DEC52AF124F2B81C5E8800C055457"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consult with relevant heads of Federal departments and agencies, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E2760B6803E419BAB24DDB0F0D2C6FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31FCD8899BE445A49AC77203DF74211D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7B0A995398A4B05BD5944214D4620FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9020ADFE54274DB3B91ECCBED4AD05E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C9676B79F6D4EE080170EE1B1ECEB0F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDCFD2080FB14413BE2BE15FC9F73CF8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Secretary of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H893FCFF27B8B4E5885643389C30D4E2A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E5C5EC9845942669CEEB36EACA91AC0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDF600A9DFEC467FA8EF066953828F05"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10458B123F714C129BD9308E15C79781"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Geological Survey;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA01977ABE1E04E11ACD84E5C3D89E1BB"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02605FC8D0914F39A20B1F03346B2A26"><enum>(L)</enum><text>any other Federal department or agency head the Director determines necessary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H940B84EF82744352AE6E2315F8220C82"><enum>(7)</enum><text>establish mechanisms when establishing loan terms, contracts, and agreements as described in this Act to collect the necessary data required by this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB50E5947CD294F84B4FF687A11DBE64B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, carry out the responsibilities of this section using existing government data and information.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC562BADF12A34E8C9CC957F18ADB3E15"><enum>204.</enum><header>Critical mineral and material market risk and vulnerability assessment</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H732F7D3D9B364F12B978F0E9E6422A21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Reserve a division, to be known as the <quote>Division of Risk and Vulnerability Evaluation</quote>, which shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1080C83163234FC0A1CB5652D22E3436"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be led by a Director selected by the Board;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE857CC4DCBEA47D29AABA382B3C534FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop or, to the extent practicable, use existing sophisticated models to evaluate threats and risks in critical mineral and material markets across United States industrial sectors, including defense, energy, agriculture, transportation, health, and emerging technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E2C41B0A54A49DCA7DFC6C41E17A557"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintain a comprehensive database of critical mineral and material price movements, supply chain vulnerabilities, production and processing capacities, and consumption patterns;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AF223E4D00D435CBF92C341138B194E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify critical dependencies in critical mineral and material markets that could threaten national security or economic stability;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5AB8305FC454D08977FBAFF1CE2AB1A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess the potential for geopolitical events, natural disasters, technological disruptions, or market failures to impact commodity markets;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8391034AEBF42EFA631A15D421A17F1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop and implement methodologies for modeling the impact of various critical mineral or material shocks on the United States economy;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H772418171B4B4508971219BD737347B4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>assess vulnerabilities, including price spikes, supply disruptions, transportation failures, export controls, and financial market disturbances;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C898BCBE4CD4B76A8C5EE79EE7414E8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>model the cross-sectoral impacts of critical mineral or material price or supply shocks, including effects on inflation, employment, government finances, and consumer welfare;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE77761E87A9040CBB8C1DAC0A52046AE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>assess the specific impact of critical mineral or material disruptions on infrastructure, national security assets, and essential services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3F7F4B4A4BA4BB8B35B647680A7E0BF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, carry out the responsibilities of this section using existing government data and information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE798D8D2E8AA42C7A17C7E8EFBCE018A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandatory risk assessment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B70D5DCD19F4B2389C551DA13542BBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Reserve shall conduct and submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the President, and the heads of Federal departments and agencies listed in section 203(6) a biennial comprehensive risk and vulnerability assessment for critical minerals and materials, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H26D6516964B54E1D9B2FB647AD22AD35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identification of specific threats to stable supply and prices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA77FDEBC6AD043A3ABAAB3D9E7198C0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of current market conditions, including geographic and ownership concentration of suppliers, transportation bottlenecks, and financial vulnerabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F2318597E094C72B60CD794EEA347D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of substitution possibilities and technological alternatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA00166E687DA43948785ADB21561C9D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for risk mitigation strategies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6144A1D5096B47E496C071DA64D80CB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of assessment</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB19BF74D8D42461392E730B62F6FC343"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each assessment required by paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H87BD6F1EA8534C61B6BEFCDEE8B77BF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be submitted in unclassified form; but</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H289CB358AF634FD6B4AE224C92818C7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include a classified annex.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3F9D079A8EC414EB530CD772064FE1A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any assessments required by paragraph (1) that include a classified annex shall include an unclassified summary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9366FC23DBB648A5BC4E2F82A4B46330"><enum>205.</enum><header>Production standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established within the Reserve a division, to be known as the <quote>Division of Production Standards</quote>, which shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H648F6D6BCF8E49B4A0261F0D5DBAC891"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be led by a Director selected by the Board;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F9A4AB4543248639DA845321D8ACC1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop methodologies for evaluating relative risk in global environmental and labor standards and practices for the production, extraction, processing, reuse, repurposing, and recycling of critical minerals and materials, including transparency, traceability, and forced labor risk, which may include incorporating existing research;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D3DCCD8A6E240EF8B4218556CBBC671"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct periodic risk-based assessments of environmental and labor standards and practices for the production, extraction, processing, reuse, repurposing, and recycling of critical minerals and materials in foreign countries producing critical minerals and materials, and, to the extent practicable, significant production projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF96B996D0654AC0ADA348E9E457AB21"><enum>(4)</enum><text>publish an annual report summarizing the methodologies used and describing the results of the most recent assessments conducted under paragraph (3) for each foreign country and significant production project, and, to the extent practicable, mitigation measures used in transactions and loans made by the Reserve, without identifying proprietary or sensitive commercial information.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H9273624AF44B411B9510985ABAA09D3E"><enum>206.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Financing and acquisition of critical minerals or materials</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC8CAEAD57F44D68A98E528C0BD73DE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCBB80657BAE48B09F9C90DEFB64BC68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Reserve may deploy financing and acquisition tools as described in subsection (b) to achieve the purposes of the Reserve, subject to the condition that the Reserve may not deploy such tools to benefit a foreign entity of concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8DBD49528B747C2915E00CA2B0C653B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Reserve shall consider—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H231D265644BA47A0A542618B38810E3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of the assessments described in section 205(3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H862EC7C6E9AB445F86F19819D72B1587"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of the Reserve to efficiently achieve the purposes of the Reserve with limited resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06AD4CAB1CD2498FAAC5B28BEF0ED2C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>diversification across critical minerals and materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H074EC1929EDB4ACD9F5D787015F20D8A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>non-Reserve investments and market developments regarding a specific critical mineral or material;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D52D5C93A7E441680324461AD4E63CC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to deploying financing and acquisition tools with a specific producer or processor, the management, financial condition, and ability of the producer or processor to fulfill any contractual obligations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0257CB788FA41F4B7D44E7BD2F784A4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other factors the Reserve determines valuable to achieving the purposes of the Reserve over an extended period of time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C58CAB821504932893D2836A0103EAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal Government Investments</header><text>The Reserve shall, to the maximum extent practicable in carrying out this section, consult, coordinate, and leverage existing Federal Government investments, including by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B02829A682C4C5FA6A9F9B39D1C2A49"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Export-Import Bank of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B9190C9A7A644AA93BF6B3032179837"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9D83B7CA707418686E73C517FC19341"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Energy, pursuant to title XVII of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16511">42 U.S.C. 16511 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30FAC02FFBDF48CEA149D252521405CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of Strategic Capital of the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A756C84784648AC8682C11EF1ED6B86"><enum>(E)</enum><text>applicable execution offices of the Department of Defense for contract actions carried out under title III of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4531">50 U.S.C. 4531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74936751448E4D6CA9A72B9AE5352752"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Means of support</header><text>The financing and acquisition tools referred to in subsection (a) include the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0FA4321F0164DDD8D526FBED682EE72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Loans to authorized intermediaries</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H471137C7D51D4653AFE7988BA4273567"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Loan program authorized</header><text>The Reserve may make loans to authorized intermediaries who may use those funds to enter into financing and purchasing agreements with producers and processors of critical minerals or materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F50E8BD0A154B0AAC0FA6C427428563"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Loan conditions</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB78FED49E684754B91F6A18E665B0DD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making loans under subparagraph (A), the Reserve shall establish such terms and conditions as the Reserve determines appropriate to achieve the purposes of the Reserve.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAAACE6E589548309BF47F9105C57B79"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjustment of loan terms</header><text>The Reserve and an authorized intermediary may adjust loan terms under a loan issued under subparagraph (A) if the Reserve and that authorized intermediary agree to the adjustment.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E3D71C37B654F7C91DDCE1668C0F679"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Preferential terms for certain loans</header><text>In making loans under subparagraph (A), the Reserve—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H448EF735FBB741248E84E70A0738293E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may provide preferential loan terms—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H423F7DE95EFC40ACB11F52B569BB25D8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which may include an interest rate equal to the Federal funds rate, to an authorized intermediary that will use the loan to enter into financing and purchasing agreements with producers or processors of critical minerals or materials; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7459E3C2D5C4EBC9D2C656231BDBC19"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to authorized intermediaries that will use the loan to enter into financing and purchasing agreements with producers or processors of critical minerals or materials in partner countries, in such manner as the Reserve determines appropriate; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFD6D7538A204DB99EB86BA8787D1719"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCA27C0F9E1E44C69E3BC338099FED79"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the heads of Federal departments and agencies described in section 203(5) with respect to the loan terms described in subclause (I)(aa); and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF59051AAD8D44589A950ED47ECEF70D3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>ensure that, under the terms of such loans, authorized intermediaries shall, to the maximum extent practicable, give priority to United States suppliers of critical minerals and materials and preference to the United States supply chain.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32D1824FB7BA47A7A3C533A7EAC7240D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Proposal solicitation</header><text>To be eligible to receive a loan under subparagraph (A), an authorized intermediary shall submit to the Reserve an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Reserve may require, including the proposed financing or purchasing agreements described in that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC235C4EC2CCF471AAE9DFF38B84CCDBD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Uncured default</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C7D363D044A4CC09257B144D15E8827"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an authorized intermediary fails to make a required repayment on a loan under subparagraph (A) for a 90-day period, the Reserve may—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05356C6F96E943B8A076FDF0AFDD943D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>recoup the amount of that loan by taking possession of the critical mineral and material inventories of the authorized intermediary and any other contractual rights of the authorized intermediary to receive critical minerals or materials from suppliers;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9962234E042E4C6E9E6330F9A6385266"><enum>(II)</enum><text>revoke the participation with the Reserve of the authorized intermediary;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38B9CA6A149E485FBB60350AF8988AD8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>subject to clause (ii), appoint itself as conservator or receiver of the authorized intermediary;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09D37FF0D75748688D83E9D5555D038A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>obtain a lien on the assets of the intermediary pursuant to section 102(c)(5)(J); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11D3E2BE6FC24146B85754493BBB7B8F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>adjust the loan terms pursuant to subparagraph (B)(ii).</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC2AB63A5EDC4B9EBD7D7488FDDE31B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authorities under conservator or receivership</header><text>If the Reserve appoints itself a conservator or receiver of an authorized intermediary under clause (i)(II), the Reserve shall have the same authorities with respect to the authorized intermediary that the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation has with respect to an institution for which the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation has appointed itself as conservator or receiver under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3BDECA253024299818C463B56B6C027"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Treatment of bankruptcy</header><text>An authorized intermediary for which the Reserve has appointed itself a conservator or a receiver under clause (i)(II) may not be placed into bankruptcy under title 11, United States Code, during that conservatorship or receivership, and any bankruptcy process under title 11, United States Code, that is in effect when the appointment occurs shall be terminated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8EE584E754040749B634E121C49920D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acquisitions</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13903296A11746899AB824A4EE270CBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Acquisition through solicitation and direct contracting with private counterparties.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA47B20B334824D6596B2CE91EB45D1A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Acquisition through physically cleared financial instruments, such as futures contracts through intermediaries, including financial exchanges.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F7DA6A677D44C16B024794729E71EE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Acquisition through options contracts directly or through intermediaries, including financial exchanges.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41A4417FD2614ACE91666639CFF787D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-recourse lending</header><text>Non-recourse lending to projects secured by a portion of the expected production of the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48D0759E7FBE44B984896A8DFA855DAD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other transactions</header><text>Other financing and acquisition transactions, including contract for differences, advance or milestone payments, advanced market commitments, and minority, non-controlling equity investment, as determined by the Board as necessary to fulfill the purposes of the Reserve, except that equity investment shall only be used with—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EF3FAF0454E4C559B32CF541FDFFCC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a written justification describing how other financing and acquisition tools in this section are not sufficient; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0083C19CDD8144AAA3DC90AFAFDD0751"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a written explanation of the intended exit strategy for the equity investment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D03560F41CE4CD987AE8955AD258F7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Partner co-Investment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7541CE6140B64C17BD21CACBC26F68B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A partner country may, if approved by the Reserve, make capital contributions of at least $100,000,000 to the Reserve for purposes of financing or acquisition under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H148F440AFB284F5DAAA3820A476EDFD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum amount</header><text>The Reserve shall annually adjust the amount in paragraph (1) by the percentage increase in the Personal Consumption Expenditures Price Index of the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce, rounded to the nearest $1,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC24240C51C6B484AA08767FD5C865751"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of capital contributions</header><text>The Reserve—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA502A67635E4476E8AF397BAF285B280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall maintain separate accounts for the capital contributions of each partner country that provides such contributions under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEEBE160C9C54F47BACC22C49311F48A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not commingle the capital contributions of any partner country with any other partner country or the funds of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H216930DC2F87470F8D9350AE0F8D8BA4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may return such capital contributions to the partner country at any time, without obligation or penalty, or under such other terms and conditions as agreed to by the Reserve and that partner country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72F3E689C2E5416B93EE43501B1F4F2E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may not guarantee the repayment of such capital contributions to a partner country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAE4891E76E6428C9D86DE517E364C52"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Loans made with partner co-investment funds</header><text>Financing and acquisitions made under subsection (b) with capital contributions under paragraph (1) shall be made in the same manner as financing and acquisitions made under subsection (b) with funds of the Reserve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H686AB77EF3174242BC1BF2B451435616"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>The Reserve may not approve a partner country under paragraph (1) unless the partner country certifies that the capital contributions being made are coming from funds of the partner country and not from funds of a foreign entity of concern or a covered country.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AFD99BF26FC419AAB991C7BE9465903"><enum>(d)</enum><header>International advisory council of partners</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BB38F84A9554856A3D8210151A4F4D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Reserve may establish an International Advisory Council of Partners comprising—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7E01216C63B4F00B488A52A3D819E35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Vice-chairperson, who shall be the head of the council; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20563E663911490AA1467E19A36022BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 representative from each partner country that makes a capital contribution under subsection (c)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CB6F2128634468194EBEC7D2F5D2CD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The International Advisory Council of Partners shall, at the request of the Reserve, advise the Reserve on financing and acquisitions made with capital contributions under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H438A7BA4D58B4F9F98FAA622FD641FBB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability of FACA</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply to the International Advisory Council of Partners.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AFA3968623348738FB0E25AF42AB098"><enum>207.</enum><header>Sale of critical minerals or materials</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE2BCF15B4324E909E0C3F9FCBE903DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sale</header><text>The Reserve may sell critical minerals or materials stored in the Reserve in accordance with the purposes of the Reserve and this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D44399D75DF4AE1BB39747F17A8A953"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sale of critical minerals or materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Reserve may sell a critical mineral or material stored in the Reserve if the Board determines that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD57A1BAA9B4A4F66A2F0ADDFB4F80E66"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a supply shortage or potential supply shortage of that critical mineral or material threatens—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B76B73F0E3D42839434F10EE9E89773"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national or economic security of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A3C4F584E8B4F9DAE1D9D4BB5612545"><enum>(B)</enum><text>price stability in the value chain of that critical mineral or material; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB85D8741C8E040BE8C8650C011C0BE77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the sale is otherwise necessary to support the purposes of the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD79E5AD6FA9B4052B9A9AC8DA338091F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sale of non-Critical minerals or materials</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B9CBB7A07E54B81A73C5BB79B1F3979"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Reserve may sell a mineral or material stored in the Reserve that, as of the date of sale, is no longer included on the list of critical minerals and materials established by the Reserve under section 202(a) if the Board determines that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03D8826A80D740B2BC6D52605D17580D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mineral or material is unlikely to be imminently re-added to the list of critical minerals and materials established by the Reserve under section 202(a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0B4928035BD4FD1A561221A0F0334C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the mineral or material is available in sufficient supply or is no longer necessary in large quantities for economic or national security purposes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B1D4D620B7645F392C29985AD906A49"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a supply shortage or potential supply shortage of that mineral or material threatens—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H330FDADB9A3446048306E3AF0C27A865"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national or economic security of the United States; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEA93DC199684DCFB174AFFCD08FED93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>price stability in the value chain of that mineral or material; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H766D669D70EF48D68200213C10A076C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the sale is otherwise necessary to support the purposes of the Reserve.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F0C46C1CCFE4D1FA5FC192641AD3E67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use for research purposes</header><text>If the Board determines that a mineral or material stored in the Reserve that is no longer included on the list of critical minerals and materials established by the Reserve under section 202(a) does not have a substantial market value, the Board may enter into a contract for the transfer and use for research purposes of that mineral or material with—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1376C838CFBC47B9BF6FF93EAFD2DD34"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal departments and agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD745641D4A7494388C726D94EC28555"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H076B7BF1B3C04F649A64542DE5BB5224"><enum>(C)</enum><text>National Laboratories (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2194C7A785E844379C1BBEC29E8966F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C4AC74B869948A4B0C31338C706EB9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Means of sale</header><text>The Reserve may carry out a sale described in subsections (b) and (c) through—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B6A4835EB604B02B8B2968C86980808"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicitation and direct contracting with private parties;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43B38BE701C74975B5F05A0C25922952"><enum>(2)</enum><text>physically cleared financial instruments, such as futures contracts through authorized intermediaries;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H474D77FF8BC94C49A6B053A45077CE94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>options contracts directly or through authorized intermediaries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D1BA639544D4098A1708D79C5B82A25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other transactions, including public auctions, as determined necessary by the Board to support the purposes of the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0F0FF01EEDC4631B56B3D8D506428C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Foreign entities of concern</header><text>The Reserve may not carry out a sale described in subsections (b) and (c) to a foreign entity of concern.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H1EC9737FF7604362970DA814E4946D38" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><section id="HFC8EB1414F684B869461F7A46B3F8A2C"><enum>301.</enum><header>Corporate powers</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84DE1832445F404BA0C7C35FB5A878CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Reserve—</text><paragraph id="H1C9468561E444704A8A52B5F0CB9F119"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may adopt, alter, and use a seal, which may include an identifiable symbol of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H648FCA96A2094A9F9EFDA4C3D3117959"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notwithstanding division C of subtitle I of title 41, United States Code, may make and perform with any person contracts, including no-cost contracts (as defined by the Reserve), grants, and other agreements, that are necessary for carrying out the functions of the Reserve;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEA82001BBBB4E6F897EFB55AA7A0CB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may lease, purchase, or otherwise acquire, improve, and use real property that is necessary to carry out the functions of the Reserve;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86DAC247A2274B42A311F579DFE7BA44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may use the United States mails in the same manner and on the same conditions as the Executive departments (as defined in section 101 of title 5, United States Code);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H481793CB04964BFD8C84321A114DADFB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>may contract with individuals for personal services, who shall not be considered Federal employees for any provision of law administered by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E5BCA7079214E8DBF63B688D60EB6A8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>may hire or obtain passenger motor vehicles;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56407808910A4D17B17A7328164E5EAB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>may acquire, hold, or dispose of, on such terms and conditions as the Reserve may determine, any property (real, personal, or mixed), tangible or intangible, or any interest in such property;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF85A1AB228AB44BB8F5290AAA6ECD6A8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>may lease office space for the use of the Reserve;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD82231EC1DF947FE88E75B5ACFBECBE7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>may indemnify directors, officers, employees, and agents of the Reserve for liabilities and expenses incurred in connection with their activities on behalf of the Reserve;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6007F52B380454F9CF96EF58D957F3A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>notwithstanding any other provision of law, may represent itself or contract for representation in any legal or arbitral proceeding;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF7D91999B92439CBE82F47F70D399B3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>may exercise any priority of the Federal Government in collecting debts from bankrupt, insolvent, or decedents’ estates;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC540D9127BD54DF4BBDD0F4C541E645C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>may collect, notwithstanding section 3711(g)(1) of title 31, United States Code, or compromise any obligations assigned to or held by the Reserve, including any legal or equitable rights accruing to the Reserve;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8E5ABB65D03484BA2D7AEFD33764B08"><enum>(13)</enum><text>may sell direct investments of the Reserve to private investors on such terms and conditions as the Reserve may determine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H866242BFB7794B26AF073B0521D58423"><enum>(14)</enum><text>shall have such other powers as may be necessary and incident to carrying out the functions of the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FA51528F9F54F948DC07AFC2C12ECDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of property</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of property by the United States, the Reserve shall have the right in its discretion to complete, recondition, reconstruct, renovate, repair, maintain, operate, or sell any property acquired by the Reserve pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H958C2888C6FE41639B5BFB2D19DBBCD8"><enum>302.</enum><header>Records and accounts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F2DCB99932548C5B33BDFF53B3921D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preparation and maintenance</header><text>The Board may require any person to prepare and maintain such records or accounts as the Board, by rule, determines necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D598A559E7D405BB77466A5DA9258EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audit of operations of storage facilities</header><text>The Board may audit the operations of any storage facility in which any critical mineral or material acquired is stored or required to be stored pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22E5229D9828456BBA3E1897C907520D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access to and inspection of records or accounts and storage facilities</header><text>The Board may require access to, and has the right to inspect and examine, at reasonable times—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F4BA96E96ED4B198DDE39442622A587"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any records or accounts required to be prepared or maintained pursuant to subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0873E54D0174F768581240E9835C938"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any storage facilities subject to audit by the United States pursuant to this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H34EE0646D0554A24BDA8F94944C6D99B" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Oversight and accountability</header><section id="H60329E84737D41408D030E27E9577B06"><enum>401.</enum><header>Risk and audit committees</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CD2434582AD4982A81FDA3A82970DB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Reserve shall establish—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H307DE841DDF04FC9B49128D726E1057A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a risk committee; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFD938AB5582438DADC7F5AFBD24ACB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an audit committee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H768776CFDCA8455C9C46431F47C2E583"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties and responsibilities</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3874DCE5101E4A949DEF92BE932DC041"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Risk committee</header><text>Subject to the direction of the Board, the risk committee established under subsection (a)(1) shall be responsible for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC4816E0AEA84978B0F25F8128754518"><enum>(A)</enum><text>formulating risk management policies of the operations of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66A335E7277C454E94147BC11355E3C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reviewing and providing guidance on the operation of the global risk management framework of the Reserve;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3613F2648A4B4E3CA47B9962995855FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing policies for enterprise risk management, risk monitoring, and the management of strategic, reputational, regulatory, operational, developmental, responsible production, and financial risks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE37B10B9E13B4DAC9887B02AE3244B34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing the risk profile of the Reserve, including a risk management and compliance framework and governance structure to support such a framework;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF65C5AED6A204C25B90227223E3FFBFE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>monitoring Reserve participants to ensure existing participants do not become foreign entities of concern; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2948D8232FFE4745949E7770607561D8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>developing and using a mechanism to remove participants if more than 25 percent of that participant is owned, controlled, directed, financed, or otherwise influenced, directly or indirectly, in whole or in part by the government of a foreign entity of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCB7FB6652344B889320566FD8EDB166"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audit committee</header><text>Subject to the direction of the Board, the audit committee established under subsection (a)(2) shall be responsible for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15DC74008FE44469BAA9F3CC21602DF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the integrity of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27E9F58D6960438282727B593E675545"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the financial reporting of the Reserve;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8394160E70C142A9A010C1F985E1EE73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>systems of internal controls relating to finance and accounting of the Reserve; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H562991E5DC464325B6A09C9031B5ACC6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the financial statements of the Reserve;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE669A8FDE9374D4BA98AAB0249FAF103"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the performance of the internal audit function of the Reserve; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC697463934164D959475044244A9D06C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the compliance of the Reserve with legal and regulatory requirements relating to the finances of the Reserve.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43985669E65A4EF9B90C5DF2614CFDDB"><enum>402.</enum><header>Annual audit and comptroller review</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36186CB662CF4D1B8DA8DCA1E6C2CCCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual independent audit</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9915FF89290C4AE39F2CDDF8661A0255"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, an independent qualified public accountant selected by the Board shall audit the financial statements of the Reserve, the results of which shall be made publicly available.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06058ACD4C4F4276B69D9C1D3E90F22F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An independent qualified public accountant selected under paragraph (1) shall be—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92F5A6B8FA3C4E21A85B7ED6BB07B831"><enum>(A)</enum><text>certified and licensed by a State board of accountancy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91597F3C450D4E0AAA61812690F87637"><enum>(B)</enum><text>independent of the Reserve and each authorized intermediary within the meaning of section 210.2–01 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0876F9E706A1494FAA94175E885A453B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>registered with the Public Company Accounting and Oversight Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C0A559C55D24C21B5DFB8E12D2EA216"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a biennial review of the Reserve, to include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H519768D0CB934291AEC7CD1FADC752FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reviewing the most recent annual report submitted pursuant to section 403(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0208B4D4B7F43D683F7DD17E3A60447"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the operations and functions of the Reserve as managed by the Board; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF45E6969C2C94BC5854A66F80F668B58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the performance of the Board in fulfilling the purposes of the Reserve.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94758199DC9D45A68F6AD8FDD4205C47"><enum>403.</enum><header>Reporting and transparency</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB812B4366CFD4EA7B0E23B540A4C00D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4BEA282028240E49EF16964B7C8981D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall submit to the President, the Comptroller General of the United States, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the appropriate congressional committees, an annual report describing the operations of the Reserve during the preceding calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D7C7C48842548F1B79A3B4A0B05271F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7D2BAB732F34FD4BAF48B5822541F1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information regarding the administration of the functions of the Board, including recommendations the Board determines appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF20DE2A227C144348B107BE47E5652E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the assessment of the Board of the extent to which compliance with the requirements of this Act and the purposes of the Reserve have been achieved;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3390AD8AFEE6489194BB86E9F81668CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of transactions and loans made by the Reserve during the preceding calendar year, to include how well those transactions and loans have helped achieve the purposes of the Reserve; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84B5170BD363444A8199F94D88CE8494"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information regarding vulnerabilities, risks, and audits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAAEF750C8D54548968640FAD4CF7875"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Testimony</header><text>The Chairperson shall appear before the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives not later than 30 calendar days after the date that a report required under subsection (a) is submitted.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB31BA67824B40C8AE3C61C3B43FFE73"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Database</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H492F7DE418FC4C9D9F3B90012084B136"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Reserve shall maintain a database with detailed information on all transactions undertaken pursuant to section 206.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CF7EF1788FD4F9BA4F83430BE32143A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The database maintained under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C30AEE5BA794C6483FEC1A44F6D9CF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be user-friendly;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H916562F7746B4EE980DFCDCB5CB415D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (3), be publicly available; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19FDCA6DC06B492999BA7887A34361D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, include a description of the support provided for each project, including the information contained in the report required under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABC2CF0427D74CBF88C56312D3211270"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limit on public availability</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3157CCDD8D7444787082402CA0F94F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identified subset of the database maintained under paragraph (1) shall not be made publicly available if the Board determines doing so would be harmful to the national security of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A15E74BE286471D87A0C76E17F8F41A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text>If the Board makes a determination under subparagraph (A) that public availability of the identified subset of the database maintained under paragraph (1) would be harmful to the national security of the United States, the Reserve shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA7DB313A4E14742A8F0E472634444C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the identified subset of the database accessible to the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D77550319C246F581364FC3A9F4DA92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 3 years after a transaction undertaken pursuant to section 206 occurs, make the information about that transaction publicly available.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

