<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5D732B0DA0F54EE7B61579AA12835FD1" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 949 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the first Saturday in May as “National Lowrider Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 949</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the first Saturday in May as <quote>National Lowrider Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas lowriders and lowrider culture can be traced back to 1940s Chicano communities across the American Southwest;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowrider culture embodies the spirit of <quote>low and slow</quote> and demonstrates the beauty of peaceful cruising;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowriders, both the drivers and cars, have strong pride, style, and community identity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowrider vehicles are mobile works of art that showcase elaborate paint work, shiny chrome, intricate upholstery, and state-of-the-art craftsmanship and hydraulics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowriders have historically served as a form of cultural identity for Latino communities and a means of resistance in the face of discrimination;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowriders were persecuted and prosecuted for the mere act of driving their artwork down the road;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowrider clubs support communities across the United States through service, mentorship, charity events, car shows, and cultural celebrations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the artistry and mechanical innovations of lowriders hold deep influences on American popular culture, art, music, and fashion;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in recent years, multiple States and local governments overturned bans on cruising, recognizing the cultural and economic value of lowrider events and gatherings;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cities across the United States now officially recognize and celebrate lowrider culture through public art, cultural institutions, and community events;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in recent years, the United States Drug Enforcement Agency has supported youth lowrider bike building programs for at-risk kids;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Smithsonian’s National Museum of American History and the Smithsonian Institution Traveling Exhibition Service share the history and culture of lowriders through two exhibitions, <quote>Corazón y vida: Lowriding Culture</quote> at the museum in Washington, DC, and the traveling exhibition, <quote>Lowrider Culture in the United States/Cultura Lowrider en los Estados Unidos,</quote> which will visit communities across the country through 2029;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowrider culture reflects core American values of creativity, freedom of expression, innovation, and community building; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the first Saturday of May is a fitting time to celebrate <quote>National Lowrider Day</quote>, as the weather across the United States becomes more favorable for cruising: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE08ADA8B03B34748BC6A031F066B2B24"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB4F01616BB7C4542A89FE61C3CDD33C0"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H760223514D0247149E3C901648874041"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and celebrates lowrider culture as an integral part of the historical and cultural fabric of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3D06248619746338778E67DD0ABB7E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the contributions of lowrider builders, artists, families, and clubs who have preserved and promoted the lowriding tradition for generations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H634A3E232D3243D1985F7EEC9A4A7DFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of lowrider culture as a method of community building;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D211742FD914ABBA6D172EE6897894A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges the challenges faced by the lowrider community, including discrimination and criminalization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91B2FEF9228243638CE111760214575C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls upon local, State, and Federal entities to support public events and educational programs that honor lowrider culture and heritage.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

