<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-DAV26599-Y23-KT-R2P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 158 IS: Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sales to the Government of the United Arab Emirates of certain defense articles and services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 158</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed foreign military sales to the Government of the United Arab Emirates of certain defense articles and services.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9C2E52D41B6B4895AF900093904886AC"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H989ECF5139D54D76ADB5C1A2622B7489"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following proposed foreign military sale to the Government of the United Arab Emirates is prohibited:</text><paragraph id="idF210BC563F08469C9EECCBEA40A05D30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sale of the following defense articles and services, described in Transmittal No. RSAT 26–46, submitted to Congress pursuant to section 36(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776(b)(1)</external-xref>), and published in the Congressional Record on March 19, 2026: The following Major Defense Equipment (MDE): Three (3) GBU–39/B inert practice bombs; One thousand five hundred (1,500) GBU–39/B Small Diameter Bombs Increment I; Nine hundred (900) KMU–556 Joint Direct Attack Munition (JDAM) guidance sets; and Three hundred (300) KMU–557 JDAM guidance sets. The following non-MDE items: GBU–39 tactical training rounds; FMU–139 fuze systems; DSU–42 and DSU–40 laser illuminated target detectors; ground support system for Link 16; AN/PYQ–10 Simple Key Loaders; KG–250 Link Encryptors; precision navigation; Joint Mission Planning System with unique planning components and software; aircraft maintenance support equipment; spare and repair parts, consumables and accessories, and repair and return support; weapons and weapons support equipment; test equipment; training aids, devices, and spare parts; classified and unclassified software and software support; classified and unclassified publications and technical documentation; personnel training and training equipment; transportation support; aerial refueling; U.S. Government and contractor engineering, technical, and logistics support services; and other related elements of logistics and program support.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

