<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B32D0EED381415D85672FB3D77072D1" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 850 IH: Expressing support for the designation of November 8, 2025, as “National First-Generation College Celebration Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 850</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of November 8, 2025, as <quote>National First-Generation College Celebration Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas November 8 honors the anniversary of the signing of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) by President Lyndon B. Johnson on November 8, 1965;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) was focused on increasing postsecondary access and success for students, particularly including low-income and first-generation students;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Act helped usher in programs necessary for postsecondary access, retention, and completion for low-income, first-generation college students, including the Federal TRIO programs under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Federal Pell Grant program under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>);</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Federal TRIO programs under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11 et seq.</external-xref>) are the primary national effort supporting underrepresented students in postsecondary education and are designed to identify individuals from low-income, first-generation backgrounds and prepare them for postsecondary education, provide support services, and motivate and prepare students for doctoral programs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Pell Grant program under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>) is the primary Federal investment in financial aid for low-income college students, and is used by students at institutions of higher education of their choice;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a <quote>first-generation college student</quote> means an individual whose parents did not complete a baccalaureate degree, or in the case of any individual who regularly resided with and received support from only one parent, an individual whose parent did not complete a baccalaureate degree;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas first-generation college students face additional academic, financial, and social barriers compared to what their continuing-generation peers face while pursuing higher education;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 45 percent of current baccalaureate students pursuing degrees are first-generation;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas two-thirds of all community and technical college students identify as first-generation, with 14.2 percent having attained an associate’s degree and 10.1 percent having attained an undergraduate certificate;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas first-generation students navigate multiple competing priorities, and 73 percent were employed while in college, in paid jobs, internships, or work-study;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas first-generation students hold significant roles within their household, with 27 percent having dependents to care for while in school;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 37 percent of first-generation graduates expect to attain a master’s degree, and 16 percent expect to attain a doctoral degree upon completing a bachelor’s degree;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Council for Opportunity in Education and the Center for First-generation Student Success jointly launched the inaugural First-Generation College Celebration in 2017; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the First-Generation College Celebration has continued to grow, and institutions of higher education, corporations, nonprofits, and elementary schools and secondary schools now celebrate November 8 as <quote>First-Generation College Celebration Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8A3C95075CE1424BB2EE9496071FBF69"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H156767FEB9FC4B9C9D03BDADF5EB939A"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives urges all people in the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="H1938095D3748464B973064E13474D184"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrate <quote>National First-Generation College Celebration Day</quote> throughout the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8A0F2865D374D139E24DCBB12107806"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognize the important role that first-generation college students play in helping to develop the future workforce; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75E8C133384748588D1CA83EA89D087B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrate the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) and its programs that help historically excluded students access higher education.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

