<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26278-LHG-PK-D4L"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3914 IS: Supreme Court Ethics and Investigations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3914</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 28, United States Code, to establish an Office of Ethics Counsel and an Office of Investigative Counsel within the Supreme Court of the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H06F00E5BE8C74CD78009574A1806DB0B"><section section-type="section-one" id="H2851EF4F7D1B46EA855093BA35338A4F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supreme Court Ethics and Investigations Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H690BEBE20FB44028955BF9898EA08C82"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the office of ethics counsel within the supreme court of the united states</header><subsection id="HF2A073723EE3466EB6BDEA11F33C666F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/45">Chapter 45</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H895D3AC4ADC3491EAA6B0EDEFA589846"><section id="H28D3C41CD8DA42E1AB16C5275C56C625"><enum>678.</enum><header>Office of Ethics Counsel</header><subsection id="H04FF5C63F75C4002B19DF1A7DC750F0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>The Office of Ethics Counsel</header><text>The Chief Justice is authorized to establish an Office of Ethics Counsel within the Supreme Court of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H059A835DEAB84A949E4DB707F8243CE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constituted by one chief ethics counsel who may employ such officers and employees, subject to the provisions of title 5, governing appointments in the competitive service, and the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B2CF9B60AD645FDBB8767786A9AD1A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to advise and provide guidance to justices of the Supreme Court, and their spouses, on matters of judicial ethics, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1B3A4E78DDAA4331BB0F08EC74DC66A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>financial disclosure requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0139150242C4ADABAA03DE0CCFA1DC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the acceptance of gifts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5400BBA1A504334A41FA4B071EB80DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>political activity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFCD90A574014412BBB9CC71D27D0399"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conflicts of interest and recusal; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H295D0E313F2C47E7822AB4832E1B9373"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the unauthorized disclosure of official Court documents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCFEED051D53C4E1CA4CAFABB58E89F9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ethics counsels</header><paragraph id="HB3A1D3B3197148559C785AFDF8E86A1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staffing and compensation of counsels</header><subparagraph id="HDD8A34E0F0DD4080B922BDF05833F459"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Chief Ethics Counsel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chief ethics counsel within the Office of Ethics Counsel—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H586623B4EFF840A8A5E961C8F9E346E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be employed by the Court on the date of enactment of this section;</text></clause><clause id="H56C6EF73476F49CDA8D9304BC1AA7176"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be appointed by the Chief Justice;</text></clause><clause id="HE17B755A78944AC699A239C66116C394"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall serve not more than two 6-year terms; and</text></clause><clause id="H0D48414EAC5B430D88047220F6B3B71D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall receive an annual rate of pay of at least $225,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9645696D6376486CADC453541D1D97D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other counsels</header><text>Any counsel other than the chief ethics counsel within the Office of Ethics Counsel—</text><clause id="H52B6626A23B44B39B489D388BBA5F3A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not be employed by the Court on the date of enactment of this section;</text></clause><clause id="HF934449315594C1093088D4AEEB85105"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be appointed by the chief ethics counsel;</text></clause><clause id="H0EFDE9E71A6C47FC8758860A2BA6C1BF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall serve not more than two 6-year terms; and</text></clause><clause id="H94472F60300149B6B444F7B9798B5947"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall receive an annual rate of pay of at least $180,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB30E8E955C974E589BC7A2E84A5669B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Each counsel of the Office of Ethics Counsel shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD30D85D1E8A54574AA30D88477A12BBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be licensed to practice law in a State or territory of the United States and a member of the bar in good standing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EB1C123754245D2A33C963FD77105AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>possess at least 5 years of experience as a practicing attorney.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBDA099D2F8240B2B27869F58DB060BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expertise</header><text>Each counsel shall be an individual of exceptional public standing who is specifically qualified to serve within the Office of Ethics Counsel by virtue of the individual’s education, training, and experience, as determined by the Chief Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0825FD7243D4846A1937D795C168B9B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination of counsels</header><text>The employment of a counsel may only be terminated by the Chief Justice for cause.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC16C90704F3D415CAD78C6D9516BB63A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a biannual basis, the Office of Ethics Counsel shall provide, and each justice shall take, a training course on the judicial ethics matters described in subsection (a)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAF08EE925F314264B61BB83546E93EFE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis, the chief ethics counsel shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate a report on the ethics advice given by the Office of Ethics Counsel during the previous year, including—</text><paragraph id="H55BDF8EA6A84485A8A4C7EF649B3FCF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of times advice was sought and given;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7356B3E6D43A45DA833FF24730108D87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the advice was sought by judicial officers or by judicial employees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE341FA2097DF460FB6A4037005074D5C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information about the topics covered by the advice given, including the number of questions related to gifts, financial disclosures, nonpublic information, and political activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CCCAB6196B34EA7979910A08E801E25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number and types of mitigation measures that were recommended, including recusal, divestiture, resignation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5EE28A020A94A069D1B5D1356F2EC92"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of times advice described in this subsection was not followed by the individual to whom it was given, if known by the Office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F2991F814894253B216CF707113FA07"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H82FD008A92BE4B4FB733C93647E89151"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gift</term> means any gratuity, favor, discount, entertainment, hospitality, loan, forbearance, or other item having monetary value. The term includes services as well as gifts of training, transportation, local travel, lodgings and meals, whether provided in-kind, by purchase of a ticket, payment in advance, or reimbursement after the expense has been incurred.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79B93422CB54D9FA53D5D367C7BF95D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>political activity</term> means political engagements, such as paid speaking events, fundraisers, or donations to political parties, politicians, political action groups, or endorsements of political candidates.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H96964944E7114CD38E2110690A2D760B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/45">chapter 45</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/678">section 678</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1ACE9EC68F245049B371D6B5A8FD635"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">678. Office of Ethics Counsel.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H069C38912ADB4C85B1171A663EA71887"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of the office of investigative counsel within the supreme court of the united states</header><subsection id="HEE455A5CF8944CE08F63FB3511F83BE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/45">Chapter 45</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H980B7637C2354E7B931999DE5B621EF0"><section id="HC4EB494F86424D278895FBC09856EC12"><enum>679.</enum><header>Office of Investigative Counsel</header><subsection id="H66E25EB6A5384CC88CA8545D6339EB0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of investigative counsel</header><text>The Chief Justice is authorized to establish an Office of Investigative Counsel within the Supreme Court of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H5426680C339C43E98DC9FDADD075BD82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>constituted by one Chief Investigative Counsel and at least two additional investigative counsels; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EDDA5D0150C40A09F67A8213228C3CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to review and investigate ethics complaints against justices arising from their actions or the actions of their spouses and dependents.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB3A4B36A961430BB6B61DAF836C2D2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigative counsels</header><paragraph id="H1300354C0FBE4340BFEFE467712921B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staffing and compensation of counsels</header><subparagraph id="H042829C4BD5A4D9BB316877013EC335E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Chief investigative counsel</header><text>The Chief Investigative Counsel—</text><clause id="HD8F488827FF24730975642CDD842E0DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not be employed by the court on the date of enactment of this section;</text></clause><clause id="H79EE1345C54F45FF884206BFB5BB6227"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be appointed by the Chief Justice;</text></clause><clause id="H518EBBA341FD44518A2525188FA85D97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall serve not more than one 6-year term; and</text></clause><clause id="H0FD7A9A5381D455EAB196C250CBF642E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall receive an annual rate of pay of at least $225,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FC2A5A990D24692AE3F5249BE886230"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional investigative counsels</header><text>The investigative counsels—</text><clause id="H65881507854F424BBE591F9B3F378DF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be employed by the court on the date of enactment of this section;</text></clause><clause id="H946D0A11FB8A46EB879B6FC1247CF315"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be appointed by the Chief Investigative Counsel;</text></clause><clause id="HAE10C2F0C48B4498AEEF1152246981DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall serve at the pleasure of the Chief Investigative Counsel; and</text></clause><clause id="HE3B990CDAB134F988C59D2FDDAA135DA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall receive an annual rate of pay of at least $180,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5EC5F22A1C549D49D2FE8FFB9B2B04E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Each investigative counsel of the Office of Investigative Counsel shall—</text><clause id="HF2EF68C3420541879727B66BC2862B13"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be licensed to practice law in a State or territory of the United States and a member of the bar in good standing; and</text></clause><clause id="H9FA20402EA71420082740E3EE509F951"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>possess at least 7 years of experience as a practicing attorney.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D30726B26114C62A4014DC92DB82410"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Expertise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each investigative counsel and the Chief Investigative Counsel shall be an individual of exceptional public standing who is specifically qualified to serve within the Office of Investigative Counsel by virtue of the individual’s education, training, and experience.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0682E71BB8354693B7EAF36B063ED140"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Termination of counsels</header><text>The employment of the Chief Investigative Counsel may only be terminated by the Chief Justice for cause.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1092355182464E4A8EA719FED3681442"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subpoena power</header><subparagraph id="H8E2FF123974E4A71981D498F11C9982D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the discharge of their duties, the Chief Investigative Counsel shall have the authority to issue subpoenas to compel witnesses to appear and testify and to produce books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, documents, or other relevant records. The Chief Investigative Counsel may issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence relating to any matter under investigation by the Office of Investigative Counsel, which the Office is empowered to investigate by this section. The attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence may be required from any place within the United States at any designated place of hearing within the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC538F94705D4CE883F9479785C5B1DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to obey a subpoena</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person refuses to obey a subpoena issued under subparagraph (A), the Chief Investigative Counsel may apply to a United States district court for an order requiring that person to appear before the Office of Investigative Counsel to give testimony, produce evidence, or both, relating to the matter under investigation. The application may be made within the judicial district where the hearing is conducted or where that person is found, resides, or transacts business. Any failure to obey the order of the court shall be punishable by contempt of court.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF063C64579A4763B0422267DDD15DA9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Service of subpoenas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The subpoenas of the Office of Investigative Counsel shall be served in the manner provided for subpoenas issued by a United States district court under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure for the United States district courts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H386D0D38C1D54D6884F83C35722B528D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All process of any court to which application is made under subparagraph (B) may be served in the judicial district in which the person required to be served resides or may be found.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A9A839ECE6A4ED28E482088AC18B886"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ethics complaints</header><paragraph id="HDFCD6AB8A7E54C14967115F11B5C93F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Filing</header><text>An ethics complaint against a justice may be filed with the Office of Investigate Counsel by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9CECD7378CD44644822A1E74224997BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chair or ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives or of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H36DA564BDAC546F99B7A1BCF48B1DF55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Majority Leader or Minority Leader of the Senate; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H55285471AF0E4365BE88F68973389C11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Speaker or the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADC6750FA80C4EE89E0D75D82A68D1FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after an ethics complaint is filed under paragraph (1), the Office of Investigative Counsel shall review the complaint and determine whether a full investigation is appropriate. In making a determination under this paragraph, the Office shall consider whether the alleged behavior of a justice violates the Code of Conduct of the Supreme Court, the Judicial Code of Conduct, or any applicable law or regulation. Upon making a determination under this paragraph, the chief counsel shall respond to each ethics complaint filed under paragraph (1), regardless of whether the Office of Investigative Counsel determines that an investigation is appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B4D42AE1CD453D95FB5CB1813E484B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>If the Office determines that a full investigation is appropriate, it shall open the investigation not later than 15 days after making such determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4310C19F32904D3C9FE9BF7356AE2B92"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><subparagraph id="H8E79D419105546C3BFA156A11D99C4BC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office of Investigative Counsel shall submit to the Chief Justice a report containing its findings and recommendations about an ethics complaint filed under paragraph (2) (including in the case of a complaint with respect to which the Office determines that no violation has occurred), except that in the case of an ethics complaint with respect to which the Chief Justice is the subject, the Office shall deliver such report to the most senior associate justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3820B6BC20B54E86B9AD3E2938A0807B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="H6C144DF9B00A4E169452AB56EA4B07CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each violation of the Code of Conduct for the Supreme Court committed by the justice who was the subject of the investigation under paragraph (3), including any such violation that arose as a result of the actions of a spouse or dependant of the justice; and</text></clause><clause id="H198976D4E9D3439185C56EF1F7C9CAB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>substantive and actionable recommendations from the Office of Investigative Counsel including recusal, divestment and neutralization conflicts of interest, and other remedies.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD266B9F67A149C0976A7145927C26DE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication</header><clause id="HF91758D0FAF443BEBA21E6BFC051D76D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Chief Justice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Justice may, in his sole discretion, release to the public a report received under subparagraph (A), but may not alter such a report in any way, except to redact any classified or personally identifiable information. In the case of an ethics complaint with respect to which the Chief Justice is the subject, the most senior associate justice is authorized to carry out this clause.</text></clause><clause id="H68B13B5D8EA647B0B27133003CF541FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Availability to Congress</header><text>Not later than 10 days after completing a report under subparagraph (A), the Office of Investigative Counsel shall make the report available to—</text><subclause id="HC10C7C89D2724CA7B79B84EE780E397E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE674A25C1A22415C8FBC090964EB7BB6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC6CF5C0023944E2C8979B827F664035C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0E7FC90C99ED4FBCBF6894BC1B49C9C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Duty to inform the Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties of the Office, the Investigative Counsel shall report expeditiously to the Attorney General whenever the Investigative Counsel has reasonable grounds to believe there has been a violation of Federal criminal law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6180E728A1214778AB91BC23DEE365BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/45">chapter 45</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/678">section 678,</external-xref> as added by section 2, the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0C74C740BA74D40A83DC976A93B9495"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">679. Office of Investigative Counsel.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H79A83271D59045A09EE8D2F5C9BF360F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or any application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of this Act to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

