<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H393141AF4141461889B5F59C3DCC43CD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1360 IH: Expressing support for the designation of June 12, 2026, as “Women Veterans Appreciation Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of June 12, 2026, as <quote>Women Veterans Appreciation Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, throughout all periods of the history of the United States, women have proudly served the United States to secure and preserve freedom and liberty for—</text> <paragraph id="id83920FC756F5430489A1025B60833459"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the people of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id703C6C8E02C1439B909DE7AC2D994347"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the allies of the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas women have formally been a part of the United States Armed Forces since the establishment of the Army Nurse Corps in 1901, but have informally served since the inception of the United States military;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas women have served honorably and with valor, including—</text> <paragraph id="id1F2CE4A6B9334B759A1357837C0EDFD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disguised as male soldiers during the American Revolution and the Civil War;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idBA50EAE9319C45DF8AB9B23CABBB88D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as nurses during World War I and World War II; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5D0EE74B2640459A80DB2D638A7DE40F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in combat roles in the Persian Gulf, Iraq, and Afghanistan;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, as of October 2021, women constitute 17 percent of United States Armed Forces personnel on active duty, including—</text> <paragraph id="id01DF213A92DF4D309BCCEFB301128D96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>21 percent of active duty personnel in the Air Force;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id95112537912E49F1B5B88517613993D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>21 percent of active duty personnel in the Navy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idB24B4EB3D1AE4788A6D5D6CF64A5FBAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>16 percent of active duty personnel in the Army;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idD7B19E6AD7AF4DB4B871CEAFFB56188F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>9 percent of active duty personnel in the Marine Corps;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A610EC974A04542B271F44BB3C2A5B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">20 percent of active duty personnel in the Space Force; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id8E505F988A57452387FA7EBC7B5D553A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>15 percent of active duty personnel in the Coast Guard;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, as of October 2021, women constitute nearly 21 percent of personnel in the National Guard and Reserves;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas as of 2021—</text> <paragraph id="id8D033EA75DC7424D95D4F8B0E9209F6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the population of women veterans exceeded 2,000,000, which represents an exponential increase from 713,000 women veterans in 1980; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id5DBB32985FD44950A0DA0705951A16BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>women veterans constitute approximately 10 percent of the total veteran population;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas women are the fastest growing group in the veteran population;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an estimated one in three women veterans enrolled in the VA Healthcare System report having experienced Military Sexual Trauma (MST) during military service;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States is proud of and appreciates the service of all women veterans who have demonstrated great skill, sacrifice, and commitment to defending the principles upon which the United States was founded and which the United States continues to uphold;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas women veterans have unique stories and should be encouraged to share their recollections through the Veterans History Project, which has worked since 2000 to collect and share the personal accounts of wartime veterans in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on June 12, 1948, all women were, for the first, time, authorized by statute to serve as permanent, regular members of the Armed Forces with the signing of the Women’s Armed Services Integration Act by President Truman; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, by designating June 12, 2026, as <quote>Women Veterans Appreciation Day</quote>, the House of Representatives can—</text> <paragraph id="id18445755D651404DBA76A5CEB9F18C4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>highlight the growing presence of women in the Armed Forces and the National Guard; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id09E4D0ABB965418EBED706313C2A796F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pay respect to women veterans for their dutiful military service: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA12CFB8E9CAE4D2DA08F50F0ADE12FCC"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA2CCE42478314700B037510B6CE28D4C"><text>That the House of Representatives expresses support for the designation of <quote>Women Veterans Appreciation Day</quote> to recognize the service and sacrifices of women veterans who have served valiantly on behalf of the United States.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

