<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-NEW26256-NGN-9X-YKK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4721 IS: Restoring Renewable Energy Parity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4721</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prevent certain executive actions and repeal certain executive documents, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id39f9aef57e0f41e08e1ba1d374d01728" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Renewable Energy Parity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id566079699bce4a3eb50c41b80c9cedd4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prevention of executive actions and repeal of executive documents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefb5bbb045e1456283c3c9e197be40e2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prevention and repeal</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89c5f9dd054040f2a2ec18d2f48fd8b4"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf448285b01614cebb7884be7c2019ce6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce shall discontinue the investigation into imports of wind turbines and their parts and components initiated under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>), as described in the notice of the Bureau of Industry and Security entitled <quote>Notice of Request for Public Comments on Section 232 National Security Investigation of Imports of Wind Turbines and Their Parts and Components</quote> (90 Fed. Reg 41380 (August 25, 2025));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f3b766f704a4dc9bf0c9b6689805fb0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall not take any action that hinders any wind, solar, or geothermal development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id590ad2311e6a4b69ac536ec485996cf7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Executive documents described in paragraph (2) (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Executive documents</quote>) shall have no force or effect and no Federal funds may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out the Executive documents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59ace2c1b7314a308c6683b1cba63777"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive documents described</header><text>The Executive documents referred to in paragraph (1)(C) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="id502204f4179d4aac9a5b4a7069777572"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Executive Order 14315 (90 Fed. Reg. 30821; relating to ending market distorting subsidies for unreliable, foreign-controlled energy sources).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd64139d4841147339294936e2a2968cf"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>The Presidential memorandum entitled <quote>Temporary Withdrawal of All Areas on the Outer Continental Shelf from Offshore Wind Leasing and Review of the Federal Government’s Leasing and Permitting Practices for Wind Projects</quote> issued on January 20, 2025 (90 Fed. Reg. 8363).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id376497e3329b4637a04348166a4c032b"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretarial Order 3417, issued by the Secretary of the Interior on February 3, 2025 (relating to addressing the national energy emergency).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id541d232a01eb4eabace7ff804cb4b879"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Secretarial Order 3418, issued by the Secretary of the Interior on February 3, 2025 (relating to unleashing American energy).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bc2830bab6b4409b9752f017e5d2c5c"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretarial Order 3437, issued by the Secretary of the Interior on July 29, 2025 (relating to ending preferential treatment for unreliable, foreign-controlled energy sources in Department decision making).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d85f2eeae4546a5a5c571c752a1c713"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Secretarial Order 3438, issued by the Secretary of the Interior on August 1, 2025 (relating to managing Federal energy resources and protecting the environment).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42d7848af8944659b81153aea0d0e624" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The memorandum of the Secretary of the Interior issued on July 15, 2025, entitled <quote>Departmental Review Procedures for Decisions, Actions, Consultations, and Other Undertakings Related to Wind and Solar Energy Facilities</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f8227b4c05f49bd8be0d9b36c9ca971"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The memorandum of the Secretary of Agriculture issued on August 21, 2025, numbered 1078–016 and entitled <quote>Efficiency Screening Criteria for Proposals Concerning Power Generation on National Forest System Lands</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide20fca9594fb4742b7783b4504c9f55e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Internal Revenue Service Notice 2025–42 (relating to beginning of construction requirements for purposes of the termination of clean electricity production credits and clean electricity investment credits for applicable wind and solar facilities).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34046c3068e04d299a3e8e9be66e66c9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The guidance of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, described in the news release published on the website of the Corps of Engineers on September 22, 2025, entitled <quote>Army Corps of Engineers begins implementing policy to increase America's energy generation efficiency</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1aeb490492443e6913f37f09f056853"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Substantially similar documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President or the head of the applicable Federal department or agency may not reissue an Executive document in substantially the same form, and a new order, memorandum, notice, or guidance document that is substantially the same as an Executive document may not be issued, unless the order, memorandum, notice, or guidance document is specifically authorized by an Act of Congress enacted after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1e5b0d36f6d44928e56542c58ecb3cd"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Required action by Secretary of Defense</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall approve and sign any mitigation agreement relating to a wind energy facility, solar energy facility, transmission line, or distribution line that was initiated before January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62b5c6fe027e411cb293b38cf10f3edf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>IPaC portal</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall not prohibit any person requesting a permit for a wind, solar, geothermal, or storage project from using the Information for Planning and Consultation Portal (commonly known as the <quote>IPaC Portal</quote>) of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to process the project.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5dd9f0c53b0f4208b43aafdef5ee92bf"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial assistance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7fd41127b5a4207964d645ff3f9b719"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of continuation application</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>continuation application</term> means an application to secure continuing distribution of a Federal financial assistance award that was designated to be distributed over multiple fiscal years.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id516ae39a3b6e4daa8c5dbdad24f23db6"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Continuation application</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bc966a43eb34033b0e6518fcf3b9484"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date on which a continuation application is submitted by an applicant, the head of the applicable Federal department or agency shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8c37c3ac7af408f97fa92ad6f38c717"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grant or deny that continuation application; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id651a46dc1809471085ad5ec72d9cfedc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the applicant of the determination made under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11973242c4c4461ab2c87bd82826df23"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continuation application</header><text>A continuation application submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be in such form and contain such information as the head of the applicable Federal department or agency may require.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba26902374a4434cbb4228b43793b7e4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>A continuation application granted under subparagraph (A) shall contain the same terms and conditions as the original application, as applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6057334430a411b96a8e08bc2da6832"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>A continuation application that is not responded to by the deadline required under subparagraph (A) shall be considered granted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a088f12780249a1b0c1eb7d306d4f25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rescission limitation</header><text>No amounts may be rescinded from amounts provided under any appropriation Act (as defined in section 3 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/622">2 U.S.C. 622</external-xref>)) for fiscal years 2026 or 2027, unless the rescission is made through an appropriation Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

