<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25813-N81-R2-700"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3417 IS: Main Street Lending Improvement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3417</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on the disbursement process for certain small business loans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HB7E6B21481E04219A1F0A814E8AF1B8F"><section section-type="section-one" id="H54720FAFD173454DB8F8459BA37956CE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Main Street Lending Improvement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB134183F20AE4024B5C37D73F91A1D39"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disbursement process for certain small business loans</header><subsection id="HC20DE2FDD25640C7B66F466360664EF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8113ED90847B47F9B84A42514707289F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appalachian region</header><text>The term <term>Appalachian region</term> has the meaning given such term by section 14102(a) of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11BE9AD80BE140628E52B166A2256C87" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered region</header><text>The term <term>covered region</term> means a region of the Administration that includes any part of the Appalachian region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8267EE2A843A4DAF83746F670646F428"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Region of the Administration</header><text>The term <term>region of the Administration</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8265AA9AEB994919906AE60C72FA7733"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given such term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E1D8EDDE1C249D480E3F4958A4A94D4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small business loan</header><text>The term <term>small business loan</term> means a loan made under title V of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/695">15 U.S.C. 695 et seq.</external-xref>), section 7(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</external-xref>), or section 7(m) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(m)</external-xref>), except that such term excludes any loan made under a program established in response to the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC3FD31E8DC34A5FA960A537C0250BCE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the disbursement process for small business loans.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98D16937443940B7B89783FC43837C0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><paragraph id="H27EB9C2BB1DD48E9AE6F05B99B0FA355"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (b), the Comptroller General shall determine for each year during the period beginning on January 1, 2021, and ending on December 31, 2024, for each covered region, the measures described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H171A6AD6A97349F9B10090B41AB460D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Measures described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The measures described in this paragraph with respect to a covered region are, for each of the portion of such covered region that is part of the Appalachian region and the portion of such covered region that is not part of the Appalachian region—</text><subparagraph id="H5E02C8B958B0418B9BDFF787DAC66BA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average length of time—</text><clause id="H618C63C5B9C64B24BD62A0A71FEBC8BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">between the submission of an application for a small business loan by a small business concern for which the principal place of business is located in such portion and when funds are disbursed with respect to such application; and</text></clause><clause id="H3880D6EE08F749C1AFE69CF347775212"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to complete each step of the application and disbursement process for small business loans for small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H255C59F67C264966BEA7FA878FE16BBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number that is equal to the product of—</text><clause id="H93815106F04E45A595DEF6856AB2CAAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of small business loans disbursed to small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion divided by the total number of small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion; and</text></clause><clause id="H4E4176AD21104B15944D7E34E8204B49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1000;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H466D8F48B6A04A998DDDE2F8D73E5EDC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number that is equal to the product of—</text><clause id="HE634262CF7DC44F49D002DB6EF115BF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of small business loans approved for small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion divided by the total number of small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion; and</text></clause><clause id="H8B74A0B0F22E499EBFEE118680F3A0B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1000;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5387363EDE74AF28CF9588F5FC65CA3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average and median dollar amount of small business loans disbursed to small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74BCCF16D67B4E7B8028D941A600FBA3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number that is equal to the product of—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0AB90D6C5C7493B8CA669264C7E78EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate dollar amount of all small business loans disbursed to small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion divided by the total number of small business concerns for which the principal place of business is located in such portion; and</text></clause><clause id="HAF22FCA80B3C44C9BC2E0661E0A583C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H358C4FE198244E9785102D2C068500D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing and report</header><paragraph id="H80F56D3A1B194D68AB07F7FC6C65F9EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim briefing</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall provide to Congress a briefing on the progress of the study required by subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F99D284D2B41BF9553716C40ABFC48"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="H6699126884FB479E903CB05BBC9EA6CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study required by subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC012B38AFC6A4A39951F6FDBE0373EF1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The report required by subparagraph (A) shall include recommendations of the Comptroller General for changes to the small business loan disbursement process to—</text><clause id="H8ADC1472273D4EABAB8811F518104106"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase accessibility of small business loans;</text></clause><clause id="HFA54B8BA3FE943B481136159FEBF81AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">decrease the average length of time from when an application for a small business loan is submitted to when funds are disbursed with respect to such application;</text></clause><clause id="H24002229F9B34990A21C8D70EC85FF67"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the availability of information to an applicant for a small business loan regarding the status of the application of such applicant, including if any additional information is needed from the applicant to continue processing the application of such applicant and an estimate of the length of time until the funds with respect to such application will be disbursed; and</text></clause><clause id="HC93E6BE89A0B4EA5BEF52494960988A8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify mechanisms and processes internal to the agencies involved in making small business loans that can be changed to reduce inefficiencies of the Government with respect to the processing of applications for small business loans.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

