<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2CDDC840987549F09139A7F19CB22BAB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8051 IH: Transforming Education through College and Hands-On Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8051</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that qualified technical schools offering certain career pathway and job training programs have the same access to Federal grants as 2-year and 4-year institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB6C91BCEDB2448FCB1F1596E561E0D18" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB89F0A21502944DE8BC9892B68392FFA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transforming Education through College and Hands-On Training Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TECH Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9BBA9096413D4A8693F119DD0B5F7350" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification to eligibility for certain Federal grant programs</header> <subsection id="H740B6572DC4940779F385CDC3ECB25E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a qualified technical school shall be eligible to participate in any covered Federal grant program to the same extent, and on the same basis, as any 2-year or 4-year institution of higher education.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4392B56FBB974483BEDCDB9ED65CFB75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency action</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each Secretary concerned shall—</text> <paragraph id="H90F5C0B2CAE44652B584BF939E8977B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modify the eligibility criteria and application procedures for the covered Federal grant programs under the jurisdiction of such Secretary, as necessary, to ensure that qualified technical schools are eligible to participate in the program to the same extent, and on the same basis, as 2-year and 4-year institutions of higher education, as required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FFC68D8E6EE4FC48B464D8218448742"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue guidance that specifies how grants under such program should be dispersed among qualified technical schools and 2-year and 4-year institutions of higher education to ensure that the sectors and occupations described in subsection (c)(4)(A)(ii) have an adequate workforce pipeline to replace the aging and retiring current employees.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDF7049A5224C425C875F3FEF55BCDD5D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H62E0EB8BE3654E2F9AD90D3A483F519F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>2-year or 4-year institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>2-year or 4-year institution of higher education</term> means in institution described in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C 1001(a)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H758208AA3EBE4E8F93C9B38C184BD1F3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered Federal grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered Federal grant program</term> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9465B929984C4ED2939E042088E8D634" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants made by the Department of Education under—</text> <clause id="HA0D9A5029BA34A9B8D728A0FA81F5630" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Strengthening Institutions Program authorized under part A of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1057">20 U.S.C. 1057 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H82B7AB36194B4A9781567C0B4ADD3241" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal TRIO Program authorized under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause> <clause id="H402AEA00F447438BBD382FE3DA5E4E45" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Child Care Access Means Parents in School Program (commonly known as the <quote>CCAMPIS Program</quote>) authorized under section 419N of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070e">20 U.S.C. 1070e</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56B06BF79A60454A93812520D08BD551" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants made by the Department of Labor under the Strengthening Community Colleges Training Grants Program authorized under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C7F822C651D4B0B9A1B61DD5E3EF872"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible career pathway program</header><text>The term <term>eligible career pathway program</term> means a program that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2BC9B9184CCD411CB2E2EF2987206776"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the requirements of section 484(d)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091">20 U.S.C. 1091(d)(2)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4DD6455007B4F4DA1BFE08E67D684C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is listed on the provider list under section 122(d) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3152">29 U.S.C. 3152(d)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6500D5126F4A4FB7BB368A640E66EAD6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is part of a career pathway, as defined in section 3 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72A768AC6F3140CAAE7E8B50563417F9" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is aligned to a program of study as defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC61B13109654252B0189DFF0BCA0DB0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible job training program</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF1F37EEDB06F47CAB7C02B2B6B538875"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The term <term>eligible job training program</term> means a career and technical education program at qualified technical school that—</text> <clause id="HC1B4B1A646AF4720917C8890189FB0AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a program of at least 150 clock hours of instruction, but less than 600 clock hours of instruction, or an equivalent number of credit hours, offered by a qualified technical school during a minimum of 8 weeks, but less than 15 weeks;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H06C2182B56004533B36FE5F8F9FC8587"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides training that is—</text> <subclause id="H466F3034463C4FF79B97004CC2940A99"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a sector or occupation determined by the Secretary concerned to be essential for national security, public safety, supply chain security, transportation, critical manufacturing or infrastructure, healthcare, or public health; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCB0DF2FC8AE14246872B978C0A7FC37D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>aligned with the requirements of high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations in the State or local area, as determined by an industry or sector partnership;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H45A25E2C9D1C4F2BA4BC129DA519ABF5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a program of training services, and provided through an eligible training provider, as described under section 122(d) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3152">29 U.S.C. 3152(d)</external-xref>);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4642F8B0E183478593B35010D11506A7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provides a student, upon completion of the program, with a recognized postsecondary credential that is recognized by employers in the relevant industry, including credentials recognized by industry or sector partnerships in the relevant industry in the State or local area where the industry is located and the job training program is provided;</text></clause> <clause id="HE4E32AC308B8470190749352F3616BC7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>has been determined by the school (after validation of that determination by an industry or sector partnership) to provide academic content, an amount of instructional time, and a recognized postsecondary credential that are sufficient to—</text> 
<subclause id="H70EF0B32867E4778B4B3FC99658F9D36"><enum>(I)</enum><text>meet the hiring requirements of potential employers; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7A7E26938DCD485BBD2FB121E22F46AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>satisfy any applicable educational prerequisite requirement for professional licensure or certification, so that the student who completes the program and seeks employment qualifies to take any licensure or certification examination needed to practice or find employment in an occupation that the program prepares students to enter;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFAE291091FAB40E098043551B386E36C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>may include integrated education and training;</text></clause> <clause id="H8A407FE81A3647CFBA3AE4BBCB75DCE3"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>may be offered as part of an eligible career pathway program; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE6259AAB8E52497C8F26BE1B4FD80C85"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>does not exceed by more than 50 percent the minimum number of clock hours required for training if the State has established such a requirement.</text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE70C642D30E64510953258FB6913144E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval by the Secretary</header><text>In the case of a program that is seeking to establish eligibility as an eligible job training program under this paragraph, the Secretary of Education shall make a determination about whether the program meets the requirements of this paragraph not more than 60 days after the date on which such program is submitted for consideration as an eligible job training program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3650437A4A604C889BC89EE7B1B67C64" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional assurance</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall not determine that a program is an eligible job training program in accordance with subparagraph (B) unless the Secretary receives a certification from the appropriate State board containing an assurance that the program meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AF1AEFA1BC24367B95C89EA953AD3D8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified technical school</header><text>The term <term>qualified technical school</term> means a postsecondary vocational institution (as defined in section 102(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</external-xref>) that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H481093A7C82645F799B06F03EFAA53D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offers an eligible career pathway program or an eligible job training program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78342201EF5849CD86553DD76484FC1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28C1EC4BE63049AAB1D22AECBCD69496"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7BE1001DF3134A19ABF5109C43D696E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education, with respect to covered Federal grant programs administered by the Department of Education; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D54082C44104DE2B8C87887C817F21B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Labor, with respect to a covered Federal grant programs administered by the Department of Labor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2A737B1A304478CAC46494C5FDA6D7C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>WIOA terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>industry or sector partnership</term>, <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term>, <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term>, and <term>State board</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

