<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD1E0A1553EE49F2945C52876B0022D4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8500 IH: Timely Access to Coverage Decisions Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8500</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure timely review of local coverage determination requests under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H262B49CF6BE54800A2DA843C3EF97C3D" style="OLC"><section id="HE195C0EC2ED940F0ABB30AD855CA9D07" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Timely Access to Coverage Decisions Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4FA73E2F1CBC46AB9CF6D0881C5483FF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring timely review of local coverage determination requests under the Medicare program</header><subsection id="HF32FA78E95244A139721216B3FD85393"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1862(l)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7143404369C748A7B0FAB820B1D90EA1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H12C4057CB5B54039AED508E96C34B1FF"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Timeframe for decisions on requests for local coverage determinations</header><clause id="H387442DF7FEE413A8F3F6B8B25B2867A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require each Medicare administrative contractor that receives a formal LCD request on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph to determine whether such request is a complete request or an incomplete request not later than 60 days after such contractor receives such request.</text></clause><clause id="H082420BF025C488AA0D2D5D716507DA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notification with respect to incomplete requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that a Medicare administrative contractor makes a determination described in clause (i) with respect to a formal LCD request that such request is incomplete, such contractor shall, not later than 60 days after the date on which such contractor received such request, transmit to the entity that submitted such request a written notification of such determination that includes a specification of each item of additional information needed to make such request complete.</text></clause><clause id="H951CA6AC701945EABC502E7B7A627402"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Decision timeline for complete requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that a Medicare administrative contractor makes a determination described in clause (i) with respect to a formal LCD request that such request is complete, such contractor shall, not later than 1 year after the date on which such contractor received such request, take the actions described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (D).</text></clause><clause id="H5C93B81D39CC497AA9FCD6664086607B"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Formal LCD request defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph, the term <quote>formal LCD request</quote> means a document that identifies itself as a formal request for a local coverage determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H48A5E0DA9DF041B7B4EC711457E0A5D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reconsideration requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1862(l)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)(5)</external-xref>), as amended by <internal-xref idref="HF32FA78E95244A139721216B3FD85393" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block id="H9FF04A9FA93D4420B3D573DE24D0CA01" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H92F6154FFC184F8CB71FFB009E7FB7BE"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Timeframe for decisions on reconsideration requests for local coverage determinations</header><clause id="H735FB58C87824E449CD4DCF52A779A42" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require each Medicare administrative contractor that receives a formal reconsideration request on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph to determine whether such request is a complete request or an incomplete request not later than 60 days after such contractor receives such request.</text></clause><clause id="H8B00BD0E531545B3B5B60528B3D4E269"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notification with respect to incomplete requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that a Medicare administrative contractor makes a determination described in clause (i) with respect to a formal reconsideration request that such request is incomplete, such contractor shall, not later than 60 days after the date on which such contractor received such request, transmit to the entity that submitted such request a written notification of such determination that includes a specification of each item of additional information needed to make such request complete.</text></clause><clause id="H11CBFB5A20024F4A9FEEB761ACEFB405"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Decision timeline for complete requests</header><text>In the case that a Medicare administrative contractor makes a determination described in clause (i) with respect to a formal reconsideration request that such request is complete, such contractor shall, not later than 1 year after the date on which such contractor received such request, take the actions described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (D).</text></clause><clause id="HC0850D553E7143CE9EA3259E1A5A54CF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph:</text><subclause id="HF5FAF53925E74B7999E234786EE952AF"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Formal reconsideration request</header><text>The term <quote>formal reconsideration request</quote> means, with respect to a Medicare administrative contractor, a document that—</text><item id="H0AB0FC0AFBE849BDB1B01472FA110619"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>identifies itself as a formal request for reconsideration of part or all of a finalized local coverage determination made by such contractor with respect to a geographic area; and</text></item><item id="H560362691FF24C97A25D68FD793564FA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is submitted by an interested party.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H7740DBDCF6874245B527F91C2C3299CE"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Interested party</header><text>The term <quote>interested party</quote> means, with respect to a local coverage determination made by a Medicare administrative contractor with respect to a geographic area—</text><item id="HE9877FB10EB245538C74E923B6ECF03E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B who resides in, or receives items or services in, such area;</text></item><item id="H85F5EF9E0A454124BFE77B4F1697C0B5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a provider of services or supplier that, in such area, furnishes, provides, or supplies items or services that are subject to such determination; or</text></item><item id="H6FC2B5FF2EF0483E84F99F9933E15D6C"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any entity that the Secretary determines to be an interested party in such area.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC833A7181D514AEEA74295E66DE08231" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Agency review of reconsideration decision</header><text>Upon the request of an interested party (as defined in subparagraph (F)(iv)), the Secretary shall review the final determination (as defined in subparagraph (D)(ii)) made by a Medicare administrative contractor following a complete formal reconsideration request made under subparagraph (F). Such review shall include an analysis of whether—</text><clause id="H9C2EF04D53D348099A4234FBADB2FAD2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the determination did not apply, or inaccurately interpreted, qualifying evidence (as defined in subparagraph (D)(iv)) relevant to such determination;</text></clause><clause id="H0BFBF2554E70436683C75692300AB5BB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the determination used language that exceeded the scope of the intended purpose of the determination;</text></clause><clause id="H58378B2ED08F40F8A585DC8277D718E6" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the determination was incorrect in its determination of whether such item or service is reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury under section 1862(a)(1)(A);</text></clause><clause id="H022C6AFF8C37464FACB17A7368D8FDB8" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the determination failed to describe, with respect to such an item or service, the clinical conditions to be used for purposes of determining whether such item or service is reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury under section 1862(a)(1)(A);</text></clause><clause id="HCBA1BF90CD5B4ACE8B81C05245623F44" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the determination does not apply with respect to items or services to which it was intended to apply; or</text></clause><clause id="H08EC39D3A45646C8A2F043136CAF1F19" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the determination conflicts with any other law, rule, regulation, or national coverage determination, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB663FB66DA154A6BB050366249005907"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development process for specified LCDs</header><text>Section 1862(l)(5)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)(5)(D)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H98D3B2F7F5954C42A4D91C9EDB0AA9CA" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H41F1F27AC2CB42E0AC58989AB9345ACE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Process for issuing specified local coverage determinations</header><clause id="H9022AD38E35347778C414BADC821F602"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a specified local coverage determination (as defined in clause (iii)) within an area by a Medicare administrative contractor, such contractor must take the following actions with respect to such determination before such determination may take effect:</text><subclause id="H339B0F3AE77C4BBFBDC6AE72A2C2A647"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Publish on the public internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services commonly referred to as the <quote>Medicare Coverage Database</quote> (or a successor website) and on the public internet website of the Medicare administrative contractor a proposed version of the specified local coverage determination (in this subparagraph referred to as a <quote>draft determination</quote>), any related coding or billing information, a written rationale for the draft determination, and a description of all evidence relied upon and considered by the contractor in the development of the draft determination.</text></subclause><subclause id="H69E888858E904609A7D935339F2E409C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Medicare administrative contractor publishes the draft determination in accordance with subclause (I)—</text><item id="H0DCB4070BBA6462187FB080D2E044752"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convene one or more open, public meetings to review the draft determination, and, with respect to each such meeting, make available means for the public to attend such meeting remotely, and make the planned agenda for such meeting publicly accessible at least 14 days in advance;</text></item><item id="HB273EFBA4BC9444794CD874DC7AB7587"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>receive comments with respect to the draft determination; and</text></item><item id="H2E6A7ADB467E494CA3F40178891F283F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>secure the advice of an expert panel, which shall include—</text><subitem id="H19A46394CFA74B60A1EF250EB72660B9"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>1 or more physicians;</text></subitem><subitem id="H4E609B5D867B4D7590F60DB59A622A7D"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more members of the Contractor Advisory Committee (as described in chapter 13 of the Medicare Program Integrity Manual, as in effect on February 12, 2019); and</text></subitem><subitem id="H007DB8B734A9418EB2BF29F7908AA907"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more entities advocating on behalf of one or more individuals entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B.</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="HBAAB0A504CD2481F8ACC76800D13B93A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>With respect to each meeting convened pursuant to subclause (II)(aa), post on the public internet website of the contractor, not later than 14 days after such meeting is convened, a record of such meeting, which may include a video or audio recording of the meeting.</text></subclause><subclause id="HAD7A309B970142BA9A5E5103695D1C4A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Provide a period for submission of written public comment on such draft determination that begins on the date on which all records required to be posted with respect to such draft determination under subclause (III) are so posted and that is not fewer than 30 days in duration.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1DBC932CDA47441E8B1F12A05EDBFD50"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Finalizing a specified local coverage determination</header><subclause id="H2EB8268CF7C74AEFBDC9361CDE3CA781"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <internal-xref idref="HBCE368EE26054F73ACCE051CBE91143C" legis-path="(D)(ii)(II)">subclause (II)</internal-xref>, a Medicare administrative contractor that has entered into a contract with the Secretary under section 1874A shall, before a specified local coverage determination (in this subparagraph referred to as the <quote>final determination</quote>) takes effect, post on the Medicare Coverage Database and the public internet website of the contractor the following information:</text><item id="H0C68F26906644FF099A5A19CD0DBE160"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>A response to public comments received and the relevant issues raised at meetings convened pursuant to clause (i)(II)(aa) with respect to the draft determination.</text></item><item id="HE8A7EDF2D0E0439392D9D4C23A69A99A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The full text of all such public comments received.</text></item><item id="H04566D5C87124D279ECA46447997D724"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>The rationale for the final determination.</text></item><item id="HEBC7E0803EB748A6B7A9292569F92DDF"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>In the case that the Medicare administrative contractor considered qualifying evidence (as defined in clause (v)) in the development of the determination that was not described in the written notice provided pursuant to clause (i)(I), a description of such qualifying evidence.</text></item><item id="HBBFC0E25940F4941988BD3192B240277"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>An effective date for the final determination that is not less than 45 days after the date on which such determination is so posted.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HBCE368EE26054F73ACCE051CBE91143C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Logical outgrowth requirement</header><text>Notwithstanding <internal-xref idref="H2EB8268CF7C74AEFBDC9361CDE3CA781" legis-path="(D)(ii)(I)">subclause (I)</internal-xref>, a final determination may not take effect unless such determination is a logical outgrowth of the draft determination published under <internal-xref idref="H9022AD38E35347778C414BADC821F602" legis-path="(D)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8987C0A132734BD9AD119BD5EEE51669"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Specified local coverage determination defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>specified local coverage determination</quote> means, with respect to the relevant geographic area—</text><subclause id="H02003EFB291649DE8B83D66986F3204E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a new local coverage determination;</text></subclause><subclause id="H24CB0AE9297F470CB3508CE87CEFF157" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a revised local coverage determination that makes a substantive revision to one or more existing local coverage determinations (such as by imposing new requirements with respect to coverage of the relevant item or service or by changing any coding or billing information related to such determination); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H4150DFB98352460396FDE6114316CD57"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other local coverage determination specified by the Secretary pursuant to regulations.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H04256CBC905E4AB9B6A68BB5EBA52CA8"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Qualifying evidence defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>qualifying evidence</quote> means publicly available evidence of general acceptance by the medical community, such as published original research in peer-reviewed medical journals, systematic reviews and meta-analyses, evidence-based consensus statements, and clinical guidelines.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H800131812F3E404DB07D01900F57B2AE" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

