<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53B7ACE7F334421DA6D3B0F36C6206A8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 971 IH: Condemning the coercive actions of the People's Republic of China against Japan in response to statements regarding Taiwan and reaffirming the United States commitment to its allies in the Indo-Pacific region.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 971</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251219">December 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the coercive actions of the People's Republic of China against Japan in response to statements regarding Taiwan and reaffirming the United States commitment to its allies in the Indo-Pacific region.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States and Japan have maintained a close alliance since 1951 under the United States-Japan Mutual Security Treaty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Japan is a vital democratic partner and ally of the United States in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the maintenance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait is essential to the security and prosperity of the entire Indo-Pacific region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Japan has crucial security interests in the peace and stability of the Taiwan Strait given its geographical proximity and economic interdependence with the region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China (PRC) has engaged in diplomatic pressure, economic coercion, and military intimidation against Japan in response to Prime Minister Takaichi’s November 7, 2025, comments before the Japanese Diet that if the PRC were to use battleships against Taiwan or engage in a naval blockade of Taiwan involving the use of force, it could constitute a <quote>survival-threatening situation</quote> for Japan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to Japan’s peace and security legislation of 2015, Japan can exercise collective self-defense if an armed attack on another country <quote>in a close relationship with Japan</quote> threatens Japan’s survival;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 8, 2025, PRC Consul General Xue Jian posted on X responding to Takaichi’s statement, <quote>That filthy neck that barged in on its own—I’ve got no choice but to cut it off without a moment’s hesitation. Are you prepared for that?</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 10, 2025, PRC Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Lin Jian stated, Japan is interfering in <quote>China’s internal affairs and violates the one-China principle</quote>; <quote>Taiwan is China’s Taiwan</quote>; and that Japan’s security policy shifts are <quote>a provocation to the post-WWII order</quote> and that Takaichi’s remarks were <quote>extremely egregious</quote> and that <quote>China exppresses strong dissatisfaction and resolute oposition</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 11, 2025, a People’s Liberation Army Navy guided missile destroyer sailed eastward through the Osumi Strait in Japan’s near Kyushu Island;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 16, 2025, a China Coast Guard fleet patrolled the contested territorial waters of the Senkaku Islands to enforce its claim;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 6, 2025, Chinese J–15 fighter aircraft launched from the aircraft carrier Liaoning intermittently locked fire-control radar on Japanese Air Self-Defense Force F–15 fighter jets over international airspace southeast of Okinawa Prefecture on 2 separate occasions, constituting a dangerous and escalatory military action;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 9, 2025, 2 Russian Tu–95 nuclear-capable strategic bombers flew from the Sea of Japan toward the East China Sea, where they rendezvoused with 2 PRC H–6 bombers and 4 PRC J–16 fighters as they flew between Japan’s Okinawa and Miyako-jima Islands;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 14, 2025, the Government of the People’s Republic of China issued a travel advisory urging Chinese citizens to avoid traveling to Japan, citing alleged security concerns and claiming that Prime Minister Takaichi’s remarks had created significant risks to the personal safety of Chinese citizens in Japan;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, following the travel advisory, major Chinese airlines including Air China, China Eastern, and China Southern offered full refunds and free changes for Japan-bound flights with travel dates before March 28, 2026, resulting in the cancellation of approximately 430,000 tickets and an estimated loss of $1,200,000,000 to Japan’s tourism sector;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 19, 2025, the People’s Republic of China reimposed a complete ban on all Japanese seafood imports, just days after partially lifting restrictions, thereby disrupting legitimate trade and harming Japanese fisheries and exporters;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the freedom of expression and the right of sovereign nations to express their foreign policy positions are fundamental principles of international relations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas attempts to silence or punish allies of the United States for expressing concerns about regional peace and stability undermine the rules-based international order;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China’s coercive behavior toward Japan sets a dangerous precedent for other nations in the region; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has a vital national interest in supporting its allies against coercion and in maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific region: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H834E403E685C432EBC694A5304AE84D0"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9DBBC5A557874A95AFB2FB8C5726298C"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HDF53732EA99649C4AA40E1CC1CF4B77F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the coercive actions taken by the People’s Republic of China against Japan in response to Japan’s statements regarding Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF03911B46B1F4E59A45854F30E58D319"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaffirms the ironclad commitment of the United States to its alliance with Japan under the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H241F3E86BAE64D5F91D3E63D89D6EA00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the sovereignty of the Government of Japan and its right, along with other sovereign nations, to express views on matters of regional and international concern without fear of economic or military coercion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39ED0AFE420147A194A0555771E0927D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends the Government of Japan for its commitment to peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait in the face of pressure and coercion from the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C58D6FF3A81421E83F2440B1B974A63"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the shared interest of the United States and Japan in maintaining peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB73F3893ED74E02AC4C27F68A84669F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls upon the Government of the People’s Republic of China to cease its coercive actions against Japan, including travel bans, import restrictions, cultural cancellations, historical revisionism, and dangerous military provocations, and to engage in constructive dialogue on matters of regional concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H152222A1C4FE420EA0987E8A7EC741A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>urges the President of the United States to work with allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific region to counter coercive economic and diplomatic practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1BFBA8FBA79478CBB0C9B691C516A9D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>reaffirms the importance of a free and open Indo-Pacific region based on respect for international law, freedom of navigation, and peaceful resolution of disputes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47B0A5FBEE3C4A8CB1A621365D49FC2F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>commits to strengthening cooperation with Japan and other regional partners to deter aggression and maintain stability in the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

