<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KIN25600-V3F-6V-782"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3401 IS: Pathways to Prosperity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3401</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish, improve, or expand high-quality workforce development programs at community colleges, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pathways to Prosperity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE00A7E50BE2D48A086B5E39F6C645145"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strengthening community colleges workforce development grants program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle D of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3221">29 U.S.C. 3221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfecc90c9ffee43e3a9e0c862ffcc2fb3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 172 as section 173; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cc6c940e9624788a92f59b36f3a35d6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 171 the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA0A66A02FB374C75BD52F5B54D2E8444" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><section id="H284A6C91F84D40A483E86172F5EF677F"><enum>172.</enum><header>Strengthening community colleges workforce development grants program</header><subsection id="H3BC667F941B24C70BB8935D475E1A5C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text><paragraph id="HC6F45EB7845B40E3A7E11F9984B58B78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish, improve, or expand high-quality workforce development programs at community colleges; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC39135EE59A7473EBE2258B522FC9D0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to expand opportunities for individuals to obtain recognized postsecondary credentials that are nationally or regionally portable and stackable for high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2BFF8DDCB134198AC61FAF0BDAC7678"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strengthening community colleges workforce development grants program</header><paragraph id="HF91E955B24484CFDBA6D943BAE6A30AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section and not reserved under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall, on a competitive basis, make grants to eligible institutions to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H191782AB3A1D4CBC95D98F09574AFFCB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary may reserve not more than 2 percent for the administration of grants awarded under this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="H487CFEC9BC7F48DBB7949D56ABBED7B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing technical assistance and targeted outreach to support eligible institutions serving a high number or high percentage of low-income individuals or individuals with barriers to employment, and rural-serving eligible institutions, to provide guidance and assistance in the process of applying for grants under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80BF01ECF7B5494C9CC6902DF758F799"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluating and reporting on the performance and impact of programs funded under this section in accordance with subsections (f) through (h).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCCBBB1FC07554901BB9BD2D6A3DBFE03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Award period</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4a21409a5bf439d93dbc9583e8598d2"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id906065154041451e83d5d54e7cc9da32"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered grant</header><text>The term <term>covered grant</term> means—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbc02ed7cfd3433da9a6372a95057611"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the grant recipient received a first grant under this section for a period of more than 1 year, that first grant; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46a391f9a3ad42828102910e29068a23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the grant recipient received first and second grants described in paragraph (2)(B), that second grant.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BFD951ACF214C2F8958B0FF95C63043"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periods for first and second grants</header><text>For grants awarded under this section—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ae3ac83a5384921a12307bc143a2770"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each first grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of not more than 2 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7454dd875e24052b017facbafab1310"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a recipient that receives a first grant for a period of not more than 1 year, may receive a consecutive second grant for a period of not more than 1 year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0D633A3161542ADBA4675C4F2F1DC43"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible institution that receives a covered grant under this section may receive one or more subsequent grants under this section, but only as described in this paragraph. The institution may not receive a subsequent grant until the day that is 2 years after the period of the covered grant. The institution may receive a subsequent grant for a period of not more than 2 years, if the eligible institution demonstrates that, during the most recently completed grant period for a grant received under this section, such eligible institution achieved the levels of performance agreed to by the eligible institution with respect to the performance indicators specified in subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6693FBF1DC2744BB96A9B980A27C9A3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H895DAF3D4E6A4419B1371EAB27283EBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible institution shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA07250174D054AD5933B81B12448F07C"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Contents</header> <text>An application submitted by an eligible institution under paragraph (1) shall include a description of each the following:</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H06C9A4F484794B97B1E4501BCF063211">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The extent to which the eligible institution has demonstrated success building partnerships with employers in high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations to provide students with the skills needed for occupations in such industries and an explanation of the results of any such partnerships.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H08B8509BAC4841EFB68F508A2C4B25FF" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The methods and strategies the eligible institution will use to engage with employers in high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations, including any arrangements to place individuals who complete the workforce development programs supported by the grant into employment with such employers.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HFBF21E7AE82A4224AC604E64A0E68BE7">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>The proposed eligible institution and industry partnership that the eligible institution will establish or maintain to comply with subsection (e)(1), including—</text>
                                    <clause id="H1B0E84CE45124A9E822EDB013995E310">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the roles and responsibilities of each employer, organization, agency, or institution of higher education that the eligible institution will partner with to carry out the activities under this section; and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="HE3776E4BDED74177B63F23F81C394E2D">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the needs that will be addressed by such eligible institution and industry partnership.</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H11466D1717004BB382A7F37190CC7FD2">
                                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>One or more high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations that such eligible institution and industry partnership will target and real-time labor market data demonstrating that those industry sectors or occupations are aligned with employer demand in the geographic area to be served by the eligible institution.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H2493AA4D358F45AA84EDDEC99FBBD079">
                                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>The extent to which the eligible institution can—</text> <clause id="H1AB69AE118E54EF58C1F3434858FCA2B"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>leverage additional resources to support the programs to be funded with the grant, which shall include written commitments of any leveraged or matching funds for the proposed programs; and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="HE6C9705822214B5486703CE442DBCEF0">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>demonstrate the future sustainability of each such program.</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HECD09AAE217A4E7AB166814238B3BADC">
                                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>The steps the institution will take to ensure the high quality of each program to be funded with the grant, including the career pathways within such programs.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HD83A7CB0649C465685CF3293456BA6FF">
                                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>The population and geographic area to be served by the eligible institution, including the number of individuals the eligible institution intends to serve during the grant period.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H150EA6FE0DCE4C65958A24EF0D509F43">
                                    <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>The workforce development programs to be supported by the grant.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H707D9A9140B34635951E544B4659D3D1">
                                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>The recognized postsecondary credentials that are expected to be earned by participants in such workforce development programs and the related high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations for which such programs will prepare participants.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="tw1_nzq_5hc">
                                    <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text>The evidence upon which the education and skills development strategies to be used in such workforce development programs are based and an explanation of how such evidence influenced the design of the programs to improve education and employment outcomes.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H848B212FE5B84ABEB24306788BF53B4D">
                                    <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>How activities of the eligible institution are expected to align with the workforce strategies identified in—</text>
                                    <clause id="H3DE7A46A5A0A45FF9ABCC7395907F277">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>any State plan or local plan submitted under this Act by the State, outlying area, or locality in which the eligible institution is expected to operate;</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H351CD45DB439462EBD3DBD7C703BDCB2">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>any State plan submitted under section 122 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2342">20 U.S.C. 2342</external-xref>) by such State or outlying area; and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H7396E2110C8844ADA2AB67A360CC2D51">
                                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>any economic development plan of the chief executive of such State or outlying area.</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HF8883381625149289D5DEE3A0F58CCA9">
                                    <enum>(L)</enum>
 <text>The goals of the eligible institution with respect to—</text>
                                    <clause id="H44B1F373E82C441186BECCABD39FAF55">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>capacity building (as described in subsection (f)(1)(B)); and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H03E107B3E42045E3852ACFB47A517BCE">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the expected performance of individuals participating in the programs to be offered by the eligible institution, including with respect to any performance indicators applicable under section 116 or subsection (f) of this section.</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5D7EF9B3DB740F2BC755E93DC565C7D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration of previous experience</header><text>The Secretary may not disqualify an eligible institution from receiving a grant under this section solely because such institution lacks previous experience in building partnerships, as described in paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32A8E6D6F2EC4EA885D79FB264C21C5C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible institutions that—</text><subparagraph id="H99B79F10157F429EBFC19E46A581C6F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will use the grant to serve—</text><clause id="HDA5B14CCF3C94756A4302ED09636776D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals with barriers to employment; or</text></clause><clause id="H25102B70FCDE432D84B7B0FC146EED43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incumbent workers who need to gain or improve foundational skills to enhance their employability;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA23A579A0B548D697FEBA324084A6ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use competency-based assessments to award academic credit for prior learning for programs supported by the grant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB240B19841804417A5853F4DFA765E02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have, or will seek to have, the career education programs supported by the grant included on the list of eligible providers of training services under section 122(d) for the State in which the eligible institution is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13094316416E4602AA7FFEDE964C92ED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><paragraph id="H35ACEEDF199340F7A5E30D95BC86B65E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible institution and industry partnership</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out the activities specified in paragraphs (2) and (3), an eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall establish a partnership (or continue an existing partnership) with one or more employers in a high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sector or occupation (in this section referred to as an <quote>eligible institution and industry partnership</quote>) and shall maintain such partnership for the duration of the grant period. The eligible institution shall ensure that the partnership—</text><subparagraph id="HD34304FD2A1A490F9ECC66BDDED99A05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>targets one or more specific high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F572B876E02472891761272AC484BC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes collaboration with the workforce development system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2A94001262B424897259E8B07D49246"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serves dislocated workers, incumbent workers, and new entrants to the workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAECB6299F5534675B6F40FE32A9E2C4B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>uses an evidence-based program design that is appropriate for the activities carried out by the partnership;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E7E954A31E34D14BC910FCBC4111FB7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>incorporates work-based learning opportunities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC805E11B0894159AE8DA9E63D516021"><enum>(F)</enum><text>incorporates, to the extent appropriate, virtual service delivery to facilitate technology-enabled learning.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7426D490804948C28EB432BA89C143D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall, in consultation with the employers in the eligible institution and industry partnership described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H53864AF1F3354564A43F752726E6E548"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish, improve, or expand high-quality, evidence-based workforce development programs, which may be career pathway programs or work-based learning programs (including apprenticeship programs or preapprenticeships);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCEA4CEBE51F4E95ACAB3F24EBC092A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide career services to individuals participating in the programs funded with the grant to facilitate retention and program completion, which may include—</text><clause id="HAA746E316AD2414D90B4B42FC9FB40F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>career navigation, coaching, mentorship, and case management services, including providing information and outreach to individuals with barriers to employment to encourage such individuals to participate in programs funded with the grant; and</text></clause><clause id="H927C4D0C9C73420989D03AEFFE4E96FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing access to course materials, technological devices, required equipment, and other supports necessary for participation in and successful completion of such programs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78629A6AD44B44C68BD4E10B8D06762C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make available, in a format that is open, searchable, and easily comparable, information on—</text><clause id="HC4F378D96B5F432382EAF3F670182F0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>curricula and recognized postsecondary credentials offered through programs funded with the grant, including any curricula or credentials created or further developed using such grant, which for each recognized postsecondary credential, shall include—</text><subclause id="H9D82978DD9D546838F9883274B6BF0DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the issuing entity of such credential;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9F2EF416962A431C8185ECDB00BC2A12"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any third-party endorsements of such credential;</text></subclause><subclause id="H950262BEFAA64597989D979FD6C9F99E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the occupations for which the credential prepares individuals;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7621B8971BB2464A99BB204B1D65834A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the skills and competencies necessary to achieve to earn such credential;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3EE1E95F79F04378A4A8A9BD092D2844"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the level of mastery of such skills and competencies (including how mastery is assessed); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1B33636B53484287A088EB5B9CAE7836"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>any transfer value or stackability of the credential;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H362967C9A466459D878405E5FE79BDC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any skills or competencies developed by individuals who participate in such programs beyond the skills and competencies identified in clause (i)(IV); and</text></clause><clause id="H85D08FBF804D49B8AAEE2C403380F9A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>related employment and earnings outcomes on the primary indicators of performance described in subclauses (I) through (III) of section 116(b)(2)(A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBCB04BB9DA1401E894E20CD16318951"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the activities required under paragraph (2), an eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall, in consultation with the employers in the eligible institution and industry partnership described in paragraph (1), carry out one or more of the following activities:</text><subparagraph id="HD6334DD0DB2C46E794B3B2340039B6E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establish, improve, or expand—</text><clause id="H43779409F3644AE7926D5F2157D5B1EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>articulation agreements (as defined in section 486A(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1093a">20 U.S.C. 1093a(a)</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="HE6251C0FA002417F83DB20F944CCF829"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>credit transfer agreements;</text></clause><clause id="HA3323949C939413EB7405A0604D21CF5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>corequisite remediation programs that enable a student to receive remedial education services while enrolled in a postsecondary course rather than requiring the student to receive remedial education before enrolling in such a course;</text></clause><clause id="HDB0FF2884D524403B794BF01B0D319E3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>dual or concurrent enrollment programs;</text></clause><clause id="HCF201EB9F5C74F8E96FBBFA8FD848AF7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>competency-based education and assessment; or</text></clause><clause id="HF72C84FC3148446FAE2C9142C94125DB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>policies and processes to award academic credit for prior learning or for the programs described in paragraph (2)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H547530C4CFF845FB83E91847BAE830FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Establish or implement plans for providers of the programs described in paragraph (2)(A) to meet the criteria and carry out the procedures necessary to be included on the list of eligible providers of training services described in section 122(d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09E2036FA05440929A91C8E561BBB116"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Purchase, lease, or refurbish specialized equipment as necessary to carry out such programs, provided that not more than 15 percent of the funds awarded to the eligible institution under this section may be used for activities described in this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE124D83ADE04A82A0A98C84D9F7E202" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reduce or eliminate unmet financial need relating to the cost of attendance (as defined under section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>)) of participants in such programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H787E8A621F4B45D19814212065624330"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative cost limit</header><text>An eligible institution may use not more than 7 percent of the funds awarded under this section for administrative costs, including costs related to collecting information, analysis, and coordination for purposes of subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4BCBEFDA393474591FB7048740209CF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Levels of performance and performance reviews</header><paragraph id="HC245BED3D016437BB2AAC2F368A407CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop and implement guidance that establishes the levels of performance that are expected to be achieved by each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section. Such levels of performance shall be established on the following indicators:</text><subparagraph id="HFFB69EEBCE6B4ABB84F418BCD2F633D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each of the primary indicators of performance for adults described in section 116(b)(2)(A)(i), which shall be applied for all individuals who participated in a program that received funding from a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H775C194D0E024E069750EE0041668A5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible institution built capacity by—</text><clause id="HFACCD7C168174635880EB20FE1B8331F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increasing the breadth and depth of employer engagement and investment in workforce development programs in the high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations targeted by the eligible institution and industry partnership established or maintained by the eligible institution under subsection (e)(1);</text></clause><clause id="HBB9396BAD1094F3B9AA0117028616413"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designing or implementing new and accelerated instructional techniques or technologies, including the use of advanced online and technology-enabled learning (such as immersive technology); and</text></clause><clause id="H6C03A4D0D9044C46AC581701B3094F46"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increasing program and policy alignment across systems and decreasing duplicative services or service gaps.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A1BD94D31346A79021E39FD9B7AEFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to individuals who participated in a workforce development program funded with the grant—</text><clause id="HB5C6C6ED047E42B499EFEE440D69E4A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the percentage of participants who successfully completed the program; and</text></clause><clause id="HC747567ECF1949E89CF4DCE7C21ACE0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of the participants who were incumbent workers at the time of enrollment in the program, the percentage who advanced into higher-level positions during or after completing the program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2563C96B3994EF98F938FD785231CD5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation and determination of levels of performance</header><subparagraph id="H3DB699677C174F76AF3C0E3F80D0438A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing levels of performance in accordance with paragraph (1), the Secretary shall take into consideration the goals of the eligible institution pursuant to subsection (d)(2)(L).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D69FC9678354F2F9BDF16AB88929D1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After completing the consideration required under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall separately determine the levels of performance that will apply to each eligible institution, taking into account—</text><clause id="HE541EC33FB1E4027804950D4C5071AEC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the expected levels of performance of each eligible institution with respect to the goals described by the eligible institution pursuant to subsection (d)(2)(L); and</text></clause><clause id="H7A1C95FB9D9640529D47F2CA41FB409A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local economic conditions in the geographic area to be served by the eligible institution, including differences in unemployment rates and job losses or gains in the industry sectors or occupations identified in subsection (d)(2)(D).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD25DD1782F9D4FB4AEFA6FBB337B6BD9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice and acknowledgment</header><clause id="HAEDAE34BCA7D43EDBDD7B99B8B7F9B35"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide each eligible institution with a written notification that sets forth the levels of performance that will apply to the eligible institution, as determined under subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause id="H116B341D62C4413394F34B152DC31F18"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Acknowledgment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After receiving the notification described in clause (i), each eligible institution shall submit to the Secretary written confirmation that the eligible institution—</text><subclause id="HB40FC2CD951E4BABAE38E41126CB4A9E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>received the notification; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H85D2DFA900A84F549FFE673022DC34F2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>agrees to be evaluated in accordance with the levels of performance determined by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37F2F79D77B04AF8A848F2C4C04FA2FB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Performance reviews</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis during each year of the grant period, the Secretary shall evaluate the performance during such year of each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section in a manner consistent with the levels of performance determined for such institution pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80FDD79192AD45649D17C3F385F25169"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure to meet levels of performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After conducting an evaluation under paragraph (3), if the Secretary determines that an eligible institution did not achieve the levels of performance applicable to the eligible institution under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE0F9EEDBB2DD4C6C9D317DD3C0BE3556"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to the eligible institution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6A853B712BF41689A70C3FB3105EDE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a performance improvement plan for the eligible institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H250B9ADBFC8B4EA5B734BA6203D6DF8B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluations and reports</header><paragraph id="H91FEB3C90F974A3FB9AD4DC93434B98D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date on which the first grant is made under this section, the Secretary shall design and conduct an evaluation to determine the overall effectiveness of the eligible institutions receiving a grant under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB53B5037E974D0595B986C2398B8B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The evaluation of the effectiveness of eligible institutions conducted under paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of the general effectiveness of programs and activities supported by the grants awarded to such eligible institutions under this section, including the extent to which the programs and activities—</text><subparagraph id="HDF6F4A39E7C34B63ACCD9AF128E3F4D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developed new, or expanded existing, successful industry sector strategies, including the extent to which such eligible institutions deepened employer engagement and developed workforce development programs that met industry skill needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7298E68A052542CB8430B26D70912153"><enum>(B)</enum><text>created, expanded, or enhanced career pathways, including the extent to which the eligible institutions developed or improved competency-based education and assessment, credit for prior learning, modularized and self-paced curricula, integrated education and workforce development, dual enrollment in secondary and postsecondary career pathways, stacked and latticed credentials, and online and distance learning;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8F42A306CFA41CDA2A42FD9FB0C2865"><enum>(C)</enum><text>created alignment between eligible institutions and the workforce development system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H828F731D06E44C93B38A426E03F9F006"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assisted individuals with finding, retaining, or advancing in employment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H168F907B6B414B718762CED037182B57"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assisted individuals with earning recognized postsecondary credentials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H166DC7B383EE49CEAFA30D0AE76F1BCA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provided equal access to various demographic groups, including people of different geographic locations, ages, races, national origins, and sexes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H777856B8A48A49AA97089A9B8C22FA34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Design requirements</header><text>The evaluation under this subsection shall—</text><subparagraph id="H568037BF811F42209CDF149D83E34DEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be designed by the Secretary (acting through the Chief Evaluation Officer) in conjunction with the eligible institutions being evaluated;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4720AA7E442146058CD62A7125154091"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include analysis of program participant feedback and outcome and process measures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H654E5796D0C64AF29B94C183AA0E85F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>use designs that employ the most rigorous analytical and statistical methods that are reasonably feasible, such as the use of control groups.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC77ED473CB49A3A32947C784B5B3A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data accessibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Labor any data collected as part of the evaluation under this subsection. Such data shall be made available in an aggregated format that does not reveal personally identifiable information and that ensures compliance with relevant Federal laws, including section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69D3AD07295247459648124468FE6AF3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Publication and reporting of evaluation findings</header><text>The Secretary (acting through the Chief Evaluation Officer) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H60964A26D04144678ED3655D3A078DC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with the timeline determined to be appropriate by the Chief Evaluation Officer, publish an interim report on the preliminary results of the evaluation conducted under this subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30600F9D802A430FAC51C0BA4731A3F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date on which the evaluation is completed under this subsection, submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives a report on such evaluation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57212DE451E049B4AAEFE2A73B6A8A70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after such completion date, publish and make the results of such evaluation available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Labor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H862016B88053430CBEA560DDDBD10A45"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>The Secretary shall make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Labor, in transparent, linked, open, and interoperable data formats, the following information:</text><paragraph id="HC7E66D106BA24CE1B10318ED233A5ECC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The performance of each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section on the capacity-building performance indicator set forth under subsection (f)(1)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA67A0650FCBF411195DDB0ED36E09614"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The performance of each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section on the workforce development participant outcome performance indicators set forth under subsection (f)(1)(C).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4636C4EF24248E18643DB04DF5539CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of individuals enrolled in workforce development programs funded with a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C304C88465B4172878219B61377349F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HDCF7584E10E14140A8ECD1A0A826740C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chief evaluation officer</header><text>The term <term>Chief Evaluation Officer</term> means the head of the independent evaluation office located in the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Policy of the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A5C73D766BF43B8949584FAA73B2A82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community college</header><text>The term <term>community college</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA112795ABBB04782B53C53ED05BE783E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), at which—</text><clause id="H06E3E0994B8140EC894EAEC28FE4DD78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest degree awarded is an associate degree; or</text></clause><clause id="H26EB2467F8704E3CA3EC563683D93494"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an associate degree is the most frequently awarded degree;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DF7229263DD4E2EAB3CC0BA89639BD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a branch campus of a 4-year public institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)), if, at such branch campus—</text><clause id="H508B8C5B65D84706B51A658B07AEF9A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest degree awarded is an associate degree; or</text></clause><clause id="H9E6B3203EF12412BA7A07FC76C6D7D09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an associate degree is the most frequently awarded degree;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9630F028A54C448BACB71FCDA554A471"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a 2-year Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316(b)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)(3)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1F5AF34645949F1A6821B68B4C1EE92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a degree-granting Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316(b)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)(3)</external-xref>)) at which—</text><clause id="H7F6AE92F3F3944E8B2EEA789A99E0A51"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest degree awarded is an associate degree; or</text></clause><clause id="H7DB196514F49472CA114ED48107FFD11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an associate degree is the most frequently awarded degree.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C4433FC827C4043B883F004678BE156"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H02BE7CA741A64DF4BC6A3BB21AE5B9AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a community college;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC389AA792E8248B1AB01CC9EB51A3B5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a postsecondary vocational institution (as defined in section 102(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1993D43A323C4632A48451C400894987"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a consortium of such colleges or institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECFE01EE608247A49B8E7A5E6E65697A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Funds made available under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, and local public funds made available for carrying out the activities described in this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id911fa6b972354858aa4e3b177423e9c3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended by striking the item relating to section 172 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9921DB2805AC4B1BBA5E80ABF1411F83"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 172. Strengthening community colleges workforce development grants program.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 173. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

