<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26E52-H12-P4-426"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4723 IS: Eliminate Chinese Organized Crime Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4723</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a program to provide assistance to strengthen the capacity of law enforcement agencies in Latin America and the Caribbean to prosecute Chinese organized criminal groups and Chinese government-linked organizations engaged in criminal activity.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idb5d5fc728a7a41b89e3a5c10e6be18c1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminate Chinese Organized Crime Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="iddd251fee82734abcaf06c792f98d1362" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program to provide assistance to build the capacity of Latin American and Caribbean law enforcement agencies to disrupt Chinese organized criminal groups</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 8 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2291">22 U.S.C. 2291 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc828500de2f748af808e3044f55b2f94"><section id="id71fe2b8bf9ef435e8d73432a29585ab9"><enum>490A.</enum><header>Program to provide assistance to build the capacity of Latin American and Caribbean law enforcement agencies to disrupt Chinese organized criminal groups</header><subsection id="id176fb97bea4f4787afda9608dd5e3229"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 660, the Secretary of State may establish a program to provide assistance to strengthen the capacity of law enforcement agencies of the countries described in subsection (c) to help such agencies collect information on, disrupt, and prosecute China-linked transnational criminal organizations that are engaged in narcotics trafficking, money laundering, illicit finance, transnational repression, foreign interference, and other related activities the Secretary determines are appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="id63eb65445d9445c596a9840276e934c8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>Assistance authorized under subsection (a) shall be provided in coordination with the Attorney General and, if appropriate, the Director of National Intelligence.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb4940790915493c9ef1f59d9a9f45c2"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance described</header><text>Assistance authorized under subsection (a) may include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd981fef8f46448b99325a33242dcaaa4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consultation between law enforcement agencies in the countries described in subsection (e) and Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies with experience investigating, disrupting, and prosecuting China-linked transnational criminal organizations that are operating in the United States or abroad;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc61bdd53c57f46229ab1aeacc7ade0bd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training regarding financial investigations, money laundering and illicit finance prosecution, and asset forfeiture related to China-linked transnational criminal organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28777d198a3642ac9103a2d3d2d16841"><enum>(3)</enum><text>technical assistance, including digital forensics, telecommunications intercept coordination, and all-source and open-source intelligence relevant to China-linked transnational criminal organizations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id217ed3693485486ca9b7ca5deb901075"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support for vetting and screening programs to ensure foreign law enforcement agencies receiving assistance are not compromised by China-linked transnational criminal organizations, in accordance with the prohibition under section 487.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf03957c40440447fa55c3868f620ef90"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship certain certifications</header><paragraph id="id35fea0dc6b76426fae453aaa00b4905a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding a determination under section 490(a)(1) that a country has demonstrably failed to adhere to its obligations under applicable international counternarcotics agreements, assistance authorized under subsection (a) may be provided to such country if the Secretary of State determines that providing such assistance is in the national interest of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a5f7367b0864d9fa047aa2e2e5830aa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary of State may not provide assistance pursuant to paragraph (1) unless not later than 15 days before providing such assistance, the Secretary submits to the appropriate congressional committees a determination that providing such assistance is in the national interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idefe3dd4bd03f45d08e88d00178772d8c"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Countries described</header><text>The foreign countries described in this subsection are countries in Latin America and the Caribbean where China-linked transnational criminal organizations engage in criminal activities, including narcotics trafficking, money laundering, illicit finance, and foreign interference.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf082f17f6f9f43e795a9665ebb458e3d"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report on Chinese organized crime in Latin America</header><paragraph id="id50e5e6041ab644a79bb6d7f3a91d4485"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><subparagraph id="idb8e78988acea4dbbbb258435d42ce22c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies all United States assistance provided to countries under this section, including each country that received assistance and a description of the assistance provided;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaabc9cc4ed9482ebd2fcca56c54b084"><enum>(B)</enum><text>summarizes known organized criminal activity by China-linked transnational criminal organizations taking place in Latin American or the Caribbean; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96ac3980a7f94b03ad80a9bad586201d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>summarizes all known instances of the People’s Republic of China providing law enforcement assistance or support to the countries described in subsection (c) to facilitate or disrupt such criminal activity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3c421375a3e40af8e519b0492167c52"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifies any mutual legal assistance treaty requests or other such assistance submitted by each county that receives assistance described in subparagraph (A), and the status of such requests.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc76b171ab33d4a4aa6b288a5c0fd0f28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classified form</header><text>To the extent possible, the report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, with a classified annex, if necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d7c28eb1a81401dbd5d85fb61640911"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="iddf8c56ea56434d7380717aca3b792a26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id6ef820e82b4c44b1aae9bfa0a0617c3c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc19d36f31ad46f28566934392b00a84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f705eb8a7c940cb974144eb227dc265"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd67cb04a524b413080857d86b2ce2b57"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id956a4d6164194aa69e641c6b31a0739c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Caucus on International Narcotics Control of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f425e38da344668a735efddc1f30b30"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1005fdadad4640f5a997f0aee90eee7c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6e88b5c2bd3407490673160d2e19e19"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a66f57ad1384fdc811b3a7f36540f8b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f168a15475449318344c5502fe161ae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>China-linked transnational criminal organization</header><text>The term <term>China-linked transnational criminal organization</term> means an organization that—</text><subparagraph id="id091b155bcbc24266af723a23b2a53ffc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes 1 or more foreign person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id387955a87c864df9b21577114a61fad9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engages in or facilitates an ongoing pattern of serious criminal activity involving the jurisdictions of at least 2 foreign states, including the People’s Republic of China, or 1 foreign state and the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id377b3c59a28b4c0fac795eb9aefb5057"><enum>(C)</enum><text>threatens the national security, foreign policy, or economy of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf5aed59412d4122963517795c6bc68a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>meets any other criteria the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

