<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26422-9W7-7H-71H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4360 IS: Investigation Status and Governance for Honest Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require that the Employee Benefit Security Administration make annual reports to Congress on investigations relating to enforcement and on adverse interest agreements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2B60A634F7FD4E97B2F702F874C36959"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6B06B8D3C3164453B69DAAD0053C59DE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investigation Status and Governance for Honest Transparency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INSIGHT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H286F9E2232F64222AD66B89AD3F5F337"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on investigations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 504 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1134">29 U.S.C. 1134</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8700B283ECAE4168A32682BF66425F7D"><subsection id="HDCF65CE17DE345C09D4D5ADDE1A7796B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report on investigations</header><paragraph id="H2E2EB0DCDA304E4FBA2645274E40B1E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of each year following the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the status of cases in enforcement status, including investigations that are active, or in relation to which the Secretary asserted investigative authority or engaged in targeted compliance monitoring, under subsection (a), during the preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB6DD8ABA8444DFA9FDF90B2D24D6933"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><subparagraph id="H316BBE53CB6E4BEC878C3F28D0EBFA7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following information in relation to each investigation under subsection (a):</text><clause id="H05CE772D142640EB9248F1D6156603D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The regional or district office, or any other office, of the Employee Benefit Security Administration that opened the investigation.</text></clause><clause id="HF5D54C585EED41CEB5FC1BDC19238C1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The date the investigation was opened.</text></clause><clause id="HABD1093C4429456D9F3FA54A4CA9EB04"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The date on which the Secretary first requested documents from the target of the investigation.</text></clause><clause id="H00E93B44F8DA4356B5412E16D7056DD6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In relation to the date on which the Secretary first requested documents from the target of the investigation in relation to such investigation—</text><subclause id="HA8BDCD5FA8894AA88B42EAC9AA959306"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the investigation was concluded within the 36-month period beginning on the date of such request; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H17F255EA8FAE4107BEA89E8B37807D43"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such investigation has not been concluded by the end of such 36-month period—</text><item id="HC837C2ECD7D14A1D9F1690EE81402109"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>information on why such investigation has not been concluded; and</text></item><item id="H868E174AF25A4264BBC3FD01211E70C3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estimated date of conclusion.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0E0DF83F3634D2D96F3FC9A7807F628"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excluded information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report shall not include any information that identifies any private party to the investigation, including any plan, plan sponsor, fiduciary, service provider, employee, or participant or beneficiary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02B453C95E354F6DAEB6E8C048099640"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conclusion of investigations</header><text>For the purposes of paragraph (A)(iv), an investigation shall not be considered concluded until the later of—</text><clause id="H9F7FF0C90EA348618D6467F534FE979A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the Secretary ceases to assert investigative authority in relation to such investigation; or</text></clause><clause id="HB88DF7AA398C43A3A568A9CBB20008D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, terminates any targeted compliance monitoring,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">in each case as memorialized in a closing letter delivered to the target of the investigation or the party subject to compliance monitoring. In the event that the issues or topics under investigation change during the course of an investigation, the Secretary’s continuing assertion of authority under this section shall be treated as a continuing investigation and not as a separate investigation.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H2ECB048C8DEB413CA59C3ED922B55020"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on adverse interest agreements</header><subsection id="H2E68EA526D074FB5BF9246E379FFCE85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 504 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1134">29 U.S.C. 1134</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1876671E3F8E4784BDC80F65745AB3CA"><subsection id="HD8AD89EABDC04078912F8120A4AAD6AF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Collaboration with plaintiff attorneys</header><paragraph id="HC2E1A05C41754FF3BD0BD017A05CACDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event that the Secretary provides adverse assistance to an individual, prior to providing the adverse assistance, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H76C229B37DA94B3DA1E97A4CDD5BEE8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enter into a written agreement with the individual that details the nature and scope of such assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DE61F625D1949CDA6779FE0F4570726"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a copy of such agreement to any employer, plan sponsor, or fiduciary that may be directly and adversely impacted by such assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFA73D39F55547C7BFF71712715F4A01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adverse assistance defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>adverse assistance</term> means assistance or advice, including the disclosure of information as described in subsection (a), that is directed specifically toward an attorney for potential use in a civil action under section 502(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8994691F6CE4149974CA74528D6CF73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="HBEDBA4D6A00C4665B98C880F383633D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, and by December 31 of each year that begins after such date, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing information on all agreements to provide adverse assistance in effect for the preceding fiscal year, including, in relation to each such agreement—</text><clause id="H5E2C22152C6042D4A756066DE3DA3B67"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a copy of the agreement, with any information described in subparagraph (B)(ii) redacted;</text></clause><clause id="HEC28C780A0D04025A6449F8E0BB66F1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date the agreement was entered into;</text></clause><clause id="HF24BEF0C0104467B86CCE1A22BBA85D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a detailed description of the nature and scope of the assistance provided during the fiscal year, including—</text><subclause id="HE3C4D677AA8048C387047036D8417DDD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the information shared, including the source, type, and amount of the information, and the date on which such information was shared;</text></subclause><subclause id="H639EDAB7D01D4B7B879DA576408D3F2A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a log of verbal communications, including—</text><item id="H4E770C042E614FF98821357BF71313E6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the date of each communication;</text></item><item id="HF05FD33AA9E14220B2861271956478D2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the parties engaged in such communication;</text></item><item id="H630E1EC372BA43F8BBF23153AD4DC983"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the mode of communication; and</text></item><item id="H4DC55542F3C24EB0BB9253E7368BC932"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the nature of any information shared; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H18241C2F2BF94375A66FE291947FBEBF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a log of meetings, including—</text><item id="HCACB464ECB8F4C13808B00349BBEAE26"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the date of each meeting;</text></item><item id="HA6EF1A73ABAF4BB9AF525E681F1FF969"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the parties present at the meeting;</text></item><item id="H46801B8764AD4A2C95F29244768E32E1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>mode of the meeting; and</text></item><item id="H507A335EF3604474864148702FB679B7"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the purpose of such meeting and the nature of any information shared; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HDBA36B3699764B7FA01D0975C9A9D0D5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an explanation of how such agreement is consistent with the public policy of promoting the voluntary sponsorship of employee benefit plans subject to this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B9EE24B3DF043F6A0967F1DA8186C18"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identifying information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report described under paragraph (A)—</text><clause id="H23F29C324C5548839ED4E204EC2EA258"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall identify the parties to each agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="H4311EC118B614E60AE87468CEC05B62C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not include any information that may be used to identify any other person (including an employer, plan sponsor, plan fiduciary, service provider, or any other potential defendant).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H044F4D14225C4103A68CD1C4D7B10D6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8115472A12ED4B03BBBF7F01D5BB5690"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to any adverse assistance provided on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD640E4877CE343A8BF3C139256BF9F5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing agreements</header><text>For the purposes of section 504(g)(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1134">29 U.S.C. 1134(f)(1)</external-xref>) (as added by subsection (a)), if, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor takes the actions required in paragraphs (A) and (B) of such section 504(g)(1) in relation to an existing arrangement to provide adverse assistance, the Secretary shall be deemed to have taken such actions prior to providing such adverse assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H40B1DB2B0F8949D3B446065879DF2311"><enum>4.</enum><header>Private pension plans as integral to the continued well-being and security of employees and their dependents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDE2AA4588DB4C9AA5BD0BE6B26D233C"><subsection id="HEF2BEB26D10C4941AFFA10FA33D39426"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that the retirement security of millions of employees and their dependents is directly impacted by the voluntary sponsorship and maintenance of pension plans. It is hereby declared to be a policy of this Act to promote, encourage, and facilitate the voluntary establishment and maintenance of, and contribution to, such plans.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

