<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07F57727E83B48FDBD28A06570365506" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5816 IH: Halting Education Loan Payments during Federal Employment Disruptions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5816</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251024">October 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit penalties, interest accrual, negative credit implications, or other adverse actions for qualified student loans for Federal employees during a lapse in Federal funding.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA2831D28B8A24B2F866F40A45F35D61F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9B4BE6DACA11495E92475FE753C7A49F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Halting Education Loan Payments during Federal Employment Disruptions Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HELP FEDs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF2F7D77704AE451F94ECDAF9CC987664"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H10461BAF4E3548DEB9D4DBF6956D2949"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal employee</header><text>The term <term>Federal employee</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0DC4B76ED8584C2CBA21935D7F99E9D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee as defined in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A5CCBA8F2514C638C5B35F6D7B13319"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee as defined in section 2107 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22C6E431119E432D9E0760736AA37035"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a judicial employee as defined in section 13101(9) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE9FE075D6D2478998FF4E46FA878A92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified education loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified education loan</term> means any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071–1087ii</external-xref>), including loans held by the Department of Education or contracted loan servicers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB50A82C0B7D44C63AC03459C1A697EED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Involuntary disruption of pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>involuntary disruption of pay</term> means a situation where a Federal employee does not receive their scheduled wages due to a lapse in funding resulting in the Federal Government to cease operations as identified under section 1341 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFE4DA68B88804DE2B3833E861E4CB567"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection from penalties and adverse credit actions during involuntary disruption of pay</header> 
<subsection id="HB873E15FE93E46CBA0CE25B8912DAA8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver of penalties and late fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal employee shall be assessed any late fee, penalty, or other adverse action on any qualified education loan for any payment missed due during a period of involuntary disruption of pay.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD714FA52D96042B7AA2A0417050B42FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver on interest accrual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal employee shall incur additional interest on any qualified education loan during a period of involuntary disruption of pay.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7FE4813F512343E0876BD432BD86B919"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No adverse credit reporting</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall coordinate with credit reporting agencies and loan servicers to ensure that no adverse information related to delayed or missed payments of a Federal employee described in subsection (a) is furnished to any consumer reporting agency, as defined in section 603 of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB534A2A8137D43939992543507BEAB16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Retroactive application</header><text>This section shall apply retroactively to any instance of involuntary disruption of pay occurring on or after October 1, 2025. The Secretary shall coordinate with credit reporting agencies and loan servicers to remove any adverse credit information that was inappropriately reported.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H37959A20F43049E4A70360475ED037BD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation</header> 
<subsection id="H7FC11099D92544819DDAB3F1EBDFE85C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the Clerk of the House of Representatives, and Secretary of the Senate, shall issue regulations and guidance for the Department, borrowers, loan servicers, and credit agencies necessary to implement this Act within 30 days of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEAB6DD9C667B4566A722C33297D8EC32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance and enforcement</header><text>Loan servicers and credit reporting agencies shall cooperate fully with the Secretary of Education in implementing this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5C57B5C25C744B7E88B0985320C499BB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to excuse the full repayment of qualified education loans or to eliminate any otherwise existing repayment obligation.</text></section> <section id="HBAB99DF523724265934ABCAAC25EA2B0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act shall not be affected.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

