<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26061-147-1W-NTL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 592 ATS: Supporting the designation of 2026 as the “International Year of the Woman Farmer” to recognize and honor the critical role of women in agriculture.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 592</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of 2026 as the <quote>International Year of the Woman Farmer</quote> to recognize and honor the critical role of women in agriculture.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States proudly recognizes its agricultural heritage and acknowledges the vital role that women have played in advancing agriculture both domestically and globally;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women are essential to agriculture, serving as leaders on and off the farm, with more than 1,200,000 female agricultural producers in the United States comprising 36 percent of the agricultural producers of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to their leadership in farming and ranching operations, women in agriculture continue to make significant contributions across a wide range of sectors, including research and development, manufacturing, sales and distribution, agricultural education, agribusiness, and advocacy, benefitting communities in the United States and around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2026 has been designated as the International Year of the Woman Farmer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women professionals and leaders in agriculture in the United States should be recognized and celebrated for their contributions during this designated year: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idab5a70b43fcc48d1bb70413791107edb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of 2026 as the <quote>International Year of the Woman Farmer</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc8a0d516d3044799261f22896caaed2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the critical role of women in agriculture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59fb9a476ef14c00908001f6cae8f5dd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all citizens to—</text><subparagraph id="id33c6b64196b646e8a8b7af7fffa828f2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>honor and recognize the contributions of women working in agriculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d5f134a9c3047b58bdd266f3775e1b0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>celebrate the positive impact these women have on the food systems and agricultural workforce of the United States by encouraging and empowering women to—</text><clause id="idd92b89bee7004100bb535282eb3241b7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pursue careers in agriculture, a high-demand and essential field;</text></clause><clause id="id07d9ae4c45eb4cfdb353c50c02ac1957"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cultivate leadership opportunities; and</text></clause><clause id="id26af304d06794a06b4b7cbcebed95ef0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>help feed a growing and hungry world.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

