<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H20CB677D3F904736A632ABE786774A62" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6230 IH: Tehran Incitement to Violence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6230</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To designate certain individuals as specially designated global terrorists.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HA0A0304A014F43AFA6F5D92E47FDC3B1" style="OLC">
<section id="H25E3FD8EA5FB4BBBB287AA7B40E50D79" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tehran Incitement to Violence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA722FC415BFF47B09D9E4E27EB85A43F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HE8DB340EC59D40A8A79A517E5AFC7EDC"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Abdolmajid Kharghani, a hardline cleric and Quranic studies expert, reportedly revealed an online fundraising campaign to the assassination of U.S. President Donald Trump and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. Khargani claimed that this could be achieved in Europe with $10–$20 million.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEF84FC7264A4F21925D0B1AC4EC4E03"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following Abdolmajid Khargani’s remarks, the website THAAR.IR was launched to crowdsource funding to execute the aforementioned assassination attempts, which has since claimed to have raised more than $20 million. This figure and fund have not been independently verified.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6AF916147016454388F74D461C3E4847"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During and following the 12-Day War against the Islamic Republic of Iran’s nuclear, missile, and military facilities, Iranian clerics and various other political and religious figures have charged U.S. President Donald Trump and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu with being a Mohareb (one who wares against God), a Mahdur al-Dam (one whose blood must be spilled), a Mufsid fil-Arz (a spreader of corruption on earth), and a Kafir Harbi (a waring infidel) all of which under Islamic Law (Sharia) invite violence against the offender.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26882F93E0034DD49BB3DFDD62F8C08D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Hossein Mazaheri has issued a fatwa against President Trump, Prime Minister Netanyahu, and others charging them with the crime of Moharebeh which under the Islamic penal system has had various punishments throughout which include the death penalty, crucifixion, cross amputation, and exile. Under the laws of the Islamic Republic of Iran, this charge carries the death penalty.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A9284802041480794F1DCA9F3281833"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Jafar Sobhani, a senior member of the Assembly of Experts, similarly issued a fatwa charging President Trump, Prime Minister Netanyahu, and others, with the crime of Moharebeh.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF11E9F428064E99A26144458EECD07E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alireza Panahian, a senior member of the Office of Supreme Leader, is an extremist cleric affiliated with—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4E6DEC308DA34D659CDE51283D8D9F82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFAB5FDC44F6456DA3947E1C8C1BC758"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the IRGC’s intelligence-security apparatus, which is involved in gross human rights violations in Iran and proliferating terrorism abroad;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H27FD328B6B4140FF941F9BDAA40765AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the inner ring of Mojtaba Khamenei’s personal network; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB9E237A52C84F9CB0B1BACCB1FFE5EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the so-called <quote>Habib Circle</quote>, one of the regime’s highest informal security-intelligence networks, which has committed human rights violations and is involved in terrorist activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H523D1621514F479B9C8E188C01BED702"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alireza Panahian has promoted the fatwas of Ayatollah Naser Makarem-Shirazi, a member of Iran’s Assembly of Experts and an illicit profiteer in Iran’s sugar market, and Ayatollah Hossein Nouri Hamedani, disciple and former representative in Europe of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, which includes a call to assassinate President Trump and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu by charging each as a Moharebeh.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC7F0EE1E3CC49018BEE3C204CA3D720"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Alireza Panahian functions as a leader in the IRGC’s antisemitic and violent, Islamist extremist indoctrination program, including serving as one of the key ideological architects of the IRGC’s militaristic and apocalyptic doctrine of Mahdism.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58CB00F7816143E6B0001E5215E247D5"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The apocalyptic doctrine of Mahdism as understood within the confines of Iran’s political and religious system after the 1979 Islamic Revolution advocates for the destruction of Israel to herald the return of the Hidden 12th Imam.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H020D5D75D4894F7EB8F639F07436793C"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Abbas Kaabi, a member of the leadership committee of the Assembly of Experts, an affiliate with the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, a key figure in the establishment of Hezbollah in Lebanon, and who possesses extensive ties to Iran-backed Shia militias in Iraq, has publicly endorsed the charge of Moharebeh against President Donald Trump, Prime Minister Netanyahu, and others.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAAF6EDDAD034BF4A2520B37770A5172"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Ahmad Khatami, a member of the Guardian Council and Assembly of Experts and Interim Friday Prayer Leader of Tehran, has been sanctioned by the European Union for human rights abuses due to his egregious conduct and has called for the executions of President Donald J. Trump and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2D7E36FA029459699EE701EFBDDD636"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Mohsen Araki, a member of the Assembly of Experts and Expediency Council and the Supreme Leader’s former representative to the United Kingdom and head of the Islamic Center of England, has threated President Donald J. Trump and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu by saying <quote>their lives and property are no longer protected</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3494EBEA2A5B4428BFACF8D5573919ED"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Mohsen Araki declared the United States Government, including President Donald J. Trump, as a <quote>hostile infidel government by all Muslims</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DBD085F8A1543FB932A46B2B42FCB00"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Qom Seminary, and including the organization’s head Ayatollah Alireza Arafi, has endorsed the charge of Moharebeh against President Donald J. Trump, Prime Minister Benjamin Netenyahu, and others. Accordingly, professors, students, and administrators have signed and released a statement declaring their readiness to implement the fatwa, thus endangering President Donald J. Trump and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu’s lives.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF86A6825B1A142A0967552352799ADEA"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These Fatwas and charges of Moharebeh by senior clerical leaders from Iran’s state-linked clerical institutions and religious leaders are a clear incitement of violence and consequently endanger the lives of President Donald J. Trump and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, thus imperiling the national security of the United States and Israel.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H951AA7A15F514B32A183A20F41958FEE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination on certain organizations</header> <subsection id="H9968185FE4194442AC6F62D170F2FD63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for a period not to exceed 6 years, the Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination as to whether the individuals and entities described in subsection (b) meet the criteria for designation in subsection (c).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB63F22A947864FC5BC0DEB6C77592B58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individuals and entities described</header><text>The individuals and entities described in this subsection include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H43339EBB1F714809A2F7369483C396BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Naser Makarem-Shirazi.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8EF9C54A3DDC46E69D74862ED7746EDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ayatollah Hossein Nouri Hamedani.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F6E3AB21FF44213AF4E1429685426B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Ayatollah Hossein Mazaheri.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3EF9E8470264C5CA10269E116DE628F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ayatollah Ja’far Sobhani.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19538A324578424DA4FA73D1D04E0889"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Alireza Panahian.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D7971A355D64E759FBFA5899F791D72"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ayatollah Abbas Kaabi.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1981B80A31C64EB58422508C179FA1B8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Abdolmajid Kharghani.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAD08B47BFA0244D4AAB6D35468089E98"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ahmad Khatami.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H206A1424AF694196861B496E6B85CA9C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Mohsen Araki.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H54054D5CF7224AA896F26CBD661D0BB2"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Alireza Arafi.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H209DA505907D4D87BA07E7BBA15EAF62"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Qom Seminary (Howzeh Elmieh Qom).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43FC53123BC04333AA71F9A45A6D924E"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting (IRIB).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF182BFA32F84DDD94F18C46781CC956"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Assembly of Experts.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA951AB3E7C74F36BC3FF3DC2A507BEE"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Expediency and Discernment Council.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BF064F4E3BB44F384B0DDEFD446A246"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Guardian Council.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC21B0C908DEF41D1B9B58EA3880BBF52"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Ayatollah Ahmad Alamolhoda.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4A995F5F8F24390AA4C9713FF20613F"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Society of Seminary Teachers of Qom (Jaameh Modaresin Howzeh Elmieh Qom).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5C55B178E76B435C910A11F8D125E372"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Hojjat al-Eslam Amin Assadpour.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5EF171D00BDD4B6FA12C8B991B1941A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The criteria for a designation described in this subsection includes the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HE521270DA6384299A678D283DFF10FBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31917E5CCCDB4326AF4E583D8CF4BEC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>FTO.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDB4C1CD630B24E04BC8B354E813BEF71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>GLOMAG.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4C0AA19C593443883CD068C0408D7E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Conduct or status that meets the criteria for designation under the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H8A4702CE126D4926A2B802AA1CECDCC4"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">13949—Blocking Property of Certain Persons with Respect to the Conventional Arms Activities of Iran.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B0ACB45ED5A46D6A843AC8243F8CD96"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>13902—Imposing Sanctions With Respect to Additional Sectors of Iran.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H08C1F594CF264910802394D997CD4562"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>13876—Imposing Sanctions with Respect to Iran.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H150DB6F20D5847A28B703E47C9AAC70C"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>13871—Imposing Sanctions with Respect to the Iron, Steel, Aluminum, and Copper Sectors of Iran.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H493B91FD7C454D6EA8700E4B234C9D3E"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>13846—Reimposing Certain Sanctions With Respect To Iran.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45F7CF3E1A6D4A71A7C519B5325A61F6"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>13608—Prohibiting Certain Transactions With and Suspending Entry Into the United States of Foreign Sanctions Evaders With Respect to Iran and Syria (Effective Date—May 01, 2012).</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9FBB9B1A598E4194A995CFF680D75C97"> <enum>(G)</enum> <text>13606—Blocking the Property and Suspending Entry Into the United States of Certain Persons With Respect to Grave Human Rights Abuses by the Governments of Iran and Syria via Information Technology (Effective Date—April 23, 2012).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE73AA47CC644E7781C3720EDB010582"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text>13599—Blocking Property of the Government of Iran and Iranian Financial Institutions (Effective Date—February 06, 2012).</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H116590966C5F4043B467C709ED7B3BDC"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>13553—Blocking Property of Certain Persons With Respect to Serious Human Rights Abuses By The Government of Iran and Taking Certain Other Actions (Effective Date—September 29, 2010).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

