<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H20CB677D3F904736A632ABE786774A62" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6230 EH: Tehran Incitement to Violence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6230</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate certain individuals as specially designated global terrorists.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA0A0304A014F43AFA6F5D92E47FDC3B1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H877A23AA28C14ECE992EF5E9477CA9D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tehran Incitement to Violence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF68DCC8229754C9988D2480699F8705B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8C184CD52B14441884E9302A46585CCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Abdolmajid Kharghani, a hardline cleric and Quranic studies expert, reportedly revealed an online fundraising campaign to the assassination of U.S. President Donald Trump and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. Khargani claimed in a state-television appearance that this could be achieved in Europe with $10–$20 million.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E4D5CA13546479BB52C8E0A1B83B786"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following Abdolmajid Khargani’s remarks, the website THAAR.IR was launched to crowdsource funding to execute the aforementioned assassination attempts, which has since claimed to have raised more than $20 million. This figure and fund have not been independently verified.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FE49A74CEC4417F8A52650401FC1E84"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During and following the 12-Day War against the Islamic Republic of Iran’s nuclear, missile, and military facilities, Iranian clerics and various other political and religious figures have variously described U.S. President Donald Trump and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu as being a <quote>Mohareb</quote> (one who wares against God), a <quote>Mahdur al-Dam</quote> (one whose blood must be spilled), a <quote>Mufsid fil-Arz</quote> (a spreader of corruption on earth), and a <quote>Kafir Harbi</quote> (a waring infidel) all of which under Islamic Law (Sharia) invite violence against the offender.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09A6467EDCB94A799432FEA83E12AF74"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Hossein Mazaheri has reportedly issued a fatwa against President Trump, Prime Minister Netanyahu, and others charging them with the crime of Moharebeh which under the Islamic penal system has had various punishments throughout which include the death penalty, crucifixion, cross amputation, and exile. Under the laws of the Islamic Republic of Iran, this charge carries the death penalty.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H744F0813055346C8BE6F1346C3086348"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Jafar Sobhani, a senior member of the Assembly of Experts, reportedly issued a fatwa charging President Trump, Prime Minister Netanyahu, and others, with the crime of Moharebeh.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17E741F9C71C475EBE853195B404FD07"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alireza Panahian, a senior member of the Office of Supreme Leader, is an extremist cleric affiliated with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5C53BCFE356A4E16BBE32E912D61EDDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4168AB47EBA54E21B614CBC9CD06B1E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the IRGC’s intelligence-security apparatus, which is involved in gross human rights violations in Iran and proliferating terrorism abroad;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C5B433FC75C40849544ED6D88D68E33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the inner ring of Mojtaba Khamenei’s personal network; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC21DA3B8CDE466ABACB6D2F70D26231"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the so-called <quote>Habib Circle</quote>, one of the regime’s highest informal security-intelligence networks, which has committed human rights violations and is involved in terrorist activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60C92C9BADFC44D69536A09B575E2502"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alireza Panahian has publicly endorsed and propagated the fatwas of Ayatollah Naser Makarem-Shirazi, a member of Iran’s Assembly of Experts and an illicit profiteer in Iran’s sugar market, and Ayatollah Hossein Nouri Hamedani, disciple and former representative in Europe of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, including their characterization of President Trump and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu as a <quote>Moharebeh</quote>—an offense that, under Iranian law, can carry the death penalty.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF597FCA1502A47FBBE15C311320975CC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Alireza Panahian serves as a leading figure in the IRGC’s indoctrination system and is described by analysts as one of the main ideological architects of its militarized, apocalyptic Mahdism doctrine.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA2FC9A7021A4201B67D908A25D05C83"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within hardline currents of Iran’s post-1979 political-religious establishment—especially IRGC-linked Mahdist ideology—Mahdism is interpreted as requiring the destruction of Israel as a prelude to the return of the Hidden 12th Imam.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B973F15FCCB4437BD2A3239E2051AC5"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Abbas Kaabi, a member of the leadership committee of the Assembly of Experts, an affiliate with the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, and is described as a key figure in the establishment of Hezbollah in Lebanon, and who possesses extensive ties to Iran-backed Shia militias in Iraq, has publicly endorsed the charge of Moharebeh against President Donald Trump, Prime Minister Netanyahu, and others.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F6563F2F93D426F9939F4CA49366365"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Ahmad Khatami, a member of the Guardian Council and Assembly of Experts and Interim Friday Prayer Leader of Tehran, has been sanctioned by the European Union for human rights abuses due to his egregious conduct and is reported to have called for the executions of President Donald J. Trump and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE572ACE393A643A29C4BC5B44AED8E61"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Mohsen Araki, a member of the Assembly of Experts and Expediency Council and the Supreme Leader’s former representative to the United Kingdom and head of the Islamic Center of England, has threated President Donald J. Trump and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu by saying <quote>their lives and property are no longer protected</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81ED8C6C34B84AF283117E71CE6BF58E"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Mohsen Araki declared the United States Government, including President Donald J. Trump, as a <quote>hostile infidel government by all Muslims</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC589B025285F41458CCADAAC5B5B948A"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Qom Seminary, and including the organization’s head Ayatollah Alireza Arafi, has endorsed Moharebeh Fatwas against President Donald J. Trump, Prime Minister Benjamin Netenyahu, and others. Statements released through Qom’s Seminary’s press office and signed by hundreds to thousands of clerics, professors, and students describe President Donald J. Trump’s <quote>blood wealth</quote> as religiously permissible, effectively signaling their willingness to see the fatwa carried out.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D528367DA254A37B35AE7166B366B17"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These Fatwas and charges of Moharebeh by senior clerical leaders from Iran’s state-linked clerical institutions and religious leaders are a clear incitement of violence and consequently endanger the lives of President Donald J. Trump and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, thus imperiling the national security of the United States and Israel.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H4B9C5B3E3F424EDF886F6D7AF2911594"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination on certain organizations for imposition of sanctions</header> <subsection id="H1125E9F406724DED86532A0CEBB5007D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, not later than 2 years thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination as to whether the foreign persons described in subsection (b) meet the criteria for sanctions described in subsection (c) based on their role in issuing and amplifying fatwas advocating for violence, including as the fatwas relate to the deaths of President Donald J. Trump, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, and other political leaders.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F7F981CCB2B4D5792A4596C76C43C8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign persons described</header><text>The foreign persons described in this subsection include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H6F698AA2BA8B463AAC12A8C0E4EBC040"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Naser Makarem-Shirazi.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF2C0BE7BF984B768F0F645076141BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ayatollah Hossein Nouri Hamedani.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49C6A29EE3DA4D13A1AA79F6832D5FA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Ayatollah Hossein Mazaheri.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5A54E485FD14DA58CD821E78023E014"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ayatollah Ja’far Sobhani.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED1309FEFF6644D7833242C92DCD6CDD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Alireza Panahian.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97473EF75D8B46B5ACB893F2E866B215"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ayatollah Abbas Kaabi.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7F679A111E44F979D35E4B58CDA39F8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Abdolmajid Kharghani.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DA75CD78E2442C5B34EBAC349B2F986"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ahmad Khatami.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H360B7B5D6A0C40E48982EB640C5EFE3A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Mohsen Araki.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B054606966D4DD398EDB05A751EE120"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ayatollah Alireza Arafi.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97A53C24C61D4F94963CCD8E3E7711CE"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Qom Seminary (Howzeh Elmieh Qom).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC38B816CA1C4D15A70E256D321EA851"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting (IRIB).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAE02DFF28A64460AEF6208FDF7DDC22"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Assembly of Experts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7DF23A41EBA4A87ACE6DF5036D08FC5"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Expediency and Discernment Council.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1BADC228B674CF8BD1AA2458F12E434"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Guardian Council.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E7B6449D91D4EEB8F8DB48418A0A4E6"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Ayatollah Ahmad Alamolhoda.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8FE1AD0F5E8478287D113AD8E57E8D2"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Society of Seminary Teachers of Qom (Jaameh Modaresin Howzeh Elmieh Qom).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC495BA217A040169397F715D6711869"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Hojjat al-Eslam Amin Assadpour.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4CA89A8675B241E7ADEEB3C0FA778863"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDBF6CB12EE8F4ADD90A3A84DD09929AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all authorities granted under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of foreign persons described in subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H515A67E913CB45568563CBC18AA887AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header> <subparagraph id="HD920EF0D9C1E414FA95E21D182E56C06"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (b) shall be—</text> 
<clause id="H15604001F80E4FB68E4A32D4760A9ADB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H52631A870DFF49C1BA3F41A76E3728D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H28A8546F05484F008DD9D4BC7FBA130A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C45D4E5651D473495D6A201ACA5C82F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header> <clause id="H23F5725467EF40FCB4B71D09BF7B0722"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of any alien described in subsection (b) shall be revoked regardless of the issue date of the visa or other entry documentation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H87F410A702FA439F83D722E0E5B0413D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>)—</text> <subclause id="H8C879DACBCD344AB8BE01BAD17B71767"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3E751D2643C64A1EB16D2FDE535BE109"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5F96F53C06CB411DB6FDF050C6939D42"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Any person that violates, or attempts to violate, subsection (c) or any regulation, license, or order issued pursuant to that subsection, shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Economic Emergency Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6BE28A99AF6B4A85A905AF795A3528EF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if, not later than 15 days after the date on which the waiver is to take effect, the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a written determination and justification that the waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H90599D2D28B545308655FE134CE9D0A7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out any amendments made by this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H138F2C09AB68444FAF1020151DD4794C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HEB2E74F0E90941E3AEDCE5AF88BAA750"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> <paragraph id="HAA34F61B201A4D768813725EAEEE426A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0864CEDC68DE44699D275F3E535709A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations and for law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F60C69B1DD94D8093F74E0A38874216"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1EFE95A2B93409B9BC4EB254E92F6BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out or assist authorized law enforcement activity in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H000306CEE3AC450FA15EA552A2A0F549"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header> <subparagraph id="HCB1C5E1E0E9A443781239DBE9ED964DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this section shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C7CD01B97CD4211BB789C5B69417445"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD949164849C14871A01B4AFE8ECCFE04"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination of sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall cease to be effective beginning on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Government of Iran no longer repeatedly provides support for international terrorism as determined by the Secretary of State pursuant to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF1D1EAEAEC354A419421552743FD3BA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1754(c)(1)(A) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF0D71DD6CAC45029386FE2603E8287B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E71F02AB92B48FDAC6A7BDAE6F21E15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7608581D49B045A9B6B214F07CB9D8E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H226A0851A79E43F08269B7D5D2F63690"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HBC5E90D3BD53491DB71EB1DC7DBEA926"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37E6EA1A574443E6AE4F2B1B7D412677"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1002964BCC904AE4B3A08AF4E10B07B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8D487ACB2784AD3B21089813386A18A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>foreign person</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HA91B9ACF4B2B434E9BF958BABB3CDDAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual or entity that is not a United States person; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H28F32907D7694F51815EA8993484A937"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a foreign state (as such term is defined in section 1603 of title 28, United States Code);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H778C367306E745848704E9CBEF1A1311"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Government of Iran</term> has the meaning given such term in section 560.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on January 1, 2021; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD82C187E7CA4395BB350C7F08F81588"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HA89ADF2A0013449183650854B051805D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6284D06312D248898D88C0641602C517"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a permanent resident alien of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6CD64701B8C44F09CBD0F36A9628EC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB93A15A4E3B45A8BDED65CFCEF93821"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260608" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 8, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

