<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF2D79996B63149F399EB674E8BE5C7D9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8119 IH: Helping to Optimize Patients’ Experience with Fertility Services Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure coverage for the treatment of infertility for certain conditions.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCAF55DBD82C447D697F25BF1E9A92D9B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HF37C22414665454EBD4ADDFF0D6F6F8E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping to Optimize Patients’ Experience with Fertility Services Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HOPE with Fertility Services Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H692BA5AEBD6B47DAB792A16FB5E6E657"><enum>2.</enum><header>ensuring benefits for treatment of infertility and iatrogenic infertility</header> <subsection id="H34745686829C447B93A5ED4F4E65F04D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart B of part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1185">29 U.S.C. 1185 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 714 the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H167E376C556F41C59CA2B500C4E63FF0" style="OLC">
<section id="HB2DAF80F6E4344D5B9665991A518E8A1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>714A.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for treatment of infertility and iatrogenic infertility</header>
<subsection id="HCE7446DA51EE4A86ACCFCB0A517A1784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall ensure that such plan or coverage provides coverage for infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatments, including—</text> <paragraph id="HC967E367035A47A49783565173501358"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the treatment of infertility, if such plan or coverage provides coverage for obstetrical services; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F0FDA6DD2734CBA8CA603D52FE6E413"><enum>(2)</enum><text>standard fertility preservation services when a medically necessary treatment described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of subsection (b)(1) causes, or is expected to cause, iatrogenic infertility.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2B9FB53F868E4A87BF9672903D068F2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HA4C503F289914FAEB518EBA8E42F27C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Iatrogenic infertility</header><text>The term <quote>iatrogenic infertility</quote> means an impairment of fertility due to damage of reproductive organs and processes resulting from—</text> <subparagraph id="H2904EA9AE40B4BF584D2D28648E1C769"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a surgical or other invasive medical procedure as a result of an injury or life-threatening illness, or involving a reproductive organ or process in a manner likely to cause damage to such organ or process;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7EB63740FB574FCD8F032BCA0DECC2C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>radiation therapy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB2FAD46DDED4CCDB476FCEB02AB7BCE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>chemotherapy; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD92CB63632842CE89EA14E24D67E360"><enum>(D)</enum><text>myeloablative conditioning.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB009E1AAADFB42D6A63AFA701AE1A0A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Infertility</header><text>The term <quote>infertility</quote> means a disease or condition characterized by—</text>
<subparagraph id="H18B146A90BB6453EBAF0D83526EDF90F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the inability to achieve spontaneous pregnancy without medical treatment after a period of at least 12 consecutive months of unprotected sexual intercourse;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C6A42812949477B888F04F0D2270D73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the inability to achieve pregnancy after receiving standard clinical treatment protocols under the supervision of a treating physician who is a board-certified reproductive endocrinologist or obstetrician-gynecologist;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC7FDC7FBB0534ED9AEB71382043B9D6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>being incapable of reproduction to live birth based on medical and reproductive history, age, physical findings or diagnostic testing of the individual, as determined by a treating physician; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF78630F3A55841AB918D276AC79682C5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the inability to achieve spontaneous pregnancy on account of a diagnosed condition that is a disorder of ovulation, or a testicular or hormonal disease or disorder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27772A7EA357417799024206C02DE678"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatment</header><text>The term <quote>infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatment</quote> means treatments or procedures with the intent of facilitating a pregnancy, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HA555801D50254F27B8A31A017E44944B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such treatments or procedures that involve the handling of human egg, sperm, and embryo outside of the body, including in vitro fertilization and maturation, egg and embryo cryopreservation, egg and embryo donation, and intracytoplasmic sperm injection; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H297C1B8C7F8845C9B54A55B69BD110E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such treatments or procedures that do not involve the handling of human egg, sperm, and embryo outside of the body, including ovulation induction, genetic screening and diagnosis, sperm cryopreservation, and intrauterine insemination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2B9AF0F874684290A175D37ED72AFE64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required coverage</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage that includes coverage for obstetrical services shall provide comprehensive coverage for infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatments, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with relevant stakeholders, provided to a participant or beneficiary if—</text>
<paragraph id="HF5D1905AAAC342E7896914E01CE4C7C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the participant or beneficiary has infertility, including iatrogenic infertility; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73DA5EBFFC5D48B18287F12C43B8934B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the treatment or service is performed at a medical facility that is in compliance with standards set by appropriate Federal and State agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7F9391EBABE142D9A8AC4540EADB16F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Financial requirements and treatment requirements</header><text>Any coverage provided by a group health plan or health insurance issuer in accordance with this section may be subject to coverage limits (such as medical necessity, pre-authorization, or pre-certification) and cost-sharing requirements (such as coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles), as required under the group health plan or health insurance coverage, that are no more restrictive than the predominant coverage limits and cost-sharing requirements applied to substantially all medical and surgical benefits covered under the plan or coverage.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H75E4D1B266BB4122937C009D4BB91BAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage may not—</text>
<paragraph id="HEAB8A3F6CD70461D8FC83AB17A560324"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide incentives (monetary or otherwise) to a participant or beneficiary to encourage such participant or beneficiary not to be provided infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatments to which such participant or beneficiary is entitled under this section, or to providers to induce such providers not to provide such treatments to qualified participants and beneficiaries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA71509E67EE9427D9316B98BCB9BA1EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit a provider from discussing with a participant or beneficiary infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatments or medical treatment options required to be covered under this section; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8564EB997D9C43B1AFE54DFC85DDE2E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>penalize or otherwise reduce or limit the reimbursement of a provider because such provider provided infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatment services to a participant or beneficiary in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE97F67C96FCF4AB4A4F73B06DF920711"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text>
<paragraph id="H4783170A5064406DAE4E88F3CF99FF2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require a participant or beneficiary in a group health plan or group health insurance coverage to undergo infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC1BA4AAEC934FFCA98E50B4306FE0A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impact the use by a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage of utilization management tools; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED5D85D188BA4A498B3D82F7025B8A74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prevent a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage from contracting with providers as to the level and type of reimbursement with a provider for care provided in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44EAB783A8364F418A1013674A6FB574"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Utilization management tools requirements</header> <paragraph id="H86AC551A6433403384E035C8F4EAD2A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage that imposes utilization management tools on infertility and iatrogenic infertility treatment benefits, for the first 5 plan years that begin after the date of enactment of the Helping to Optimize Patients’ Experience with Fertility Services Act, such plan or issuer shall perform and document analyses of the design and application of the utilization management tool such analysis and the following information:</text>
<subparagraph id="HD4FD986C961D43CD960475B3858AAFFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The specific plan or coverage terms or other relevant terms regarding the utilization management tools and a description of all infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatment benefits, to which each such term applies in each respective benefits classification.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BE3D8E20CA14752A27552B2DC551C44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The factors used to determine that the utilization management tool will apply to infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatment benefits.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE69D2AEB99B4CC7ADC3F10FC63B2CDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The evidentiary standards used for the factors identified under subparagraph (B), when applicable, provided that every factor shall be defined, and any other source or evidence relied upon to design and apply the utilization management tool to infertility and iatrogenic infertility treatment benefits.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CE0991C178C47BFA604953DCC918E6B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis demonstrating that the processes, strategies, evidentiary standards, and other factors used to apply the utilization management tools to infertility and iatrogenic infertility treatment benefits as written and in operation, are consistent with, and are applied no more stringently than with clinical guidelines for infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatments.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2BBC6336A94C4217AA18336229E45A33"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The specific findings and conclusions reached by the group health plan or health insurance issuer with respect to the health insurance coverage, including any results of the analyses described in this paragraph that indicate that the plan or coverage is or is not in compliance with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC92F62C2CAB1476387680FA91DD00786"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission process</header> <subparagraph id="HB590F2C8130246668284BA53C50B512C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual submission</header><text>A group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall submit to the Secretary the analyses described in paragraph (1) annually for first 5 plan years that begin after the date of enactment of the Helping to Optimize Patients’ Experience with Fertility Services Act. For subsequent plan years, the Secretary may request that a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage submit the analysis described in paragraph (1) in the case of potential violations of this section or complaints regarding noncompliance with this section that concern utilization management tools and any other instances in which the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC697BCBC57CD413A91AB5928E9182C97"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>If the Secretary concludes that a group health plan or health insurance issuer has not submitted sufficient information for the Secretary to review the analysis described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall specify to the plan or issuer the information the plan or issuer is required to submit pursuant to subparagraph (A). Nothing in this subparagraph shall require the Secretary to conclude that a group health plan or health insurance issuer is in compliance with this section solely based upon the inspection of the analyses described in paragraph (1), as requested under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21D5C07100FB42BEAE48FB23BCC65EDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required action</header> <subparagraph id="HF05BB46171ED49AE84B2625147CDFBDB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, after review of the analyses described in paragraph (1), the Secretary notifies the group health plan or health insurance issuer that such plan or issuer is not in compliance with this section, the plan or issuer—</text>
<clause id="HD5506942131B443E81CEB56903B37018"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall specify to the Secretary the actions the plan or issuer will take to be in compliance with this section and provide to the Secretary additional analyses described in paragraph (1) that demonstrate compliance with this section not later than 45 days after the initial notification by the Secretary that the plan or issuer is not in compliance; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB2507918B53C4714BDB83A513EE9F2BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>following the 45-day corrective action period under clause (i), if the Secretary makes a final determination that the plan or issuer still is not in compliance with this section, not later than 7 days after such determination, shall notify all individuals enrolled in the applicable plan or health insurance coverage that such plan or coverage has been determined to be not in compliance with this section.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA28E245C36974BDCA97D2C3BC0ACC9C8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption from disclosure</header><text>Documents or communications produced in connection with the Secretary’s recommendations to a group health plan or health insurance issuer shall not be subject to disclosure pursuant to section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H315A5761F70F4013A43713B33FBBAB6B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report that contains—</text>
<subparagraph id="H71894DAF868244DC88B8F44962BF0AF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the analysis submitted under paragraph (1), including the identity of each group health plan or health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage that is determined to be not in compliance after the final determination by the Secretary described in paragraph (3)(A)(ii);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1088BB4284B94778A5C26AB77FFF40B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary’s conclusions as to whether each group health plan or health insurance issuer submitted sufficient information for the Secretary to review the analysis under paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBC4E509199574B8289D9310AEE0111CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each group health plan or health insurance issuer that did submit sufficient information under paragraph (2), the Secretary’s conclusions as to whether and why the plan or issuer is in compliance with the requirements under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64235BA0B1BD4107A0C327D4B511BA1F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary’s specifications described in paragraph (3) for each group health plan or health insurance issuer that the Secretary determined did not submit sufficient information for the Secretary to review the analyses described in paragraph (1) for compliance with this section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE3EF05C119AE4069A1B2438D4838F3E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the actions the Secretary specifies under paragraph (3)(A)(i) that each group health plan or health insurance issuer that the Secretary determined is not in compliance with this section is required take to be in compliance with this section, including the reason why the Secretary determined the plan or issuer is not in compliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H38C41C4E1AF447C39D5076B9D5DF072C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Beginning with the second plan year beginning after the date of enactment of the Helping to Optimize Patients’ Experience with Fertility Services Act, a group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall provide notice to participants and beneficiaries in such plan or coverage regarding the coverage required by this section in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9DB85B4C5E43401A9A89024016D64F7F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H8BA815CBC6E4408792FCCC8D7B412480" indent="subsection"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Section 502 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HB68FE764ABDD468F85DC5DB991C7A66A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(6), by striking <quote>or (9)</quote> and inserting <quote>(9), or (13)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FB299DE8BD84C00B336636B289C9930"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>subsection (c)(9)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (9) and (13) of subsection (c)</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC280399B76F44F419F64008C3DDFDC4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H65559293145D4767884E27CDE780B8EE" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H7F7B5BDCEBA0407099B4658529FC0915" indent="subsection"><enum>(13)</enum> <subparagraph id="H5B97E180472A45A1931AB8B1295AE86C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary may assess a civil penalty against a health insurance issuer for failing to provide coverage for infertility or iatrogenic infertility treatments as required under section 714A, in an amount up to $100 per day, beginning on the date on which the issuer first denies such coverage and ending on the date on which the issuer approves coverage, with respect to each participant or beneficiary denied such coverage in violation of such section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H62E3037915D444C0BDBF4099A260518B" indent="subsection"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary may assess a civil penalty against a health insurance issuer for failing to submit an analysis as required under section 714A(g)(2), in an amount up to $100 for each day, beginning 45 days after the date on which the Secretary notifies such issuer that the issuer is not in compliance with the requirement under section 714A(g)(2), and ending on the date on which the issue submits the analysis as required.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6EBBE06D6B4E424DA734A46B5C3A9EE5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 731(c) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1191">29 U.S.C. 1191(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 711</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 711 and 714A</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

