<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0EC8604CA99043D19AF3FD5BDEE2079D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7448 IH: Modernizing and Improving the National Terrorism Advisory System Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7448</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000139">Mr. Van Epps</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop a strategy to modernize the National Terrorism Advisory System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H29AA503FB06F4BCEB05D41F11EB7237A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6ED0832C51A74979989CF2761CA75E43" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing and Improving the National Terrorism Advisory System Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H442805A3E4BC4FA5AA40C51EFF219CED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy to modernize the National Terrorism Advisory System</header> <subsection id="H3BFA87A7FFC44F8E806E2834D7AE6F8F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a strategy to modernize the National Terrorism Advisory System (NTAS) (in this section referred to as the <quote>strategy</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF7E87C63F06F4BC2B5A068DD5DB4043B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The strategy shall consider the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCD4650FA81CE46DEAEEE1BE36899EC5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Designating a specific office or official within the Department of Homeland Security to oversee the NTAS.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09400F05492046D793A7DED67982980D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The criteria, protocols, and standard operating procedures for the issuance and sunset of NTAS bulletins and alerts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81A6265E8C9F4ECA879F8B89542A2BD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The public accessibility and use of NTAS bulletins and alerts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6ADDE5E1D0EE401098FF1FAF2D56B4EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The effectiveness of the current NTAS in communicating timely and detailed information to the public about potential terrorism threats.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C54CA44E5964E2E83F6AD96275C9BEA" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The impact of NTAS bulletins and alerts on the ability of Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement and emergency responders to prepare for, prevent, respond to, and mitigate against terrorism threats.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H992515734B5649EAA9B6E8A9D6786A6A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Mechanisms to ensure NTAS bulletins and alerts reach the greatest number of people possible.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1E42A9292CDC435DA22FD940D45CC34F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Engagement</header><text>In developing the strategy, the Secretary shall engage with individuals, stakeholders, the private sector, and Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement and emergency responders to receive feedback on options to modernize the NTAS, including feedback related to the considerations under subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC773BA1F92B445ACBE0A038892ED1690" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Comptroller General review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

