<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5ACF6814CB594FECAB90E03E414E2FF2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5955 IH: BIS License Fee Prohibition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5955</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the collection and obligation of any fee collected in connection with an export license and require the return of such fee to the holder of the license, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3500A6F161E54788AAE65F0C49910CF9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4FC011B64E694F2E95F1C331EB25D78E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>BIS License Fee Prohibition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4FD1EDC525794C208932DA068FE6F530"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8246BB5A787E42478E2DBACB7C57575A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Article 1, Section 9 of the Constitution directly states, <quote>No Tax or Duty shall be laid on Articles exported from any State</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF0D442D6EF84E5EA3E3F7C24BC06C0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1756 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (subtitle B of title XVII of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4815">50 U.S.C. 4815</external-xref>) states, <quote>No fee may be charged in connection with the submission, processing, or consideration of any application for a license or other authorization or other request made in connection with any regulation in effect under the authority of this part.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3AF3E9787D44E5297E0B2ABA6A6ACE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The placement of export controls on dual-use technologies to the People’s Republic of China should be based on assessments of national security and economic competitiveness.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H346CD91AEEE84A8B9AFC0C76CD276362"><enum>3.</enum><header>License fees prohibited</header> <subsection id="H5D4A23C940AB48788F75D53DBD0CB62F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No amount may be collected by the Federal Government after the date of the enactment of this Act in the form of revenue-sharing, fees, or any other monetary arrangement subject to or conditional upon which a person receives or maintains the ability to benefit from a license or other authorization under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2F10004F009499E923D4CF92AB859D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No amount collected before, on, or after such date of enactment in any manner described in subsection (a) may be obligated or expended for any purpose other than to be returned to the holder of the license under subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7DCAC1BDBFBA4C51A56B0C0F1995FF97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Not later than 30 days after such date of enactment, the Secretary of Commerce shall return to or pay the holder of each applicable license or other authorization with respect to which any amount was collected before or on the date of such enactment in any manner described in subsection (a) the full amount so collected.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H83463236A8554D2CB913222E1615E994"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the implementation of any export fee on semiconductors or otherwise indicate that such fee is consistent with the requirements of the Constitution or of section 1756 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (subtitle B of title XVII of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4815">50 U.S.C. 4815</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

