<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26337-NTY-72-RYJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4127 PCS: Transportation Security Administration Pay Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 362</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>Making continuing appropriations for essential Transportation Security Administration pay and operations during the lapse in appropriations beginning on February 14, 2026, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transportation Security Administration Pay Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id56a345254a3e441eabe96e5267a87a86"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuing appropriations for Transportation Security Administration personnel</header><subsection id="idefee3f77db974e4db7d564ca412888f7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are hereby appropriated for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the period beginning on February 14, 2026, during which interim or full-year appropriations for fiscal year 2026 are not in effect, such sums as are necessary to provide standard rates of pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments otherwise payable on a regular basis to employees of the Transportation Security Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="id712dcf0b14fc4f00909f0df98f603208"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation to individuals affected by lapse in appropriations</header><text>Amounts provided under subsection (a) may not be used to provide pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, or other payments to an employee of the Transportation Security Administration for any portion of the period described in subsection (a) for which the employee is provided with such pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, or other payments using amounts other than amounts provided under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id06f7e2ba46324edcae5939a7b7f502d3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Charge to future appropriations</header><text>Expenditures made pursuant to subsection (a) shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever an Act in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is included is enacted into law.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7d9b61a12b014960aa9c3aa222a3bf17"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>Pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments provided by the Transportation Security Administration using amounts provided under subsection (a) shall be subject to the requirements, authorities, conditions, and limitations applicable with respect to the provision of pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments by the Transportation Security Administration under the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/4">Public Law 119–4</external-xref>; 139 Stat. 9).</text></subsection></section><section id="id06603fb2701d442388748235088592eb"><enum>3.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under section 2 shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text><paragraph id="id23ab90b1a94b4291b1710768103bf540"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The enactment into law of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available in section 2.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93a5d05632d447f8a5d983cf0afad57e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The enactment into law of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb10feb346dc644e79efb34670a0f28ea"><enum>(3)</enum><text>September 30, 2026.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id146740e10a874d859fb0634614eab481"><enum>4.</enum><header>Retroactive effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect as if enacted on February 13, 2026.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

