<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H201AE3EEB93C474B843DDA80C976D943" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8989 IH: Evidence-Based Youth Suicide Prevention Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8989</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out demonstration programs to develop, implement, and evaluate evidence-based strategies to prevent suicide among children and adolescents, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0726DFC51E8A4127A72517B7108B54F8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB3DA035DCB7B4967B1D0A443E493EBB3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Evidence-Based Youth Suicide Prevention Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8B06DEE0F9D942028716AB591B466CDF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA033A14E3285466886B5F978EF621BC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">suicide is the second-leading cause of death among children and adolescents, and schools are often the first place warning signs emerge;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6013444BACC45199647C0B5637249B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in 2023, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention found that, of the high school students nationwide—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H59CA7E973FA24E13A3BDD80ABD6749BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>40 percent had reported persistent feelings of sadness or hopelessness;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H05FC54F2710D46B3BC90D13D80E98C56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>18 percent had experienced major depression; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19E454D899B34095985DAB8C47755AB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">10 percent had attempted suicide; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A5482EA86E84CDBB7BB57C295AFEA87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>school districts face an urgent need to actively manage mental health crises, yet communities still lack access to clear, comparable evidence on which approaches are proven to reduce suicide attempts and deaths when implemented at scale.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3820A54D84814D759EDF065D8825E4CE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Youth suicide prevention program</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 520C (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-34">42 U.S.C. 290bb–34</external-xref>) the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8B995F78515341ED80AF095F0BF72622" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HEDD3B8D11C6A419A92559137C99F4A2B"><enum>520D.</enum><header>Youth suicide prevention program</header> <subsection id="H8CE7131A3A554A94ADC91B193070D75D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, directly or through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements with eligible entities, carry out demonstration programs to develop, implement, and evaluate evidence-based strategies to prevent suicide among children and adolescents.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H86EE71A25EC443CBB2B89D1B73DE686A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Settings</header><text>A demonstration program carried out under this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC6C48A1B99C240259951A51069420B28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritize implementation in schools, other educational institutions, and other child- and youth-support settings; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H096B19CE399548B89BF9465BC926ACE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require coordination with State, Tribal, and local educational agencies and public health organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H68F09702BBC342DCA9214FA499F88815"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B33BC29027E4F0697E5158D51FA156D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA429DE23BCBE47118374669531C3292B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State educational agency or local educational agency (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83CAAF5A8904445E9BB57CFA46D04229"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a public organization or private nonprofit organization designated by a State or Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94BBC42E8F00418FBE8B5AC4E362D4EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as defined in section 1010 of the Higher Education Act of 1965).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6ABC2A1F88F246E2A20BC8CF818B1B69"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Activities under this section may include—</text> <paragraph id="HA7E7A651663C42EAA0155BA8078C50FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>piloting, implementing, and scaling of evidence-based suicide prevention programs in elementary and secondary schools;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4753DFBBC84F4717944B41E6F24A5652"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluation of existing suicide prevention protocols, practices, and strategies used by schools, health systems, and community-based organizations, including assessments of effectiveness, implementation, and outcomes; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64CD1DB4B4914164A4F263B7941B6598"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other activities as the Secretary determines appropriate to study the prevention of suicide among children and adolescents.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4DBBD1FED6FB427A9FEA300799CB8180"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to recipients of assistance under this section, including assistance related to outcome identification, data collection, evaluation design, and reporting.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4260FFB928F249C6BB4852D677999612"> <enum>(f)</enum> <header>Evidence-Based programs</header> <paragraph id="H071EBF55056E45D7A2C029ED8E1879D0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>evidence-based</quote> means, when used with respect to a program, an intervention—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HA9E69ED2D4C5474EAD3902DAFE865DC0">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that—</text> <clause id="H88C4E9DF326344B28D5D258D4F42C3A6"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>demonstrates a statistically significant and sustained positive impact on relevant outcomes in a real-world or community setting, based on the totality of available evidence; or</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H3D8C9819D8104392B505BA50F6AD6A54">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>describes how an intervention is implemented in practice and informs its replication or scaling; and</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H9D1189FD643C49F7B3A38814943D608B">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is supported by strong evidence, moderate evidence, or promising evidence.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H5DE6A9A46F9F42DAAA6939B5E5C20D48">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Strong evidence</header>
 <text>In paragraph (1), the term <quote>strong evidence</quote> means an intervention that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HAA9B5B65CBAD4F4A988F9EF9A0DAE97D">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>meets the criteria described in paragraph (1)(A) through not fewer than—</text>
                <clause id="HC9E3E74C304F4CBEAFE90D407372BDB0">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>2 well-designed and well-implemented experimental studies;</text> </clause> <clause id="HDB7707371CF649B5B4790E937574FA10"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>1 large, multi-site randomized controlled trial; or</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="HA02356B22AA14609A96BBDC3E88971CA">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>at the discretion of the Secretary, 1 or more quasi-experimental studies that meet rigorous standards for causal inference and are widely accepted in peer-reviewed literature; and</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HFAF09AEE359948F1BD7D521A85E691F4">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>has demonstrated effectiveness in a population or setting similar to the population or setting in which the intervention is proposed to be implemented.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HEBBCF70A9FE34751B34AA0ABB444F0CE">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Moderate evidence</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In paragraph (1), the term <quote>moderate evidence</quote> means an intervention that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H8AFDB9E7542B4C5E89B50AFB8594513E">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the criteria described in paragraph (1)(A) through—</text>
                <clause id="HD6BD3067164F4616967EBB5163FD1ED8">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not fewer than 1 well-designed and well-implemented experimental study; or</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H9B3001E02C784C188BD94231D6EFE2F5">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 quasi-experimental study capable of establishing a causal relationship between the intervention and the relevant outcomes; and</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4D040D8E58FD4A9994561A2DADEAD325">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has demonstrated effectiveness in a population or setting similar to the population or setting in which the intervention is proposed to be implemented, to the extent practicable.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H56239010921F48CAB8EF5D15B9AFCECB">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
              <header>Promising evidence</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In paragraph (1), the term <quote>promising evidence</quote> means an intervention that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H501D4637DD1248FA8567D7D5F27847F6">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is informed by relevant theory, prior research, or evidence-informed practice; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H4921F1DF516E46EEA13284B1135B61AE">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is accompanied by a plan for rigorous evaluation to determine the effectiveness of the intervention.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H34218D3F155E42C486F47F15C56D4D87">
              <enum>(5)</enum>
              <header>Interpretation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>evidence-based</quote> shall be interpreted by the Secretary, to the extent feasible, to pursue alignment with similar definitions of the term <quote>evidence-based</quote> issued by the Department of Health and Human Services and other Federal definitions governing mental health programs.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBE657A630FF042CCA660F9F3CBE71D38"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prioritization of evidence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H41101B4372264B48BB822EA91B8DF49C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allocate funding made available under this section based on the strength of evidence supporting a proposed intervention, consistent with the definition of the term <quote>evidence-based</quote> in subsection (f); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F423D522DFB4DA38799A6348118A2D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize such funding for interventions supported by higher levels of evidence, while also reserving a portion of funds to support promising and innovative approaches that are accompanied by rigorous evaluation plans.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5557B28D673A4A7493C3E11733EE41CB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Identifying and monitoring outcomes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall identify and monitor outcome measures that reflect both mental health outcomes and broader student success, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9027DDD7A9445DBBC6E180B3F4F37D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>student mental health and safety outcomes, such as suicide attempts, suicidal ideation, crisis interventions, and help-seeking behaviors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DE2BF66E5AC463EB35C3B2C91C90BEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>academic outcomes, including grades and academic achievement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B32440D6E6E4432BE0279AE2E79932D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>social-emotional learning indicators, such as student well-being, resilience, and school connectedness;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBECFD4BD633E466BAE7A2FDAF97EA614"><enum>(4)</enum><text>student engagement indicators, including attendance and enrollment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FFEDD3C6B2E4D74BD0315CA66682FCD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>access and reach metrics, including the number and characteristics of students served; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA357755D73848B19982B1D660538455"><enum>(6)</enum><text>implementation metrics, including staff participation and training completion.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A1C14D96F714E25B66BE38C0C759FAA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Community engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall meet community engagement requirements, including in any notice of funding opportunity issued pursuant to this section, in accordance with section 200.202 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), to ensure that demonstration programs under this section are developed in consultation with the communities benefitting from or impacted by the programs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9CBAF22B58DA4DC397E48DA28DED14D1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Federal program evaluation standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that evaluations of the program carried out under this section are conducted in accordance with the Federal program evaluation standards set forth by the Office of Management and Budget in OMB Memorandum M–20–12, dated March 10, 2020 (or any successor standards).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43C667AAB80B4C8185C935B05B113D06"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter during the term of the program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the activities carried out under this section, including a summary of evaluation findings, implementation lessons, and implications for future Federal investments in school-based youth suicide prevention.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFED8362109A3414B9716504A7E4B2687"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2027 through 2032.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

