<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C852152A4C347E480DEFEEFA80AF093" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7371 IH: No Flight, No Fight Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7371</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restrict the air transportation of certain live animals in interstate and foreign commerce to enhance aviation safety, biosecurity, and operational efficiency in civil aviation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B3AD614307448DF834EF6B105D82157" style="OLC"><section id="HCA7EA025AA0443389AFBADB2622C3000" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Flight, No Fight Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2469E20B596448B98413B03C3AE67D8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HB7A2455867354435B6135BCA9B639815"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Civil aviation, including the carriage of cargo by air, is critical to the national transportation system and economy of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FB1078EC1143EB928715444C060EA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The transportation of certain live animals by air, particularly adult roosters, presents unique challenges to aviation safety, biosecurity, and airline operational efficiency, including risks of stress-induced behavior, potential disease transmission, and disruptions during flight.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB108548F45884223B61C550FF6FC770C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Rapid air transport of adult roosters has been associated with facilitating illegal activities, such as cockfighting, which poses additional biosecurity risks through unregulated movement of birds that may carry avian diseases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H981958733B3D4FACB30BB3E92A14E451"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Restricting non-essential air shipments of adult roosters, while preserving exemptions for large-scale commercial poultry operations, will promote safer and more efficient air cargo operations without disrupting legitimate agricultural supply chains in the commercial egg and meat industries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2C8D2BB47AF4E0A86B3DC1CADCE4852"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Aviation Administration and the Department of Transportation have authority over the safety and regulation of civil aviation, including the carriage of cargo by aircraft.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE68CB87E3B7945AFB5B37FBC0B795F3A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restriction on air transportation of adult roosters</header> <subsection id="H614366C74BBE4B82BB7FB0D6F07E4D26"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">Chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6C00FE4CE63240489347688DCE92A346"><enum>4.</enum><header>Restriction on air transportation of adult roosters</header><subsection id="HA03E3345526B495A85E9B5EEEB61852B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), no air carrier or other person operating an aircraft in interstate or foreign air transportation shall knowingly transport an adult rooster as cargo.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF65CDA252D814E3EB3C5AA9568EF8AAA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for commercial farms</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply if—</text><paragraph id="H91EB2A1424C3451C9FBEDDD65D80741A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the transport of the adult rooster(s) originates from or is destined for a commercial farm; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6084220BCC7748FB8D29E9A6C42352B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the transport is conducted for legitimate agricultural purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53A2DE31D1CF4FFEA571A978F3C4D08D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Any person claiming an exemption under subsection (b) shall provide documentation certifying that the originating or destination farm qualifies as a commercial farm, including financial records or attestations consistent with guidelines of the Economic Research Service of the United States Department of Agriculture to the air carrier prior to the transport of the adult rooster(s). No air carrier may accept an adult rooster for transport without certification.</text></subsection><subsection id="H210C55A8EFC646D49A8BF3BA991D1EE1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4A3322A7CA8B405CB9CF109A699E2A59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adult rooster</header><text>The term <quote>adult rooster</quote> means a male chicken (Gallus gallus domesticus) that has reached sexual maturity, typically characterized by the development of spurs, a large comb, and crowing behavior, and is at least 6 months of age.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H767A3CC0235A4F8A9A84A3480A3F9947"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Air carrier</header><text>The term <quote>air carrier</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 40102.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6AEFB708561483DACD79A7A12D197AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commercial farm</header><text>The term <quote>commercial farm</quote> means any farm with $350,000 or more in annual gross cash farm income (including sales of crops and livestock, government payments, and other farm-related income), as classified by the Economic Research Service of the United States Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF8A536C39784BF9BC5CEBC162461EE3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interstate or foreign air transportation</header><text>The term <quote>interstate or foreign air transportation</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>interstate air transportation</quote> in section 40102, including transportation in foreign air commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDF9F548BCD84FAF90B37A87EC3A0AAC"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Clerical amendment</header> <text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block id="H4D07196263E0445CA068319F9B777FC0" style="OLC">
                    <toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
                        <toc-entry level="section">44949. Restriction on air transportation of adult
                            roosters</toc-entry>
                    </toc>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H102AA7B292D7415D8F5A8A8238F85874"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall enforce this Act and the amendments made by this Act, in coordination with the Federal Aviation Administration, and may promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out its provisions. Violations shall be subject to civil penalties under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/463">chapter 463</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></section><section id="HD6AC23C614BB473A9B70384031285FD9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to preempt any State law that provides greater protections for aviation safety or imposes stricter restrictions on the air transportation of live animals.</text></section><section id="H9E013C5BC3694FF68AEB0FE54999530F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

