<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28F7C2BA9103494C9779F43DDE7311DE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6243 IH: Semiquincentennial Congressional Time Capsule Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the creation of a congressional time capsule in commemoration of the semiquincentennial of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB55ACC6C530541F9936D9104C6654351" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEF5EAC1F9F1445C8B6D16BCB91C07FFA"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Semiquincentennial Congressional Time Capsule Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB2A48EA9F07E4537A69AF3DA72D1CB19"><enum>2.</enum><header>Semiquincentennial Congressional Time Capsule</header><subsection id="H1BF54129B76C4A0CADC1ABD74F684770"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation by Architect of the Capitol</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Architect of the Capitol shall create a congressional time capsule, to be known as the <quote>Semiquincentennial Congressional Time Capsule</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Time Capsule</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H60AB0455BC514AE28E5D090FCC5CD29C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><paragraph id="H8DF73DED0619476B9B896FD76C23201B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination by congressional leadership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of the Speaker of the House of Representatives, Office of the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, Office of the Majority Leader of the Senate, and Office of the Minority Leader of the Senate shall jointly determine the contents of the Time Capsule, taking into account the requirements of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H587C9D52F07C4BFB92E462CF524736D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AEC7E0CFCFD4890A23C00FDD370F31F"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The contents of the Time Capsule shall include—</text><clause id="H2399EFD89125418288AFD64BA979077C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a single, joint letter from the offices described in paragraph (1);</text></clause><clause id="HE45A40A0E47E410CBFDEBAAEACA0FA1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coins minted by the Secretary of the Treasury in commemoration of the semiquincentennial anniversary of the establishment of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H0463CA882E6F4418AE87669E47B23530"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other item that the offices described in paragraph (1) jointly determine appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52F23A9B5D374E0BBEC2C5DC6DED8D1C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Any item included in the Time Capsule under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HD9D9715EB1884C7B97121C257356F081"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be made of materials that pose a low risk of degrading, such as metal or archival paper; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3A19624663C4237BDA38EB680A96D39"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be made of any organic or inorganic material that poses a high risk of degrading.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B91383C0CF40B88D91C7BD104F9DCA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Size</header><text>The Time Capsule shall be not more than 50 inches wide, 32 inches deep, and 48 inches high.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H047695AB18D04F1E934B632017CAE437"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the offices described in paragraph (1) may consult with the Architect of the Capitol, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, and such other entities of the Federal Government as the offices consider appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B5210882AD04129BB4E9F5CC131CFBA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of Architect</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H43E126AA43804FFF8F5BD0C2400F8EB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prepare the Time Capsule to be sealed and buried in the Capitol Visitor Center, at a location specified by the Architect, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, on or before July 4th, 2026, at a time which would permit individuals attending this event to also attend the burial of a time capsule in Independence Mall in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, under section 7(f)(1) of the United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/36/101">36 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> note prec.); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D3CA6BAD604159B41B63BCD9BDC603"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">install a plaque to provide such information about the Time Capsule as the Architect, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H31F78B71CEAD4C5F8DA50C91F147D9CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unsealing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Time Capsule shall be sealed until July 4th, 2276, on which date the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall present the Time Capsule to the 244th Congress, and such Congress shall determine how the contents within should be preserved or used.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

