<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42D3BC9B9D52442CB896831C90D2167A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6558 IH: Defense Secure Mobile Phones Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to provide senior officials of the Department of Defense with secure mobile phones, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0779633789EA4D32BAD7A48FB845C44B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6F160C0D88C04CB48D6D8F1135710537" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Secure Mobile Phones Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HBA8637F3792041BCA6EDA573632B3C92" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Secure mobile phones for senior officials and personnel performing sensitive functions</header> <subsection id="HDC866DC33EDF42DCB13470857F241219"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each wireless mobile phone the Department of Defense provides to a senior official of the Department or any other employee of the Department who performs sensitive national security functions, as determined by the Secretary, and all related telecommunications services are acquired under contracts or other agreements that require the enhanced cybersecurity protections described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F63DD7CCCFA4186AFDE4704C1450F19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protections described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enhanced cybersecurity protections described in this subsection enhanced cybersecurity protections for wireless mobile phones and related telecommunication services that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HCDB27493CD3843BEA723DF5F221411C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encryption of data on the wireless mobile phones and of all telecommunications to and from the wireless mobile phones through such telecommunication services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F41687D3EAC46A7AC1791D83D3C4454"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">capabilities to mitigate or obfuscate persistent device identifiers, including periodic rotation of network or hardware identifiers to reduce the risk of inappropriate tracking of the activity or location of the wireless mobile phones; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1908F698EABA431BB07F84723336F6A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the capability to continuously monitor the wireless mobile phones.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2968D4DB9096496DA137323CC90461E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report containing—</text> <paragraph id="HFB027A1D739141DFA51E41AB65B95280"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of the contracts or other agreements entered into pursuant to subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0928A7AA0F0F4A05B5794233D7C46B65"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the criteria used by the Secretary to determine which employees of the Department of Defense performs sensitive national security functions for the purposes of subsection (a), and the total number of such employees; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C958F9FBF9C44459E8296B0F5574883"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total costs of wireless mobile phones and telecommunication services required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body></bill>


