<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1AB61D741696463D832B36BDBB076CCC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8902 IH: Workforce Assurance for Transportation and Critical Homeland Personnel Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8902</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Making continuing appropriations for essential Transportation Security Administration pay and operations during the lapse in appropriations beginning on February 14, 2026, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0556F65A5D434C17A7A8D7D45BA4E1CE" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H123EF167AE3C42CAA136F57BECB6BB7B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Assurance for Transportation and Critical Homeland Personnel Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WATCH Personnel Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8A7107977C8B496C9AB0A746CA7DCD79"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of higher rates of pay for Transportation Security Administration personnel</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32FD9F9378C2498491FB70C364A19ABF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD918DBF16254F09AF2AC29DE961DE7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, set the minimum annual salary for a Transportation Security Officer to $40,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FED5E13D4B347918905ADF57D87B945"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter, adjust the minimum annual salary for a Transportation Security Officer as provided by subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00A7C2D9940841F7A35C9BDBF3B9204B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment of salary for inflation</header><paragraph id="HF77EB93681AC4AA9A533FF2029953585"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall adjust the minimum annual salary for a Transportation Security Officer, on October 1, 2026, and at the beginning of each fiscal year thereafter, to reflect the percentage (if any) of the increase in the average of the Consumer Price Index for the preceding 12-month period compared to the Consumer Price Index for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C0E47E89FE44006BF2976D7FC828476"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rules for calculation of adjustment</header><text>In adjusting under paragraph (1) the minimum annual salary for a Transportation Security Officer, the Administrator—</text><subparagraph id="HC2A2D74F43A74208ABC93C87B7870791"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall round the amount of any increase in the Consumer Price Index to the nearest dollar; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H462103A00CA84644977F4DD54D579AF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may ignore any such increase of less than 1 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39E38C999E7D4C6685CA7BA0B332F2AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consumer price index defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>Consumer Price Index</term> means the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H77DD4B9D2E7C4C49BB0FDA8E01EC9BC8"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Continuing appropriations for Transportation Security Administration personnel</header><subsection id="H28A0E08E23754E9D85161EC8928CFD24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are hereby appropriated for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the period beginning on February 14, 2026, during which interim or full-year appropriations for fiscal year 2026 are not in effect, such sums as are necessary—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BB38B414F714227A558DFF99C78A002"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide standard rates of pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments otherwise payable on a regular basis to employees of the Transportation Security Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6336DE4DEE2F4F7C93CE01262BA47985"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide a $10,000 bonus to each Transportation Security Officer employed and working for the Transportation Security Administration as of February 14, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E1588F90C334D4CB0E2E626C69FF4B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on treatment of bonuses</header><text>A bonus paid under subsection (a)(2) shall not be considered basic pay for purposes of retirement, life insurance, or any other employee benefit.</text></subsection><subsection id="H50998ED0F83D422791EB9ABF113E9167"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation to individuals affected by lapse in appropriations</header><text>Amounts provided under subsection (a) may not be used to provide pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, or other payments under paragraph (1) of that subsection or a bonus under paragraph (2) of that subsection to an employee of the Transportation Security Administration for any portion of the period described in subsection (a) for which the employee is provided with such pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, or other payments using amounts other than amounts provided under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBFC09B376B19416398B18C9ECD54D2E3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Charge to future appropriations</header><text>Expenditures made pursuant to subsection (a) shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever an Act in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is included is enacted into law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2EE72F4589764373BB3C118D98D3D2FC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>Pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments provided by the Transportation Security Administration using amounts provided under subsection (a) shall be subject to the requirements, authorities, conditions, and limitations applicable with respect to the provision of pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments by the Transportation Security Administration under the Full-Year Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/4">Public Law 119–4</external-xref>; 139 Stat. 9).</text></subsection></section><section id="HDD3931531FE741F1BC04C5EB2DB5455D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under section 3 shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text><paragraph id="H6E937CF8587F45D7AA753028535FEF68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The enactment into law of an appropriation (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available in section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5416C98CBAB94F86B67558A106F561C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The enactment into law of the applicable regular or continuing appropriations resolution or other Act without any appropriation for such purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06DB9C061ECC4C478335EE4138EB94DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>September 30, 2026.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE0F8E56DE8A043038DFD5138F7D993FB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Retroactive effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect as if enacted on February 13, 2026.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

