<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H438D8B7EA84C48C18FF0339AD0D5A845" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9757 IH: Conversational AI Services Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9757</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish requirements and guidelines for conversational AI services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2D6E0D20FB80462EBA2E40A3C8F6F2C5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0DC9E9ADDFAB46579B3A9086C9137346" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Conversational AI Services Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAFF9AF7055D742738A2A797E761A5648"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conversational AI services minors requirements</header> <subsection id="HC60B8A3DBCE8477283F2F0B86C6BED82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements and prohibitions</header> <paragraph id="H44A38EBC7D3D4B0A84ECBF931D2D3F7D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Requirements for minors</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator shall clearly and conspicuously disclose to a minor account holder that the minor account holder is interacting with artificial intelligence through either—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H33D05D8D5A9548B4AD02AD611A1E1353">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a persistent visible disclaimer; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HB4AB1014BAD4428AAF4B1D03E567D8C2">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a disclaimer that appears—</text> <clause id="H7CD7983890414A79992949E544404627"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>at the beginning of each interaction between the conversational AI service of the operator and a minor account holder; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HE6FAE3B0BEFC4E11BDD147E96FF76093">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least once every 3 hours of continuous interaction between the conversational AI service of the operator and minor account holder.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H794A75AE580B4F479CB897FF012C0239"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Points and rewards prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator may not provide a minor account holder with points or similar rewards at unpredictable intervals with the intent to encourage increased engagement with the conversational AI service of the operator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BB9E4F9BD6C4208BCDB8B1A9D8EB391"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Safety measures required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator shall institute reasonable measures to prevent the conversational AI service of the operator from doing any of the following for minor account holders:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8DAB4403973544029AC17E8D71B680CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Producing visual depictions of sexually explicit material.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C36085189B84B37BE4AA77FE206AEF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stating that the minor account holder should engage in sexually explicit conduct.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H81D19157EFAE4EC19D8365397221CBA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sexually objectifying the minor account holder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4CC4E43A1534AB99DB0B437B1E28111"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirement for measure to prevent deception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator shall institute reasonable measures for minor account holders to prevent the conversational AI service of the operator from generating statements that would lead a reasonable individual to believe that the individual is interacting with a human, including any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H21B7C2DF3A6E48558AF8434B4C915B54"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Explicit claims that the conversational AI service is sentient or human.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79E5E14960344786B1A573646DDBF828"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statements that simulate emotional dependence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D68FB8107EC41F4BB55B29EB3EDA0FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statements that simulate a romantic interaction or a sexual innuendo.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA139D8DA6C1646F292F15E2C1C2814E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Role-playing an adult-minor romantic relationship.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8AFEFD4E5414356B7012EA0A51153DD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Parental supervision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator shall make available tools for a minor account holder and any parent or guardian of the minor account holder to manage the screen time and account settings of the minor account holder.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FEDE805269C49768E465AF178CBA1A8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consumer disclosures</header><text>An operator shall clearly and conspicuously disclose, using a persistent visible disclaimer or a disclaimer that appears after every 3 hours of continuous interaction with the conversational AI service of the operator, that the conversational AI service is artificial intelligence if a reasonable individual interacting with the conversational AI service would believe that the individual is interacting with a human.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7D731E79CF947779F73C7D5AD445B26"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Suicide and self-harm protocol</header><text>An operator shall adopt protocols for the conversational AI service of the operator for responding to user prompts regarding suicidal ideation or self-harm that includes making reasonable efforts to refer the user to a crisis service provider such as a suicide hotline, a crisis text line, or other appropriate crisis service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACDC3A990B6841E7B7DE63F1BDC442B4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Mental health care</header><text>An operator may not knowingly and intentionally cause or program a conversational AI service to make a representation or statement that would lead a reasonable individual to believe that the conversational AI service is designed to provide professional psychology or behavioral health services for which an individual would require licensure.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA02E3F52240E4A0BBEF0FA3008528EC0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H509E1C80CA9B4C5996DADCAE65CDAC82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94F9A11A638C465D8448000ECD78177A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce subsection (a) and any regulation promulgated under such subsection in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates such subsection or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H160D6BE2BD3C4EE496A2ED46029299BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC3B927FA1BB349CDA8A1BB96D0558436"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Account holder</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>account holder</term> means an individual to which an account or profile to use a conversational AI service belongs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB6BA4599A074AB8938640687B10F3FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conversational AI service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>conversational AI service</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H505184A8EA0C479CB0F62D493E0920DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an artificial intelligence, available by software application, web interface, or computer program, that is accessible to the general public and that has the primary purpose of simulating human conversation and interaction through text, audio communication, or visual communication; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C4B1F2C10DF45D2A2061FD749B4593A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a software application, web interface, or computer program that is—</text> <clause id="H5DCBECBC55E647E993E6F25F5279A16C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primarily designed and marketed for research and development purposes;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H89C18A2A23484AD7B6C2D6C48361A597"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a feature within another software application, web interface, or computer program that does not have the primary purpose of simulating human conversation and interaction through text, audio communication, or visual communication;</text></clause> <clause id="H614FB15B00494837BB53B02B73331AAA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designed to provide outputs relating to a narrow and discrete topic;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HECB643B33B9F4A499F76884DB3A7A829"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primarily designed and marketed for commercial use by business entities to assist customers in obtaining services or purchasing goods from the business;</text></clause> <clause id="H83A69013401C46BAA461064F84F1989F"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">functions as a speaker and voice command interface or voice-activated virtual assistant for an electronic device widely available to consumers; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC51E7488B80B4EEF9582818F2065923C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used by a business solely for internal purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H193A8E55B07149689387ED1F1E2E9932"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minor</term> means an individual an operator knows is, or is reasonably certain is, under 18 years of age.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14AE8290B437495284C0CED7BE55C92F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Operator</header><text>The term <term>operator</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3ABCD1A6A02D42D4B85CA994191F37C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a person who develops and makes a conversational AI service available to the public; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD88D78152C7B4917823D2D5BECB832AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a mobile device application store or a search engine solely because the mobile device application store or search engine provides access to a conversational AI service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2730CD6879DC40CCA35E4ECB5A285913"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sexually explicit conduct; visual depiction</header><text>The terms <term>sexually explicit conduct</term> and <quote>visual depiction</quote> have the meaning given those terms in section 2256 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H283A9C4FECFC44229E0736057205FE1A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall take effect one year after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

