<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F9189EA382E4FA5A089E10F2F0BF185" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7335 IH: Humanitarian Standards for Individuals in ICE and CBP Custody Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7335</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260203">February 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection to perform an initial health screening on detainees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB141A402723540B2BB704BD134362BBA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H107A69DDFDBA4E86ABFAF4138A777B0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HBF9B616928694B2A9A7F2F24AE747F9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Humanitarian Standards for Individuals in ICE and CBP Custody Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDF4923526C3540F19961C9AA4A466CFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H107A69DDFDBA4E86ABFAF4138A777B0D" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H571DF5A797734734B78B5266B18049E0" level="section">Sec. 2. Initial health screening protocol.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0F9FADFF01E14E58A27AE6D63F06B235" level="section">Sec. 3. Water, sanitation and hygiene.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H78D17D0F515B4AEF9D859A3C290503CF" level="section">Sec. 4. Food and nutrition.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF504C24142484E5B9DB97631E4D392D2" level="section">Sec. 5. Shelter.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H66080EFB33C041EEA0BDBC022FB37A0B" level="section">Sec. 6. Coordination and Surge capacity.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7DC1040A528C4D3A965FE1E9639927B3" level="section">Sec. 7. Training.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H45AA4F3A85494D218493174E42B5EE08" level="section">Sec. 8. Interfacility transfer of care.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAAA7E9B7200F4263928D95888782D1A7" level="section">Sec. 9. Planning and initial implementation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H33620629226A437580F3DE1E468E85A3" level="section">Sec. 10. Contractor compliance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCB953AD158834D9F8AE31A31FF00827D" level="section">Sec. 11. Inspections.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAAE213395162475DBDF69235847E0739" level="section">Sec. 12. GAO report.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H451E0932509F4930BD1D4FC7289AD801" level="section">Sec. 13. Rules of construction.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE0C427F1B44745CF97E8ACBFCB5F6F74" level="section">Sec. 14. Publication of data on complaints of sexual abuse at ICE and CBP facilities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7CEBBEE16E594DA193015C9A24661BD3" level="section">Sec. 15. Definitions.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H571DF5A797734734B78B5266B18049E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Initial health screening protocol</header> 
<subsection id="HA3AADE06E5E04CC3A60FFA13484B0E4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Director and Commissioner</quote>), in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, and nongovernmental experts in the delivery of health care in humanitarian crises and in the delivery of health care to children, shall develop guidelines and protocols for the provision of health screenings and appropriate medical care for individuals in the custody of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (referred to in this Act as <quote>ICE</quote>) or U.S. Customs and Border Protection (referred to in this Act as <quote>CBP</quote>), as the case may be, as required under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7A9F467F0B6C4B02AD51A508ADE0A56E"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Initial screening and medical assessment</header> <text>The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that any individual who is detained in the custody of ICE or CBP, as the case may be, (referred to in this Act as a <quote>detainee</quote>) receives an initial in-person screening by a licensed medical professional in accordance with the standards described in subsection (c)—</text>
        <paragraph id="HAE57DEE669F34285AA365528CFCB5011">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to assess and identify any illness, condition, or age-appropriate mental or physical symptoms that may have resulted from distressing or traumatic experiences;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H28BDEEAB122243A2A642B4F1A7839D70">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to identify acute conditions and high-risk vulnerabilities; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5548B3121CC54FE9AC74055ABF3B86EC"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>to ensure that appropriate healthcare is provided to individuals as needed, including pediatric, obstetric, and geriatric care.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H752DAEFE7ED74878814CA99F28632789"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standardization of initial screening and medical assessment</header> 
<paragraph id="H410F3A9E945F4DCA8B2DD5EC98F1666B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The initial screening and medical assessment shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA6F6BB2B245C48F490295BAA4AB7B902"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An interview and the use of a standardized medical intake questionnaire or the equivalent.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2B15F04E33F404ABC31A83CC47E8DDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Screening of vital signs, including pulse rate, body temperature, blood pressure, oxygen saturation, and respiration rate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1C347644BC645FD923BB906AA83A6A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Screening for blood glucose for known or suspected diabetics.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9609B58F39E14ED6BC838AE1D979F141"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Weight assessment of detainees under 12 years of age.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97437E12AB69486DA897687F58A77463"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A physical examination.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H324EE0A4ABE646E39ABEC64FA39CDAF7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A risk-assessment and the development of a plan for monitoring and care, when appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAEC4E595A4D4C238948227F354C37CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prescription medication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The medical professional shall review any prescribed medication that is in the detainee’s possession or that was confiscated by ICE or CBP, as the case may be, upon arrival and determine if the medication may be kept by the detainee for use during detention, properly stored by ICE or CBP, as the case may be, with appropriate access for use during detention, or maintained with the detained individual’s personal property. A detainee may not be denied the use of necessary and appropriate medication for the management of the detainee’s illness.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF9B691ED9A94D18AF82B884D32B5968"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed as requiring detainees to disclose their medical status or history.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCF46E74A9A91403CADC38E686F4EA779"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing</header> <paragraph id="H71F0E3080FE44CF7A8EDD869287F1484"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the initial screening and medical assessment described in subsections (b) and (c) shall take place as soon as practicable, but not later than 12 hours after a detainee’s arrival at an ICE or CBP facility, as the case may be.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H372317B2E74B449BA58D411889BA5226"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High priority individuals</header><text>The initial screening and medical assessment described in subsections (b) and (c) shall take place as soon as practicable, but not later than 6 hours after a detainee’s arrival at an ICE or CBP facility, as the case may be, if the individual reasonably self-identifies as having a medical condition that requires prompt medical attention or is—</text> <subparagraph id="H04BED7DFD3CF40E783CC769DA0D0D033"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exhibiting signs of acute or potentially severe physical or mental illness, or otherwise has an acute or chronic physical or mental disability or illness;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E527DCFF7904974AF0FC482005D84BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pregnant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41108362370E454C9B02903059F13005"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a child (with priority given, as appropriate, to the youngest children); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3675199C2BA476E804B25E3897E57DE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>elderly.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9B9D8A4912CE407CA4A1485110CA4CC7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Further care</header> <paragraph id="HB10382E0E9F7470F9C9CC0950B6F23BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, as a result of the initial health screening and medical assessment, the licensed medical professional conducting the screening or assessment determines that one or more of the detainee’s vital sign measurements are significantly outside normal ranges in accordance with the National Emergency Services Education Standards, or if the detainee is identified as high-risk or in need of medical intervention, the detainee shall be provided, as expeditiously as possible, with an in-person or technology-facilitated medical consultation with a licensed emergency care professional.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC990D56892F640E4A2A2B94E8C297A4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Re-evaluation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H933D01A79D9A4263B0BB8EEDE0557764"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Detainees described in paragraph (1) shall be re-evaluated within 24 hours and monitored thereafter as determined by an emergency care professional (and in the care of a consultation provided to a child, with a licensed emergency care professional with a background in pediatric care).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18C1E434994A481583EAE3224DDA72FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reevaluation prior to transportation</header><text>In addition to the re-evaluations under subparagraph (A), detainees shall have all vital signs re-evaluated and be cleared as safe to travel by a medical professional prior to transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67EAA852D7344061802A4455A9DDD48B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pyschological and mental care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that detainees who have experienced physical or sexual violence or who have experienced events that may cause severe trauma or toxic stress, are provided access to basic, humane, and supportive psychological assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0088A1D55CC548818E45E858F98E3B4A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Interpreters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To ensure that health screenings and medical care required under this section are carried out in the best interests of the detainee, the Director and Commissioner shall ensure that language-appropriate interpretation services, including indigenous languages, are provided to each detainee and that each detainee is informed of the availability of interpretation services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC83E0427AD8041F29A990144357C2444"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Chaperones</header><text>To ensure that health screenings and medical care required under this section are carried out in the best interests of the detainee—</text> <paragraph id="HA2108947EDEB4E329D4470506620BC1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director and Commissioner shall establish guidelines for and ensure the presence of chaperones for all detainees during medical screenings and examinations consistent with relevant guidelines in the American Medical Association Code of Medical Ethics, and recommendations of the American Academy of Pediatrics; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE641A081D624043B08039A98AC1794B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, the physical examination of a child shall always be performed in the presence of a parent or legal guardian or in the presence of the detainee’s closest present adult relative if a parent or legal guardian is unavailable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H94C36C6326CF4DD98A53202836D38E50"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that the health screenings and medical care required under this section, along with any other medical evaluations and interventions for detainees, are documented in accordance with commonly accepted standards in the United States for medical record documentation. Such documentation shall be provided to any individual who received a health screening and subsequent medical treatment upon release from ICE or CBP custody, as the case may be.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE728E89D85C4A7EBC37920DBCFC7811"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Infrastructure and equipment</header><text>The Director and Commissioner or the Administrator of General Services shall ensure that each location to which detainees are first transported after an initial encounter with an agent or officer of ICE or CBP, as the case may be, has the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFF53B90951E743128AB66CF6EFCD9ACC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A private space that provides a comfortable and considerate atmosphere for the patient and that ensures the patient’s dignity and right to privacy during the health screening and medical assessment and any necessary follow-up care.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6331AC0FBB7D4910BB66241FDE6EA941"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All necessary and appropriate medical equipment and facilities to conduct the health screenings and follow-up care required under this section, to treat trauma, to provide emergency care, including resuscitation of individuals of all ages, and to prevent the spread of communicable diseases.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D1C2763CE19432981823913BBAC7BA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Basic over-the-counter medications appropriate for all age groups.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77B365FC79AC4EEB8E1C8E0BC6C1704C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Appropriate transportation to medical facilities in the case of a medical emergency, or an on-call service with the ability to arrive at the ICE or CBP facility, as the case may be, within 30 minutes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB3EE9BBD34F842E7B08CE30C525B636F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner or the Administrator of General Services shall ensure that each location to which detainees are first transported after an initial encounter has onsite at least one licensed medical professional to conduct health screenings. Other personnel that are or may be necessary for carrying out the functions described in subsection (e), such as licensed emergency care professionals, specialty physicians (including physicians specializing in pediatrics, family medicine, obstetrics and gynecology, geriatric medicine, internal medicine, and infectious diseases), nurse practitioners, other nurses, physician assistants. licensed social workers, mental health professionals, public health professionals, dieticians, interpreters, and chaperones, shall be located on site to the extent practicable, or if not practicable, shall be available on call.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H230787E72E9540599D5312059DAFE830"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Ethical guidelines</header><text>The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that all medical assessments and procedures conducted pursuant to this section are conducted in accordance with ethical guidelines in the applicable medical field, and respect human dignity.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0F9FADFF01E14E58A27AE6D63F06B235"><enum>3.</enum><header>Water, sanitation and hygiene</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that detainees have access to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1116094485D04EC89380D4A20D97079B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not less than 1 gallon of drinking water per person per day, and age-appropriate fluids as needed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H574C53A7D37E4FAFAC46B1D0BE587A5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A private, safe, clean, and reliable permanent or portable toilet with proper waste disposal and a hand washing station, with not less than 1 toilet available for every 12 male detainees, and 1 toilet for every 8 female detainees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC26141B606594D61861DF3DCFBF2E88D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A clean diaper changing facility, which includes proper waste disposal, a hand washing station, and unrestricted access to diapers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50BB2CFDF2594E84A4E034049FFD111D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The opportunity to bathe daily in a permanent or portable shower that is private and secure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A16A6E8948241149DC4A5AA9F1F52E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Products for individuals of all age groups and with disabilities to maintain basic personal hygiene, including soap, a toothbrush, toothpaste, adult diapers, and feminine hygiene products, as well as receptacles for the proper storage and disposal of such products.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H78D17D0F515B4AEF9D859A3C290503CF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Food and nutrition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that detainees have access to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H45DE525E6A35435BB94FF477B8D5DF5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Three meals per day, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H5C79B2125E994AF0954398D602D4160D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of an individual age 12 or older, a diet that contains not less than 2,000 calories per day.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E169E783185450A96ABE0A276AC6B67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a child who is under the age of 12, a diet that contains an appropriate number of calories per day based on the child’s age and weight.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE752BA1BEA0C441A8E31B0B15555B7B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Accommodations for any dietary needs or restrictions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56C3583F194F4C148026C2DB2B090142"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Access to food in a manner that follows applicable food safety standards.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF504C24142484E5B9DB97631E4D392D2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Shelter</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that each facility at which a detainee is detained meets the following requirements:</text> 
<paragraph id="H22E0069E1F8442D1B8F75122F03AD092"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), males and females shall be detained separately.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03C52545C13B44BD95313286AC971059"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of a minor child arriving in the United States with an adult relative or legal guardian, such child shall be detained with such relative or legal guardian unless such an arrangement poses safety or security concerns. In no case shall a minor who is detained apart from an adult relative or legal guardian as a result of such safety or security concerns be detained with other adults.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE51029CE11484D32B2E1D0021B499616"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case of an unaccompanied minor arriving in the United States without an adult relative or legal guardian, such child shall be detained in an age-appropriate facility and shall not be detained with adults.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72A1AD66C394494CB3C7ECEB863A8DBE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A detainee with a temporary or permanent disability shall be held in an accessible location and in a manner that provides for his or her safety, comfort, and security, with accommodations provided as needed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DDC5FB24E7140279F08C03450562BE7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>No detainee shall be placed in a room for any period of time if the detainee’s placement would exceed the maximum occupancy level as determined by the appropriate building code, fire marshal, or other authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H478DB1D6AAEB43288205DED96EDF7377"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Each detainee shall be provided with temperature appropriate clothing and bedding.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DEAA42C1D434070A25D116FD1CE45D3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The facility shall be well lit and well ventilated, with the humidity and temperature kept at comfortable levels (between 68 and 74 degrees Fahrenheit).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC044CE52B9FB418C8464C5E64112B54B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Detainees who are in custody for more than 48 hours shall have access to the outdoors for not less than 1 hour during the daylight hours during each 24-hour period.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9884CF76D009423D97059AE41A6D8171"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Detainees shall have the ability to practice their religion or not to practice a religion, as applicable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92DE7203B44D4823910460D78C328DEE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Detainees shall have access to lighting and noise levels that are safe and conducive for sleeping throughout the night between the hours of 10 p.m. and 6 a.m.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF815184FC0234B5B8ECF733E5D045083"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Officers, employees, and contracted personnel of ICE or CBP, as the case may be, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE4E4E25764F4760BC27129C9BD15DB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>follow medical standards for the isolation and prevention of communicable diseases; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8ECD0EE57794AF589E0B90DBA73A471"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure the physical and mental safety of detainees who identify as lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and intersex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H832A1B1B335C4BE98325B079CCB442B6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The facility shall have video-monitoring to provide for the safety of the detained population and to prevent sexual abuse and physical harm of vulnerable detainees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2D121AC1A2A49248807C272B7D9E8A5"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that language-appropriate <quote>Detainee Bill of Rights</quote>, including indigenous languages, are posted or otherwise made available in all areas where detainees are located. The <quote>Detainee Bill of Rights</quote> shall include all rights afforded to the detainee under this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C17239138D048BEA7EAA098004BD2F6"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Video from video-monitoring must be preserved for 90 days and the detention facility must maintain certified records that the video-monitoring is properly working at all times.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H66080EFB33C041EEA0BDBC022FB37A0B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Coordination and Surge capacity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall enter into memoranda of understanding with appropriate Federal agencies, such as the Department of Health and Human Services, and applicable emergency government relief services, as well as contracts with health care, public health, social work, and transportation professionals, for purposes of addressing surge capacity and ensuring compliance with this Act.</text></section> <section id="H7DC1040A528C4D3A965FE1E9639927B3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner shall ensure that ICE and CBP personnel, respectively, assigned to each short-term custodial facility are professionally trained, including continuing education as the Director and Commissioner, respectively, determines appropriate, in all subjects necessary to ensure compliance with this Act, including the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4D108E467AF047FDA3A143AF2DA836A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Humanitarian response protocols and standards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B3C3C1A88EE4A4EA2DF0F09549DAE3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Indicators of physical and mental illness, and medical distress in children and adults.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94421B6C8BC8434E84D5DFFAC138264B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Indicators of child sexual exploitation and effective responses to missing migrant children.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1321DC343194C75B7B1C4A07B76E1F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Procedures to report incidents of suspected child sexual abuse and exploitation directly to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H45AA4F3A85494D218493174E42B5EE08"><enum>8.</enum><header>Interfacility transfer of care</header> 
<subsection id="HC2D318720960499E8F5A33D52529A8C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When a detainee is discharged from a medical facility or emergency department, the Director and Commissioner, as the case may be, shall ensure that responsibility of care is transferred from the medical facility or emergency department to an accepting licensed health care provider of ICE or CBP, as the case may be.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H955E8BADB1B04E39B4D69B6EC51FC07F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities of accepting providers</header><text>Such accepting licensed health care provider shall review the medical facility or emergency department’s evaluation, diagnosis, treatment, management, and discharge care instructions to assess the safety of the discharge and transfer and to provide necessary follow-up care.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAAA7E9B7200F4263928D95888782D1A7"><enum>9.</enum><header>Planning and initial implementation</header> 
<subsection id="H88CD4882E43C4000A665312EEF6CBBFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Planning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a detailed plan delineating the timeline, process, and challenges of carrying out the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6036D496E9684A11B1BB8EEFCC22212F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the requirements of this Act are implemented not later than 6 months after the date of enactment.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H33620629226A437580F3DE1E468E85A3"><enum>10.</enum><header>Contractor compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that all personnel contracted to carry out this Act do so in accordance with the requirements of this Act.</text></section> <section id="HCB953AD158834D9F8AE31A31FF00827D"><enum>11.</enum><header>Inspections</header> <subsection id="H4F8AC4FDF10A4CBB8ABB5E9A6DF48CCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2BC3BC15FF394A84BAC241B35569FF8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conduct unannounced inspections of ports of entry, border patrol stations, and detention facilities administered by ICE or CBP, as the case may be, or contractors of ICE or CBP, as the case may be.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H807D524C029C49E98CEB6F882F4D1113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Submit to Congress, reports on the results of such inspections as well as other reports of the Inspector General related to custody operations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H31B32F1C87504754B77AD08B26D546BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Particular attention</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall pay particular attention to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H634532E446134B76928C36BFC555BA7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The degree of compliance by ICE and CBP with the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H071B77D13ACA46D9AFEF7FC4C53145EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Remedial actions taken by ICE and CBP.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49594BDE0EF340D6841941F7235D2BAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The health needs of detainees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8F0C54959E542048F4E9112EC96F0AA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The degree of compliance with part 115 of title 6, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly known as the <quote>Standards To Prevent, Detect, and Respond to Sexual Abuse and Assault in Confinement Facilities</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9E56FB3E1002430EBE4BBE057FB1488B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access to facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director and Commissioner, as the case may be, may not deny a Member of Congress entrance to any facility or building used, owned, or operated by ICE or CBP, as the case may be.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAAE213395162475DBDF69235847E0739"><enum>12.</enum><header>GAO report</header> 
<subsection id="H72CB562FA70B42C6BE6C77672C000683"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9381808A1DE4480BB58B5B8709DB0E71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, commence a study on implementation of, and compliance with, this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9099D0BE054F40E4BC4641B9C9B48A16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report to Congress on the results of such study.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF5697FEE6FDA44E0B110026F50EEE279"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Issues To be studied</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study required by subsection (a) shall examine the management and oversight by ICE and CBP of ports of entry, border patrol stations, and other detention facilities, including the extent to which ICE and CBP and the Department of Homeland Security have effective processes in place to comply with this Act. The study shall also examine the extent to which ICE and CBP personnel, in carrying out this Act, make abusive, derisive, profane, or harassing statements or gestures, or engage in any other conduct evidencing hatred or invidious prejudice to or about one person or group on account of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, age, or disability, including on social media.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H451E0932509F4930BD1D4FC7289AD801"><enum>13.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text> <paragraph id="HCC7F8983174C404A96A9304011E70835"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as authorizing ICE or CBP to detain individuals for longer than 72 hours;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8B08B33E43240279940564128E4A4CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as contradicting the March 7, 2014, Department of Homeland Security rule adopting Standards to Prevent, Detect, and Respond to Sexual Abuse and Assault in Confinement Facilities, which includes a zero tolerance policy prohibiting all forms of sexual abuse and assault of individuals in U.S. Customs and Border Protection custody, including in holding facilities, during transport, and during processing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06236130B3B54B1F9DAD1B14B44B76C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as contradicting current protocols related to Department background checks in the hiring process;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD14F71669623462F98638FEAF4F1F411"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as restricting the Department from denying employment to or terminating the employment of any individual who would be or is involved with the handling or processing at holding facilities, during transport, or during processing, or care of detainees, including the care of children, and has been convicted of a sex crime or other offense involving a child victim; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC004A314070740EBBE3C5E19AA7EE2A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>as affecting the obligation to fully comply with all applicable immigration laws, including being subject to any penalties, fines, or other sanctions.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE0C427F1B44745CF97E8ACBFCB5F6F74"><enum>14.</enum><header>Publication of data on complaints of sexual abuse at ICE and CBP facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting in coordination with the Office of Inspector General and Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, shall publicly release aggregate data on complaints of sexual abuse at ICE and CBP facilities on its website on a quarterly basis, excluding any personally identifiable information that may compromise the confidentiality of individuals who reported abuse.</text></section> <section id="H7CEBBEE16E594DA193015C9A24661BD3"><enum>15.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A3359E09645424E87ACDEF226E7563F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <quote>child</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD12E3C10100E4083AC9305702AA57DE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forward operating base</header><text>The term <quote>forward operating base</quote> means a permanent facility established by CBP in forward or remote locations, and designated as such by CBP.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75789DBDE9084529B92EFFC637AA69F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interpretation services</header><text>The term <quote>interpretation services</quote> includes translation services that are performed either in-person or through a telephone or video service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75DF875C827944C5A70F03B83FD50BB9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>U.S. Customs and Border Protection facility</header><text>The term <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection Facility</quote> includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB744B45A043E4775B963DD32E543FA42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>U.S. Border Patrol stations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H805DE200986C43FE8A48BB6857737B02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ports of entry.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA54F9E4A8E6B4CFDA48D6A4E052CD846"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Checkpoints.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEFC76C638F0143158EAC325C2191F37E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Forward operating bases.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0800630BFD9F463B97564F7B618FAD47"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Secondary inspection areas.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88D0A6F3C2D2426984079977A8BFE8D2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Short-term custody facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD04CA071C3044519532EF045A8383F1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>U.S. Immigration and Customs enforcement facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement facility</quote> means a confinement facility operated by or pursuant to contract with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) that routinely holds persons for over 24 hours pending resolution or completion of immigration removal operations or processes, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF4AA4580F26B4DB4B258E2B549678233"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Facilities that are operated by ICE.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H10B255D2974A4D4BB6E0F0681DE63DF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facilities that provide detention services under a contract awarded by ICE.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66A26315CC8F4384AE6C0D9A7B86BA23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Facilities used by ICE pursuant to an Intergovernmental Service Agreement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

