<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99219EF9D4654E15AFCB3BE80CCCCAE2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5962 IH: Abducted Ukrainian Children Recovery and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5962</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To authorize the Department of Justice and the Department of State to provide law enforcement and intelligence technical assistance, training, capacity building, and advisory support to the Government of Ukraine to achieve the exchange of prisoners of war, the release of civilian detainees, and the return of forcibly transferred Ukrainian children, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H7B9F5F9E4E044164AD25CCC4FBD0865D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD1471D5C8FF743C4A8275963F05DC2E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Supporting the identification and recovery of abducted Ukrainian children</header> 
<subsection id="H7538A41784CB469F89A880C77FC6FDF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This section may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abducted Ukrainian Children Recovery and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H245E7DD023E9418AA8F791AB41D2C47F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H98FFDA9112B3459B8070001456F7A463"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to a White House press release, dated March, 2025, <quote>The United States and Ukraine agreed that the United States remains committed to helping achieve the exchange of prisoners of war, the release of civilian detainees, and the return of forcibly transferred Ukrainian children.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21D78DB58D804C33B39AEF4E7516840E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To implement the commitment referred to in paragraph (1), the United States Government requires an organized and resourced policy approach to assist Ukraine with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF12DFA6D67414C18ADD9DD05347C7B45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>investigations of Russia’s abduction of Ukrainian children;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8271DF2F1B94F46B9421CB0B0486E58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the rehabilitation and reintegration of children returned to Ukraine; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H272299BF7691458799F80E8F8FE47F0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>justice and accountability for perpetrators of the abductions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1FA6FB2B1B36471797B95E460A23ADEC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of technical assistance and advisory support</header> <paragraph id="H74583D662E764E3BAFE4A975E2BA3AB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Department of Justice and the Department of State are authorized—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9BF83C7CB066408E89EE6404472F40D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide law enforcement and intelligence technical assistance, training, capacity building, and advisory support to the Government of Ukraine in support of the commitment described in subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0CCB2F6398840FD93D69777F8A139A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to advance the objectives described in subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H752F6AE55A2A4C0AABF780C2B340CDA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Type of assistance</header><text>The law enforcement and intelligence technical assistance authorized under paragraph (1)(A) may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D76049B2F7644A39BEC5DF03D3B8C40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training regarding the utilization of biometric identification technologies in abduction and trafficking in persons investigations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED6E7983F51C4F2DAA7D1AE42BA14B8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assistance with respect to collecting and analyzing open source intelligence information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96C2B64712544A13B45E5D5EA73AB57E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assistance in the development and use of secure communications technologies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H804B25BA416143CB93CEE544B67EE48C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assistance with respect to managing and securing relevant databases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95182FF2592247CF8C7F20520DB297F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the determination to provide assistance in any category identified in this subsection, the Secretary of State shall brief the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H709F9F92802A4C51ABFD3B99C87AB3E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of assistance determined to be obligated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3BF8FB1870644E9A4A05488FF9D5A95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the type of assistance to be utilized; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H591377013A6D46E1A36E46C1741BF5A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any information on the technology operationalized to support the means identified in this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F47DE4BF54D4C1ABEE8FC592659E54C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header> <paragraph id="HAE598BC7568A4A20B494F750C4089145"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nongovernmental organizations</header><text>The Department of Justice and the Department of State may coordinate with, and provide grants to, nongovernmental organizations to carry out the assistance authorized under subsection (c).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC496529F6534BB88C170A5D55D05AD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agencies</header><text>The National Security Council may coordinate with appropriate representatives from the Department of Justice, the Department of State, the intelligence community (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>)), and other Federal agencies, as needed, to carry out the assistance authorized under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H29066A7FEE04427597C7B413C343FB9D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rehabilitation and reintegration</header> <paragraph id="H621C5026AB384E8FB0601256BB444A0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of assistance</header><text>The Secretary of State is authorized to provide support to the Government of Ukraine and nongovernmental organizations and local civil society groups in Ukraine for the purpose of providing Ukrainian children (including teenagers) who have been abducted, forcibly transferred, or held against their will by the Russian Federation with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB5AA447F756B4091AAA57380EA5D0596"><enum>(A)</enum><text>medical and psychological rehabilitation services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4502D93180C4F669DCAFD12714F783A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family reunification and support services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE515C9142A7D4FE2BD35A6C67BBA5501"><enum>(C)</enum><text>services in support of the reintegration of such children into Ukrainian society, including case management, legal aid, and educational screening and placement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FC3F76304934A35B245B86BA1534EE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives that describes all current or planned foreign assistance programs that will provide the assistance authorized under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50940FE54EDE41D5B49C07B16C576184"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Atrocity crimes advisory group for Ukraine</header><text>The Department of State is authorized to support the Atrocity Crimes Advisory Group for Ukraine by providing technical assistance, capacity building, and advisory support to the Government of Ukraine’s Office of the Prosecutor General, and other relevant components of the Government of Ukraine, for the purpose of investigating and prosecuting cases involving abducted children, and other atrocity crimes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE60684E7B97140B295FCED379E49D2ED"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Department of Justice</header><text>The Department of Justice is authorized to provide technical assistance, capacity building, and advisory support to the Government of Ukraine through its Office of Overseas Prosecutorial Development, Assistance, and Training, which shall be coordinated by the Resident Legal Adviser at the United States Embassy in Kyiv, for the purpose of investigating and prosecuting cases involving abducted children, and other atrocity crimes.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H83438017E6FB4DC18F64FE20BDD83C58"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H3C14E07CC91246C1A1F701827A431305"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, shall submit a report to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives that describes current and planned United States Government support for the Government of Ukraine’s work to investigate and prosecute atrocity crimes; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC00CCD21A0E34CAA8191A3B1D992A440"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a report to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives that outlines—</text> <subparagraph id="HA8572D177420427E968EAA0170BAB869"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any discrepancies between the sanctions regimes of the United States, the United Kingdom, and the European Union with respect to those responsible for the abduction of Ukrainian children; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4A3EDCDCB2C4DF2B8346A11DAEC5A53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts made by the United States Government to better align such sanction regimes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

