<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25B37-VN5-F2-8CM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 496 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of November 8, 2025, as “National First-Generation College Celebration Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 496</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of November 8, 2025, as <quote>National First-Generation College Celebration Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas a <term>first-generation college student</term> means an individual whose parents did not complete a baccalaureate degree, or in the case of any individual who regularly resided with and received support from only 1 parent, an individual whose parent did not complete a baccalaureate degree;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas November 8 honors the anniversary of the signing of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) by President Lyndon B. Johnson on November 8, 1965;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Higher Education Act of 1965 was focused on increasing postsecondary education access and success for students, particularly low-income and first-generation college students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Higher Education Act of 1965 helped usher in programs necessary for low-income, first-generation college students to access, remain in, and complete postsecondary education, including the Federal TRIO programs under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Federal Pell Grant program under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal TRIO programs are the primary national effort supporting underrepresented students in postsecondary education and are designed to identify individuals from low-income backgrounds that would be first-generation college students and prepare them for postsecondary education, provide them support services, and motivate and prepare them for doctoral programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Pell Grant program under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>) is the primary Federal investment in financial aid for low-income college students and is used by students at institutions of higher education of their choice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas first-generation college students may face additional academic, financial, and social challenges that their peers do not face in pursuing higher education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 54 percent of all college students pursuing degrees at the time of the introduction of this resolution are first-generation college students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Council for Opportunity in Education and FirstGen Forward, formerly the Center for First-generation Student Success, jointly launched the inaugural First-Generation College Celebration in 2017; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the First-Generation College Celebration has continued to grow, and institutions of higher education, corporations, nonprofit organizations, and elementary and secondary schools now celebrate November 8 as <quote>First-Generation College Celebration Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id4f0cfe21e0b24079af77d9520d95f141"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of November 8, 2025, as <quote>National First-Generation College Celebration Day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4d32f748c5c4054a1c2bd8681281af7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges all people of the United States to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb85a5545f8f343f8950413af707481c9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>celebrate <quote>National First-Generation College Celebration Day</quote> throughout the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53207ea4e8f6467aa94dc68fbfb9520f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recognize the important role that first-generation college students play in helping to develop the future workforce; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida54ea668aa3041ca910b6c806225d9cf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>celebrate the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) and its programs that help underrepresented students access higher education. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

