<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26C71-648-60-YGM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4781 IS: Make More in America Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4781</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To expand the mission of the Export-Import Bank of the United States and focus on building export-related domestic critical industries that produce goods and services that support employment in the United States and strengthen global competitiveness, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71c58a3992e14ef1886265d7c5d2dd69"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Make More in America Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc91ee19cfa24f11a8ce1d2947ff516f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id134fafc93c3e44f885b0b7fcf4e4b90c">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id688d15ba103b4281a83cbbf4127ef1fe">Sec. 3. Purposes.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb7fd019a393343c9b180484fbb09ea21">Sec. 4. Modification of powers and functions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idcbeac8f4160f4bd6b3272985b13dfe5f">Sec. 5. Make More in America Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id30046974afe848d295ebf144366ad3d6">Sec. 6. Modification of aggregate loan, guarantee, and insurance authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id66d52956cfe5408ba9c4da19f8e4197b">Sec. 7. Modification of default rate and lending cap.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3e8b5da6be3742bc89712794732e719e">Sec. 8. Investment Committee.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id26b364150f8b48b8a24da8be4e2abc70">Sec. 9. Interagency coordination.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id54618eac011845e5a2459975a5374533">Sec. 10. Limitation on eligibility for support.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb9b477b8c1d4471e8355d2a0f1d53990">Sec. 11. Modification of Program on China and Transformational Exports.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9da03a6603d04ff9aa5381b04b3dfc48">Sec. 12. Increase in goal for export of goods and services related to renewable energy sources, energy efficiency, and energy storage.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id954bd8d4862d486597207cd80e83c766">Sec. 13. Employment authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4f44672c1bf04e44bdc8df18ec2154f6">Sec. 14. Expansion of guarantee coverage.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id134fafc93c3e44f885b0b7fcf4e4b90c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id6c6745b2b02b429a8cd5c2f62c27cd8e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China poses a significant competitive threat to the United States, accounting, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, for 35 percent of manufacturing volume globally and 29 percent of value-add (as opposed to 12 percent of volume and 16 percent of value-add for the United States). The People's Republic of China continues to gain ground in higher value-add technologies that were traditionally United States strengths.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b376f86f1ad46fb99ed64ba051b3089"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The People's Republic of China’s increased competitiveness can be traced to multiple sources, including coordinated initiatives such as Made in China 2025, which channeled resources toward manufacturing in higher value-add industries. However, the People's Republic of China also, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, leads in research and development in 66 of 74 areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a76d769ec3346778f9838480043f5be"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Taken together, the two trends described in paragraphs (1) and (2) suggest that the People's Republic of China's lead in exports will grow, not shrink, unless serious action is taken by the United States to strengthen its domestic innovation and industrial investment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id38ac917b8cbb47f8bd30325895b5d679"><enum>(4)</enum><text>This is especially true for critical industries of the future, such as next-generation automotives and drones, industrial automation, biotechnology, biomanufacturing, quantum technology, and fusion energy, unless the United States takes steps to support technology development in those markets. Many of those markets are, or could be, vital export opportunities with meaningful economic, national security, and job creation implications for the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0eb4c10de9047e097f227f0e6508ab4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States also faces supply chain vulnerabilities in critical inputs for those industries of the future, including energy, semiconductors and associated technologies like circuit boards, critical minerals, batteries, and other technology components.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id067c05313e2748aa8112da6f43d3d215"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Capital-intensive industries with long production cycles, such as shipbuilding, chemical processing, and nuclear energy systems, face particularly acute financing challenges during the commercialization phase and the scaling of domestic production. Similarly, drone manufacturing and advanced robotics require coordinated investments in both production capacity and workforce training that private markets struggle to provide. The result is that countries with patient public capital, particularly the People's Republic of China, have captured dominant market positions in sectors where United States innovation initially led.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1dfa6e6b60c40ba86921f3d94af9b73"><enum>(7)</enum><text>If the United States does not respond, manufacturers in the People's Republic of China will continue gaining global market share in critical technologies at the expense of United States companies and the United States stands to lose critical industries that provide jobs, create production capacity, and serve essential national security goals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8420d203b0e4a3ca992d9caa7d879a6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As such, Federal policy should focus on ensuring that technologies that are invented and developed in the United States are commercialized and produced in the United States, along with the products and services those technologies create. That will require a whole-of-government effort dedicated to revitalizing the <quote>innovation and industrial infrastructure</quote> of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7143696ce57e4723ac0cfae7af6ebf12"><enum>(9)</enum><text>While this is a multi-faceted issue that the Export-Import Bank of the United States (in this section referred to as the <quote>Bank</quote>) cannot solve alone, the Bank can play a much more strategic role than the Bank is playing as of the date of the enactment of this Act by supporting the development phase of future technologies in areas that are underfunded by existing private sector tools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66915ad905064ade81bbc874256da066"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Bank has an opportunity to create the export markets of tomorrow by helping to fund the development, commercialization, and production of critical technologies in the United States, which will expand the long-term export base of the United States by increasing the overall competitive edge of the United States, and in doing so, support employment in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc733f99d51e24101bb03486a4c2a03c9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>There exists an opportunity to enhance the Bank’s strategic planning capabilities and deepen the Bank’s focus on catalytic and scale-up financing. Such a repositioning would support technologies with substantial domestic manufacturing footprints in industries that represent not only strategic national security and competitiveness priorities but also significant employment opportunities across manufacturing communities in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id090428ecc0d64119a358e4e16abefcfc"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Congress has already directed the Bank to undertake efforts in that direction, such as through the Program on China and Transformational Exports established under section 2(l) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635(l)</external-xref>), which explicitly requires 20 percent of the Bank’s funds to be invested in certain areas deemed highly strategic, including artificial intelligence, biotechnology, renewable energy, semiconductors, quantum technology, and fusion energy, among other industries. A logical next step would be to expand that program to broaden its aperture and importance within the Bank, while reaffirming the Bank’s mission to support export-related transactions that directly support United States jobs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf998881c29604a74800701fefbedd75b"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In 2022, the Bank’s Board of Directors with a unanimous vote launched the Make More in America Initiative to support <quote>export-oriented domestic manufacturing projects</quote>, extending some of the Bank’s existing demand-driven, export-contingent financing programs to a more domestic focus to help revitalize United States manufacturing, directly support United States jobs, improve the resiliency of domestic supply chains, and level the playing field for United States companies competing in overseas markets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04dc88bbe7464e36bfa4eb43402421a6"><enum>(14)</enum><text>There is an opportunity for the Bank to play a convening role in developing a cohesive investment roadmap for the Bank’s own mandate, informed by input from across the Federal Government, including the industrial investment efforts of other Federal agencies, such as the Department of Commerce, the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Labor, the Department of Health and Human Services, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id688d15ba103b4281a83cbbf4127ef1fe"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="id3605771d733340e5b7e87d6900876b8c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure that advanced technologies critical to economic growth and national security are developed, commercialized, and produced in, and exported by, the United States and allies and partners of the United States, rather than adversaries of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id201ebf32d3fd4b74a620a1b7aa299c80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address capital market failures in sectors where United States production capacity and innovation is in the national interest;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1b5c236d25646b09fd4adea146d8a99"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to coordinate the resources of the Federal Government—</text><subparagraph id="id14cd6f26785346ada416e3b2ef505e28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote domestic technology invention, development, commercialization, production, and exportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7d544f700dd43ae915698f7e292b079"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to support the unmet capital needs of manufacturing companies of all sizes to grow domestically;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc298fa48d5cc4a6aa8f6a64ba06b525f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to encourage workforce training to support the growth and resilience of domestic manufacturing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ebf8c9dc5394ac9942b86b7da1ce328"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to accelerate permitting related to domestic manufacturing projects; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c6fb004ac5240769a610ea9e252f6c8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to improve access to physical infrastructure, such as energy and logistics, for the growth of domestic manufacturing; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5ea056f7d1f40a9a50d04033834586c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote the creation of good jobs in communities across the United States, along with the benefits of advanced industry development on local development.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idb7fd019a393343c9b180484fbb09ea21"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modification of powers and functions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(a) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id47ac0915795b40c4b508b2089fd60227"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd824275b22c24903a845cec5201edede"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the second sentence, by striking <quote>to facilitate exports of</quote> and inserting <quote>to facilitate the development, commercialization, and production in the United States, and the export of</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05da91ec15744183b0db1abe9147b8af"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the third sentence the following: <quote>The Bank shall provide loans, guarantees, grants, cooperative agreements, offtake agreements, price insurance and other insurance facilities, and other instruments through other transaction authority under paragraph (4)(A) to accelerate the development, commercialization, and production of technologies that are critical to the national security, innovation, and economic growth of the United States and direct employment of United States workers, including technologies that emerge from federally funded research.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id77585d53a3e64ed2b70f8f4f2d57f710"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd2f69d4c1c64c83ab85345568d6c1cc"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3fe7756402c486c8bb6d69ac6abd7c8" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional powers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the powers and authorities set forth in paragraph (1), the Bank may—</text><subparagraph id="id9041c021a33646c6b32443adf04a1270"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent authorized by law, enter into such agreements, including contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, offtake agreements, price insurance and other insurance facilities, and other instruments, and may enter into other transactions, including providing subordinated capital, to facilitate investments and the provision of financial assistance on such terms as the President of the Bank and the Board of Directors consider appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3e58950fd7a4bbe84f23b62d9a3bd0d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make advance payments under agreements and other transactions authorized under subparagraph (A) without regard to section 3324 of title 31, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11af6bf5f7414580912ff953260f08d0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>procure temporary and intermittent services of experts and consultants in accordance with section 3109 of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae448dc54d8747ff957d4318c6b3a002"><enum>(D)</enum><text>notwithstanding section 3104 of title 5, United States Code, or any other provision of other law relating to the appointment, number, classification, or compensation of employees, make appointments of scientific, engineering, and professional personnel, and fix the basic pay of such personnel at a rate to be determined by the President of the Bank at rates not in excess of the highest total annual compensation payable at the rate determined under section 104 of title 3, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc9a88eeac6c4294b6554c3f82ec1c96"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with the consent of another Federal agency, enter into an agreement with that Federal agency to use, with or without reimbursement, any service, equipment, personnel, or facility of that Federal agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id658739ea622147c8ad99459c6fbd57dc"><enum>(F)</enum><text>establish such rules, regulations, and procedures as the President of the Bank and the Board of Directors consider appropriate and that are consistent with other statutes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="idcbeac8f4160f4bd6b3272985b13dfe5f"><enum>5.</enum><header>Make More in America Program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f6f933935754fd09b4d355fb8fd31ba"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f572dbfd9934eab91fff52ed92c9ce0"><subsection id="id764e38e9665441fe8b2f67e1648a82bc"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Make More in America Program</header><paragraph id="id3c5b955be3e64401a9e913c14a0e99be"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4956a5b328b4b039c0ab4a250d5615b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall establish the Make More in America Program (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>), under which the Bank shall provide support, by providing financing and entering into other agreements and transactions authorized under paragraphs (1) and (4) of subsection (a), for export-related manufacturing projects in the United States, in support of manufacturing companies of all sizes, including startups, in priority industries described in paragraph (2), industries described in paragraph (3), and suppliers that enable those industries, all of which directly support employment in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide0a6643b6a21400e85ee49d7a2ae6d33"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Future exports</header><text>The Bank may provide support under the Program to support future exports by an applicant for such support, even if the applicant does not produce goods for export at the time the support is awarded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb2785786c8d4ebdbbfdc22d1eb9017c" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority focus areas</header><text>Under the Program, the Bank shall advance export-related manufacturing in the following industries:</text><subparagraph id="idedd33554e12641909eb0faa02a425f9f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Strategic industries for which there is evidence of subsidies or production support by other countries that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4aff8d8537a8453aae9abaf7d8c74ef1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has resulted in overreliance or created foreign chokepoints for United States supply chains; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc79752c09ecb4ffc963bd16331e7828c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise presents a persistent risk to United States supply chains.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ee2185b71284a4a8318b5719ee7f8d1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Strategic industries critical to the national security and economic competitiveness of the United States, including, at a minimum, industries described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id515227a411ed4e10afd014cf6cae006d" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Emerging industries that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a8d1a80c11b42ce94a149c7b833d46e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are critical to the national security and economic competitiveness of the United States; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56dd5fad05724169a62da9317e33778c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have not reached commercial scale and therefore are unable to receive sufficient private capital funding for demonstration scale operations, equipment purchasing, commercialization, or sustained manufacturing for export.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5dc9b61a49744c02a2a115d7f05f3a3a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Industries of interest</header><text>The industries described in this paragraph are industries, and components thereof, critical to the national security and economic competitiveness of the United States, which may include the following:</text><subparagraph id="ideb2ae8782861478faec0686d60e7ac44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The transformational export areas under the Program on China and Transformational Exports specified in subsection (l)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b5c9149af80429da4f4246552f94b26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Critical minerals (as defined in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd8ed65c4cd644beb19784e4bbe9eb72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Shipbuilding and ship repair.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae329f6276b243cca5537b7b3d189534"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Cyber-physical systems and mechatronics, including robotics.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27f21791d22442b48d5ff195e61a2e64"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Aerospace and aviation, including unmanned aircraft systems (as defined in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code) and the components and subsystems thereof, including propulsion systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49df715879904f4bb6127175aec8b5bd"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Transport systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec5b649f810e4fcd9fc09bdf77237cf4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Advanced energy and industrial efficiency technologies, such as batteries and advanced nuclear technologies, including for the purposes of electric generation, consistent with the restrictions on the National Science Foundation under section 15 of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1874">42 U.S.C. 1874</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3bddc3f84dc54ec388e4dc143a7d523a"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Advanced materials science, including composites 2D materials, other next-generation materials, and related manufacturing technologies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c93e41f938d414081d46246dd624e2b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Critical sensing technologies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bbc5365b124455eb1058a20dd9e648a"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Such other industries as the Bank, with the approval of the Board of Directors, considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23f6f2698188469c8b1760c8c406311d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements for projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicant seeking support from the Bank under paragraph (1) with respect to a project is required—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1c1ee791cee4a8083d018174678be8e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to demonstrate that the project—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7fdb149157484f53a1249426d5f6436c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aligns with the goals of the investment roadmap developed under section 3(n)(3);</text></clause><clause id="id501b5fa3921e49488d912b86474a4abb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a credible pathway to financial sustainability and, as appropriate, provides reasonable assurance of repayment; and</text></clause><clause id="id0f8f87957602453397a2a45f9cb87940"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supports employment in the United States directly related to the project; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcfa40f5e30a94b8e90e5907299fe4d6c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to submit documentation on the number of jobs in the United States that the applicant estimates will be created, and the quality of those jobs, if the support for the project is approved; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5da395225234aeb98012c0766520561"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to make commitments to investing in—</text><clause id="id5cfc7b0c02224333bed08d45aed8a689"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>workers and communities associated with the project, including through training and education benefits paid by the applicant, wrap around services that support workforce reliability, and commitments secured from regional educational and training entities, including joint labor-management organizations, and institutions of higher education to provide workforce training, including apprenticeship programs registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8b712f4d6da84238b86d7cb0325d6335"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the quality of jobs associated with the project, as determined based on higher wage levels than the local median wage, incentive programs (which may include employee ownership plans and profit sharing arrangements), benefits, and worker protections.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id78761d664fa24d4faa8d97c848d5e876"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Preferential terms for certain projects</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27794c41420f4705859b4869c68bb4be"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank may provide support under paragraph (1) on more favorable terms or in a larger amount for a project—</text><clause id="idb01c73bdfdf944c1bb73b8c54f40570a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is located in or directly benefits an economically distressed region; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b0e880b33134c84aaa7c545ca2f9d73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if more than 70 percent of the jobs created by the project are expected to pay more than 110 percent of the mean pay for the county in which the project is located.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45367f0cb3364bf6a43844121550e4a5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Economically distressed region defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>economically distressed region</term> means a region—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a9b4fddb98b4ca5b4fa6ebd8c5ab19e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">described in—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b46a48e3ec84c9d8e1971b4c426a03b"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 301 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3161">42 U.S.C. 3161</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26103f8dbff044cba8e27b34f8e38928"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 29(j)(1) of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3722b">15 U.S.C. 3722b(j)(1)</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id828b1b17c2124694aab812e74513a4f0"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 6702(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfda1c5b3ebb4415194ee893a2e16134e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that meets the definition of <quote>persistent poverty county</quote> in section 736 of division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 4503).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03186c9ad4d44091ac27671d68905454"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Use of funds</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc7a26fa462745df97ea4438ce82c293"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project that receives support under paragraph (1) may use the support for any purpose that—</text><clause id="id74b4964ad1b544e2bb315ca56b324b9a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is reasonably related to development, commercialization, or domestic production in industries described in paragraph (3), including support for workforce development by means of direct training, support for building or expanding a facility, or for related site development; or</text></clause><clause id="id7a364edef382441fa507a41ec6df7ffb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the President of the Bank and the Board of Directors determines to be consistent with the objectives of the Program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc5494695e5440658adf2970d6b5891c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text>Support provided under paragraph (1) may not be used—</text><clause id="id7fa61ae458a34813a35c7484378e2f94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to repay debts incurred by the person receiving the support before the disbursement of the support;</text></clause><clause id="id5b011c5ec6bf40be8256278442d8ed09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to make distributions, dividends, or other payments to shareholders or equity holders of the person; or</text></clause><clause id="id97b6a77e999a47839ded252bceedff22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to fund the acquisition of another entity unrelated to the project.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc971cf5be8c54060b1e81d8c6f8d01bd" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Target dates; clawback for failure to meet</header><subparagraph id="id4c00833dbf734aa586820f5ebcb4a10a" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Target dates</header><text>For each award of financing or financial assistance provided under paragraph (1) with respect to a project, the President of the Bank shall, before distributing the award, determine target dates by which a project shall commence and complete.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38fed863860541c4aeeaa71ef423a278" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Progressive recovery for delays</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41c9c489128c453c977cd65f8c2b3ef0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a project does not commence and complete by the target dates established under subparagraph (A), the President of the Bank shall progressively recover up to the full amount of the award provided under paragraph (1) with respect to the project.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id399b48a312144a418733ed9e064f6b0d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Clawback provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President of the Bank and the Board of Directors shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfbf79273842c42d1b04c623f58776cd6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include, in each agreement providing for an award made under paragraph (1), clawback provisions to govern recovery under clause (i); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1844435fce24c6bbc09c3921fa0af48"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives with respect to those provisions.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id291bbd10657f447aa30bedf898130317" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>In the case of a project that receives financing or financial assistance under paragraph (1) and experiences delays, the President of the Bank may waive elements of the clawback provisions incorporated into the agreement providing for the award—</text><clause id="idc3154a895ed64835b489e657dc6bebd2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after making a formal determination that circumstances beyond the ability of the person that received the award to foresee or control are responsible for delays; and</text></clause><clause id="id3f037fb8e11c44bdbb8a9a1c4fe8a002" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 15 days after notifying the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives of the intention of the President of the Bank to issue the waiver.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d05e5ff3557459db83c3a3b5aa81e93"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Workforce protections</header><text>An applicant seeking support from the Bank under paragraph (1) with respect to a project and that has 100 or more employees shall make a good-faith certification that—</text><subparagraph id="ide4bccb0863a746d1bf702d0688999225"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicant will not abrogate existing collective bargaining agreements for—</text><clause id="id994e1eb336b649a9b5e00621a9db195a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the duration of the project; or</text></clause><clause id="id21b33a46b0094b5eaa30daf590f6bf6c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term of the support and 2 years after the termination of the support; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2172918271e94dd7a4e6ec8decedf410"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicant will remain neutral in any union organizing effort for the term of the support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3324091D71B840B1A49DCC30D5E900C7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(9)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monitoring of job creation and job quality</header><text>The Bank shall develop a process for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3627ecc8fa0b4cb9be88d73cae5dbddc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">verifying that the estimates made under paragraph (4)(B) are reasonable when made;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3be076d17b084557bc53ea8bd685ecf0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitoring the creation and sustainment of jobs through the portfolio of projects for which financing or financial assistance is provided under paragraph (1) over time, including estimated downstream and supply chain employment effects and measures of job quality, such as median wages, incentive programs and benefits for workers, and labor representation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb91f342ce9e544d39e171957cbc9c563"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitoring compliance with the prevailing wage requirements under paragraph (12), in coordination with the Department of Labor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfac8e6488ced44ca94268dbc561cb2ea"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reporting, not less frequently than annually, to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on the aggregate employment impact of the portfolio described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0a7a1d3bf584e999ae1f010596b4b2e"><enum>(10)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support goal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be a goal of the Bank to ensure that not less than 30 percent of the applicable amount (as defined in section 6(a)(2)) in each fiscal year is made available for financing or financial assistance under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bfb302d7b6c4e1eb469807d08defd53"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Approval of certain transactions by Board</header><text>The approval of the Board is required for financing or financial assistance in excess of $50,000,000 to be provided to a project under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85c9e1fb19b54e3e972fe2294c8d5b8e"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Prevailing wage protections; clawback for failure to comply</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66181e0d128049cbab3e834cae889e5e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of construction, alteration, or repair work carried out, in whole or in part, with financing or financial assistance from the Bank under this subsection shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a character similar in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55bbe23ba63649018b9b8b8906fc3f9d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the labor standards specified in subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78aec681d81c457a8d2c37b662e460bd" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Progressive recovery for failure to comply</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2babfecf96614daeb517fe904683b088"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a project does not comply with subparagraph (A), the President of the Bank shall progressively recover up to the full amount of the award provided under paragraph (1) with respect to the project.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0d722cc9e694266851b29b5a309489f"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Clawback provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President of the Bank and the Board of Directors shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe16fea33b2648118039a767cab316a8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include, in each agreement providing for an award made under paragraph (1), clawback provisions to govern recovery under clause (i); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida85cf1c99c394cbebe5795e2b56bfa50"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives with respect to those provisions.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf575674047f84385b379e450a24c6551"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Waiver of repayment assurance</header><text>In the case of loans provided under this subsection, the Board may waive the requirement for reasonable assurance of repayment under subsection (b)(1)(B) if amounts are appropriated to provide financing for purposes that are inconsistent with such requirement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb827e20779245c6a8982dada70e071d" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Guarantee coverage for participating lenders</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfde6ec4dc03c4643bafbcafa71c4dadc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing a loan guarantee under this subsection, the Bank shall provide a 100 percent guarantee to an acceptable commercial bank or community lender—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59f0b3752c0a423aba079fc6c98c99b6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for up to 90 percent of the value of the loan, in the case of a loan for a small or medium-sized exporter; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0012c9105e84461c88b36ebcc422f0c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for up to 80 percent of the value of the loan in any case not described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e15a24fdc84494999a057090497f099"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Delegated authority program</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f28dc9e92aa4a1cb7d17e241cd66cf9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, the Bank shall develop a delegated authority program under which the Bank provides 100 percent guarantee coverage for up to $50,000,000 per loan made by a commercial bank or community lender to a small or medium-sized exporter.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b453f2e18de44e5972a81da6b34d235"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank, in consultation with private lenders, shall develop set of lending standards that offer a sufficient likelihood of repayment for purposes of the delegated authority program required by clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6d075fbf9c34cbeae7d69fc5e5ace9f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Small or medium-sized exporter defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>small or medium-sized exporter</term> means an exporter with annual sales of $1,000,000,000 or less.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idac176cc444044977aa6e36a36a354e3d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion in annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635g">12 U.S.C. 635g</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idef9355f485b741a6a82791f381c43dee" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="id2edf06f9b0ca4718b45e8b08418c1212"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Report on Make More in America Program</header><text>The Bank shall include in its annual report to Congress under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b5a50cb71834c46bc9ead6cd161e312"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all projects supported under the Make More in America Program pursuant to section 2(m);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cd1977e47314872b6ec823b8fafa453"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the geographic distribution of those projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideadd0434c6b848d2ad510c2b8fdead65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of the financial performance of those projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb42756d6ecbc4eb08bcdc09e08984b31" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an estimate of the number and quality of jobs in the United States created through those projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id943e9b29214e4e7e9e340d8bfe61760e"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of the private capital mobilized by those projects, in aggregate and by project;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6a61d478d364991a62fd6d1b1a14627"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the strategic production capacity created through those projects, including production volumes, supply chain positions secured, and import dependencies reduced; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddab63c547c7749d99110ba5c103c39c3"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ratio of private capital mobilized to public financing provided under the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id30046974afe848d295ebf144366ad3d6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Modification of aggregate loan, guarantee, and insurance authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6(a)(2) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635e">12 U.S.C. 635e(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f22934c06864e1aafd1867ac200f99a"><paragraph id="id954c17afcbc74aa281cd17918d266f11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable amount defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>applicable amount</term>, for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2033, means $205,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id66d52956cfe5408ba9c4da19f8e4197b"><enum>7.</enum><header>Modification of default rate and lending cap</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide888d2611fd5412fa7c1d1b93a96340b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6(a)(3) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635e">12 U.S.C. 635e(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e4818345c664bc6bca539a8895b76bd"><paragraph id="HB677B92A015B4948A954E3B688DFBEF0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Freezing of lending cap if default rate exceeds certain limitations</header><subparagraph id="idd487b44256794954a6173308bbbdd5b6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Traditional export credit portfolio</header><text>The Bank may not exceed the amount of loans, guarantees, and insurance in the traditional export credit portfolio (as defined in section 8(g)(1)(B)) outstanding on the last day of a quarter if the rate calculated under section 8(g)(1) with respect to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17e35d2c81d04ad7bee234435feb3dc6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>oil and gas transactions is 2 percent or more for that quarter; or</text></clause><clause id="id2213c4b625124b9d980008c00e38f820"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all transactions in that portfolio other than oil and gas transactions is 4 percent or more for that quarter.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcdfe88f9cd8d43adbf76d89a402c6da0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Make More in America Program portfolio</header><text>The Bank may not exceed the amount of loans, guarantees, and insurance in the Make More in America Program portfolio (as defined in section 8(g)(1)(B)) outstanding on the last day of a quarter if the rate calculated under section 8(g)(1) with respect to that portfolio is 10 percent or more for that quarter.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0c94b3120c94ecdb3265394bc3384cd"><enum>(C)</enum><header>China and Transformational Exports Program portfolio</header><text>The Bank may not exceed the amount of loans, guarantees, and insurance in the China and Transformational Exports Program portfolio (as defined in section 8(g)(1)(B)) outstanding on the last day of a quarter if the rate calculated under section 8(g)(1) with respect to that portfolio is 10 percent or more for that quarter.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6404fd1697eb46fc85e50077bf3ab33b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Termination of freeze</header><clause id="idec00f6db1e0f45769939b1347363f358" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Traditional export credit portfolio</header><text>A freeze under clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) shall remain in effect until the rate calculated under section 8(g)(1) with respect to—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34d7449e4f2e4e6885ab5478c1512311"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a freeze under clause (i) of that paragraph, oil and gas transactions is less than 2 percent for that quarter; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id9e949dc6e9414ba0b698a6d07deeabd8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a freeze under clause (ii) of that paragraph, all transactions in the traditional export credit portfolio other than oil and gas transactions is less than 4 percent for that quarter.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0c9668b7a69846b69b531d7670e3a643"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Make More in America Program portfolio</header><text>A freeze under paragraph (1)(B) shall remain in effect until the rate calculated under section 8(g)(1) with respect to the Make More in America Program portfolio is less than 10 percent.</text></clause><clause id="id23e73df833164cf6a764c5ad04485774"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>China and Transformational Exports portfolio</header><text>A freeze under paragraph (1)(C) shall remain in effect until the rate calculated under section 8(g)(1) with respect to the China and Transformational Exports Program portfolio is less than 10 percent.</text></clause><clause id="id7d4751bf9c2343bd91dc8f86116333ae"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Contingencies</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1), a freeze under any such subparagraph shall terminate if—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdf2ea3c7c5b4035854328613c102360"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce determines that the continued operation of the Bank is in the national security or economic interests of the United States and notifies Congress not later than 30 days after making that determination; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22eb653822234103af3bbd1aa7ac112c"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Treasury determines that a financial crisis exists that requires the Bank to provide liquidity or risk enhancements to protect United States exports and notifies Congress not later than 30 days after making that determination.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idaa663237fb67461c8c531069c8cfa426"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Calculating of default rates by portfolio</header><text>Section 8(g)(1) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635g">12 U.S.C. 635g(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide52483e29a314ec8b68ef5bb77036800"><paragraph id="ID544385F4355C4B52AF7D2A94D4C2108A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monitoring of default rates</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4dc441b21564268861e63b700195062"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than quarterly, the Bank shall calculate the rate at which the entities to which the Bank has provided short-, medium-, or long-term financing are in default on a payment obligation under the financing, by dividing—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65870d25524e4045930e045a5c9fea2d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of the required payments that are overdue and are expected to become net losses after using the Bank’s reserves from collected interest and fees, by</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide49b212eb8af4e0e9cb1d16a5c6ed455"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable amount (as defined in section 6(a)(2)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id147475cacedd4214b4be50d5a5ec5053"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Accounting and default rates by portfolio</header><text>The Bank shall maintain separate accounting of, and calculate a separate default rate under subparagraph (A) for—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id349f2ba25d904d86b886b42c08b92809"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all loans, guarantees, and insurance provided under the Make More in America Program pursuant to section 2(m) (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Make More in America Program portfolio</quote>);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6933e73647b64994987e8ca566965be2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all loans, guarantees, and insurance provided under the China and Transformational Exports Program pursuant to section 2(l) (in this Act referred to as the <quote>China and Transformational Exports Program portfolio</quote>); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a3df121b772474293a1d58ab5c01605"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all loans, guarantees, and insurance provided under authorities other than the Make More in America Program pursuant to section 2(m) or the China and Transformational Exports Program pursuant to section 2(l) (in this Act referred to as the <quote>traditional export credit portfolio</quote>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e930cb6e14543eeae6f8e8064bd3204" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Separate risk reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than quarterly, the Chief Risk Officer of the Bank shall report separately on the default rate, risk exposure, and portfolio performance of the traditional export credit portfolio and the Make More in America Program portfolio.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id1e9a145f14134083af0de47e2cf7798d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion of transactions relating to Make More In America and China and Transformational Exports programs</header><text>Section 8(g) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635g">12 U.S.C. 635g(g)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id539a47892920471e89287bc3b2e37aab"><paragraph id="idc60be3a9f93e41fbbbfce95265051aa0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Exclusion of transactions relating to Make More In America and China and Transformational Exports programs</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, if financing provided under the Make More in America Program pursuant to section 2(m) or the China and Transformational Exports Program pursuant to section 2(l) results in a default rate calculated under paragraph (1) exceeding an applicable limitation under subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 6(a)(3), the Bank may, subject to the approval of the Board of Directors, exclude such financing from the calculation of the default rate.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id951ccab0003246ca9abcc0603876ed99"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 8(g) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635g">12 U.S.C. 635g(g)</external-xref>), as amended by subsections (b) and (c), is further amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62ed38a7a81b446cbee40e18cb3225cc"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd51a2328dc9e479cacc856baa4793515"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>exceeds 2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>exceeds a limitation under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 6(a)(3)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffc662339a02497d915af199a35a9984"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>be at least 2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>equal or exceed that limitation</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1547b99194174e07bc99293895ba0349"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>less than 2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>less than that limitation</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c02828e08ff4fef910d592f23d55f24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B), by striking <quote>less than 2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>less than the applicable limitation under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 6(a)(3)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7530ad0e30e4871ba82d38d4880d6ed"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb9523954d224d909db7574689cc42b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">is at least 2 percent</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">equals or exceeds applicable limitation</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7175bee1ef34b3f8a3dd485137f792a"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>the default rate</quote> and inserting <quote>a default rate</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92239baee78240eca5a381e6e5f4f498"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>is at least 2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>equals or exceeds the applicable limitation under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 6(a)(3)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf39d425da37443bab6fd8629fa3123be" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f3c74ba0a5d4667b781807482354b0f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>the default rate</quote> and inserting <quote>a default rate</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0b79496f3f94a7888166975bd1fb338" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>remains above 2 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>continues to equal or exceed the applicable limitation under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 6(a)(3)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3e8b5da6be3742bc89712794732e719e"><enum>8.</enum><header>Investment Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635a">12 U.S.C. 635a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id0bd8913a7402448ca2c1af2693a3a664" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="id0b22f120dd114d9bade7d699a562eaaf"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Investment committee</header><paragraph id="IDC15B0D1E8E1744B0BED44FCA6B453C92" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a management committee to be known as the <quote>Investment Committee</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87c8af9bb2674e21abe3b5c40fb4fa56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Investment Committee shall be composed of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9979a93e622425487a5e769c62f6ec2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President of the Bank, who shall serve as chairperson;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc998c1118c694f1bad49aaaeee3cc7c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Board of Directors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4baa5e62b71548448f22e51e1d1c068c"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative of the Department of the Treasury, designated by the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6ae62435eb84280a67e9f095596bf33"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative of the Department of Commerce, designated by the Secretary of Commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc667b74101ef4e97b011c6191becd554"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative of the Department of Energy, designated by the Secretary of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb82e12fdcaa428c839adb44801a3f9d"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative of the Department of Defense, designated by the Secretary of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75e4242376b6405b859b65f666963899"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative of the Office of the United States Trade Representative, designated by the United States Trade Representative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24ddc1d86cd64b54a8911ce120e54db0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a representative of the Small Business Administration, designated by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3a3828ef2ef4bf39699298ac641d361"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a representative of the Department of Agriculture, designated by the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca1ed083bc3a4fa280647a316e197976"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a representative of the Department of Health and Human Services, designated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e28dd82f55147f0afa7bc43f700901f"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative of the Department of Labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c6dec748f414437854d0fbdfdc43051"><enum>(L)</enum><text>a representative of the Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id777cb4d321e243799e857d6b693198e7"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">three Members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate, each for a 2-year term; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id411da49ea82643588d5c20f494b0ece6"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">three Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, each for a 2-year term.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06eb8e78471249aa873bfc4c6f35048d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investment roadmap</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cd0f5366d0443a78c54c5a5e99af935"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Investment Committee shall be responsible for—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ef0cbf95b3d4871a2fcea5617e22bdd"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing a 10-year investment roadmap for—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd385ff3c252245baaaf985b1e4eaf755"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified technology areas and industry priorities for public sector investment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idbd4e30f30c86482c9c7a6c979bb0f54b" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identified missions of national interest to focus public sector investment and coordination across sectors to improve the lives of the people of the United States through greater capacity in innovation, production, deployment, lower costs, and problem-solving; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideedaa1e13e384c87a0510480038edac4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>obtaining the approval of the National Economic Council, the National Security Council, and the Office of Science and Technology Policy with respect to the investment roadmap.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ceae70951b7460d8bcd3ebef97e4ee4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of roadmap</header><text>The investment roadmap required by subparagraph (A) may inform the Bank and other agencies represented on the investment committee with respect to investment strategies that are consistent with their missions and policies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf74058ae837a4c929ccc9ebfe687e57a"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration of models</header><text>In developing the investment roadmap required by subparagraph (A), the Investment Committee shall be informed by other technology roadmaps (such as the National Security Strategy and the Critical Technology Areas of the Department of Defense) and supply chain risk analyses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41ed8f24cb4246758d5ed0a4221a1413"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The investment roadmap required by subparagraph (A) shall be updated not less frequently than once every 4 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e42eac9c293468a80be53e0c7bbb816"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The investment roadmap required by subparagraph (A) and each update under subparagraph (C) shall be made available to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcdbebd611974a0d99c9119787fd0223"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Advisory committees</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6df61828dbf47869c54bb3ff29d683f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Investment Committee shall establish advisory committees for each technology area of interest or mission of national interest identified in the investment roadmap required by paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88a3e8f6acdd46408a8dec7486c4ceeb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Role</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An advisory committee established under subparagraph (A) with respect to a technology area of interest or mission of national interest shall be responsible for providing to the Investment Committee critical inputs into overarching goals, milestones, and focus areas in the technology area of interest.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1bac278c4bc54d5ea1cc4c3c9e8154f1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An advisory committee established under subparagraph (A) shall include representatives from other Federal agencies, State governments, industry, labor organizations, research institutions, and other entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id26b364150f8b48b8a24da8be4e2abc70"><enum>9.</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13 of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635i-7">12 U.S.C. 635i–7</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e2d1410164140468a3b504923284f2c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">Cooperation on export financing programs</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">Interagency cooperation</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id632b896ef05b4921868b4fc2d0f470f2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Bank</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ebbd92a8e7f49ee9a9753f06f9b0b51"><subsection id="id3e6b9a7d3180475bbeaa70a81d3e174d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cooperation on export financing and financial assistance programs</header><text>The Bank</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6932b6ff8f5d422cab9b65b9b43bb917"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id4ecb11c9f7bc4e478b8b6c79747a1350" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="id3d1e08dff703432d9af7f6cd4c9e2c96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency working group</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66c4407cb718448bba7d73e153ae6d02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established an interagency working group.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id363f85ea688e4b39adc6c81b57b04765"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The working group established by paragraph (1) shall be responsible for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a235abce22841e5bb6b3da82899f174"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing guidance to the Bank on priority advanced manufacturing and critical technology industries; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id809b273ab27845158716b741569c728f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring coordination across Federal programs for financing and supporting advanced manufacturing and critical technology development in service of strategic economic competitiveness imperatives, including efforts to align performance metrics and to ensure timely review of applications and deployment of capital; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf3135a2a6c7845f3b97bb3fa64e2c583"><enum>(C)</enum><text>aligning the work of the working group with the activities of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee established under section 2312 of the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4727">15 U.S.C. 4727</external-xref>); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63c6dd552a974be4aa75fb853c2b3844"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conducting briefings required by paragraph (6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77965be7a1914bfd8dc5f8922f874aed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Co-chairpersons</header><text>The President of the Bank and the Director of the National Economic Council shall serve as co-chairpersons of the working group established by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4619bf7e064949dea5064b20fecbbb80"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Domain-specific working groups</header><subparagraph id="idea2338c7f8314195aff4989023e958d4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Investment Committee established under section 3(n) shall establish domain-specific working groups corresponding to the technology areas identified in the investment roadmap required by section 3(n)(3). Such domains may include biotechnology (including biomanufacturing), next-generation energy (including fusion energy), advanced computing, robotics, and critical minerals. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1e60d8c83df4c34ab35a70a8a090f0f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Missions of national interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One of the domain-specific working groups established under subparagraph (A) shall be established to identify missions of national interest to focus public sector investment and coordination across sectors to improve the lives of the people of the United States through greater capacity in innovation, production, deployment, lower costs, and problem-solving.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e866ae777674559b3081159bd7895c6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (D), the Investment Committee shall determine the membership of each domain-specific working group established under subparagraph (A), drawing from relevant Federal agencies, including the agencies described in paragraph (5), and from such other entities as the Committee considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id754568729f634015a738b3dab9abffb8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Standing membership</header><text>Each domain-specific working group established under subparagraph (A) shall include representatives of the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id61ae72de643047ebb16aab11ffa94d2d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Technical input</header><text>In carrying out the duties described in paragraph (2), the working group established by paragraph (1) and domain-specific working groups established under paragraph (4) shall seek technical input from relevant Federal agencies and entities, and other partners, including—</text><subparagraph id="ida20575bee1ee4b9e846344e54d800f2d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal investment entities, including the Office of Strategic Capital of the Department of Defense, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Loan Programs Office of the Department of Energy, and Federal agencies to which authorities under the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4501">50 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>) have been delegated;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7876e724f2244ccaaf50706c23f282b"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>Federal research and innovation agencies, including the National Science Foundation, the Advanced Research Projects Agency–Energy, the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health, and the Small Business Innovation Research program, with a focus on agencies conducting aligned federally funded research with support from the Federal Government, including from the Bank, to translate research into new startups and to scale companies in the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d5caa5316db468094aea5cfe45e6b4a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mission agencies, including the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Institutes of Health, the Small Business Administration, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c4642b02a184ae18b53c421c07b230f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>State governments, to coordinate with respect to, and align, where possible, with, State investment to strengthen domestic industrial capacity in critical industries, including federally funded initiatives like the State Small Business Credit Initiative; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id870a7a21640443e1abf6013c8bf9c5ef"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other agencies and entities as the Bank or the Investment Committee considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc39da3f3d85f46798f07b3f32cd0095e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the working group established by paragraph (1) shall brief the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Executive Office of the President with respect to, for the year preceding the briefing—</text><subparagraph id="ida00bff1bf6bf49aaa65e883daf3664bb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requests for financial assistance considered by the Bank;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44f821a7ea004a068339b89c8f6e76ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agreements made under this Act; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide4d6f0b177834116bf2d7408bbf8247a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opportunities for and consideration of policy changes to improve coordination across Federal programs with the goal of ensuring the success of investments facilitated by financing or financial assistance under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1dbc2d91bb7c4c11ab22941fb44434fe"><enum>(D)</enum><text>challenges identified by applicants for financial assistance across Federal programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8e94da65c5d943acbba66085758379c1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with respect to technology development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall convene meetings with other agencies to coordinate with respect to enhancing capacity for critical technology development in the United States.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id54618eac011845e5a2459975a5374533"><enum>10.</enum><header>Limitation on eligibility for support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635a">12 U.S.C. 635a</external-xref>), as amended by section 9, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56d9261b3071420cbc7fe8d453067ee0"><subsection id="id35bfebb48c554758949dee632c91ffe3"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Limitations on eligibility for support</header><paragraph id="id3c56efc79d8a4476a2b0aef93e9a7c26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act or any other Act, a covered entity is not eligible for financing or other support under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida424692e1087400da2c8d6749f45608a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="ida56ce7799310465f8c2492598cd6f067"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id382bf4a8eabb4b919beac90ccc3fc6c6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term> means an entity in which a covered individual directly or indirectly holds a significant interest.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id634a2c46ca2a4ff881afd65d6acd40d6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Aggregation of securities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining whether an entity is a covered entity for purposes of clause (i), if securities of the entity are owned, controlled, or held by 2 or more covered individuals who are related as described in subparagraph (B), such securities shall be aggregated.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23af900be8e94409945661ef09a5b783"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means—</text><clause id="id12df0be11c09497998e2007f095cfa0b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the President;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23bdc52835204b4c938a63132d1659e1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Vice President;</text></clause><clause id="idb777ea19ba0443af81c41b5a92e1f2d7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Member of Congress;</text></clause><clause id="idede17e6bd1684ae684fdfb8f2145406a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an individual appointed to a position in an agency (as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code) for which appointment is required to be made by the President;</text></clause><clause id="idaba9159260904168a44358795e1af176"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a special Government employee, as defined in section 202 of title 18, United States Code, associated with the Executive Office of the President;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11573dd9bbdd4c1b91dae14c8169600c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a member of the Investment Committee established under subsection (n); and</text></clause><clause id="id0dd8aeef0986478f9d0e529a455604e0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the spouse, child, son-in-law, or daughter-in-law of an individual described in any of clauses (i) through (vi).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c1ab93e66a8489ebfba6a9e2155a9bf"><enum>(C)</enum><header>De minimis interest</header><text>The term <term>de minimis interest</term> means an equity interest in an entity that—</text><clause id="id7297cad2a66342f5ae908f3cd36433b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not exceed the threshold specified in section 2640.202(a)(2) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation);</text></clause><clause id="id0f3d0486fc08418fafc1bee33172c5bf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is purchased and owned as part of an Excepted Investment Fund or a mutual fund; or</text></clause><clause id="id775b7bcfeddf4c688449c5e2f9d67899"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is purchased and owned as part of a widely diversified employee benefit plan or a pension established and maintained by a Federal, State, or local government.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc191e4bedc374a48ad6ad557ed84496f"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Equity interest</header><text>The term <term>equity interest</term> means—</text><clause id="id5f781c4cb28040169533cec73177069a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a share in an entity, without regard to whether the share is—</text><subclause id="id3bb9e38620dc407686dac291e8337f67"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transferable; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idf83db609090a4547b79a211ac2ca43db"><enum>(II)</enum><text>classified as stock or anything similar;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7341d45a99344fb2a89d474ac06eb402"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a capital or profit interest in a limited liability company or partnership; and</text></clause><clause id="id151abfbf62d24692be8ce0cddcde4194"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a warrant or right (other than a right to convert) to purchase, sell, or subscribe to a share or interest described in clause (i) or (ii), respectively.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2901ab8062044be2956f11cd57254d8f"> <enum>(E)</enum> <header>Excepted Investment Fund</header> <text>The term <term>Excepted Investment Fund</term> means a widely held investment fund described in section 13104(f)(8) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c1eaa8c44c24cad9f6a45740516363c"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Significant interest</header><text>The term <term>significant interest</term>, with respect to an entity, means owning, controlling, or holding any equity interest, other than a de minimis interest, in the entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idb9b477b8c1d4471e8355d2a0f1d53990"><enum>11.</enum><header>Modification of Program on China and Transformational Exports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(l)(1) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635(l)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id36888c20e8c14a778a42b1d4a6d85531"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or by a covered country</quote> and inserting <quote>, the Russian Federation, or a covered country</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id290ffbd9e7ec4e32b4711b20100eb730"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or by a covered country</quote> and inserting <quote>, the Russian Federation, or a covered country</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2cc810589ba045079405a87079b19f17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="id40791b7e33b14b1fabbc1012e6d22226"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking <quote>computing</quote> and inserting <quote>technologies</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5130c0b60ed7446fafd27c4b06f4bf9d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (vi), by inserting <quote>nuclear energy,</quote> after <quote>Renewable energy,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id9da03a6603d04ff9aa5381b04b3dfc48"><enum>12.</enum><header>Increase in goal for export of goods and services related to renewable energy sources, energy efficiency, and energy storage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(b)(1)(K) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(K)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>5 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>10 percent</quote>.</text></section><section id="id954bd8d4862d486597207cd80e83c766" commented="no"><enum>13.</enum><header>Employment authority</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfda4f734a6a9459894a2d4f460d9828e"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635a">12 U.S.C. 635a</external-xref>), as amended by section 10, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cdc8d8a1cf3423a9ce47cf52ee3c4ba"><subsection id="idff68f3ed658144809fd3653aa2b7bcee"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Employment authority</header><text>The Board may compensate not more than 150 employees of the Bank without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 or subchapter III or VIII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b2fc7e67424475f845f4270f6c41792"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming repeal</header><text>Section 117 of the Export Enhancement Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/429">Public Law 102–429</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635a">12 U.S.C. 635a</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></subsection></section><section id="id4f44672c1bf04e44bdc8df18ec2154f6"><enum>14.</enum><header>Expansion of guarantee coverage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(c)(3)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635(c)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0efbe4138d7b447195b3e8beeb8cb520"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>For the guarantee program provided for in this subsection,</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id102a16329e2d45fea5e2f4d2d6d519db"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce6b06352527403391c1f4f7d898ddec"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a guarantee program described in clause (ii),</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id91569de524d84095ab2cf41c7fec4e3f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id789394d82462401f838f1d21f7db5b8d"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbabd0d88a73f477ea9eed328e720a59c"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Programs described</header><text>A guarantee program described in this clause is—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54a9f4a9afd44ee792b24f56fd7bbaf2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a guarantee program provided for in this subsection;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c3df25c6a4d45a082a14c2004208c19"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Make More in America Program established under subsection (m); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida81976d4214b4109afe22232ee81533c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>subject to clause (iii), the Working Capital Guarantee Program.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd07e8b35d6a540b3aafbb4af19ec7333"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation on Working Capital Guarantee Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Working Capital Guarantee Program, the Bank may not provide 100 percent coverage of an amount of principal that exceeds $50,000,000.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

