<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD8A6DD29806A4641BA30CC7D4780350C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7497 IH: Supporting Trauma-Informed Education Practices Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7497</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act to improve trauma support services and mental health care for children and youth in educational settings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9701039EDB684220825608809E38EEF4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H272A7B1942B74C02A0DBCA995CCD562B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Trauma-Informed Education Practices Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4864CFD611F446C79E6CE5E73E44B031"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7134 of the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280h-7">42 U.S.C. 280h–7</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H12E77C21C3A348A8B189CEE61BE54204"> 
<section id="H8F48A94E4AAE4C53ACB05566FD57C6BD"><enum>7134.</enum><header>Grants to improve trauma support services and mental health care for children and youth in educational settings</header> 
<subsection id="H8CCCD5738FF943F9A7302638E29FCF74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of grants</header> 
<paragraph id="H0DEE2C7BB9564D6C82D186AE5DD4B191"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, is authorized to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, an eligible entity for the purpose of increasing student, teacher, school leader, and other school personnel access to evidence-based trauma support services and mental health services by developing innovative initiatives, activities, or programs to connect schools and local educational agencies, or tribal educational agencies, as applicable, with community trauma-informed support and mental health systems, including such systems under the Indian Health Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4853DEFBE31A4A43A4B9367583007687"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text>From the total amount appropriated under subsection (l) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A5D6A6AD6184375AAC1C008270AE013"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 3 percent to conduct the evaluation under subsection (f); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8972A8D3DE74A00A40F9AFD0A45E893"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent for technical assistance and administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD7EFDD3BAA54747974DCD39F99515B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>With respect to a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded or entered into under this section, the period during which payments under such grant, contract or agreement are made to the recipient may not exceed 5 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H31117A660B9B44F9BB0A1AA6B8D0822C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives or enters into a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section shall use amounts made available through such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for evidence-based initiatives, activities, or programs, which shall include at least 1 of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5CA6F9DB994D49F091D05DF87BDEE4D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancing, improving, or developing collaborative efforts between schools, local educational agencies or tribal educational agencies, as applicable, and community mental health and trauma-informed service delivery systems to provide, develop, or improve prevention, referral, treatment, and support services to students.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A0A696FDA7B4B898B9563C5E38CC5A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implementing trauma-informed models of support, including positive behavioral interventions and supports in schools served by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H084F9B09F7F4488BB916319614B9727B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing professional development to teachers, paraprofessionals, school leaders, school-based mental health services providers, and other specialized instructional support personnel employed by local educational agencies or tribal educational agencies, as applicable or schools served by the eligible entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7118EE0E11D84431B9A69A2D1063C26C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fosters safe and stable learning environments that prevent and mitigate the effects of trauma, including through social and emotional learning;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E73C6844C4E4D4D90BFD9EB7D966CA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improves school capacity to identify, refer, and provide services to students in need of trauma-informed support or mental health services, including by helping educators to identify the unique personal and contextual variables that influence the manifestation of trauma; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H12E6EF0671504EFA9784AEFCCAF01C62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reflects the best practices for trauma-informed identification, referral, and support developed by the Interagency Task Force on Trauma-Informed Care (as established by section 7132).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DDD44DF87E4468CAB61098C818AF4AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing trauma-informed support services and mental health services to students at full-service community schools served by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAE96660C1F741C092A2180C32E5BD65"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Engaging families and communities to increase awareness of child and youth trauma, which may include sharing best practices with law enforcement regarding trauma-informed services and working with mental health professionals to provide interventions and longer term coordinated care within the community for children and youth who have experienced trauma and the families of such children and youth.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CD9102F3B2747D88DDBA810F0AC1B1F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Evaluating the effectiveness of the initiatives, activities, or programs carried out under this section in increasing student access to evidence-based trauma support services and mental health services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE811EAB5B5F0418DAF1E222947CC3CEF" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Establishing partnerships with or providing subgrants to early childhood education programs or other eligible entities, to include such entities in the evidence-based trauma-informed or mental health initiatives, activities, and support services established under this section in order to provide, develop, or improve prevention, referral, treatment, and support services to children and their families.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A66603F5C7F417693DF20F081018154"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing new, or enhancing existing, evidence-based educational, awareness, and prevention programs to improve mental health and resiliency among teachers, paraprofessionals, school leaders, school-based mental health services providers, and other specialized instructional support personnel employed by local educational agencies or tribal educational agencies, as applicable, or schools served by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H49BB1C85DAA74F089691AC2031F3425A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, which shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCBDBA2BD40114C38B89BA5B5713DCC18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the innovative initiatives, activities, or programs to be funded under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, including how such initiatives, activities, or programs will increase access to evidence-based trauma-informed support services and mental health services for students, and, as applicable, the families of such students.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE301A4DCFAE477D8A8E70EC9CAC321F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the initiatives, activities, or programs will provide linguistically appropriate and culturally competent services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBDB1530783C4F7C879A7842982A9D01"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the initiatives, activities, or programs will support schools served by the eligible entity in improving school climate in order to support an environment conducive to learning.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBF8CDE12B62497CB8F0A1DB9FB3998D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assurance that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F2455BB71484A68969AEB91D9E28173"><enum>(A)</enum><text>persons providing services under the initiative, activity, or program funded by the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement are fully licensed or certified to provide such services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H620E9E63FD5144399879565071EE03E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>teachers, school leaders, administrators, school-based mental health services providers and other specialized instructional support personnel, representatives of local Indian Tribes or tribal organizations as appropriate, other school personnel, individuals who have experience receiving mental health services as children, and parents of students participating in services under this section will be engaged and involved in the design and implementation of the services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H286E976B36EC4DA084610F321C99CAA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the eligible entity will comply with the evaluation required under subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97A4F0F9F8C44EE1AB5004799C959A15"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will support and integrate existing school-based services at schools served by the eligible entity with the initiatives, activities, or programs funded under this section in order to provide trauma-informed support services or mental health services for students, as appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B3307DFD51E4217880B5888D5936C52"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will incorporate peer support services into the initiatives, activities, or programs to be funded under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H862A59737BCE4CB197AF0AA86E9C12F3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will ensure that initiatives, activities, or programs funded under this section are accessible to and include students with disabilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA27E3A0FE474708A73F88D115844BFB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An assurance that the eligible entity will establish a local interagency agreement under subsection (e) and comply with such agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBED36ACF85DA4972815832882C2116A9" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency agreements</header> <paragraph id="H70E83E32DEE2467AA23A04C945B0A4F9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local interagency agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out an evidence-based initiative, activity, or program described in subsection (c), an eligible entity that receives a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, or a designee of such entity, shall establish an interagency agreement between local educational agencies, agencies responsible for early childhood education programs, Head Start agencies (including Early Head Start agencies), juvenile justice authorities, mental health agencies, child welfare agencies, and other relevant agencies, authorities, or entities in the community that will be involved in the provision of services under such initiative, activity, or program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0AA3ECF721A44D5B347C4D3252A0B6D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The local interagency agreement required under paragraph (1) shall specify, with respect to each agency, authority, or entity that is a party to such agreement—</text> <subparagraph id="H7AB7E6681E194E4B84D33C4B617780FE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the financial responsibility for any services provided by such entity;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D18E85CC56844DC80AD1AEC82AC5549" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conditions and terms of responsibility for such services, including quality, accountability, and coordination of the services; and</text>
                            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EE0FCEC574C4F95833DBEF1598FE25E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the conditions and terms of reimbursement of such agencies, authorities, or entities, including procedures for dispute resolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5491BD1017924B48BC84883681265E63"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a rigorous and independent evaluation of the initiatives, activities, and programs carried out by an eligible entity under this section and disseminate evidence-based practices regarding trauma-informed support services and mental health services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7AF91E976C6C4E68843C7D287EFD40FA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Distribution of awards</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements awarded or entered into under this section are equitably distributed among the geographical regions of the United States and among tribal, urban, suburban, and rural populations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2EEFD9D6147A49FF81BD2E85FC4531B3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD1AAB2EEA6894AC999517A146E3F317A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prohibit an entity involved with an initiative, activity, or program carried out under this section from reporting a crime that is committed by a student to appropriate authorities; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB70150DE2BC4B15ADD6D89733AFC144"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement and judicial authorities from exercising their responsibilities with regard to the application of Federal, State, local, and tribal law to crimes committed by a student.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB290059AF4C54166A58B5EB6A0753F5C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, or local funds available to carry out the initiatives, activities, and programs described in this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB20E589604554438964B300FC2CA3928"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>In awarding or entering into grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall, in a timely manner, meaningfully consult with Indian Tribes, Regional Corporations, Native Hawaiian Educational Organizations, and their representatives to ensure notice of eligibility.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1B8F52461014F6180B5A6B09AA29692"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB1E7BF1911634F369776FD207B447224"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8B9B26432224494B578B21BE7C0B122"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HD94CF7AE86EE4924B8689172A588CF6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E288578164541E5BA0D66E0DEEF3C61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E6FD6277C8A4DD6A32369EB6B1E18F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act) or their tribal educational agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC10D2B8FBBB64F5988F6EC7AD9F4E928"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H767CA0197496441A9BDEB2162D748E16"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a Regional Corporation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3B3E3E26AC42447788EE9ABA7F8345BE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian educational organization; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8CEC7C817634AB7A79AB57A52887091" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State, Territory, and Tribal Lead Agencies administering the Child Care and Development Fund as described in section 658D(a) of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858b">42 U.S.C. 9858b(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59C71BCADE034FE696247B4CED7589A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1893E01FF17145C79BE65A93B1132D25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>evidence-based</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>paraprofessional</term>, <term>parent</term>, <term>professional development</term>, <term>school leader</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, <term>specialized instructional support personnel</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7EF75868F4F477497E9B51FED670088"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>full-service community school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4622 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7272">20 U.S.C. 7272</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD066235250EF4B1FB40E3486984D3EA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian educational organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 6207 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFA7FBDE4E874A35A6338E8A15C15FFC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>school-based mental health services provider</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4102 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7112">20 U.S.C. 7112</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE737155860BE4B1E90AF82FA76591B5E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional corporation</header><text>The term <term>Regional Corporation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B9FF837EDD0497F8F4EA34C21381A3F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School</header><text>The term <term>school</term> means a public elementary school or public secondary school.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48150E32551245BB865110E5C821E83B"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

