<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBD16EE6F78A7467FAD3A0C92577049F6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9288 IH: Terminating Infrastructure Maintenance and Expenditures for Obstructionist Urban Trash heaps Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9288</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for relocation of certain Federal office space located in sanctuary jurisdictions and to prohibit establishment or occupation of any Federal office space in a sanctuary jurisdiction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H236B6DA3C3AC421996B766A5951E93E7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H99B5AA40E15443E08F3C34583287A0CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terminating Infrastructure Maintenance and Expenditures for Obstructionist Urban Trash heaps Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TIMEOUT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H164860E43A974B9F8CC17819AF8D5831" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Relocation of certain Federal facilities in sanctuary jurisdictions</header> <subsection id="HEF4276403CD844A0AB29ABA53BD47D86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of offices and facilities</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the General Services Administration, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the heads of any other relevant agencies, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H879D805C7DDE4C449F461F270543DEF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify covered office space that is located in a sanctuary jurisdiction; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DD63D1910D448AC9F03811E95FE279C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to each relevant agency head—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBD1E26DFE4544288B6D5412B28D2E1AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notification of each unit of covered office space identified under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H826C44C1B089463AAA3C1184CB8E1B81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the process for relocation of such office space under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H24ECC37E88764994A201FA9F18376034"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relocation required</header> 
<paragraph id="H082062E2EFF94F9C8AEDD51205B489FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any covered Federal agency with covered office space identified in subsection (a) shall relocate such office space to a location that is not in a sanctuary jurisdiction.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1FFB84C9835141C687D441098E2C91D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of relocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any relocation required under paragraph (1), the covered agency shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEDC94944C2BB4385B8FFF4A82B54D4FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit relocation plans to the Administrator of the General Services Administration and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget not later than 60 days after receipt of the notification under subsection (a)(2); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H160854B2893648ED9A783F7D76C3DAAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relocate all identified covered office space not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4502D7B489D44963BBACE1D47C0CFA20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No covered Federal agency may—</text> <paragraph id="HFE5CB231867144D293C76F06B3918162"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, acquire, lease, renew, extend, or otherwise occupy covered office space in a sanctuary jurisdiction; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FB552FE3B704F58A94E8CFCC6DCE2E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>use Federal funds for new or renewed covered office space in a sanctuary jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC46164C76A0344D2AA8BECFF65F85212"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the General Services Administration shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7BEE18CC15914C57AAB8E11CAA31BCB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each unit of covered office space identified under subsection (a)(2); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB26E6B3B5FBF4EE6BC7501FEE433528E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on relocation status, lease renewals, exceptions, and estimated costs or savings from relocation with respect to each such unit.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H601E2E874FD045919FA425B591E7B1D9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8D2746CE15894637A0F2F73A9995675E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered Federal agency</header><text>The term <quote>covered Federal agency</quote>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE02986FBD6E64F7AA9DA7D577601451E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an executive agency, as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26D5BC4E85854D33A798D25E5C531B6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include the Department of Homeland Security or any component, directorate, or other office of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD52C17FEF3074E03B3FF7215D5C40215"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered office space</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered office space</quote> means nonessential administrative Federal office space of a covered Federal agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE9113969A1F4611BFC76ADA4687179B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sanctuary jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sanctuary jurisdiction</term> means any State or political subdivision of a State that has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts any government entity or official from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H346F8C65CA0F481C8264F965B955DD1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sending, receiving, maintaining, or exchanging with any Federal, State, or local government entity information regarding the citizenship or immigration status (lawful or unlawful) of any individual; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD764307EE8F141BA9F45EB9056FEAB4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>complying with a request lawfully made by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) to comply with a detainer for, or notify about the release of, an individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

