<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H767CFB678846490BA36C38685443A3C1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7419 IH: Foster Care Stabilization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7419</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to establish a demonstration grant program to provide emergency relief to foster youth and improve pre-placement services offered by foster care stabilization agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7A663E24D082405B810A85C782F5F045" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0E6E2EB6DE8B4994868DD4A29DFF4597" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foster Care Stabilization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H99E5CC659DD04578BFBD34C1AB55F53F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to improve pre-placement services for foster youth</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 426 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/626">42 U.S.C. 626</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAB99B4D42D3E487F9286F4BB8396825B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H621B580D3595481380A3E4F00EF3B699"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Grants To improve pre-Placement services for foster youth</header> <paragraph id="H24FDB200208F40519444798FF52CC2C1"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Establishment</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award 3 demonstration grants of not more than $1,000,000 to foster care stabilization agencies for the purpose of providing emergency relief to foster youth and improving pre-placement services for foster youth waiting for placement.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="HD95C63E91D674E67A9E9B8EE5E0755E2">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
                        <header>Duration</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foster care stabilization agency that receives a grant under this subsection shall have 3 years to spend funds awarded by the grant and return any unused grant funds to the Secretary.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="H330C243AA0914F81B3D16CBD878ECA21">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
                        <header>Application</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A foster care stabilization agency that desires to receive a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, that shall include the following:</text>
                        <subparagraph id="H8634DA30C6EA4BFBB144E42AF0C9E2B4">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how grant funds will be used to provide emergency relief to foster youth by the foster care stabilization agency.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H2D7F94382DE44D56B42D4C0B8A7C70D2">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how grant funds will be used to improve pre-placement services offered by the foster care stabilization agency.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="HAF4BA0AED5454571A3990FD67ABBBE4F">
                        <enum>(4)</enum>
                        <header>Application dissemination</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the solicitation of applications for a grant under this subsection is posted publicly on the website of the Administration for Children and Families and shall make special dissemination efforts to rural areas and among Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, and Native Hawaiian organizations. </text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="HE5C577702D8847BAA8C987F931D2DC20">
                        <enum>(5)</enum>
                        <header>Use of funds</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this subsection may be used to carry out any of the following activities:</text>
                        <subparagraph id="HA23F7942BB7D482FB455ED707A6318EE">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hiring of personnel necessary to provide emergency relief to foster youth and ensure that services, resources, and assistance reach such youth.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H4A21F68978644CCCA58046E603BEE8D6">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provision of clothing and other personal necessities to a foster youth for a total not to exceed $250 per foster youth, per year.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="HD23904CCC3FE49DEBDF3E388B808B579">
                            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purchase of food and equipment needed to prepare food for foster youth.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="HB6A4F6144DBE4F29AB8EA0B2894309D4">
                            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provision of service and support to prevent and respond to occurrences of child abuse and neglect with respect to foster youth.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H61CAF9F0DFAC411EB5A7794FB6FF4503">
                            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other extraordinary or emergency assistance needed to promote the safety and self-sufficiency of foster youth.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H3AC9E8F351014B5789EAE2340D700FEF">
                            <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other purpose that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="H2213402BA3E1452E9AFA5133F91E61B6">
                        <enum>(6)</enum>
                        <header>Reservation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reserve $45,000 of any amounts referred to in paragraph (9) for administration, oversight, and technical assistance activities related to this subsection.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="H2B1D3DD1AF614D40A275949AFFD497CE">
                        <enum>(7)</enum>
                        <header>Report</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report that—</text>
                        <subparagraph id="HEB371BC854C8466AB82F20246618F0E7">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes how grants awarded under this subsection have been used to provide emergency relief to foster youth;</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H83FB33F5B1F549CC8E10F71FE9AFBDAE">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes how grants awarded under this subsection have been used on pre-placement services;</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="HE96DADE0351B4F13A33BE1E77BE6D8F4">
                            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains data on the extent of clothing and other necessities purchased with grant funds awarded under this subsection that have been provided to foster youth;</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H16B936E626CD45EDA2061BA88987B60A">
                            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides an evaluation of case outcomes for foster youth who have benefitted from grant funds; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H48FD3BB9EEF44D99A784FAC4699288C7">
                            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">states the number of home transfers for each foster youth that has benefitted from grant funds.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="HC150E2DEED1A40BDA2F8A86A9A546C1C">
                        <enum>(8)</enum>
                        <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H56C7CF8A8D694944AE00446279F35F2E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Foster care stabilization agency</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foster care stabilization agency</quote> means a local public or private nonprofit entity, including a community or faith-based organization, with expertise and experience providing direct services to 1 or more of the following:</text>
                            <clause id="H5C4FA325D92E4327A7ADB77053DCBF31">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Children who are under the care and placement responsibility of a State or tribal agency that administers a plan under this part or part E.</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H22C32F78F8644160A227CA2F8E9CE058">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Foster youth who have not attained 18 years of age.</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H613FDF8C1C434A37B08EFD5E54C9EE0E">
                                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Foster youth who have attained 18 years of age.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H0B5BEC22A8584D9D82BDB4F79D6E589F">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
                            <header>Foster youth</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foster youth</quote> means an individual in foster care who has not attained 26 years of age.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="HA2233028E46F4DBC9DB57EAF3BFFEFD1">
                            <enum>(C)</enum>
                            <header>Home transfer</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>home transfer</quote> means the initial placement of a foster youth in foster care, and any subsequent placement of that foster youth while in foster care. </text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="HDE16A7571E934E36B26E3756492AC6AC">
                        <enum>(9)</enum>
                        <header>Funding</header>
 <text>To the extent that the total of the amounts made available under subsection (a) for a fiscal year exceeds $5,000,000 more than the amount so made available for the previous fiscal year, the Secretary shall use the amounts to carry out this subsection.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

