<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC72012294E244826902B9A59447D127A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 956 IH: Condemning the antisemitic shooting in Sydney, Australia, and all forms of hatred and violence directed at religious communities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 956</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the antisemitic shooting in Sydney, Australia, and all forms of hatred and violence directed at religious communities.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on December 14, 2025, a gunman opened fire during a Hanukkah celebration in Sydney, Australia, resulting in loss of life, injuries, and terror within the Jewish community;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this act of violence occurred during a sacred religious observance and was intended to intimidate and target individuals because of their Jewish identity; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States stands with Australia, with the Jewish community worldwide, and with all those affected by this heinous attack: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H25DC894546EE48EDBB633C773AFDE7BC"> <section id="H5207644ADAD74B1D8129D904B2183252" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2376916B05AF488FBA4BF0524D977E39"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strongly condemns the antisemitic shooting in Sydney, Australia, and all forms of hatred and violence directed at religious communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E21BA5C336E44D59F794E8D44C8B9A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses heartfelt condolences to the victims, their families, and the people of Australia;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA0C8C83917743B296F9A8D75806F35D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms the right of all people to worship freely and safely;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD855C5F22110402E8A8AAB21822F6855"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reiterates the commitment of the United States to combating antisemitism and terrorism in all its forms; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD413796A58A4E9EA4942B18432F2EAB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls on the Australian Government to take action to address rising antisemitism and protect its Jewish community.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

