<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26315-LR8-6J-5MV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 762 IS: Supporting the designation of the second Friday in June as “National Service and Conservation Corps Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 762</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of the second Friday in June as <quote>National Service and Conservation Corps Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas there exists a network of National Service Programs (in this preamble referred to as <quote>Service and Conservation Corps</quote>) that receives funding pursuant to subtitle C of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such network includes more than 140 Service and Conservation Corps across the country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these Service and Conservation Corps annually provide education, workforce development, and support services to approximately 22,000 young adults and post-9/11 veterans;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas today’s Service and Conservation Corps are locally based organizations that engage young adults (generally ages 16 to 25) and veterans (up to age 35) in service projects that address recreation, conservation, disaster response, and community needs;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these Service and Conservation Corps are direct descendants of the Civilian Conservation Corps, a Great Depression-era Federal work-relief program that mobilized 3,000,000 young men to dramatically improve the public lands of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Civilian Conservation Corps participants received food, shelter, education, and a $30-a-month stipend;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, from 1933 to 1942, the Civilian Conservation Corps planted 3,000,000,000 trees and helped build trails, roads, campgrounds, and other park infrastructure still in use today;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States will commemorate the 250th anniversary of its founding in 2026, a milestone that highlights the enduring importance of civic engagement, public service, and stewardship of the natural and cultural resources of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas most modern Service and Conservation Corps are nonprofits or are operated by units of State or local government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, through public-private partnerships, Service and Conservation Corps work with a range of organizations, government agencies, and institutions to engage Service and Conservation Corps members (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Corps members</quote>) in meaningful projects that address local and national issues;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, through a term of service that could last from a few months to a year, Corps members experience the <quote>Corps Model</quote>, where they gain work experience and develop in-demand skills;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corps members are compensated with a stipend or living allowance and often receive an education award or scholarship upon completing their service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, additionally, Service and Conservation Corps provide Corps members with educational programming, mentoring, and access to career and personal counseling, and some Service and Conservation Corps operate or partner with charter schools to help Corps members earn their high school diploma or GED certificate;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas Corps members contribute to the preservation of historic sites, cultural resources, and public lands that reflect the 250-year history of the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corps members complete thousands of community improvement, resilience, and resource conservation projects every year, strengthening the communities of the United States as it approaches its 250th anniversary;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 250th anniversary of the United States provides an opportunity to recognize and invest in programs that prepare young people in the United States to lead the country into its next century of growth, resilience, and innovation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corps members typically serve on crews alongside other young adults or in <quote>individual placement</quote> or internship positions that provide additional capacity to Federal, State, and local resource management agencies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Service and Conservation Corps have longstanding partnerships with Federal, State, and local community development and resource management agencies to engage Corps members in meaningful and necessary projects across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Service and Conservation Corps projects include—</text><paragraph id="id80cce730dee647318b4db1d5a0a83eaf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the enhancement of neighborhoods and community public spaces, including urban gardens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id735b4f3ebb86413c8bebdd23ed1c075f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the preservation and protection of public lands, shorelines, waterways, habitats, and wildlife;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bd079cf479e4c27b18f3bdbc1f97b70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the preservation of historic structures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5045888e6a04a9084ac0d27a665df3a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the provision of access to, and enhancement of, recreation on public lands and waters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbf070bfc9ef471aafa77a24dd16d031"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the enhancement of resilience to natural disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id812491f3e3024e7cbd3ce4be31caaba8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the mitigation of, response to, and recovery from natural disasters, including hurricanes and wildfire;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab348795a3c040ce915374a2c15e4ab7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the improvement of energy efficiency and resource conservation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5987e5dd44643f581656d8f1fd8ef8c"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the building and maintenance of alternative transportation and sustainable infrastructure;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States needs to respond to decades of deferred maintenance of public lands and waters and make its communities more resilient;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States also has millions of young people facing unemployment and barriers to opportunity; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the existing network of more than 140 Service and Conservation Corps is ready to meet the needs of these young people in the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idd9d81cc78a0a4fb59c9b5578a3c62d22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of a National Service and Conservation Corps Day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2043472d77224c00aeb88742da0d8a38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates the existing network of more than 140 Service and Conservation Corps on its contributions to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9953dc11156e4c0c8271fb93c0bc0386"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the citizens of the United States to recognize the importance of national service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52b5f6286f5842d0867fc63761b3d853"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the continuation and expansion of the national network of Service and Conservation Corps under the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12501">42 U.S.C. 12501 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2eebfea236484597ac396bd1b696851b"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the role of Service and Conservation Corps in honoring the 250-year legacy of civic engagement and public service in the United States.</text>
      </paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

