<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEFD5E6CB551D4F67BC29AD5A03E5BBC3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1220 IH: Condemning the attempted assassination of President Donald J. Trump on April 25, 2026, condemning the multiple attempts against the President’s life, and recognizing the critical mission of the Department of Homeland Security.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1220</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001099">Mr. Haridopolos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the attempted assassination of President Donald J. Trump on April 25, 2026, condemning the multiple attempts against the President&#8217;s life, and recognizing the critical mission of the Department of Homeland Security.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on April 25, 2026, an attempt was made on the life of President Donald J. Trump in Washington, DC, at the White House Correspondents’ Association dinner;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the White House Correspondents’ Association dinner is an event celebrating the free press and First Amendment;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, during this attack, law enforcement personnel performed their duties with professionalism and heroism;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on July 13, 2024, and on September 15, 2024, attempts were made on President Trump’s life;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Homeland Security is facing the longest lapse in appropriations in history due to radical Democrat demands during a period of increased threats; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas continued calls for violence against the President of the United States and other public officials are contradictory to the American tradition and risk undermining the democratic process and endangering the lives of public servants: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H29954182959D477ABD3D819875F0BDDC"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA764038C125B43E4A98F23E0A2E16731"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H0020D09FC8C04B988ACFFBE5937668C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the assassination attempts against President Donald J. Trump on July 13, 2024, in Butler, Pennsylvania, on September 15, 2024, in West Palm Beach, Florida, and on April 25, 2026, in Washington, DC;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F2A0F48C7B041AEA8B4156DBEF88976"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses gratitude to the law enforcement officers who responded to the attack at the White House Correspondents’ Association dinner;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A3B379F61C1492E80DBD4071307BE03"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms that the United States Secret Service is the agency responsible for protecting the country’s highest elected officials and is therefore central to upholding the Nation’s constitutional values;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54AE84252412426F883C2A96CD9E728F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges the roles of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Metropolitan Police Department in countering threats in Washington, DC;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B3386F87F9A4055954DD1EFE6FB92DA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the vital mission of the Department of Homeland Security and acknowledges the importance of fully funding the Department’s components; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F7B17BA6B69487BA8626AA8EE24086E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>calls on all Americans to unite against political violence and condemns those who incite violence against the President of the United States and other public officials.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

