<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25799-1NX-M6-7JJ">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3036 IS: Chinese Communist Party SDR Exchange Prohibition Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3036</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251023">October 23, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> introduced the
                following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
                Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from engaging in transactions
            involving the exchange of Special Drawing Rights issued by the International Monetary
            Fund that are held by the Chinese Communist Party.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA0A9EBA60F964129ABB310F104D97AB8">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H83E79B3A29EB40D0A72357159EA25101">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chinese Communist Party SDR Exchange Prohibition Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HE4DCA7BE42434BBA802C317E43E0EF90">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Prohibition on exchange of Special Drawing Rights held by Chinese Communist
                Party</header>
            <subsection id="HFF1311CC39BC46A49AB8DE8D1A16CB12">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury may not engage in any transaction involving the exchange of Special Drawing Rights issued by the International Monetary Fund and held by the Chinese Communist Party.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H34A9C8FC0AB64A99920CDA93D5DB2E6E">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Advocacy</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8F6083E4F2E4490FBCB7CB2DCA717F89"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>vigorously advocate that the government of each member country of the International Monetary Fund, to the extent that the member country issues a freely usable currency, prohibit transactions involving the exchange of Special Drawing Rights held by the Chinese Communist Party; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H96DEDE6F3E92400B980F81F523E12006">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>direct the United States Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any allocation of Special Drawing Rights to the Chinese Communist Party.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id51C0C0E6B0E64B54890B6E518969C9F3">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Waiver</header>
 <text>The President may waive the application of this section if the President—</text>
                <paragraph id="idCF484824CF744B3B8F8E29CD006C9CAD">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>determines that a waiver is in the national interest of the United States; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id2AE2BE87133847F8BCE82D36F31C0D65">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>submits to Congress a notice of and justification for such waiver.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H6AF02D9491FC463AB9F5560823BE5F7F"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Termination</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall terminate on the earlier of—</text>
                <paragraph id="H44BAE4CFA4DE4367A7134C62CE6256BF">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5802E9AEBD2B4A83B1AAB5449B5BC43E">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the date on which the President determines and reports to Congress that termination of this section is in the national interest of the United States.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

