<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LAN26366-0R2-9F-RR4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4990 IS: McCarty and Heideman Air Safety Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4990</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to review and update Federal Aviation Administration regulations, policies, and guidance related to low-altitude airspace safety, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>McCarty and Heideman Air Safety Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id4e28773be109498498dd506af09a684f"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review of FAA policies and regulations related to low-altitude airspace safety</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07f197b367d24892a226c2964192c572"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75703511eec343b490a2674fe5fe8f6a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), in consultation with the stakeholders described in paragraph (3), shall review existing Federal Aviation Administration (referred to in this section as <quote>FAA</quote>) policies and regulations related to low-altitude airspace safety for the purpose of identifying appropriate policy, operational, or technical improvements, such as updated requirements related to markings on slacklines.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59116e3e6fd5442f9d650919f43e5203"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In conducting the review required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consider the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf758a36a86744ba0932b4084dd954726"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether existing FAA policies regarding obstruction marking and lighting clearly identify when slacklines, tight ropes, highlines, wires, and similar temporary obstructions should be marked, lighted, or otherwise identified and whether such policies are effective in reducing the risk of low-altitude aircraft strikes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa653fcf510046d0bf1bc317aa1f9d9a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether the FAA can improve Notices to Airmen, obstacle data, or other aeronautical information products to better support consistent digital depiction across flight planning tools, electronic flight bags, avionics systems, and other associated tools utilized by industry, including information related to coordinates, radius-distance, maximum height above ground level, effective dates and times, responsible party information, and any marking, lighting, or identification required by the FAA.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41da2dfec17945ac9b80ba3dea6ee529"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the FAA can improve coordination with relevant Federal, State, Tribal, and local land management agencies, including the National Park Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the United States Forest Service, with respect to activities that may create low-altitude aviation hazards.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id91a64584e2b74e94b78065c490547585"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether the existing penalties for violations of low-altitude airspace requirements are sufficient to ensure the safety of such airspace.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfee6a6eddd1d48db84da1d36d5e76ab8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Suggested improvements to FAA outreach to non-aviation communities whose activities may create hazards in the national airspace system to improve awareness of, and compliance with, applicable requirements and guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id864f487c7eb44e1380d50a7b9b5c12c0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the stakeholders described in this paragraph are representatives of the following:</text><subparagraph id="idb8a60129dd0d4296993142619f23f1cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Helicopter and powered-lift aircraft operators and pilots.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id084d55ba81fc4a52864cd0f15096c1fb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Air medical operators.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84049ea5d2604d989855776185d870d4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>General aviation pilots and aircraft owners.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64792f32344b45798668ccb9247f08ad"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Agricultural aviation operators.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae7c6f9ad610495aa80db2e394909fe2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Uncrewed aircraft system operators.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce7b036bae294b28a26ce802be65606b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Aviation safety experts with specific knowledge of vertical flight operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50827dd011b14eea9500d3e9654dd7a1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other stakeholder the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd55200ef2100440e9ad8f20400f40548"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updated regulations, guidance, and policies</header><text>If, upon conducting the review required under subsection (a), the Administrator determines that the policies described in subsection (a)(2)(A) do not adequately identify requirements related to markings or lightings for slacklines or other temporary obstructions, the Administrator shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, update FAA regulations, guidance, or policies as necessary.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id671318e88d124033a61a5d908cb7b851"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the completion of the review required under subsection (a), the Administrator shall brief the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives regarding—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd277455c4a694a15b424840adfd8e021"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of such review;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b0d6b51702d4920bb8472713860f580"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regulations, guidance, or policies to be updated pursuant to subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3b7e210cadf45dc8ee870cbadb467f9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for legislative action determined appropriate by the Administrator to improve the safety of low-altitude airspace.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

