<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0F2E85B0BC846C6B6C1E21E02CE6E9C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8466 IH: Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8466</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require certain agencies to develop plans for internal control in the event of an emergency or crisis, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H756E55350C4640338910369566D89EDD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H67865DA41F054E17848866040AFB9B3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TRUE Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7B188691CA5B462FAF6530E35AC9985F"><enum>2.</enum><header>OMB guidance</header> <subsection id="HD38514E53528419180AB487BA4771E6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plans for emergency spending</header><text>Subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HCA8DEDCFC40249C9AB1A9157FAA06B42" style="USC"> 
<section id="HD0301ACABF48435CB282BDCD590E86AF"><enum>3359.</enum><header>Requirement for financial and administrative controls for emergency spending</header> 
<subsection id="HB46D07F2551B406AB70BE6C488571250"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H90A44224D21C4525AF7235B9FC03BEC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <term>covered agency</term> means an agency described in section 901(b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H866BA35E7048457F826F89C6E4209828"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C552443E1C840989C49E95B77BB13D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Internal control</header><text>The term <term>internal control</term> means a process that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC1EDB75017B14CD289BE40D7BBB3094D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affected by the management and other personnel of an entity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5FB0BE1739A48AAA164D26D16FEC052"><enum>(B)</enum><text>designed to provide reasonable assurance with respect to the achievement of objectives relating to—</text> 
<clause id="HBBE2852BD4CE4E209A5BC3B51B00608E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>effectiveness and efficiency of operations;</text></clause> <clause id="H476D6121DDDB4998A61CD4FFB87AB4B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reliability of financial reporting; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE63BB7ECBCCF445EB5B3B801754E9961"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>compliance with applicable law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC8269DF2B95F4F37B95A35191A6C6CD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header> <paragraph id="HC212A08CC578463E84E1D785B0A57525"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director shall issue, and every 3 years thereafter review and if necessary update, guidance to covered agencies for the development of plans for internal control that are ready or adaptable for immediate use in a future disaster, pandemic, economic relief, or other such emergency supplemental appropriations legislative measure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96417156CE3C4986BA1F0F85D7C411DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The guidance issued under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HABAAD33C3D6141C5917ADAF7C2EB48B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporate relevant governmentwide documents and best practices for preventing improper payments and mitigating fraud risks in Federal programs, including the documents of the Government Accountability Office entitled <quote>A Framework for Managing Improper Payments in Emergency Assistance Programs</quote> and <quote>A Framework for Managing Fraud Risks in Federal Programs</quote> (or any successor document); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5BE48FB3B9CE49B1A8B3D05FABB10DBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require a plan for internal control of each covered agency to include—</text> <clause id="H837FFF14664E4EA0AC8B25C11848BF15"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the identification of a senior official of the covered agency to be responsible and accountable for the implementation of the plan; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2CE05065E2954033BEC74BF29FC6F86F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>policies and procedures to timely—</text> <subclause id="H08297DD2E3DA40C897798CB701C1F551"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in accordance with paragraph (3), assess the risks of improper payments and fraud relating to the implementation of any supplemental appropriation, or other increase in budget authority, that may be made available to the covered agency for a purpose relating to implementing a disaster, pandemic, economic relief, or other such emergency supplemental appropriations legislative measure;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCD2DD826EE72418DA5096F0099EF8C79"><enum>(II)</enum><text>develop and implement mitigation strategies to reduce the risks described in subclause (I), including any change to internal controls, to ensure that, to the greatest extent possible, appropriate controls are in place prior to the expenditure of funds; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0280BEF9FF4A47D9924E11D247713D60"><enum>(III)</enum><text>adopt real-time, data driven payment monitoring techniques to identify and reduce improper and fraudulent payments, such as anomaly detection, volume plausibility checks, and network analysis.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FBD740C265548A6B51EA2AC1A48DFAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessment of risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessment of risk required by paragraph (2)(B)(ii)(I) shall include at a minimum—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B6B5D156BAD43A6BAAFC7DA6F2BD675"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a substantive evaluation of the risk of financial loss to the Federal Government caused by improper payments and fraud; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB04BAA7B1154B50900BF1EC2B88D39D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of the risk tolerance for the agency program or activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6D6E6F85E045465583747FFBE3EFF004"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan submission</header> <paragraph id="HE5E2B5DDE989484FAE8C98060C447DE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the head of each covered agency head shall submit to the Director the plan required by subsection (b)(2)(B).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB61B548449414986ABD63F8F5EC74B82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the head of a covered agency submits a plan under paragraph (1), and not less frequently than once every 3 years thereafter, the head of each covered agency shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H074FB8E4F3514D8FBB0D7A9866315FB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review and, if necessary, revise the plan of the covered agency; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD20B7E0AFD5B4DD5972F0ACAD26DC315"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Director any revised plan of the covered agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E374D5372324C9DB0BD1CB39143A435"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 months after the date of the enactment of this section, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Director shall assemble and submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives the plans submitted by covered agencies under paragraph (1) and a summary of the plans to help agencies prepare to implement such plans, including any action planned to harmonize the agency programs and activities and any legislative recommendations for a future disaster, pandemic, economic relief, or other emergency supplemental appropriation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3EFD049EB2784A358FCF2A69D4B8260A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3358">section 3358</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HD5F08AB5B18442BCA6984E10EBA22154" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="item">3359. Requirement for financial and administrative controls for emergency spending.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB2DCC161E0C5495280D202F57256428F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

