<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDFA51342103B469DBA10FC938F3EAC94" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6370 IH: Baby Changing in Health Centers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6370</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to require certain health centers to equip restrooms with baby changing tables, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC29A13D8E864BB5826C68D831A770BF" style="OLC"><section id="HC29D2A2EC2174B0AA55ACF1104D3161B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Baby Changing in Health Centers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H493FB4C084404BEA956FA66D8E6C1967"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equipping certain health centers with baby changing tables</header><subsection id="H39E03651CD6C40C0A948D5A7F4642FC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 330 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9C87C744A5164F0CB5770088B6423A38"><subsection id="H99878E7B7F254AE29C5DE6D815886EF4"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Baby changing tables</header><paragraph id="H8A352366BF3742F4A492F3CDCAB7AE7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition for the receipt of a grant under this section, the Secretary shall require a health center receiving assistance under the grant to provide assurances that restrooms in the facilities of the health center are equipped with baby changing tables that are physically safe, sanitary, and appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H036C1C2752DF4BD6AADD3D1782E65E6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply—</text><subparagraph id="HE893CEF23F554EBA9FE504082B408538"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a restroom in a facility that is not available or accessible for public use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DF90E2F4D424B9C903F9790400A9784"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a restroom in a facility that contains clear and conspicuous signs indicating—</text><clause id="HD3ADC2CE52E547DCBD6B48017CCDD598"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a men’s restroom, where another men’s restroom, or a gender-neutral restroom, with a baby changing table is located on the same floor of such facility;</text></clause><clause id="HD983119686B94D53A60AFC71F978D907"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a women’s restroom, where another women’s restroom, or a gender-neutral restroom, with a baby changing table is located on the same floor of such facility; or</text></clause><clause id="H183F99FDA91B401F87DA144C16D02FF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a gender-neutral restroom, where—</text><subclause id="HE2F0ADB119CB45EDB1ACE14712143C1E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">another gender-neutral restroom with a baby changing table is located on the same floor of such facility; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H243C693E36E74A0CB85A6A6581DAC45F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a men’s restroom and women’s restroom with a baby changing table are located on the same floor of such facility; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B537548A1C4424C85A5F123AF6F722A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if new construction would be required to install a baby changing table in the facility and the cost of such construction is unfeasible.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73D9B40457BA4244B7EEE6581644CB3F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ADA requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of subsection (a) shall be subject to any reasonable accommodations that may be made for individuals in accordance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H306039C5F1F6429ABDEFBD64F0C9F937"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds received under this section may be used to cover costs associated with acquiring and installing baby changing tables and signs as necessary to comply with the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54D6A1CCFCCA493280B2EFEAEB1753E8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Extensions; waivers</header><text>The Secretary may extend a deadline for compliance with the requirements of this subsection, or may waive the applicability of such requirements, as the Secretary determines appropriate to account for extenuating circumstances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H808EB9ADFA3D4A609BE10263D51E5CE4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Baby changing table defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>baby changing table</term> means an elevated, freestanding structure generally designed to support and retain a child with a body weight of up to 30 pounds in a horizontal position for the purpose of allowing an individual to change the child’s diaper, including pull-out or drop-down changing surfaces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A175E3AB7D449F6A1B437D8A05C0872"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Limitation on statutory construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to supercede a more stringent requirement in a State or local law relating to—</text><subparagraph id="H86EBA5ED4C3E4EC4A9800941F10C154B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equipping restrooms with baby changing tables; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H512127FEAC5F49DA941B68FD52E988A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the standards applicable to such baby changing tables.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0B786279E91443684B04A2EF99FA741"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to other amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated a total of $5,000,000 to supplement grant amounts received under this section for the sole purpose of assisting health centers in complying with the requirement of subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBE7CBEBD6BD04C968FAEC7FEFCDBF25D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 330(s) of the Public Health Service Act (as added by subsection (a) of this section) shall apply—</text><paragraph id="HBB340359938142CB8B9CB0468F8FDDC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, in the case of a facility that is acquired, constructed, or substantially renovated beginning on or after such date of enactment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DCCABD224E849829C9FC3FC4535F357"><enum>(2)</enum><text>beginning 5 years after such date of enactment, in the case of all other facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

