<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-DAV26349-LJW-0K-NGW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 616 IS: Requesting information on Honduras’s human rights practices pursuant to section 502B(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 616</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260226">February 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Requesting information on Honduras’s human rights practices pursuant to section 502B(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.</official-title></form><resolution-body>
        <section id="id20086c9d00974369bc9b339d6c5d4e0f" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Request for information on Honduras’s human rights practices</header>
            <subsection id="id1756e2a149a641cfbe7000c7a118c5e4">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Statement requested</header>
 <text>The Senate requests that the Secretary of State, not later than 30 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, pursuant to section 502B(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(c)</external-xref>), a statement regarding Honduras’s human rights practices that has been prepared in collaboration with the Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor and the Office of the Legal Adviser at the Department of State.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id877a8f43bdf7482e99dbcd43ceaa3e2c">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Elements</header>
 <text>The statement submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="idb788cafa5e8843baa68ffd50edaea0e2"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>all available credible information concerning alleged violations of internationally recognized human rights by the Government of the Republic of Honduras under former President Juan Orlando Hernández, including—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id9cc6b38cbb1347fc856ee29407b4c67f">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>connections between high-level government officials and drug trafficking organizations, including the Sinaloa Cartel;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id70129768a3ea4d5ea853b9726217bdfb">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>corruption of government officials related to drug trafficking, including money laundering and bribery;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idb99dafa1acaf446a842ee208b73b07a4">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>torture, rape, illegal detention, witness tampering, and murder in connection with drug cartels and drug trafficking; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id9d8c654b9e3349e5a7e7e8147e01e539">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>efforts to undermine police reforms and drug crime investigations;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9bad225cc74349ba8d53411f688dfff2">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a description of the steps the United States Government has taken—</text> <subparagraph id="idfbe6db2780d64862aff82a9c391e1471"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>to promote respect for and observance of human rights as part of the Government of Honduras’s activities;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idad0463da9d2e46d499178fa2898c03a8">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>to bring Honduran government officials to justice for their involvement in drug trafficking and related crimes;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idf34d5a14ae0d4dc4bf699c947934f181">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to discourage any practices that are inimical to internationally recognized human rights; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idd9ece438de9c427baade7246247259c5">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>to publicly or privately call attention to, and disassociate the United States and any security assistance provided for the Republic of Honduras from, any practices described in subparagraphs (B) and (C); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id1efc3bb586df4d2183feb6fbee109151">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>other information, including—</text> <subparagraph id="id3617ac301f9d4c958b3c69887350020d"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>an assessment from the Secretary of State of the likelihood that United States security assistance (as defined in section 502B(d) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)</external-xref>)) provided to the Republic of Honduras has been used in support of activities related to facilitating drug trafficking and its attendant crimes;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id5cf5d8895dee4cdfa268512881f87113">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>an assessment from the Secretary of State of former President Juan Orlando Hernández’s status post-conviction and any ongoing ties he maintains to drug cartels; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id60d50312640d4ba3851343a7bde4ac2b">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a description of any actions that the United States Government is taking to ensure that the Government of the Republic of Honduras addresses corruption and human rights violations tied to drug trafficking.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </resolution-body></resolution>

