<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85DA7336EB6048348D3EB28CA3CEAB9C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7075 IH: Divesting from Communist China’s Military Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7075</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to include any entity identified as a Chinese military company on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H67E568C7E63F4D2CA6DAB1888B89179B" style="OLC"><section id="HBA19E2A2BAFC4437B29822B97012F50A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Divesting from Communist China’s Military Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6A0301AE5A3B4732AE8217B0B7B3C2F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HDCE55EE410AE42FAAC48AC01479B7D7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In Executive Order 13959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), President Donald J. Trump described the People’s Republic of China’s military-industrial complex by specifically citing the military-civil fusion strategy of the Government of the People's Republic of China, in which that Government <quote>is increasingly exploiting United States capital to resource and to enable the development and modernization of its military, intelligence, and other security apparatuses … [k]ey to the development of the PRC’s military, intelligence, and other security apparatuses is the country’s large, ostensibly private economy</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3419793102F44B89A8938C1AC0A9099"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In Executive Order 14032 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People’s Republic of China), President Joseph R. Biden reasserted those concerns and further found that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the People's Republic of China and the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse constitute unusual and extraordinary threats, expanding the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25412E89A6144D9B9E13E016F56F9B47"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Section 1260H(g) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note) defines a <quote>Chinese military company</quote> as “an entity that is—</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5DC28F4594041438EAC8914AD361AFB">
                    <clause id="H625A2F7928B641FBBA59AAE81D35B4DA">
                        <enum>(i)</enum>
                        <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HED7F95298D2C429E8F3A9C6430371F13">
                            <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly or indirectly owned by, controlled by, or beneficially owned by, affiliated with, or in an official or unofficial capacity acting as an agent of or on behalf of, the People’s Liberation Army, Chinese military and paramilitary elements, security forces, police, law enforcement, border control, the People’s Armed Police, the Ministry of State Security (MSS), or any other organization subordinate to the Central Military Commission of the Chinese Communist Party, the Chinese Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT), the State-Owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council (SASAC), or the State Administration of Science, Technology, and Industry for National Defense (SASTIND); or</text>
                        </subclause>
                        <subclause id="H4109D179868244DAAE250B1DB567A7D7" indent="up1">
                            <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified as a military-civil fusion contributor to the Chinese defense industrial base; and</text>
                        </subclause>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H784A92D4F38B4DCEBA03B4D41371B17C">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>engaged in providing commercial services, manufacturing, producing, or exporting</text>
                    </clause>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5024E82B4C284DE28AD44D6C733F4788"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The functions and objectives of Chinese military companies and contributors to the Chinese military-industrial complex are substantially similar and warrant a commensurate level of treatment under United States statutes and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40CBDE52A1EB4712AFB1377238CD12B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 805 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/31">Public Law 118–31</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4651">10 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref> note prec.) imposed restrictions on purchases by the Department of Defense of goods and services produced or developed by Chinese military companies identified under section 1260H(g) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 and entities subject to the control of such companies. Beginning June 30, 2026, the Department of Defense will be prohibited from executing new contracts with such companies and entities, and starting June 30, 2027, the Department of Defense will be prohibited from purchasing end products or services produced or developed by such companies and entities indirectly through third parties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC24E10D9AA194B15AFF670E661AAD083"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As the Department of Defense prepares to implement the procurement restrictions described in paragraph (5), it is still possible for companies and entities described in that paragraph to raise capital by selling securities to investors that trade on United States exchanges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06630124EA98477AAE0E35E360FA7D4C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In harmonizing enforcement approaches across sanctions regimes of the United States Government, Congress can assist the President to ensure consistent treatment of entities posing national security risks, thereby enhancing the effectiveness of United States sanctions and investment restrictions.</text></paragraph></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1AF30F8A8C940F68C9B5166FD35E993"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inclusion of Chinese military companies on Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List</header><subsection id="H93170F16D90048269BF0DD5C77EFA349"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the Secretary of Defense identifies an entity as a Chinese military company operating directly or indirectly in the United States under section 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note), the Secretary of the Treasury shall include that entity on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List (commonly known as the <quote>NS–CMIC List</quote>) if the entity is not already included on the NS–CMIC List.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C03152788684B5F9AB472AA5FF5ECB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of inclusion</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDECAB0E899D46148458A738F806BCB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by paragraph (2), not later than 60 days after the inclusion of an entity on the NS–CMIC List under subsection (a), the prohibitions set forth in Executive Order 13959 shall apply with respect to the entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9651161106114E58B33A8BF0B4662398"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Divestment period</header><text>A United States person may, during the one-year period beginning on the date on which an entity is included on the NS–CMIC List under subsection (a), purchase or sell publicly traded securities issued by the entity solely for the purpose of divesting, in whole or in part, such securities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F84BC74F60F4BBB808B684CAFA912C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF222450AE72E46E29D70B1CAC26DF457"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H095DEDB8379A467F91E13566490BCE84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8998F15790A3443FAA975420175C09BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0BE3AEA68614D7EA483F21D59F7C32C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive Order 13959</header><text>The term <term>Executive Order 13959</term> means Executive Order 13959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), as amended by Executive Order 14032 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People’s Republic of China).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H032B1A8E39EE43C88827A7EFD1A754B7"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Non-sdn Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List; NS–CMIC List</header> <text>The terms <term>Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List</term> and <term>NS–CMIC List</term> mean the list maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury under Executive Order 13959 or any successor order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0853898481EE4EF3B7E170C29AAC8EDB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publicly traded security</header><text>The term <term>publicly traded security</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H6D002CE1987F4CD0AAB312C975BA5F8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any security (as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)) denominated in any currency that trades on a securities exchange, or through the method of trading that is commonly referred to as <quote>over-the-counter</quote>, in any jurisdiction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5388AA8B546402F8A1CDA370227453B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any security that is derivative of or designed to provide investment exposure to a security described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFDD34549E5C480B9B4FAA3F97EB3426"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H70C15892E2374AEFA2586F3EA9EBDB31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E91CB484D6441D3AF475C99D51ADA65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States (including any foreign branch of such an entity); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C77396C24574AE4AD69FC418AFC6A7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

