<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55F4E53B32124B1FAA978180D616DBC7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1237 IH: Stop Telling other People Resolution</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1237</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Requiring certain Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives to complete a program of training in counterintelligence and classified information protection each Congress, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HDBE1F3C0756D46D5BAA34D80B178BB2C"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H354051D8C9154E3CB2DA73328E11B2AE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Telling other People Resolution</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Resolution</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HDF76F97F9CBE43C5882FCD0EEBDD6483"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory completion of program of training in counterintelligence and classified information protection</header> 
<subsection id="H9B9F8896BB7C43CF86B129F2B1BD0D47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring training for certain Members, officers, and employees</header> 
<paragraph id="H34D016E4A7CF4E89A7AC83F173153A85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, the Committee on House Administration shall issue regulations to provide that during each Congress each Member (including each Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress), officer, and employee of the House of Representatives described in <internal-xref idref="HA3708A33000D46AD93684DF8A8192057" legis-path="1.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref> shall complete a program of training with respect to counterintelligence and the protection of classified information administered by the Sergeant-at-Arms of the House.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5948D1022BD4822B319702EDC0CF9B4"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Inclusion of fellows and detailees</header> <text>For purposes of this resolution, an individual serving in an office of the House of Representatives as a participant in a fellowship program or a detailee from another office of the Federal Government shall be considered an employee of the House.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB088352A1FE44BA9B288BFCF5C72619"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for participants in new Member orientation programs</header><text>If an individual completed a program of training required under <internal-xref idref="H34D016E4A7CF4E89A7AC83F173153A85" legis-path="1.(a)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> during the new Member orientation program administered by the Committee on House Administration prior to the beginning of a Congress, the individual is not required to complete the program during that Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA3708A33000D46AD93684DF8A8192057"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered Members, officers, and employees described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member (including each Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress), officer, or employee of the House of Representatives described in this subsection is—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8EE404985D114F8185C8DB4B1DEE5E19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a Member, any Member who receives access to classified information as a result of the Member’s service in the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80040DE11B47446F88A54956453CACC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an officer or employee, each officer or employee who holds a security clearance and receives access to classified information as a result of the individual’s service in the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H462D9192F8FB43E0AB72A346D6D93B2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header> 
<paragraph id="H60D5D41F92224FE0AB01889546EA774D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the regulations issued by the Committee on House Administration under <internal-xref idref="H9B9F8896BB7C43CF86B129F2B1BD0D47" legis-path="1.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, an individual shall complete the program of training required under <internal-xref idref="H34D016E4A7CF4E89A7AC83F173153A85" legis-path="1.(a)(1)">subsection (a)(1)</internal-xref> and file a certificate of completion of such training not later than—</text> <subparagraph id="H53254D56DEA34FA0A949960AA6A82252"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who is serving as a Member, officer, or employee of the House as of the date on which the Committee first certifies that the program is in operation for a Congress, not later than 90 days after such date; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B3DC59890A94C6784D347621644CC60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of any other individual, not later than 90 days after the individual first becomes a Member, officer, or employee of the House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BB09C967DAF4588952C29E2D36C9FD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative deadlines</header><text>The Committee on House Administration may include in the regulations issued under <internal-xref idref="H9B9F8896BB7C43CF86B129F2B1BD0D47" legis-path="1.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5C5BDB42D59D4110BC0354BAE885A1D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an alternative deadline for individuals serving as participants in fellowship programs to take into account the duration of their service; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC572EE9FE2440C1BFC4F2BC2406C5BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alternative deadline for individuals who first become Members, officers, or employees of the House towards the end of a Congress to take into account the amount of time remaining in the Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58DF295B5C3B41F8AF07AF06E9ECE7D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for One Hundred Nineteenth Congress</header><text>In the case of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, an individual described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) shall complete the program required under <internal-xref idref="H9B9F8896BB7C43CF86B129F2B1BD0D47" legis-path="1.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> not later than 90 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9D071074F3BB4450A3CCE40A38488CD5"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Prohibition with respect to access to classified information for noncompliance</header> <text>If an individual does not meet deadline for completion of the training under <internal-xref idref="H462D9192F8FB43E0AB72A346D6D93B2B" legis-path="1.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>—</text>
        <paragraph id="H9B3044B2C0A04729A4F3AC7A73A89F93">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a Member, such Member may not be granted access to any classified information until such date as the Member completes the training and files a certificate of completion; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAD0CF945C4A5401F9755C81E61F5F3A0">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in the case of an officer or employee, such officer or employee may not be granted access to any classified information until the date that is 180 days after the date the officer or employee completes the training and files a certificate of completion.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H58551048F4D64B589AD359E81FB81942"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional mechanisms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on House Administration shall consider additional mechanisms to ensure compliance with the training requirement under <internal-xref idref="H9B9F8896BB7C43CF86B129F2B1BD0D47" legis-path="1.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

