<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB7E0536CFC104EC5A85ED91A64657C60" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7616 IH: Transatlantic Academic Security and Risk Mitigation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7616</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to develop a strategy to identify and mitigate relationships that pose a risk to United States foreign policy interests between certain European institutions and certain covered entities of concern, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3DCA8F54846049D49ACB3B914322D9D7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0A9E500DA65F42AABD395D5E337D6A93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transatlantic Academic Security and Risk Mitigation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H389E4F81CEF949B2B00B2CB24CCE9323"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy</header> <subsection id="H27B35FA6C623462185237F79190EE49F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy regarding covered European institutions that maintain academic, financial, research, governance, programmatic, data-sharing, or other relevant direct or indirect relationships with covered entities of concern. Such strategy shall also include each of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H84341247A9A94EFC969B897979B4365E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The manner in which the Department of State will identify, evaluate, and mitigate the relationships that pose a risk to United States foreign policy interests between European institutions and covered entities of concern.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H386315F5CA2E4DDCB7C36C46266EF851"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the scale, scope, and activities of covered entities of concern in Europe, disaggregated by country and including any other relevant operational or financial details.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6857D0B29C54CDC8DB0A294BD7CF10B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An evaluation of the vulnerabilities, threats, and national security risks posed to the United States and to European allies and partners arising from the presence, activities, or influence efforts of covered entities of concern in European countries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26F8BBD501C2465181081D6CCB222632"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A list of recommendations for bilateral and multilateral United States diplomatic engagement with European governments and covered European institutions aimed at mitigating risks associated with covered entities of concern.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7437D6A1A2248FA9FEC726304FC47F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any other matters the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs determines relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD38117C02CD046DAB0996545BA5AE837"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1C6CCC3697CB4F2983CFBB2B4B034EDE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Concurrently with the submission of the strategy required by subsection (a), the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on that strategy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB8673D65DF284867965D6373F1BCCA20"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9B6A89EA157D45DCBAC57E04BABE753A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H99F88A5D06C24FEF8F92FEE3F3F3A31E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A9C6F95D97D4B01B5E344F7A5989A63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H648476F5449B4CC697E65CC7734F9EF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity of concern</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity of concern</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD468288BCE5D4473B34DA18D684E8CBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any entity of the People’s Republic of China that—</text> <clause id="H31DFF0370E9C4E529D18739B102059D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is involved in the implementation of military-civil fusion;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7EE6411556A147BF87355432D6148539"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>participates in the Chinese defense industrial base;</text></clause> <clause id="H3FA1407E9EAB49158EA8714AD8BD5C40"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is affiliated with the Chinese State Administration for Science, Technology and Industry for the National Defense;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8D1E216BD6594C25A8B508E64240BFAA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>receives funding from any organization subordinate to the Central Military Commission of the Chinese Communist Party;</text></clause> <clause id="H18F317665A71462EA0B52DF85D8CC0C2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provides support to any security, defense, police, or intelligence organization of the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5DCF3C4FDA2D43FEBFBE65D6567F12C7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engages in coordinated activities or provides material support intended to undermine the United States relationship with Taiwan;</text></clause> <clause id="H1B80E211A06D4AC989959EACBDF90C85"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>aids, abets, or enables the detention, imprisonment, persecution, or forced labor of Uyghur Muslims in the People’s Republic of China; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8AA334767EEB497EB5EFA0F1613D0E06"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is affiliated with the Chinese Academy of Sciences or the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E63A82E37164599A06E5922997ECA7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity that participates, directly or indirectly, in a foreign talent recruitment program of the People’s Republic of China or has participated in such a program at any time in the 10-year period ending on the date of the submission of the report required by subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76CDF9EAEA4C4B3C8C78E71BB6F42642"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity that directs support or coordination of student groups, language or cultural centers, or other on-campus entities (including Confucius Institutes or Chinese Student and Scholars Associations directed or funded, directly or indirectly, by the Government of the People’s Republic of China); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78752BF77A994A458786AE4CFD858B6F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity that engages in foreign malign influence or interference involving subversive, undeclared, coercive, or criminal activities, which may include propaganda, information manipulation, or efforts to influence academic, political, or civic institutions, whether conducted directly by foreign governments, state-linked entities, or through affiliated non-state actors, or their proxies, including through and by the United Front Work Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB7A47F7B3764ED6A6CAC4BAEBD3DE54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered European institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered European institution</quote> means an institution of higher education or a research institution located in Europe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

