<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H12B20CFCA3114BD2A05876AE007A44B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6810 IH: Maximizing Agency Integration on Letter Theft Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6810</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct certain heads of Federal agencies to develop a strategy to improve Federal investigations of organized postal theft, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H78E1B42074F449738356364518FD0F02" style="OLC"><section id="HEA0B7A35490643769AEBFDE88471ACA9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maximizing Agency Integration on Letter Theft Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>MAIL Theft Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H85F3ADE49498432BA56D35244C077172"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving coordination in Federal investigation of organized postal theft</header><subsection id="H1E7592F16589448A9B64ECF521C199C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Postmaster General, and the head of each relevant agency shall develop a strategy to identify how each such relevant agency can coordinate with other relevant agencies to—</text><paragraph id="HDCBDC15C805E44BD8ECAB1F2286E8F98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve information sharing between the Postmaster General, the Chief Inspector of the U.S. Postal Inspection Service, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations, the Director of the Secret Service, and the head of each relevant agency on organized postal crime networks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC93839AAA29C48C8957CD3461FB36369"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist State and local law enforcement in compiling materials and evidence necessary for prosecution of organized postal crime; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C23C269ED7F4F0991F239C5A6B04409"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase cooperation and information sharing between each such relevant agency and State and local government agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9146D6A55EA4754BCF2E2BE4AEBFD9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Postmaster General, the Chief Postal Inspector, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, and the head of each relevant agency shall submit a joint report to the relevant committees on the strategy developed pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H02C89A2CE5D240C5BD18701D6F08557B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller general report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall publish a report on coordination between the private sector and law enforcement to deter and investigate organized postal crime.</text></subsection><subsection id="H904B0E3E315B49E98F9759F9C9BF79FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC3D6EEC1B5024514839815C1E3253653"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Organized postal crime</header><text>The term <term>organized postal crime</term> means the coordinated illegal acquisition of postal mail through theft, embezzlement, fraud, or other means that are illegal under Federal or State law for the purpose of selling or distributing such goods in interstate commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB78CEB8B73004D49B95446321848B447"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organized postal crime network</header><text>The term <term>organized postal crime network</term> means a criminal network that engages in organized postal crime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66CB714C59014C4188ECE4B0D6ED467B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relevant agency</header><text>The term <term>relevant agency</term> means any agency (as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code) determined by the Postmaster General, the Attorney General, the USPIS Chief Investigator, and the Secretary of Homeland Security to have a role in information sharing and investigation of organized postal crime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8CA572AE15A477BA02BA4FB6A8927A6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relevant committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant committees</term> means the House Committee on the Judiciary, the House Committee on Homeland Security, the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability, the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, and the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

