<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA26423-9JS-KS-10W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4664 IS: Safer Choice Program Authorization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4664</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Safer Choice Program within the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Choice Program Authorization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5445c93353747e08c13564f9a84d35e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="idc54edad7a146464cb00d19bd9d73e402"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote the development and use of safer chemical products, the Environmental Protection Agency has carried out—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefe3f2c99435455da4ea88967ce03bc8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Design for the Environment program for more than 30 years preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ccd8c5e5b0a4254a9f2ce18cca09f58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Safer Choice program for more than 10 years preceding the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id42746d88859a497cb89770a7b24b6d38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the programs described in paragraph (1) (referred to in this section as the <term>programs</term>) are voluntary, market-based initiatives that provide consumers, businesses, and institutional purchasers with clear and reliable information to inform product selection;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96f46c9d4f4545bf9bc37e3d1ecd94df"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the programs have supported United States innovation by providing a predictable framework for manufacturers, including small and medium-sized businesses, to develop products that meet high standards for safety and performance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba460097f7da4e23b351dd267e5d2f3a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the programs have enabled companies to differentiate their products in the marketplace and respond to growing consumer demand for safer products;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6df53119ce304dc78e39552044feb789"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the credibility of the Safer Choice and Design for the Environment labels under the programs depends on rigorous, science-based evaluation of chemical ingredients, including comprehensive and transparent review processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c05aba2cdf844048d6a3dc34da25544"><enum>(6)</enum><text>qualified third-party profilers play an important role in supporting efficient, consistent, and science-based product evaluations under the programs, particularly in cases involving complex supply chains and confidential business information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1487c497b93a45ff94d731eb2252c67a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency has established expertise, infrastructure, and relationships necessary to effectively administer the programs, including the protection of sensitive proprietary information; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2783b0de767449d69884d23988fa1b39"><enum>(8)</enum><text>authorizing and strengthening the Safer Choice program under this Act will—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01260104a91f4f979a784239da5b97d1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide greater certainty, transparency, and continuity for participants in the programs, while preserving the voluntary, nonregulatory nature of the programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id366ea2d199d6429d80aa0808cce67a3b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support United States competitiveness, consumer choice, and continued innovation in safer chemistry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id1340418c26e64265a615db7c9668a4d8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ide6d4db57769941ebb85d96f46093e7e8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41cbac6d62ec4a84be0583665c34059a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>Agency</term> means the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id557a069ff6b54168b28b2d0f7fa37615"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Design for the Environment label</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Design for the Environment label</term> means the label authorized under section 7(b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc27ec606841c49af80c22b3038cbf451"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Design for the environment standard</header><text>The term <term>Design for the Environment Standard</term> means the criteria, specifications, and methodologies used by the Agency for the Design for the Environment program, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, and as updated in accordance with section 4(d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ad2c8e1e6544cbea675eed1577a8082"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Safer Choice Program established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91f4a836942b44ecbe633d0670eed4ef"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Qualified third-party profiler</header><text>The term <term>qualified third-party profiler</term> means an entity that meets criteria established by the Administrator under section 5(b) to conduct technical evaluations in support of determinations under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4723e18beb2742a4bb4f9bb5b055df8c"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Safer chemical ingredients list</header><text>The term <term>Safer Chemical Ingredients List</term> means the list maintained by the Agency to identify chemical ingredients that may be used in products that meet the Safer Choice Standard.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04a13fd266db49c285461193a1345add"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Safer Choice label</header><text>The term <term>Safer Choice label</term> means the label authorized under section 7(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id289842deff9840c2bd51669c959cfaad"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Safer choice standard</header><text>The term <term>Safer Choice Standard</term> means the criteria, specifications, and methodologies used by the Agency under the Safer Choice Program, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, and as updated in accordance with section 4(d).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id0446fbbd8c794401a4da9e6b48e58c86"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of the Safer Choice Program</header><subsection id="id6be64f1a1ba1413d95e0f5cb9c452ae5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall carry out a voluntary Safer Choice Program within the Agency to identify and promote products that, as determined by the Administrator, meet the Safer Choice Standard or the Design for the Environment Standard, as applicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9a28e86f3a754407bf8f2fe921b62dfe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Program is to advance pollution prevention by encouraging the design, manufacture, selection, and use of products formulated with chemical ingredients that are safer for human health and the environment, while maintaining product performance.</text></subsection><subsection id="id366ff0f8f5b04b2aa1ce2399ea59175c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to existing programs</header><text>The Administrator shall carry out the Program in a manner consistent with, and to the extent practicable leveraging, the Agency’s existing Safer Choice and Design for the Environment activities in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8e26366ce9b14bb090159bd2e8fad1d8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates to standards</header><text>The Administrator may revise the Safer Choice Standard and the Design for the Environment Standard to account for advances in scientific understanding, regulatory developments, and innovation in safer chemistry, after providing public notice and an opportunity for comment.</text></subsection></section><section id="idaaccb543c6894be89e56f5ec77b85150"><enum>5.</enum><header>Program administration</header><subsection id="id93f3df70600c4514b0c4b2ae2d929d2a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="ide83304e00f324e55be58c9d5746b5911"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, publish, and maintain procedures for submission and review of products for certification under the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42e7131927134be2a4c706fcc6cb4cd1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make determinations regarding whether a product meets the Safer Choice Standard or the Design for the Environment Standard, as applicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd31cd1f448cc4821a89b6cb01d805a5d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish requirements and guidance for the use, display, and marketing of the Safer Choice label and the Design for the Environment label;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb814ed4787a54ae587929fc150b25a5c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance, as appropriate, to manufacturers and other applicants seeking participation in the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd249f526ee0b47efab5c8f97a0fcffd2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consult with interested stakeholders, including manufacturers, retailers, environmental and public health organizations, and scientific experts, to support continuous improvement of criteria and methodologies used under the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide79274a4e64d4165b7d0905d0e13422f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>conduct public outreach and education regarding the availability and benefits of products being certified under the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2f7e1f0403742c1b8547322ea828e7a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>convene not less frequently than annually a public stakeholder meeting regarding the scope, implementation, and planned improvements of the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id075509883b854a9ca7a69a3da74b206b"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recognize, as appropriate, outstanding leadership and achievement by Program partners and stakeholders, including through a Partner of the Year Awards program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8546a1fcb56432a8835d910a91272eb"><enum>(9)</enum><text>periodically review and update Program procedures and guidance to ensure transparency, efficiency, and scientific integrity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8d4c6c87f0044396b2d34558ed8924d3"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Use of qualified third-Party profilers</header> <paragraph id="id1b319d57e6944a87a41ba22f4bf903a0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Administrator shall establish criteria and processes for the qualification and oversight of qualified third-party profilers to support technical evaluations of products and ingredients for purposes of the Program.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id0d7b858a4b454e999c38c8fd24391ada">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Determinations</header>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="idf5336b9b7a89439f990f44c8b24f938f">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination under the Program shall be made by the Administrator.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="ide5a4e3bd52e241eebed05a4a657bbcb4">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Use of qualified third-party profilers</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may rely on information, analyses, or recommendations from a qualified third-party profiler in making a determination described in subparagraph (A).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id9ae2830323c9453ba7347e3f556a80d7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Minimum requirements</header>
 <text>A qualified third-party profiler shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idefac5d11ad87496c981420f4cc4f4bbb"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>be independent of, and not have any financial conflict of interest with, the manufacturer or formulator of any product under review by the qualified third-party profiler;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id1e5d169a3e8e464db292ed128ded1bc7">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>not receive compensation contingent on the outcome of a review; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4c0193d6cd9c4d6582f35254d97d088a"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>maintain and implement policies to identify, disclose, and mitigate potential conflicts of interest, subject to oversight by the Administrator.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5f8cb839f5924fc09c97c4a3136ae3d7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Administrator shall, as appropriate, coordinate with other relevant Federal agencies, including the Food and Drug Administration and the Consumer Product Safety Commission—</text><paragraph id="idf805a8736ca84bbd8848931cff58972e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote consistency in guidance and review of chemical ingredients across product categories;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida371c0a7026344ebaba6969de12f0f2b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to minimize duplication of effort and clarify expectations for manufacturers and other Program participants; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde9996bc75784ec6987315521daf07e0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support the safe development, marketing, and voluntary adoption of consumer products that meet the Safer Choice Standard or the Design for the Environment Standard.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id21c008e8558b4d7d863df580753ab3cf"><enum>6.</enum><header>Safer choice criteria</header><subsection id="id8bbb1633a6a74e4187daf329172e6060"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Chemical safety criteria</header><text>In evaluating whether a product meets the Safer Choice Standard or the Design for the Environment Standard, as applicable, the Administrator shall use a science-based approach that considers, as appropriate—</text><paragraph id="id34dde8e7fe244c93abd6b48e3ad9ee7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>human health hazards, including carcinogenicity, reproductive and developmental toxicity, neurotoxicity, and endocrine activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35a365ac0f3d4fe58fec575bf52e67e1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>environmental hazards, including persistence, bioaccumulation, and aquatic toxicity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb21c5adfa4ba4b30ac2cedd3043d5e7d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>product performance considerations to ensure efficacy for the intended use;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1de65ce9e6344767a0e771d222c9bcfb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>packaging sustainability and responsible end-of-life management, as practicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21a4e25b94c44dbba3b985e2c7044076"><enum>(5)</enum><text>transparency and ingredient disclosure requirements consistent with Program policies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5401285cb68c4391a42860aad347455a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Product categories</header><paragraph id="id3581138aba2c47f59be5e1a1a865a4d2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Safer choice product categories</header><text>Subject to the Safer Choice Standard and Program policies, eligible product categories under the Safer Choice Standard shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id4c67e2a295ab41828831bc907d6e9fe6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all categories recognized by the Environmental Protection Agency under the Safer Choice Standard as of the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9934955a780f4b1dba85e99db34a1097"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other consumer, cleaning, and institutional products, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8fa1567f8d546d8b6b296e589897ef6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such additional categories as the Administrator determines to be appropriate for inclusion under the Safer Choice Standard, consistent with the purpose and policies of the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38504b5bb4e34d838d14e34878e47aeb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Design for the environment product categories</header><text>Subject to the Design for the Environment Standard and Program policies, eligible product categories under the Design for the Environment Standard may include—</text><subparagraph id="id15f3436fbdb4440abde2d04c561d0306"><enum>(A)</enum><text>antimicrobial pesticide products registered under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">7 U.S.C. 136 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbef1646764c84943891dfed475916fff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other categories determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9c03cd94008b4f3584fb365c25001548"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safer chemical ingredients list determinations</header><text>The Administrator shall maintain, and as appropriate, update the Safer Chemical Ingredients List in accordance with the Safer Choice Standard, including procedures for adding or removing chemical ingredients.</text></subsection><subsection id="id97f638c8e3944eb582f8748b1a64f19b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Full ingredient disclosure requirement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3aa465deec384569ad0b094e41003152"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of certification of a product under the Program, the Administrator shall require the submission and review of sufficient ingredient information for the product, including information describing all intentionally added ingredients, ingredients contained in those ingredients, and relevant residuals present above a threshold determined by the Administrator, to enable a comprehensive evaluation of the human health and environmental impacts of the product, including through the use of qualified third-party profilers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8129c99886644c2290dc63ca289a0712"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any requirement for the submission of information under paragraph (1) shall be—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd51c005f66924350ba672c4d4c43fb51"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to appropriate protections for confidential business information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id273107c6342848d6b20de65bc1b7a60a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consistent with applicable law and Agency requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idfd9e8d0a70e24493992b7ca9bff6ade7"><enum>7.</enum><header>Labeling; unauthorized use</header><subsection id="idd5f30ca253ac41f2abc59fb76f7e9353"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voluntary participation</header><text>Participation in the Program shall be voluntary.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3764113f9e8f4070961c96f1cf5780f5"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Authorization To use labels</header> <text>The Administrator may authorize a person, subject to the terms and conditions established by the Administrator, to use—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="idb2d1a54cc06f49b082b3d476b519f436">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Safer Choice label for a product determined by the Administrator to meet the Safer Choice Standard; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id5d0ddd76fd7e4cc69c1d3f63134d2c15">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Design for the Environment label for a product determined by the Administrator to meet the Design for the Environment Standard.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf737e27887394ff4b6f75d00b0e6d79f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Protection of labels</header><paragraph id="idf348f0b80342446ab095d95336126fd1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27c57f7430dc4c6dab18d953bb73c31e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agency marks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Safer Choice label and the Design for the Environment label are marks of the Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c4fae610d534a21901ab20a19a80df2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person may use, display, reproduce, or represent the labels described in subparagraph (A) in a manner that is false, misleading, or not authorized by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id69077b1306714e5dac8614aebf335f21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id553151672bff435f9286301720829b40"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may take appropriate actions to address a violation of paragraph (1), including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3a1aea334384665aa8a74a8c81e62ee"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notifying the person of the violation and requesting corrective action;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id216d9edb3cbb40a0ae20dd5405840d50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminating or suspending authorization under subsection (b); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ef79f85196d461e8a2cf4d85b5510b9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">referring matters to the Attorney General for civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab3d78098dbb463ba6fa812ebd7d2fd3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) limits any authority or remedy available under other law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idddd9025da72042c894ad62cfcf73d464"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reporting and transparency</header><subsection id="id64f435dcda8a4876b132d7381b9eec63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report describing the implementation of the Program, including—</text><paragraph id="idbd5e41bafa47443682453b7ca8740a37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of products certified under the Program, including the number of products newly approved, renewed, suspended, or removed during the preceding year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f86ff4c201549509223701d8093f60e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of significant updates to standards, criteria, procedures, or guidance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaae49aeceeda461c845e2c9ca486c21d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>outreach, technical assistance, and stakeholder engagement activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id20219d7b380b46ae9f9170a1c0ceb3e0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Administrator to improve the effectiveness or efficiency of the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9069dd8b2ae948c18569bcfe14dc7da1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public database</header><text>The Administrator shall maintain a publicly accessible database of products authorized to use the Safer Choice label or the Design for the Environment label, as applicable.</text></subsection></section><section id="id105db1d339474131b4237bf17c872674"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this Act $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2028 through 2034.</text></section><section id="id91114e29a6c04db99dd631de62f7cede"><enum>10.</enum><header>Effective date; severability</header><subsection id="id658afcec86974a8bbea293f3ad066475"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="iddf75c0b194d040a7a7031db82443c94e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application of a provision of this Act to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provisions of this Act to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

