<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82078EBA2DF247AB89F2ECEDC6C43BD5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7525 IH: Counter Drone State and Local Defender Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7525</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To authorize counter-unmanned aircraft system authorities for State, local, territorial, and Tribal law enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H0DC74D91482A466F8D732B79C045097D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5DC9B685B0BB47E2979B116C6616A90A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Counter Drone State and Local Defender Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H260D3F2EDA9942CFB419F56C61E36AE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>FAA counter-UAS activities</header> <subsection id="H8AF6D98A9BE148AC8AE8A10D2C9A0F54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/448">Chapter 448</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HDA333919F8AB4219B5D5130AF044B196" style="USC"> 
<section id="HB1546E6EC5AA4C6EB399CEE651371D64"><enum>44815.</enum><header>State, Local, and Tribal law enforcement counter drone programs</header> 
<subsection id="H3BA79C577CE546959C7DED011B153694"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header> 
<paragraph id="H8A95E4BF74A746B5A976C4F364CED1C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may take such actions as described in paragraph (2) that are necessary to—</text> <subparagraph id="H6561C5DD0695420C80F837E4B817803F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>detect or mitigate a credible threat that an operation of an unmanned aircraft or an unmanned aircraft system poses to the safe and efficient operation of the national airspace system; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H805932E9F6874AA9970A7C386A36DCE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">test or evaluate the potential adverse impacts or interference of a counter-UAS detection or mitigation system, equipment, or technology on or with safe airport operations, aircraft navigation, air traffic services, or the safe and efficient operation of the national airspace system, or in conjunction with State, local, territorial, or Tribal law enforcement activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28DC6DFDA3384665A386190C21906115"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized actions</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator may take the following actions:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H86DA7CD08F45499DB36A8724E9FABD3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Detect, identify, monitor, and track an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent from the operator of such system or aircraft, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire, oral, or electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7564279AFEC403F988B496A9899EF36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Contact or warn the operator of an unmanned aircraft system of a potential counter-UAS action authorized under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFB0F9583302447E87283149665BE20C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Seize, exercise control of, or otherwise confiscate an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6CB64E558644BDBAB7DBCBA03AB4EFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disrupt control of, disable, damage, or destroy an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system, in coordination with any Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agencies, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire, oral, or electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C33C73A75874FC8B77CC9FBC8BEE73E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administer the authorities for State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agencies set forth herein.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCDF7A9F68C3A46C582DC3A306F3B1CEC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of other laws</header> <paragraph id="HCF9C4FF91BA141549C55D434E5B87FCA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 46502 of this title or sections 32, 1030, and 1367 and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18 shall not apply to activities authorized by the Administrator pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H089728C6BAB947C290958DEF5EFADE95" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy protection</header><text>In implementing the requirements of this section, the Administrator shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A7F852CCE2E48B3B8CBEAAA3E53C89E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the interception or acquisition of, or access to, or maintenance or use of, communications to or from an unmanned aircraft system under this section is conducted in a manner consistent with the First and Fourth Amendments to the Constitution of the United States and applicable provisions of Federal law;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3F7DFAC1A22493EB4F8076D005B20F2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>communications to or from an unmanned aircraft system are intercepted or acquired only to the extent necessary to support an action as described under subsection (a)(2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7168B54D2ED0446FB409C558FAD466FA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>records of such communications are disposed of immediately following herein authorized activity to mitigate a credible threat, unless the Administrator determines that maintenance of such records—</text> 
<clause id="H9C63178327974E79B3FF39FC6D860571"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is necessary to investigate or prosecute a violation of law;</text></clause> <clause id="HD580E8B5D19E41FABC06541BD63559D1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>would directly support the Department of Defense, a Federal law enforcement agency, or the enforcement activities of a regulatory agency of the Federal Government in connection with a criminal or civil investigation of, or any regulatory, statutory, or other enforcement action relating to, an action described in subsection (a)(2);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6E79F6E40218496097C4342DB88266D1" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is to or from the Administrator in the course of a security or protection operation of either agency or a joint operation of such agencies; or</text></clause> <clause id="HE4050A5F53A2475799EEF397D4FDE19C" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is otherwise required by law; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C2E7D08EB07441A822F5089807A9D3C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the extent necessary, the Administrator is authorized to share threat information, which shall not include communications described in this subsection, with State, local, territorial, or Tribal law enforcement agencies in the course of a security or protection operation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9C73E0CD78F94D2797D151232DCD7521"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/448">chapter 448</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H823B54DCDBE64B69B87549CB90E1787E" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">44815. Counter-UAS activities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H78B597C585154B6FA76C41579EECF239"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot programs and permanent authorization for State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="H4CC6A6BFAAEF4062A90D53AA780857D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General authority</header> 
<paragraph id="H6E218AABE25F4FC58D5925C891033700"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall establish pilot programs to assess the efficacy of approved counter-UAS mitigation systems at covered facilities or assets and determine the appropriate policies, procedures, and protocols necessary to allow State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies to acquire, deploy, and operate approved counter-UAS mitigation systems and mitigate unauthorized UAS operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8408F77E725D4AF3BE28B41B2C7106DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon termination of the pilot program established under subsection (b), the Administrator, shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H600303C59FE84440B6BFD57E3519822E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promulgate appropriate policies, procedures, protocols, and regulations necessary to permanently authorize State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies to acquire, deploy, and operate approved counter-UAS mitigation systems and mitigate unauthorized UAS operations to protect a covered facility or asset; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B173363B00641B3AC6F5ACDDFAD5D0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate findings from the pilot program established under subsection (c)(1) in such appropriate policies, procedures, protocols, and regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H84A02E2B3B504F34925432C0FC5B660F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General pilot program for State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement</header> 
<paragraph id="HD2E6C71118144687949A7C3802C95F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0FB3627A18E54F1B87F9E30DB6BE8879"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a pilot program under which the Administrator may designate and authorize State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agencies to engage in the activities authorized under paragraph (4) under the direct oversight of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E8FB941FAF84F399361B38C632A71D2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In designating a law enforcement agency under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall consult with the respective chief executive officer of such agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB394D06AB556477A8E5CB82A81178C20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation process</header> 
<subparagraph id="H55955061D1A34BBBB17420AF6DAA1407"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Number of agencies and duration</header> 
<clause id="H86DA291E02554949BA679CD0D10FF7E2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall, upon written request by an agency described in paragraph (1), designate not more than 1,000 State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies for participation in the first year of the pilot program established under such paragraph, and shall designate not more than 3,000 additional such agencies the subsequent year.</text></clause> <clause id="HF5777369F4EB47B99AABC3C555A3C756"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 4,000 agencies may be designated during the 3-year period of the pilot program established under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1E84F0CF1EB4BF4B1F2E1EBF79E1F08"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may revoke a designation made under subparagraph (A) for good cause.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3DC27E33A2548F4BB2900E7E6A06E27"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header> <subparagraph id="HEF1F71B382024C55BB9BD45163551770"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to designate an agency for inclusion in the pilot program established under paragraph (1) shall terminate 3 years after the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAEF2438611E4DB18759F0E92BB2CC1F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority of agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of an agency designated under the pilot program established under paragraph (1) to exercise any of the authorities described in paragraph (4) shall terminate not later than 3 years after the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act or upon revocation pursuant to paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87C8B405E5BF4F3BAE0DC6498681D58A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Activities authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49, United States Code, or sections 32, 1030, 1367, and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, United States Code, any State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agency designated pursuant to paragraph (2) may authorize personnel employed by such law enforcement agency with assigned duties that include the safety, security, or protection of people or covered facilities or assets to use counter-UAS mitigation systems that have been approved pursuant to paragraph (6)(A), to take such actions that are necessary to detect, identify, monitor, track, or mitigate a credible threat (as defined by the Administrator) that an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7E50DDCB0644C9AB1493683004231F6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the first law enforcement agency is designated pursuant to paragraph (2), and every 6 months thereafter for the duration of the pilot program established under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall inform the specified committees of Congress in writing of the use by any State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agency of any authority granted pursuant to this subsection, including a description of any privacy or civil liberties complaints known to the Administrator in connection with the use of such authority by such agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBE4F5A8627C431EA5D93C1A38AEC5D3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Approval of equipment and training criteria</header><text>The Administrator shall consult with the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission and the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF8384866204541C9A067941990DA75F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approve counter-UAS mitigation systems, equipment, or technology for use by a law enforcement agency pursuant to this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9622B4E10154EB084F4ADEB3A3A8F56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish criteria for training of law enforcement agencies to use such systems to take actions authorized pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38FB8CE28C654B8D880153DB363FB43E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A law enforcement agency exercising an authority granted under this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HE17EBB0E676945E2B43C4013CF7B1559"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only use equipment approved by the Administrator pursuant to paragraph (6)(A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1C68DD20A7A4428A9CEAFEEDA895E84"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, prior to exercising such authority, issue a written policy certifying compliance with the privacy protections described in section 44815(b)(2) of title 49, United States Code (as added by this Act);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F50AFDD67174000BE66CF238CCE467A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall ensure that all personnel undertaking any actions described in paragraph (4) are properly trained in accordance with the criteria established pursuant to paragraph (6)(B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC710F5E3339648E4B9D1FE90EE99945E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall comply with any additional guidance relating to compliance with this subsection issued by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9AAF0EBD4934BB6B560B43AE3FD10F7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agency designated pursuant to paragraph (2) may apply for funding from existing law enforcement focused grant programs in order to support the acquisition, deployment, training, and operation of a counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology approved pursuant to paragraph (6)(A).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86E5B61F9B524ECE9807BDD4A79BB79F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<subparagraph id="H59FD6A5550CE48A9834D746E7905F905"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the head of any Federal agency the Administrator determines appropriate, shall establish an application process for participation in the pilot program established under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19D943B77D574DBB8C954840204EDE10" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The application described in subparagraph (A) shall contain—</text> 
<clause id="HDA878D30696A48C7A1AFD1136559735C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how the applicant intends to use approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology to mitigate potential credible threats posed by unmanned aircraft systems;</text></clause> <clause id="HB8EFB4D22F5143DD9E71DB08CD8B646C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for the acquisition, deployment, and operation of such counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology, that shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H4032793C1DBF420482FD49DAD2500B5C" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be subject to the approval of the Administrator; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDD7FE91B8A31449EAC873502779A4957" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>include—</text> 
<item id="H1826C53FB13947DBB318DAF51DE27D8C" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the covered facility or asset at which the counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology will be primarily deployed and operated; and</text></item> <item id="HBC327FB999474A9E865C0BBC020A1AB6" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the time periods and dates during which the counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology will primarily be operated;</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H90D794F757234F49806C77CE048713B7" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of proposed covered facilities or assets within the applicant’s jurisdiction developed in coordination with the chief executive of such jurisdiction;</text></clause> <clause id="H69E98888C5A747628B47281C5297C4E7" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proof of training programs and operational protocols for the operation of counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4900F041B361411C9840A7A4690521C1" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification by the chief executive of the jurisdiction in which the applicant operates and the applicant’s chief law enforcement officer that all uses of the authority described in paragraph (4) shall be reported not later than 180 days after such use to the Administrator or in accordance with the procedures promulgated by the Administrator; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA8CF9E21AD514329B8F0F8B1C2DF5BEE" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other application requirement the Administrator determine to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H606EC2737E0345CA8F03EF5EC09FDF5F" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Pilot program funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be used from any existing grant programs for law enforcement, anti-terrorism, counter-unmanned aircraft security, and transportation security in the Department of Transportation and, upon approval from any other Federal agency or department administering such similar appropriated accounts, such sums for any fiscal years as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the pilot program established under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H741DB97FB94844388759224B55EAFDB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special 2026 FIFA World Cup pilot program for State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H8741FD9AAE9E4B4C8488A2038B233651"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall, establish a pilot program under which the Administrator may designate 1 or more State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agencies in and around each of the American metropolitan cities hosting tournament matches for the 2026 Féderation Internationale de Football Association World Cup (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>FIFA World Cup</quote>) to engage in the activities described in paragraph (4) under the direct oversight of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BA7BBA8C3A04852A03F704B9DE73B47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation process</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2BE05833A8E94AC495F18A0CF65E3CA3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordination with chief executive of host city</header> 
<clause id="H1C6F3F8EC5AE40EC93517712C6388A50"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immediately after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall coordinate with the chief executives of the jurisdictions that will host a 2026 FIFA World Cup tournament match to designate one or more State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agencies in and around such jurisdiction for participation in the pilot program established under paragraph (1).</text></clause> <clause id="H24E78B19B7CC403AA639972701FED4F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 40 agencies may be designated at any time during the duration of the pilot program established under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2EF420EDFAE8436B9B02AD7AC3BD637D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may revoke a designation made under subparagraph (A) for good cause.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE5B17532605493F905D816911110630"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header> <subparagraph id="H67AA7D06FBFE49F7A5F8797B900E0229"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to designate an agency for inclusion in the pilot program established under paragraph (1) shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04CCB72188A145DEA074E2621B2D5774"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority of agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of an agency designated under the pilot program established under paragraph (1) to exercise any of the authorities described in paragraph (4) shall be in effect during the period beginning on March 1, 2026, and ending on September 30, 2026, or on the date on which a designation is revoked or upon revocation pursuant to paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC90813BEBCFF48939360513D857849CF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Activities authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49, United States Code, or sections 32, 1030, 1367, and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, United States Code, any State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agency designated pursuant to paragraph (2) may authorize personnel employed by such law enforcement agency with assigned duties that include the safety, security, or protection of people or covered facilities or assets to use counter-UAS mitigation systems approved pursuant to paragraph (6)(A) to take such actions that are necessary to detect, identify, monitor, track, or mitigate a credible threat (as defined by the Administrator that an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC159A0BA2C5B41C58C95F93EF39C6ABC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the termination date described in paragraph (3), the Administrator shall inform the specified committees of Congress in writing of the use by any State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agency of any authority granted pursuant to paragraph (2), including a description of any privacy or civil liberties complaints known to the Administrator in connection with the use of such authority by such agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23C45C3F392542E6BD00235562F0077F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Approval of equipment and training criteria</header><text>The Administrator shall consult with the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission and the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8586FD9A5F3A4F5790B120B34931D6F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approve counter-UAS mitigation systems, equipment, or technology for use by a law enforcement agency pursuant to this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H021AF07C7A914AE0A6D458C2ED9540E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish criteria for training of law enforcement agencies to use such systems to take actions authorized pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H006B6C8AF559494E8D7B4636374B088E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A law enforcement agency exercising an authority granted under this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HA641C285D7D74331AB3B613C3E05CD5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only use equipment approved by the Administrator pursuant to paragraph (6)(A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E9EB06358014968BB53CFDD0B2CA03C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, prior to exercising such authority, issue a written policy certifying compliance with the privacy protections described in section 44815(b)(2) of title 49, United States Code (as added by this Act);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06128527B49B4DB3A92DF3B8B42E633E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall ensure that all personnel undertaking any actions described in paragraph (4) are properly trained in accordance with the criteria established pursuant to paragraph (6)(B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93BEF8DC38CB4724829773AA08A1F43A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall comply with any additional guidance relating to compliance with this subsection issued by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE65B9935398440AA9F8471FB4F732996" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agency designated pursuant to paragraph (2) may apply for funding to support the acquisition, deployment, training, and operation of an approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology from the Administrator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA9D7CF98DAA4E6687D844E1FB5F387C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCEA4BA01D7C94F1293949181A6593B96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the head of any Federal agency the Administrator determines appropriate, shall establish an application process for participation in the pilot program established under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A2078C0AF8E461A844D6E0E0A0D65E2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The application described in subparagraph (A) shall contain—</text> 
<clause id="H75BEA4623208424692BD99159FCD63E5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how the applicant intends to use approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology to mitigate potential credible threats posed by unmanned aircraft systems to the 2026 FIFA World Cup tournament match and surrounding festivities hosted by their jurisdiction;</text></clause> <clause id="HD4D351C41B7243428D658B31B2163311" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for the acquisition, deployment, and operation of such counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology, that shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H022939920589449C81400154F5B66F4F" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be subject to the approval of the Administrator; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H445004BF31E148CCBA1794CE265A2BF2" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>include—</text> 
<item id="H66B0B411EA394909AD147C3C0383B658" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the covered facility or asset related to the 2026 FIFA World Cup at which the counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology will be primarily deployed and operated; and</text></item> <item id="H96741E10329E42249117F014FF57C9DD" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the time periods and dates during which the counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology will primarily be operated;</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HC7CAED519CE04763B99C5AC248EDEB99" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of proposed covered facilities or assets related to the 2026 FIFA World Cup within the applicant’s jurisdiction developed in coordination with the chief executive of such jurisdiction;</text></clause> <clause id="HFFE5FCF1913848AB9BB992CE689E2868" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proof of training programs and operational protocols for the operation of counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H73E07AB536054FF59A68D0B44ED9353A" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification by the chief executive of the jurisdiction in which the applicant operates and the applicant’s chief law enforcement officer that all uses of the authority described in paragraph (4) shall be related to the 2026 FIFA World Cup and reported not later than 30 days after such use to the Administrator or in accordance with the procedures promulgated by the Secretary; and</text></clause> <clause id="H11FC3BFBA311427BB2D5E4CE98F4C23F" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other requirements the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F05FCCEC7BB45E6A3CD70A8149DB6CC" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Pilot program funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be used from any existing grant programs for the 2026 FIFA World Cup or law enforcement, anti-terrorism, counter-unmanned aircraft security, and transportation security in the Department of Transportation and, upon approval from any other Federal agency or department administering such similar appropriated accounts, such sums for any fiscal years as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the pilot program established under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8A4C09AFB69145DF9DE2536E408DD3BA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Permanent authorization</header> <paragraph id="H0C8F402B8C294201BDE0E9175885F08D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49, United States Code, or sections 32, 1030, 1367, and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, United States Code, on and after the termination date described in subsection (b)(3), any State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agency properly registered with the Administrator may authorize personnel employed by that law enforcement agency with assigned duties that include the safety, security, or protection of people or covered facilities or assets to use counter-UAS mitigation systems approved pursuant to paragraph (6) of subsection (b) or (c) to take such actions that are necessary to detect, identify, monitor, track, or mitigate a credible threat (as defined by the Administrator) that an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EC336E663D14FB5BB88DA9B0649B86C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Registration requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The registration required under paragraph (1) shall contain—</text> <subparagraph id="H60352B50565440FF85E07E7A08F55732"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how the registrant intends to use approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology to mitigate potential credible threats posed to unmanned aircraft systems; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4571C11E7C6A468D945A2E300D842F83"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for the acquisition, deployment, and operation of such counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology, that—</text> <clause id="H911568FAE7F945288CEA99AB3EEB56B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is subject to the approval of the Administrator;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H44C41944952547AD85C6AAB0AAA7E6A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a description of the covered facilities or assets at which the counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology will be deployed and operated;</text></clause> <clause id="HABBFD457802447E5B9056B9EF7551146"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes a description of the time periods and dates during which the counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology will primarily be operated;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H12D4797CAB99432297D1E961D712DF7C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>contains a certification by the chief executive of the jurisdiction in which the registrant operates that—</text> <subclause id="H9234AEDA92D0430584D34F3B15CCEA15"><enum>(I)</enum><text>sets forth a list of all covered facilities or assets within the chief executive’s jurisdiction; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H45C89B7EE0354D85B0CE5B98B2EE9C6F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>all uses of the authority designated under subsection (d)(1) shall be promptly reported in accordance with the procedures promulgated by the Administrator;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H44F0817CCEE04FAE86D1E08312CCDE63"><enum>(v)</enum><text>contains proof of training programs and operational protocols for the operation of counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3EF433E8D442408EBE458D51EFD06B68"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other requirements the Administrator determine to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC2610129A4F24520A294A00E067CAEC3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="H9E651518F9BB4523952AFCEA15E27C5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise specified, the terms in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code, shall apply to this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3922ACEF42E84223B5D838F2870762EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H36B7C721554F40F780C870F06D298640"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered facilities or assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>‘covered facility or asset</quote> means any facility or asset in the United States that is identified as high-risk and a potential target for unlawful unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system activity by the chief executive of the jurisdiction in which a designated State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agency operates after review and approval by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46FAA00CC2C441F689381B3C79A1D704"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specified committees of Congress</quote> means the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H241A519690FC49B390E9FC0DC49ADB17"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means a State, the District of Columbia, and a territory or possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


