<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR26576-PDX-FN-T1K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4876 PCS: Do Not Interfere in our Intelligence Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 450</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4876</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date>June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve handling of vacancies of the Director of National Intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id52ce1fb36f9841048fb72131393247a1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Do Not Interfere in our Intelligence Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DNII Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id281521c361f041fb8da736c7dfd57645"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vacancies in position of Director of National Intelligence</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id808d288e74034518b4789221fbdd7c2f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vacancies filled by Principal Deputy Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 3345 through 3349d of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Vacancies Reform Act of 1998</quote>), or any other provision of law, the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence, if appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, in accordance with section 103A(a)(1) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3026">50 U.S.C. 3026(a)(1)</external-xref>), shall act for, and exercise the powers of, the Director of National Intelligence during the absence or disability of the Director of National Intelligence or during a vacancy in the position of Director of National Intelligence in accordance with section 103A(a)(6) of the National Security Act of 1947. </text></subsection><subsection id="id8b3b4f7a92a74df392bcc9129311277e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contingency during vacancy of both the Director of National Intelligence and the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence</header><text>Notwithstanding the Federal Vacancies Reform Act of 1998, or any other provision of law, if, and only if, the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, in accordance with section 103A(a)(1) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3026">50 U.S.C. 3026(a)(1)</external-xref>) dies, resigns, or is otherwise unable to perform the functions and duties of the office during a vacancy in the position of the Director of National Intelligence, the President shall direct to perform the functions and duties of the Director of National Intelligence temporarily in an acting capacity an individual who—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd648ec39f77d4e8d8855a3a43d7f3799"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serves in an office within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence for which appointment is required to be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4b8abe3c523405796313924aa517761"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is appointed to such office by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida194c0fe19574854976a1574a04a8db7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contingency during a vacancy of all Senate confirmed offices within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence</header><text>Notwithstanding the Federal Vacancies Reform Act of 1998, or any other provision of law, if, and only if, all offices within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence for which appointment is required to be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, are vacant, the President shall direct to perform the functions and duties of the Director of National Intelligence temporarily in an acting capacity an individual who—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb8899a753cb45e190b4f2b6707aae64"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serves in an office of any element of the intelligence community for which appointment is required to be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8a2d90b71a445318c445f5b88ee4dc6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is appointed to such office by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0f7f23a9e89947628a4bc23e47e78401"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exclusivity</header><text>If, and only if, no other individual meets the requirements of subsections (a), (b), or (c), the President, in accordance with the Federal Vacancies Reform Act of 1998, may direct an individual to perform the functions and duties of the Director of National Intelligence temporarily in an acting capacity.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

