<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25590-PJT-MP-43X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4057 IS: American Civics Renewal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4057</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260311">March 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a congressional commission on American civics renewal, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Civics Renewal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce52e0989c824d2aaf447fcafe434586"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9122c4af29524395a0daabe743480ffe"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2ec9189cf5944828aaf394b8db5d2b7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Commission on American Civics Renewal established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id11bb278cdad249e994f08e7144e33c18"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of congressional commission on American civics renewal</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8e2c5eff18a4c1981a227a7fd87e0dc"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a congressional commission, to be known as the <quote>Commission on American Civics Renewal</quote>, tasked with identifying ways that the Federal Government can strengthen its support for civics education.</text></subsection><subsection id="id88223a3f3cc941d5b7e061434cee3b12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd20bf536e916419085ea436529d978eb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall consist of 8 members, with 1 member being appointed by each of the following individuals:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb812c24ac7084c5aae7d2eb695893685"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Majority Leader and the Minority Leader of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f6da355440c4b5bb293628bf3e4df63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id202ab8e97e3248588bdb18fc922bfddb"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8a66104a52943b98683067ab40b9fec" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair and ranking member of the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID4F911B8DB59248E29F059E5131713461" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date</header><text>The appointments of the members of the Commission shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID79CF96D103FD4274ADF268D788E44827" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson and Vice Chairperson</header><text>The Commission shall select a Chairperson and Vice Chairperson from among the members of the Commission at the initial meeting of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="ID49FC1DF7437F4D65827F32F3B59A5C61" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of appointment; vacancies</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63d627dfe3c94a69874565f2a09859bd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period of appointment</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ABA6BEF0A7647CD9CF8FFBE31E586FA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="id76B0CB8404734FF6A1DF2A252ED8694F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id484DA57A7CD74ED1BC86CBF65528ABB5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCF0A1C97534F42D0AE40072C4235EF91" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="ID713A12DE7D79416DBEBDD4057F256299" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall hold the first meeting of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID67F067576FFC463A842A5F7DA6A093C8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID7A3C368FA83449AD90220C7B181165BB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id297098b5ffb14bffaf5e106f892d3268"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of Commission</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id095e6220621f4900afecfb2f6f69c295"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall—</text><paragraph id="id7080d05501cf4ab785e2729a6efab832"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a comprehensive review of the current state of civics education, as of the date of the review, across elementary and secondary education, higher education, and adult learning;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id684c2ca3427f4bab99027adbd742c48f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate existing, as of the date of the review, Federal programs and funding streams that support civics education and recommend ways to streamline, coordinate, or scale these programs to ensure efficiency and equitable access;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13d851ff30d84ee7b67bbe2d5e51caac"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess teacher preparation programs and ongoing professional development opportunities for civics and government instruction;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id999e693148cb4c7f88f8e78a5eee38ab"><enum>(4)</enum><text>collect best practices regarding teaching and supporting civics education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide6bf4d4de84d46d6918d11e2cdfeac65"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide guidance on how Federal investment can leverage philanthropic, State, or local resources to avoid imposing an unfunded mandate on State educational agencies or local educational agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec9aa4110acd49fba0a5f5bf4faabcd3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>propose strategies to elevate civics education as a national priority, in accordance with subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id79bd46356f284ea0811fab2ac88dd5dd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stakeholder engagement</header><text>In carrying out the duties under subsection (a), the Commission shall engage with—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7246e5db59d41acb9d25a61658e4294"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public Federal entities, such as the National Archives and Records Administration, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Institute for Museum and Library Services, the Library of Congress, the Department of Education, the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the James Madison Fellowship Foundation;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id208c9729406d4824bbe4f159da3d287b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State and local education leaders who have advanced civics learning and understanding for educators and students; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida77da5e518794fd9885cf06ed3fdc354"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nonpartisan organizations described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code, that have advanced civics learning and understanding for educators and students, such as the United States Capitol Historical Society.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8513eb9f9d9841ecaa4bc78ea275ab36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Proposed curriculum and national strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After carrying out the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (a), the Commission shall—</text><paragraph id="id9e09d4cd67974cb9bb2e6707eb70dee0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a proposed age-appropriate civics education curriculum for elementary school students, secondary school students, and postsecondary education students that—</text><subparagraph id="id079b5203db744eaab89b83477502256e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promotes the political thought and history of the United States along with the impact of the representative democracy of the United States and constitutional democracies globally;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9242c92b34284908b1d84b550e3b83b4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describes how the Federal Government was founded on the principles of a representative democracy, constitutional government, individual rights, market economics, religious freedom and tolerance, and freedom of thought and inquiry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d56b4ebd209495ea32921b76738d0b0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrates the importance of students developing civic-minded engagement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22705f175cd24005af96cfa07414d229"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides examples of how lessons can be taught beyond traditional classroom instruction and incorporated into subjects other than history or civics; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0215318af7342b18619c2ac4056d04b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by not later than 2 years after the date of the first meeting of the Commission, publish a national strategy document that contains—</text><subparagraph id="idedde687a38734841aad7e541be0b31cf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>examples of how State educational agencies, local educational agencies, and schools can partner with relevant Federal partners and nonprofit organizations, including entities and organizations described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id638270eabecc4bc4a5f69345b8888e78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations on how State and local education leaders can implement the curriculum described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e56d4b5947446ebb4119064807ce3aa"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission of curriculum and strategy</header><text>By not later than 15 months after the date of the first meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall submit the proposed civics education curriculum and the national strategy described in subsection (c) to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7dc3afa1f1aa405386e42ad47211286b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbd9550e7ad64444843ec5ca8c4dafba"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25bfdbf909904c20bdeac485eaacf00f"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe8378110d4e42a3939f16fda8ac8baf"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Archivist of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7931e71f0f9450792086fdef83a2db5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties of Secretary of Education</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving the proposed civics education curriculum and the national strategy described in subsection (c), the Secretary of Education shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce43950faa2b42c5a2712aac10525a48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform all State educational agencies of the availability of the curriculum and national strategy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cd6fcbfe49e403d8703d6e4e4dc3b96"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a method, through a website or other easily accessible means, for the State educational agencies to access the curriculum and national strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="IDBF35816E08534CFC835DB84FCD77111A" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><subsection id="ID78DA905C4EAE49B0AF74CB57183B6E1A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Commission may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id385B0BF713C84647989A51A8BF846505"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id03B4F3592AD44AC5BB98277E37F689C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may secure directly from a Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEEC5F6AA1ADB46588943EF27D3AC4D94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Furnishing information</header><text>On request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of the department or agency shall furnish the information to the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID697F1CDBA8724CB4AD225E5D97B10BD6" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="IDCC4D9C4DC9ED4F319C2D4949548B9F15" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>The Commission may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property.</text></subsection></section><section id="ID5B2226B82D614F6AA60C08533C1FED30" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Commission personnel matters</header><subsection id="IDF9E4CF3EA6AC4F01B81923D97C022F5A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text>A member of the Commission who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="ID8AB9CAB7544542CBBCD32562861B7980" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="ID771CB422D4684EF88424586CBA7942C6" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Staff</header><paragraph id="ID99AD8891AD904A7EBF3A1D3EE5A99435" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to perform its duties, except that the employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDB23DD631FF0E49B589B943F8049F018B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDA9D71553FE6B470ABBF61FBF5DCE8D94" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>A Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subsection><subsection id="IDD761928855434025A0BC6D8D636885FE" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals that do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></subsection></section><section id="ID8E18677BEB06432BA5DE4BCFA806C638" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination of Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate on the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Commission submits the proposed civics curriculum and national strategy to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate under section 4(d).</text></section><section id="id3ce5325a4c5a4f6e96d91923998b16d9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Appropriations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fb9a17c3e1a4cb7949fe830494bda8d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Commission $2,000,000 to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd43b92a6660e4ec2a93ee4a15599a0c8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts made available under this section shall be available beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, and shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

