<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM25662-XX8-XJ-PD8"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3063 IS: Learning Innovation and Family Empowerment with AI Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code> 
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 3063</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20251028">October 28, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To improve student privacy, parental choice, and personalized learning innovation in education.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD691645151C64D4B87D85810A53CADD0"> 
<section id="idc7e8542d587942269a69bc0a13600d6f" section-type="section-one"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Learning Innovation and Family Empowerment with AI Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LIFE with AI Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="ida5877eb7b7444bb78adf28af76022264"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Definitions</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="idbd9ff05531774ff4817b614eed6234b2"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>ESEA Terms</header> <text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>parent</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings give those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id8b973f684b7046df8b843687bdfefaa5"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Artificial intelligence</header> <text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ide2770068f2df4b79b02253079bfaa557"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Directory information</header> <text>The term <term>directory information</term> has the meaning given the term in section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id05ce6d75f2f64fa897feb8d1059efeb6"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Educational agency or institution</header> <text>The term <term>educational agency or institution</term> has the meaning given that term in section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id0585b1e687994cb9b081e4422510e778"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Educational technology</header> <text>The term <term>educational technology</term> means physical or virtual products or services that support or facilitate learning and improve educational performance, but does not include curriculum.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc53041df74a941df9dfab3a734aff54c"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Eligible student</header> <text>The term <term>eligible student</term> means a student who has attained 18 years of age, or is attending an institution of postsecondary education.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id48bdf77773a645f3b3ce4f8d622c4832"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Instant verification technology</header> <text>The term <term>instant verification technology</term> means a system or software application, or a network of systems and software, that—</text> <subparagraph id="ide4368d21f25d4c39bb208d8b3a12bce2"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>provide real-time notifications to parents of students or to eligible students, as applicable, regarding activities that require the consent of such parents or eligible students, including in the use of educational technology during enrollment;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6492faf5776443669893fecf335472f6"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>enable parents or eligible students, as applicable, to provide or withhold such consent in real-time in an easy-to-use interface accessible on multiple devices, including smartphones, tablets, and computers; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id7946324f11294df085e07669c2bb39d7"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>incorporate features for recording parental or eligible student consent or opt-outs while handling student and parental data in a secure and privacy-protective manner.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id4731f4d9413847c7930deed298b114af"> <enum>(8)</enum> <header>Personalized learning</header> <text>The term <term>personalized learning</term> means an educational approach that tailors instruction, content, pacing, and learning environments to the individual needs, abilities, and interests of each student, usually using specific technology, including artificial intelligence and adaptive learning systems, to provide such customized educational experiences.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idcf446b96712f425391958b53dd85c8ed"> <enum>(9)</enum> <header>Secretary</header> <text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education, or such cabinet-level official as may be designated by law to carry out the functions vested in the Secretary of Education as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph> </section> 
<section id="id7231720861c84d37b10c18741ded9761"> <enum>3.</enum> <header>Improving Parental Notification and Consent for Educational Technology</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="id083c860a70354e30abf2f0b8d292b13b"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Eligible recipient</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible recipient</term> means any of the following entities to which the requirements of section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’) applies:</text> <paragraph id="id297e459065b9405283c53a9e7104b291"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>An elementary school.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="ida15fb0ee40d14fe68477f9bde9bd6405"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>A secondary school.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id9351bd6be35a40a39271b727a0065a01"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>A local educational agency.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="id468577894ca040c29e6e1770d1b2bd62"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Establishment of the Seal of Excellence</header> 
<paragraph id="idc298a2e5eac94171aa3e52afccec3e49"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Design of the Seal</header> 
<subparagraph id="idfa38b479dc1542cebd6fb2d648da1fa9"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize the process and requirements for the award of a certification, to be known as the <quote>Golden Seal of Excellence in Student Data Privacy</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Seal</quote>) to recognize eligible recipients that implement exemplary parental notification systems that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56199eeaffc24def9133078494b35f57"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use instant verification technology for consent gathering and validation; and</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6095e3e8f034aa3b52595446bcb3669"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are purchased through funds already available to eligible recipients.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97aa4e40e30f4860ad51bda5c138077a"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Consultation</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish the process and requirements for the award of the Seal in accordance with this section and in consultation with States and local educational agencies, including by consulting about the appropriate use of opt-outs and minimizing instructional burdens on schools.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id1a11890a874e4afb89d73d5463efa5e7"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Purpose</header> <text>The Seal shall serve as a mark of distinction, indicating that the awardee has met the highest standards of student data privacy through proactive parental and eligible student engagement and consent management.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id4f11775d1a314e3f8273fec6a3e4e4cf"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Qualifications</header> <text>An eligible recipient shall be qualified to receive the Seal if the eligible recipient has—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idc63e8f816d19490d81f272dd033f705a"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>not been found guilty of a violation of the requirements of section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) in the previous 5 years;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6561d2381ed04d20a6439b84146153ba"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>implemented and maintained an instant verification technology system for not less than 1 academic year that—</text> 
<clause id="id0227489e4f994f498f9fb2dcde6be529"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>provides parental notifications and eligible student notifications, as applicable, on a case-by-case basis and where appropriate, regarding the intent of the eligible recipient to use specific educational technology in the classroom;</text> </clause> <clause id="ide85dce4db2514505b0c36fae4cdeafea"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>includes information about the purpose of using the specified educational technology, the data collection practices of that educational technology, and the alternative options for students upon parental or eligible student opt-out;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="id646d8156d9f3450ca14084056adad7a8"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>is able to collect parental and eligible student consent, as applicable, throughout the academic year; and</text> </clause> <clause id="id7d18e3a126ea4e68870b9484c6018404"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>offers an accessible, user-friendly mechanism for parents or eligible students, as applicable, to opt-out of the release of some or all of a student's directory information; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idd506790fc97843a4b57af28b9c42b47d"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>in the event that a given consent request receives a majority of denials from parents and eligible students in a given circumstance, a process established by the eligible recipient for convening a meeting with parents and eligible students to discuss their concerns and reservations about the educational technology in question.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="idcd394f7edbbe4ef988e1349dd5c17f94"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Awarding of the Seal</header> <paragraph id="id77447d30ffa74831b0c563327c3c7d5a"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>State level administration</header> <subparagraph id="ided18c3e26ebc4d809378297c6802c9d0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text>A State educational agency may elect to participate in the program under this section and award the Seal to qualified eligible recipients in accordance with paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id122750c3b32e4d6a807e88b9f48c20c8"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Process</header> <text>State educational agencies that participate in the program under this section (referred to in this section as <quote>participating State educational agencies</quote>) shall establish and use the process described in paragraph (2), by which eligible recipients may apply, including by submitting documentation demonstrating compliance with the qualification criteria under subsection (b)(2).</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id7a4b853b65d044489fad0901bf11ba70"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Application and review process</header> <subparagraph id="id72a94fb8eee04b28a0df040d44ca1391"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Application</header> <text>Eligible recipients seeking the Seal shall submit an application to the participating State educational agency of their respective State, including—</text> 
<clause id="id13e48dd478a44a5a884f9466d0cb11a5"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a description of the instant verification technology system implemented;</text> </clause> <clause id="id89a30d1b78ca44f287db5c05187abd50"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>evidence of parental and eligible student engagement and consent collection practices, such as sample notifications, consent forms, and appropriate opt-out mechanisms; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="id7d403b6f7a52421abc81003b350ed79a"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>any additional information as may be required by the participating State educational agency to assess compliance with the qualification criteria under subsection (b)(2).</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id2958d0221f7042d086171a8eeeb071bd"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Awards</header> <text>Each participating State educational agency shall review each application on a rolling basis and award the Seal to eligible recipients that meet or exceed such qualification criteria.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id0ac5fa6525e14202b424037d6d0ebf41"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Expiration</header> <text>The Seal shall expire after 5 years, unless a recipient submits and meets or surpasses the qualifications described under subsection (b)(2) again in the 5th year of holding the Seal, at which point the Seal remains valid for another 5 years.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id1fe81ea7d5ec45ab88cda76d030355c4"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Recognition and reporting</header> <subparagraph id="ida8e30d26e71a49a2a3c72f53b730a4d0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Record</header> <text>Each participating State educational agency shall maintain a public record of all eligible recipients in the State that have been awarded the Seal.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id6c309b865ccc42e58cacfc90cc088547"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Report</header> <text>Each participating State educational agency shall submit an annual report by the end of the State educational agency's fiscal year to the Secretary providing the number of eligible recipients that have received the Seal during the preceding fiscal year.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="ide605f84b28e84931b0ad3510a4a89c43"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Implementation timeline</header> <text>Each State educational agency that desires to participate in the program under this section shall establish the application process and begin receiving applications for awarding the Seal not later than 12 months after the Secretary finalizes the process and requirements for the Seal.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="idd1d7486679ac4b7f9fe65cd066c59d1e"> <enum>4.</enum> <header>Directory information opt-out simplification</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5710f5415ac4c83bd7614c8e7624404"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In General</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 444(a)(5) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(a)(5)</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’) is amended by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6750883233EA410E82297073497B79BC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fd8841c2f054782b204273cc6088e05"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution that makes public directory information or allows access to directory information, unless such agency or institution meets each of the following requirements:</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e6ff63bf5a142e1b5af43f2cf30b326"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provides legible, accessible public notice, including notice online on the agency or institution’s website, of—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e4b9fac169c4cab88b9cd9f63f86e51"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the categories of information that it has designated as directory information with respect to each student attending the institution or agency;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ea8309f5a3f451ca0d4a4fe113babbf"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rights of parents to opt-out of allowing the release of some or all of the student's directory information; and</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3540ba154baa44039288afdde0f5aff4"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the form necessary for such opt-out, which shall be easily legible and not take longer than 5 minutes for the average adult to complete.</text> </subclause> </clause> 
<clause id="id579509c5cd634596b9f837cd32987aec"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>Allow a reasonable period after such notice has been given for a parent to complete the form described in clause (i)(III).</text> </clause> <clause id="id113c6a20593f400d81f080db5979b7b7"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>Ensure that the opt-out form described in clause (i)(III) shall be accessible year-round and available on multiple digital devices, including mobile phones.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0d5e946204a4d93ba78d4913a4846f5"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Effective date</header> <text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> </section> <section id="id8029a6b580c74e968f265acfb6d13968"> <enum>5.</enum> <header>Restricting use of facial recognition and student photo data in schools</header> <subsection id="id798d5cd143a2409b83cea3ce60426729"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Prohibition on use of student photographs for facial recognition AI</header> <text>Section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id557d75a242d4459b8e0c7aa1d94ea8b3"> 
<subsection id="id36bd2b417f564c6bbb6070d09c58400b"> <enum>(k)</enum> <header>Facial recognition technology</header> <text>No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution unless such agency or institution prohibits—</text> <paragraph id="ida8e2a3d3c7904d2f8c2c265bee48de9d"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the use of student photographs for training facial recognition systems, including those using artificial intelligence, without prior parental consent; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id96a71ae61547439d9966101ff769e2b6"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>doing business with a company that offers yearbook production services and uses facial recognition technology in the provision of such services, unless that company discloses such use and obtains parental consent for the use of facial recognition technology.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="idf86d3ce40bbe4861b704f88424fcaa53"> <enum>(l)</enum> <header>Yearbook production</header> <text>No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution unless such agency or institution prohibits doing business with a company that offers yearbook production services that sells data collected during the creation or processing of a yearbook.</text> </subsection> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf44159861864fec900807fc8c815d9b"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Effective date</header> <text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> </section> <section id="id272dbbc287b141d799a767d9a485f83b"> <enum>6.</enum> <header>Redefining an education record under FERPA</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea4d713e15a34dab913dbde4afa43988"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Education records</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (4) of section 444(a) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEC54A47FFA0A4C5B9035DE8B0D636DC8"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id849949e0408c436798e9bf00f0fcc6a1"> <enum>(4)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4031aedab651476cbfcb29f0d8db9c54"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>education records</term> means, except as may be provided otherwise in subparagraph (B), any data or materials which—</text> <clause id="id7d9a26a7c04e4eae8b8657c7c462f811" indent="up1"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>contain information related to a student, including data related to academic performance, attendance, health, and discipline; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="idbe0dd66e0a8d4cc082803436515c94db" indent="up1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>are maintained by an educational agency or institution or by an entity acting for or in coordination with such agency or institution.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92408dcf0bd241a3896713876931a577"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Effective date</header> <text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="id051629408fa24fb4a5ab9212d803ba8e"> <enum>7.</enum> <header>Contracts with third parties regarding educational technology</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f8c7e3b40554645a1f94fc068394e71"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">FERPA requirements for third-party contracts</header> <text>Section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’) as amended by sections 4, 5, and 6, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12B9CBC204DA47FD80246D3551DA9B61"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b853de83ed242d8a5d8e783a02c1afa"> <enum>(m)</enum> <header>Contracts with third parties regarding educational technology</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id271987cc42a04b1b95710aff340f69dc"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Covered contracts</header> <text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered contract</term> means the privacy policy of any contract or agreement—</text> 
<subparagraph id="idae7203a151954538ae955b4293416d09"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>between an educational agency or institution and a third party; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id299fe8877267462bab6678912bd5dfb4"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>that pertains to educational technology (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Learning Innovation and Family Empowerment with AI Act</short-title>) that involves education records, or personally identifiable information contained therein, including directory information.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5265807a679f4ec084dbba3b111c7e2a"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirements for contracts</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution unless such agency or institution—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c849e3cb05d46aca60b76ec9c2b02c1"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes publicly available, for a period of not less than 2 weeks prior to execution, each covered contract that the agency or institution is considering executing;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id03f69238abb44dd0a11bdbda34bafd3e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>as part of each covered contract, requires the third party to certify that the third party will ensure student data privacy and comply with all applicable privacy laws regarding student data, including the consent requirements that apply to education records; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idce4b180c15b74f97baf1ae5568a8550d"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>as part of each covered contract, requires the third party to agree that the third party—</text> 
<clause id="idc0240419a6e44dff8c7312a7e41e2624"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>may be reported to the Secretary if an educational agency or institution, or a student, alleges that the third party is not in compliance with the requirements described in subparagraph (B); </text> </clause> <clause id="id8e708f386d9f4b8cb215b81b6098ecff"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>may be investigated by the Secretary to ascertain the veracity of such claim by an educational agency or institution or student; and</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbd0b36c6ea34804a2562de048200923"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary determines, after such an investigation, that such third party is not in compliance with the requirements described in subparagraph (B), will be included on a publicly available list created by the Secretary of third parties that are not in compliance with such requirements for a period of 5 years after the determination by the Secretary, as described in section 7(c) of the <short-title>Learning Innovation and Family Empowerment with AI Act</short-title>.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f3d9d93a84b4b38a3ef327db4b3a6bf"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Rule of construction</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require that trade secrets or proprietary information of third parties be made public.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="idb75cc218d9aa40ac9c33a92a81cd0141"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Model privacy policies</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc230d8912a784a03b895ad1d5093f9dc"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a model student data privacy agreement for use by an educational agency or institution as part of a covered contract (as defined in section 444(m) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(m)</external-xref>); commonly referred to as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’), as added by subsection (a). The model shall promote clarity and consistency in student data privacy protections as part of covered contracts.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f2ae5a4bea44d7ebbb43ddff7921d0f"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Development of model form</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Privacy Technical Assistance Center described in section 8 shall partner with educational agencies and institutions, education technology companies, parents, and relevant third parties to develop such a model agreement and may consider the Student Data Privacy Consortium’s <quote>National Data Privacy Agreement</quote> in developing such model.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="id1eda945af8e744eaae27537ce0c8e86f"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Public online resource for privacy violations</header> 
<paragraph id="id1d22061072e44e6298a9becacc85b2a5"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Creation of Public Online Resource</header> <text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop and maintain a publicly accessible, machine-readable online resource listing third parties that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id237ebd411d4d4ee39c77cf6c73c5fce6"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have executed a covered contract (as defined in subsection (m) of section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(m)</external-xref>); commonly referred to as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’), as added by subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1a9c7c6dfa144b7aa56e60adb0ffe53"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary has determined, in accordance with paragraph (2)(C) of such subsection, are in violation of the requirements described in paragraph (2)(B) of such subsection, regarding student data privacy in covered contracts.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id3deaf23687c34d2fb7088656b851e58c"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Appeal</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67f602f53a9547e19344f0b5d9ca6893"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a process whereby third parties that are included in the list described in paragraph (1) may appeal such listing.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id772db3ab3ea842d3bafed14e7cd1967e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Deadline for determination</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue a determination about an appeal not later than 6 months after an appeal has been submitted to the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ad2cb011c95435e81619f917be9244b"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Limitation on additional appeals</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After a determination of an appeal under subparagraph (B), a third party shall not have another opportunity to appeal a determination under this subsection, unless there was a change in a Presidential administration between the date on which the third party submitted the initial request to appeal under this paragraph and the date on which such appeal determination under subparagraph (B) was made.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id834818fd589847d6908d84ac17dde67e"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Period of time</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b05ce9ef205443583e89521b1cb44c9"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), a third party shall remain on the list described in paragraph (1) for a period of 5 years after the date on which the third party was placed on that list, unless the violation is remediated in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3329a4c676a46118c18171667dba111"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Remediation</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A third party shall be removed from the list described in paragraph (1) when the Secretary determines that the third party is no longer in violation of the requirements of subsection (m) of section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(m)</external-xref>, commonly referred to as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>), as added by section 7. The third party shall be removed from the list not later than 1 week after the date of such a determination.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="ida548dfc531d542728c4f4366659bc240"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Effective Date</header> <text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> </section> <section id="idc9c8754bb3e845739fbbed62556c6c34"> <enum>8.</enum> <header>Support for reviewing educational technology</header> <subsection id="id4e0dc22cb6ef4199bf26cf7c4b72ab34"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Privacy technical assistance center</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d42560c0af04a2a9acfe2a2dac67f91"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Center established</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish and maintain a privacy technical assistance center (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>), to build the capacity of educational agencies and institutions, State educational agencies, and other entities, including education technology providers, to protect the privacy of students, families, educators, and other school professionals.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ad63c92420548a990f4e52f3f98c655"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Covered requirements</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall help such agencies, institutions, and other entities understand and satisfy their responsibilities under Federal privacy laws, including section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>, commonly referred to as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) and section 445 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232h">20 U.S.C. 1232h</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>Protection of Pupil Rights Amendment</quote>), and other Federal privacy laws applicable to education records and other confidential data, which are collectively referred to in this section as <quote>covered requirements</quote>.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="id89772ebd473745e6b0f0ff5b17ca8099"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Safe harbor provision</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a1e615574c042edba083383f797f8f1"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the purpose described in subsection (a), the Center may approve 1 or more voluntary safe harbor programs that meet the criteria described in paragraph (2) (referred to in this section as an <quote>approved program</quote>) that are operated by an independent organization. Such approved programs may provide safe harbor benefits described in paragraph (4) for providers of educational technology that elect to participate in an approved program for the purpose of ensuring compliance with this Act and the covered requirements.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id7bf111c1891843fb8e9637fb8c219e70"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Criteria for approval</header> <text>To be an approved program, an organization shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id6476fe1fb867452f895a956c6f7ab3d2"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>provide standards and controls that are at least as protective of student privacy, parental rights, and data security as the covered requirements;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="idabb3798745ce4d409df6cf57157d5943"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>include mechanisms for initial certification, ongoing monitoring, and periodic independent assessments of participants;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id1bccd8ebe21749ec90652a81b75fc4ed"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>require timely consumer- and school-facing remedies, including clear notice, accessible consent and opt-out pathways, and data minimization, retention, and security practices;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id64e059774d7b47e49a06c15b7164c08b"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>establish a process to receive, investigate, and resolve complaints from parents, eligible students, schools, and State educational agencies; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idcdad5af96b6a4cbab700a3ee07f801b9"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>provide for meaningful disciplinary measures, including suspension or termination from the approved program, for material noncompliance.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idc4ce3ff18086419282c24bd7f02fd538"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Application and approval</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a3674e2c19845daa1bed3f96bd6db63"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In General</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator of a prospective approved program shall submit to the Center an application describing how the program satisfies the requirements described in paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbce3f58720414e95b569fe36c8b45e39"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Time for approval</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall approve or deny such an application not later than 180 days after receipt of the application.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id405ec3520dcd428694d8e68ac47b610c"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Publication of criteria and decisions</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall publish approval criteria and approval decisions relating to approved programs and prospective approved programs on a public website.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5ac2ba1bee24af68a1ff28955bc5e82"> <enum>(D)</enum> <header>Conditions</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center may condition approval of a prospective approved program on modifications necessary to establish that participating providers of educational technology ensure parity with, or greater protection than, the covered requirements.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id3cfee17d8a964066bf67c86aa3b32288"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Effect of safe harbor</header> <text>Subject to paragraph (6), a provider of educational technology that is a participant in good standing in an approved program and in material compliance with that program’s requirements shall be presumed to satisfy the covered requirements with respect to the practices subject to that approved program, unless the Center determines, after notice and an opportunity to respond, that the approved program or participating provider of educational technology is materially deficient.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id773a98db05ea4d72a248ab2bde102c7f"> <enum>(5)</enum> <header>Maintenance of approved programs</header> <text>The Center may revoke or suspend an approved program’s approval upon a finding, after notice and opportunity to respond, that the program no longer satisfies the requirements of paragraph (2). Revocation or suspension shall be prospective and shall include reasonable wind-down provisions for participants. The Center shall provide written notice to the approved program not less than 30 days before revoking or suspending an approved program.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idd1c8ca44652b4684919cdfe2d1fa5c2e"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>No limitation on enforcement</header> <text>Participation by a provider of educational technology in an approved program shall not preclude the Secretary from enforcing this Act or the covered requirements. Participation and material compliance with an approved program shall be an affirmative defense to alleged violations of the covered requirements with respect to the practices subject to that approved program.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id6fd20be4a9f74585aab35138781e8245"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Rule of construction</header> <text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to create a private right of action.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="id02066f52ddbd4b85b36e26e27c7d4f11"> <enum>9.</enum> <header>Supporting AI integration in K–12 classrooms</header> 
<subsection id="id2ca19da21a304c088701c43fb7ece76f"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Technology training resources</header> <text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Institute of Education Sciences, shall develop resources and training guides for elementary school and secondary school teachers on integrating artificial intelligence technologies into instruction, including methods of use that protect student data privacy.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="id0e94349ff5fa423a9eef9d55e844d7ca"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>ESEA Amendment</header> <text>Clause (i) of section 2103(b)(3)(E) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 6613 (b)(3)(E)) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51dc12bcc00248a8ac146f8c689dc02b"> 
<clause id="id00afba9f059442c898f6860caeb7deaf"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>effectively integrate existing and emerging technology into curricula and instruction (including education about how to use artificial intelligence to enhance personalized learning, in addition to the harms of copyright piracy and improper student use of artificial intelligence);</text> </clause> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> </section> <section id="id7ce130a821394fe29a6c95348e16c89d"> <enum>10.</enum> <header>Improving personalized learning</header> <subsection id="id813b75b082494860bf5cc0ed2c4bf422"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>AI in education priority</header> <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, in carrying out the activities of the Small Business Innovation Research Program (as defined in section 9(e) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6389">15 U.S.C. 6389(e)</external-xref>)), referred to in this section as the <quote>SBIR program</quote>, the Secretary shall prioritize educational artificial intelligence research and development to foster innovation in personalized learning technologies, in accordance with subsection (b).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="id2b7c6822b1a64fb89ed420206a031d26"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Criteria for prioritization</header> <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, in awarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under the SBIR program, the Secretary shall give priority to proposals that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dbacaacf1794e38b2cda91bd6a9378c"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to incorporate artificial intelligence into education without reducing or inhibiting students’ critical thinking skills; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7b24e9a26ec41668d3acac948aaf520"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet 2 or more of the following criteria:</text> <subparagraph id="id1f3a22e2dad5411eb7613a0f1fc9ff3c"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>Projects that demonstrate the potential to significantly enhance personalized learning experiences by adapting to individual student needs, improving student achievement, and addressing learning gaps.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id110e386782564d1582712b083d931d8b"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>Projects that aim to make artificial intelligence technologies accessible to all students, including students with special education needs.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id984461d60c63470babe8fd7136210c0f"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>Projects that incorporate cutting-edge computational techniques to create innovative tutoring solutions.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="id129486eab8bd4856b84ed5f250114a13"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>Projects that demonstrate a clear strategy for integrating artificial intelligence into classroom settings for efficiency and personalized learning, including training resources for teachers and administrators and compatibility with existing educational tools and curricula.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

