<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H723C26D1B12A453F8711EC9494DC9370" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8075 IH: To authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to direct the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and the National Credit Union Administration to establish emergency transaction account guarantee programs, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8075</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to direct the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and the National Credit Union Administration to establish emergency transaction account guarantee programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCDA1BD47B2BF4108AD538D269F16A9FE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA39235AD72F944CE8408669CF96BD4D2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Emergency TAG program authority</header> 
<subsection id="HB3360A56FC9B4A48A19722AA0A5CFF45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Insured depository institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1823">12 U.S.C. 1823</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6A727D0B5BC740D8992F331A93DCB619" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H5FD40CD7AD9E46F4A477DDCBAE1FE95E"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Emergency TAG program authority</header> <paragraph id="HE94FC6217FC44530A3D0F585DC471DD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After a determination by the Secretary of the Treasury under paragraph (2), and subject to the limits in paragraph (3), the Board of Directors may establish an emergency transaction account guarantee program under which the Corporation fully insures the deposits of all insured depository institutions that are maintained in non-interest-bearing transaction accounts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CFF3E783BD641B9B30569CA5F67A792"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Banking stress event determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Directors may establish a program under paragraph (1) only if—</text> <subparagraph id="HFEC3A45356104FC3B11397CF1EC90BF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the President, determines that—</text> 
<clause id="H0B08B4C14B034EA4A84158FDA1EFEE08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a banking stress event exists that presents serious adverse effects on economic conditions or the stability of the banking system; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF2BDD8635A894A1C86B124F4E5B2CF76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use of the program authorized under this subsection would avoid or mitigate such adverse effects; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7440F0DCFAFE4A47BBD42D24AD5254A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Treasury gives immediate notice of such determination to the Board of Directors and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07FF1D42438A4F24B348A123E08CC966"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program limitations</header> <subparagraph id="HCDAE7E0781E3468286F10F10A028F042"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation on size</header> <clause id="H3BA083C2C28043FD85461A350768C41F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the Corporation insures any deposits pursuant to a program established under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury shall, in consultation with the President, determine the maximum amount of costs that the Deposit Insurance Fund may incur under the program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0927843C553D4C8B9D8510D248F219C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Increase</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), the maximum amount of costs for a program established under paragraph (1) may be increased, if—</text> <subclause id="H2ABF9A8B5B5C425F8AFB61178977A52E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such increase is approved in the same manner as a program established under paragraph (1); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB2E79815BDAE4E0A9A892A0AE34BA55E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury issues a report to the Congress containing data and analysis justifying the increase.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43F48228C5AA44EA8F33D980E3515F6E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on duration</header> <clause id="H90556FC64D414D89B67870BAD237CA8F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation shall terminate each program established under paragraph (1) no later than the date that is 6 months after the date of commencement of the program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA1BDF7CFA2F3451D980B7C31E06188C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), the termination date for a program established under paragraph (1) may be extended one time for an additional 3-month period, if—</text> <subclause id="H7629AA4C0DD642AA9E0712BD57DF0A3E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such extension is approved in the same manner as a program established under paragraph (1); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H741CA9A036874E3A932EC6C528CAB461"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Treasury issues a report to the Congress containing data and analysis justifying the extension.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2973DBAED26447C88CA10F16ECBCC3C7"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Testimony to Congress</header> <text>Not later than 30 days after a program is established under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury shall testify before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate with respect to the program.</text>
                                                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H482D63995E0C4B4DAF07B7BA5D56C39B">
                                                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                                                  <header>GAO review</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the termination of a program established under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall review the program and issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out such review.</text>
                                                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95CE5037F6234886B6B7DABED3E53C39"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Repayment of loss</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA436487DFD404D05843EF4BACEF1FD77"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation shall recover any loss to the Deposit Insurance Fund arising from any program established under paragraph (1) from 1 or more special assessments on insured depository institutions, depository institution holding companies (except that a special assessment on a depository institution holding company shall require the concurrence of the Secretary of the Treasury), or both, as the Corporation determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A6FA0844FE1470096CE5619DA4B1361"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of application</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, sections 7(c)(2) and 18(h) shall apply to depository institution holding companies as if they were insured depository institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE154636E4B574B8189B914CFAB2CCDB0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation may issue such rules as the Corporation determines to be appropriate to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H371A911A892442B88A56C7E770FF2344"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0B1EB957602B48DBABCBBA952761D9CF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Banking stress event</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>banking stress event</quote> means an exceptional and broad reduction in the stability of deposits at insured depository institutions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BF42F2E87EB412792FBF664866EE89A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Non-interest-bearing transaction account</header><text>The term <quote>non-interest-bearing transaction account</quote> means a transaction account that—</text> 
<clause id="H584120125A24495E8B9548E752239270">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is non-interest-bearing; or</text>
                                </clause> 
<clause id="HC3ACCFAA75B64081909542AAF193F214"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pays a de minimis amount of interest, as established by the Corporation.</text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3524AF7FD9BD493CA279C8BC5550B86B"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Transaction account</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>transaction account</quote> means a deposit or account from which the depositor or account holder is permitted to make transfers or withdrawals by negotiable or transferable instrument, payment order of withdrawal, telephone transfer, or other similar device for the purpose of making payments or transfers to third persons or others or from which the depositor or account holder may make third-party payments at an automated teller machine or a remote service unit, or other electronic device, including by debit card, and includes such other deposits or accounts maintained at an insured depository institution that the Corporation may determine consistent with this definition.</text>
                            </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H590FEBD685074AAE9CC12E31D34C8604"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Insured credit unions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 207(k) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1787">12 U.S.C. 1787(k)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H443F4D4393FE4EE88C5897E0D4E91AB5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HCD81482399044ED6AB3CB6E41918FABB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Emergency TAG program authority</header> <subparagraph id="HD2B1EEB7597D499998C570649DDFC7E9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After a determination by the Secretary of the Treasury under subparagraph (B), and subject to the limits in subparagraph (C), the Board may establish an emergency transaction account guarantee program under which the Administration fully insures the deposits and shares of all insured credit unions that are maintained in non-interest-bearing transaction accounts.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD704C8D5CF44A92BFFD2333BC50142C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Credit union stress event determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may establish a program under subparagraph (A) only if—</text> <clause id="H6742FD6C99504141ACE0F6134F6315E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the President, determines that—</text> 
<subclause id="H8637DBDC73E946428105B693E1743532"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a credit union stress event exists that presents serious adverse effects on economic conditions or the stability of the credit union system; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC24CF56C21C94EADA0D74A1AECE3F3CF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>use of the program authorized under this subsection would avoid or mitigate such adverse effects; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H7BBA2FFE60F640D0B7843D9702B84F52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Treasury gives immediate notice of such determination to the Board and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64440009EE66451BA6BD26C994FBBAA1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Program limitations</header> <clause id="HB7E01DFFB4034D2CAAE5584E1B104721"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation on size</header> <subclause id="HDEDE7368BE034E8CA0FDABE42579D940"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the Board insures any deposits or shares pursuant to a program established under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of the Treasury shall, in consultation with the President, determine the maximum amount of costs that the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund may incur under the program.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H41C057BE8CAE419AB224619EF4AD427B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Increase</header><text>Notwithstanding subclause (I), the maximum amount of costs for a program established under subparagraph (A) may be increased, if—</text> <item id="HEEC9776FD0C949A6A37F75D4B4F2AC76"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>such increase is approved in the same manner as a program established under subparagraph (A); and</text></item> 
<item id="H53B68269E09445CC838687B51F06E84B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury issues a report to the Congress containing data and analysis justifying the increase.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HCFAF2D96DFC24A7483E4624706B09469"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on duration</header> <subclause id="HAB83957905494EC8AE4574B68578C4C2"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall terminate each program the Board establishes under subparagraph (A) no later than the date that is 6 months after the date of commencement of the program.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8E57408402BB46899483740F933831EC"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>Notwithstanding subclause (I), the termination date for a program established under subparagraph (A) may be extended one time for an additional 3-month period, if—</text> <item id="H07605019C9B94749B4EF7A7544E3200B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>such extension is approved in the same manner as a program established under subparagraph (A); and</text></item> 
<item id="H69034890583E411A95AAF2633016B817"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Treasury issues a report to the Congress containing data and analysis justifying the extension.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1F7BE0CF95D4FB8A355DBFC043ACFEC"> <enum>(D)</enum> <header>Testimony to Congress</header> <text>Not later than 30 days after a program is established under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of the Treasury shall testify before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate with respect to the program.</text>
                                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97306BE420E24D238F0B1D31A9BB0C6A">
                                                  <enum>(E)</enum>
                                                  <header>GAO review</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the termination of a program established under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall review the program and issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out such review.</text>
                                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB192C78AAD147B893B7F46D3070CF88"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Repayment of loss</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall recover any loss to the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund arising from any program established under subparagraph (A) from 1 or more special assessments on insured credit unions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65F38FE8A9524257BCFFCFF78565FEE3"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may issue such rules as the Board determines to be appropriate to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D5EF408621344549DF94A6173D7898F"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H9DB3E429A9484D1489BCCF57142E541C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Credit union stress event</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>credit union stress event</quote> means an exceptional and broad reduction in the stability of shares and deposits at insured credit unions.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC1557473DDFC48EDBDEAA7F71BF37355"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Non-interest-bearing transaction account</header><text>The term <quote>non-interest-bearing transaction account</quote> means a transaction account that—</text> <subclause id="HFB6C9CA170044DE7B881921DC318B768"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not pay a dividend; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDB401A6D899A48A39999F10656F67AC5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>pays a de minimis dividend, as established by the Board.</text></subclause> </clause> <clause id="H5DE234A8D4B94F2AB85FBB696903B17D"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <header>Transaction account</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>transaction account</quote> means a deposit, share, or account from which the depositor or account holder is permitted to make transfers or withdrawals by negotiable or transferable instrument, payment order of withdrawal, telephone transfer, or other similar device for the purpose of making payments or transfers to third persons or others or from which the depositor or account holder may make third-party payments at an automated teller machine or a remote service unit, or other electronic device, including by debit card, and includes such other deposits or accounts maintained at an insured credit union that the Board may determine consistent with this definition.</text>
                            </clause></subparagraph> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

