<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA40E8AA0B2AB49DFA788DAB64660E759" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6696 IH: Restoring American Mineral Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of a Critical Minerals Security Alliance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC76DDD673804F1F99EA60F666609FBC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8CE54DA30BDE454C95EED699B1FA6E85" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring American Mineral Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF13858B9BE044F2388542F8CABE4BB57"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H51031C1035EA4228BCF244F023D6F3E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a reliable supply chain of critical minerals is essential to meet the defense, manufacturing, and energy needs of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0BB454A4A284D8ABE81977D86F37A18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as of the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States is heavily dependent on the People’s Republic of China for the production and processing of many key critical minerals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEEAA618FF4D4B4ABB0B018AE38C8516"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China has displayed a willingness to weaponize its dominance of critical mineral production and has intentionally created overcapacity and sold products at below-market rates in order to gain market share and move up the value chain;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EE01DD7D5D34AAD8D717DE70A84AA6F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States must use trade tools to combat those non-market policies and practices, and the use of trade tools is most effective when undertaken in coordination with trading partners; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H283BAEEF517F4AB0BD209940C2BC9387"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by building an alliance of trusted trading partners, the United States can combat the oversupply and market manipulation of the People’s Republic of China and promote the growth of a robust domestic United States critical minerals industry.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEB03600C73644CCF801E922E72156B25"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3EFCFF79AF674981B79970F0E70E2C05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HE19F1D7A8E9B4A529198B2A2FFC07D2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEAD2807CF66D4B0285816D638176A144"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7105B23C7914460997415B563238650A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term> means any mineral on the list of critical minerals required by paragraph (3) of section 7002(c) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E5B9767A4F248929260A2A0E5533763"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Derivative product</header><text>The term <term>derivative product</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3F22868D1AFF4D7DBEF7B2B88A788302"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a good that incorporates a critical mineral; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0B0A175D5F544908B7BCDF063A37BC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> <clause id="H848026A27AB64EC78101510E26CEE12C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a semi-finished good, such as a semiconductor wafer, anode, or cathode; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD8D3A370E6B7480FADD829207046D30A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a final product, such as a permanent magnet, motor, electric vehicle, battery, smartphone, microprocessor, radar system, wind turbine or a component of a wind turbine, or advanced optical device.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0588524890C4D50A0D6F78D61EE7FAF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Excluded duty</header><text>The term <term>excluded duty</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H100816C9F6B54FD3A80D93CDC74E1A74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>antidumping and countervailing duties imposed under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1671">19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE91F427ACC754790ADDFBCFDC52D734D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>duties, quotas, and tariff-rate quotas imposed under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2251">19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA857BC42C5C64F81949E42B6D7515341" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>duties imposed consistent with a ruling authorizing the suspension of benefits or concessions on the part of the United States, issued by—</text> <clause id="H956D3621A0F04FFC813491329E2FD1BB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a dispute settlement panel constituted under a bilateral or plurilateral free trade agreement for which explicit congressional approval pursuant to the requirements of section 151 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2191">19 U.S.C. 2191</external-xref>) has been enacted before the date of the enactment of this Act, before which the United States is a party; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD56B63CDEB5F4F689EFBAEB56494BC90" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a dispute settlement panel described in section 123 of the Uruguay Rounds Agreement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3533">19 U.S.C. 3533</external-xref>) before which the United States is a party.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69321141A6D441C7BA56437F5195F5BE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign country of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign country of concern</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H48B7658DBE504D14B39809812E0D9782"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given that term in section 9901 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4651">15 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F75283B312841AA8599202BB5466C8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9541F403C25A4CC68868F5273A581229"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given that term in section 9901 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4651">15 U.S.C. 4651</external-xref>), except that subparagraph (C) of that section shall be applied and administered by substituting <quote>a foreign country of concern</quote> for <quote>a foreign country</quote> and all that follows through <quote>title 10, United States Code</quote>.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC38CA11A980D47AA8F2D11AD3CC8344A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Processed</header><text>The term <term>processed</term>, with respect to a critical mineral, means the mineral has undergone the activities that occur after critical mineral ore is extracted from a mine up through its conversion into a metal, metal powder, or a master alloy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F85188235914DF1836FBF7E59E7CF1D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Select derivative product</header><text>The term <term>select derivative product</term> means a permanent magnet, a lithium-ion battery for an electrical vehicle, a lithium-ion battery for a vehicle that is not an electrical vehicle, or a part for a battery that is not a lithium-ion battery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35AC5E445FA74275AC37982015BD810F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Trade Representative</header><text>The term <term>Trade Representative</term> means the United States Trade Representative.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB5894AFCA8534E2EAAE3F5CB94FDE7CA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Critical Minerals Security Alliance</header> 
<subsection id="H659E7D4B8BB64655A703CA3455D09542"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization for negotiations</header> 
<paragraph id="H66B0D01CEFF44E18A5F58A53CDD99F29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Trade Representative may enter into negotiations with countries to enter into an alliance, to be known as the <quote>Critical Minerals Security Alliance</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Alliance</quote>), to establish a reliable supply chain of critical minerals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C39B7FD0D994CCB97A8A639E82487B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>While conducting negotiations pursuant to paragraph (1), the Trade Representative shall consult with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of State, and the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7A2B7489415456AB55A4241BD4DFB39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility criteria</header><text>A country is eligible to enter into the Alliance if the government of the country—</text> <paragraph id="HEC8AF88204774D13B65F3A96D79B464F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>either—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H483919328ADA481AA058710F9538E77E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increases the rates of duty the country charges for mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products sourced from foreign countries of concern to rates that are not less than the rates of duty for mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products, respectively, sourced from the People’s Republic of China imposed by the United States pursuant to section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>) and in effect on January 1, 2026;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DDC405EE3BE48DE8C46DB6BEDA0795A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agrees to increase the rates of duty described in subparagraph (A) to the rates required in such subparagraph over a period of not more than 5 years; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6D0BAE384A14D6DB0F87902246107CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopts measures comparable to, or greater in effect than, the trade remedies available under title III of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411 et seq.</external-xref>), such as prohibitions or quotas on the importation into the country of mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products sourced from foreign countries of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18F0C9400B9642A79F3B9A0DC72E09A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agrees to meet and participate in regular meetings of the Alliance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB848163BDBC4C459BF1FF2C5EDF3117"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commits to continually review the capacity of the country to extract and process critical minerals and share the results of those reviews with other countries that are members of the Alliance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H435A66F535CC41BFB911C39BC9208429"><enum>(4)</enum><text>eliminates duties on imports of mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products from countries that are members of the Alliance, other than excluded duties;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DB9251A7DCB4513962C04B25653A8D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>takes actions that are complementary to the actions of the United States to address unfair trade policies of a country that is not a member of the Alliance, including actions—</text> <subparagraph id="H48E5A4510CBA490DA6F55D8BC3156781"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address the potential illicit shipment of critical minerals and derivative products, specifically transshipment that is intended to circumvent duties, evade customs enforcement, or obfuscate the origin of products produced in whole or in part with forced labor;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1556AB1FB54452A88C3570D3843579F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to establish or maintain robust investment screening mechanisms, including to screen investments in entities that produce critical minerals and derivative products, that are at least as effective as the national security reviews and investigations required under section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF2C7CD759984FB9815DDD6DC80663D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to ensure effective trade remedies against imports of critical minerals and derivative products sourced from a foreign country of concern or a foreign entity of concern;</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5997B11E38E44A748F2068531CB0914E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">works with the United States to establish a mechanism to address shared threats to members of the Alliance from investments by foreign countries of concern;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6195838ED64B43B4A2B97D3545B0CF3A"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engages in discussions with the United States regarding trade and ways to promote and protect the economic security of the Alliance in sectors other than critical minerals; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D3B71A116CD443BA68ACA1E9B2ED7BB"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinates with the United States to enact or maintain policies to impose rates of duty as specified in paragraph (1)(A) on mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products that are sourced from foreign entities of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3E889C6424044ADF8EBECDCAD44D2DC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Engagement</header><text>The Trade Representative shall engage with countries that trade with the United States of the United States and encourage such countries to take the measures necessary to comply with the eligibility criteria described in subsection (b).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HED5949172C03486DBB668B8DD8ED4F8C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certifications of eligibility</header> 
<paragraph id="H40EACB01D9F9403B9A1F05C2271C506F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Trade Representative determines that a country complies with the eligibility criteria described in subsection (b), the Trade Representative shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text> <subparagraph id="H97117D84B2F74DCE9474D2F91F1E7806" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a certification that the country is eligible for admittance into the Alliance; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA5CE5B15A89746358EF63181504DE822" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a report describing—</text> <clause id="H83FB27425887473B858AB0637409FF22" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the compliance of such country with respect to the eligibility criteria described in subsection (b); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9AC5E9F2E9B34DDFB826CAB9AF5EF5D2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the critical minerals sector of such country.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45972A5C24CF4B6FAC2139368FB4D71B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The submission of a certification under paragraph (1) with respect to a country shall be considered notice of the intention of the Trade Representative to enter into an agreement providing for the admittance of the country in the Alliance for purposes of subsection (i).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF782E242BBCA4749BB6F313F49FA9B30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Negotiating objectives</header><text>In conducting negotiations under subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall seek to establish a reliable supply chain for—</text> <paragraph id="HE57680F55888499D82C24F5EB101A625"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 90 percent of the critical minerals on the list required by section 7002(c)(1) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)(1)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF73F7EDFC5C4F649623EEC7E7D73E12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>100 percent of select derivative products.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H791B8A8A33DF47ACA0D312332BF6D3EF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Entry into force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agreement providing for the admittance of a country into the Alliance may enter into force if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H44123C6628584FB7B4EE7D8430772CCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law under subsection (i) after the submission of a certification that the country is eligible for admittance into the Alliance under subsection (d); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC8D8C72C53A451F980B361758029215"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a period of 90 days has elapsed after the submission of a certification that the country is eligible for admittance into the Alliance under subsection (d) and a joint resolution of disapproval is not enacted into law under subsection (i) during that 90-day period.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E070C8982F244C2A018ED90BEDFA282">
        <enum>(g)</enum>
        <header>Duty-Free treatment after entry into force</header>
 <text>Upon the entry into force of an agreement providing for the admittance of a country into the Alliance, mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products imported from the country shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="HA3EE82680B6F44E5A5CF2EF7C1E628AA">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>enter the United States free of duty, except for excluded duties; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H78665BADE2B147D0940F59E02CF48594"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>be exempt from any duties imposed under section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>) or section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>) on or after the date of entry into force of the agreement.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9D1EA2D25F84FF79CEB30265360CB58"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Modifications to agreements</header><text>A modification to an agreement providing for the admittance of a country into the Alliance shall take effect if—</text> <paragraph id="H855192ABFEFB4690A8A1352764255F2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Trade Representative submits to the appropriate congressional committees notice of the intention of the Trade Representative to agree to the modification; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7278FD7888BF44B9A1474652727871C6"><enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HE8099A10EBC84687A36A0850EB0FA859" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law under subsection (i) after the submission of that notice; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7C135AD26A042F298ADDBF68BBBAD91" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a period of 90 days has elapsed after the submission of that notice and a joint resolution of disapproval is not enacted into law under subsection (i) during that 90-day period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAAA2F5EA937B4EC5AAB346E04AC5BA8D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Joint resolutions</header> 
<paragraph id="H30CA8BFAA8F248DC8B3C54DCB49C415B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HEDD30F52D70E4027A36C96F87FD7CCAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered action</header><text>The term <term>covered action</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="HF802480E82844D5893213CE5477D0D4D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the entry into an agreement providing for the admittance of a country into the Alliance; or</text></clause> <clause id="H119BADB0A70A42B99B506E824E36D65C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a modification to such an agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1EF51058F464A499A71027C34E38C3C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered joint resolution</header><text>The term <term>covered joint resolution</term> means a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC3AC36EF0E04486A6902AC07846869C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval</header><text>The term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means a joint resolution the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>That Congress approves the covered action relating to ___, notice of which was submitted to Congress on __ under section 4 of the Restoring American Mineral Security Act of 2025.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with a brief description of the covered action and the second blank space being filled with the appropriate date.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF01E0D4B62FA4F05B87F94F8FD8A02CE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>The term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means a joint resolution the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>That Congress does not approve the covered action relating to ___, notice of which was submitted to Congress on __ under section 4 of the Restoring American Mineral Security Act of 2025.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with a brief description of the covered action and the second blank space being filled with the appropriate date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC87240C6ECA54EA183193B70A801963A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>A covered joint resolution may be introduced in the Senate or the House of Representatives by any Member of the Senate or the House, respectively.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H805AC60C2C32418182C8737C4E652E92"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The provisions of subsections (b) through (f) of section 152 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2192">19 U.S.C. 2192</external-xref>) shall apply to a covered joint resolution to the same extent and in the same manner as such subsections apply to resolutions described in such section 152.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82726D19E3334004B914CEA16A41E693"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules of Senate and House of Representatives</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCD739A5F92214942B48745AE1117003C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution under this subsection, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H091C9C11AE784CF79C1C14D0F20ADF92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0010F7E3C8B54CF8A7D212283BA9F1CC"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reviews by United States</header> 
<paragraph id="HFCD2E76F1218426F9F1C3DD5FF4DABFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the entry into force of the first agreement providing for the admittance of a country into the Alliance, and every 3 years thereafter while the Alliance remains in effect, the Trade Representative, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies and appropriate congressional committees, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D7143460D1349CAB2A9A68E05B5C5CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the capacity of the United States to extract and process critical minerals to determine whether it is appropriate to terminate or modify the Alliance; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H828067A49F19405A8FD08D5D50CC61C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if commercially significant quantities of a critical mineral are produced in the United States, consider seeking the removal of that critical mineral from the products covered by the Alliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D37C886641B449B96F7389EF86594D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>First review</header><text>As part of the first review conducted under paragraph (1), the Trade Representative shall assess the feasibility and advisability of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8623C88856D748D2AF9AA1CBBCA93DD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expanding the scope of products covered by the Alliance to include derivative products; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC1A36C49F9744D5B2C9B99E4528D096"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise expanding or restricting the scope of products covered by the Alliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H126F9279EE664A3A86ACE9D09F219A36"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review of duty rates</header><text>As part of each review conducted under paragraph (1), the Trade Representative shall assess whether countries that are members of the Alliance should adjust the rates of duty imposed on mined and processed critical minerals that are sourced from foreign countries of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H47970B16D25944CB9F86449B771BE2BE"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Trade Representative shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4E7ED8B99E194D5185EC1E6A09890B7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of engagement with countries that trade with the United States under subsection (c);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA7D5BD463064EF69512F22BFC44D233"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each trading partner that the Trade Representative determines does not meet the criteria eligibility criteria under subsection (b), a detailed description of the deficiencies of the government of the country in complying with the criteria; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C9B5738DA5C4420AEBFAA49D9827739"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the information provided by countries that are members of the Alliance with respect to the capacities of such countries to extract and process critical minerals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HBEB66F94A3254048AF6291EFE95C6954"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increase in duties on imports of mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products from foreign countries of concern</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon the entry into force of the first agreement providing for the admittance of a country into the Critical Minerals Security Alliance under section 4, mined and processed critical minerals and select derivative products imported into the United States and sourced from a foreign country of concern shall be subject to the rate of duty in effect on January 1, 2026, and applicable to such products sourced from the People’s Republic of China pursuant to section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section id="H8C37373DB6704245AE6E76207A9AE057"><enum>6.</enum><header>Trust fund to support United States critical mineral mining and processing projects</header> 
<subsection id="HC0063B7819DA4A3C82DB19D0921D043A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of trust fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund, consisting of—</text> <paragraph id="H972B3866160B480489A677019DE9C6BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amounts transferred to the trust fund under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B108E1B148442C38BDCD96404F9299E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amounts that may be credited to the trust fund under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE60463B0886641C6BDE0B2ADC8C57476"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of amounts</header> <paragraph id="H75D92F931199464EB3FDAAD891D4902D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the first fiscal year in which a country has been admitted to the Critical Minerals Security Alliance under section 4 and each fiscal year thereafter during which any foreign country is a member of such Alliance, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the trust fund established under subsection (a), from the general fund of the Treasury, an amount equivalent to the amount received into the general fund during that fiscal year and attributable to duties collected on mined and processed critical minerals imported into the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2395901E119426DAF456375D29AABBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frequency of transfers</header><text>The Secretary shall transfer amounts required by paragraph (1) to the trust fund established under subsection (a) not less frequently than quarterly.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC897D80890674F0F811F73C968F00FF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investment of amounts</header> <paragraph id="HAE5888B8C01543EEB323B81A18320EA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investment of amounts</header><text>The Secretary shall invest such portion of the trust fund established under subsection (a) as is not required to meet current withdrawals in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA71E9EAC65F64735B1F33BA825842303"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interest and proceeds</header><text>The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the trust fund established under subsection (a) shall be credited to and form a part of the trust fund.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3F471A33D93D48B08CE9DABABB685578"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of amounts in trust fund</header> <paragraph id="H98FBDC310A6141C7AB173BD85967EEAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts in the trust fund established under subsection (a) shall be available, without further appropriation, as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC442985DB0C0441397EFB173E6AD3F1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>60 percent of such amounts shall be available to the Loan Programs Office of the Department of Energy for activities to support projects relating to—</text> <clause id="H12791AF4100844119C4C3F5857D2A4EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mining or processing critical minerals; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5D8B099E8C3A4F1C8EAB416FCA755BE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manufacturing of select derivative products.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44D38390F935478FB363BB1963535644"><enum>(B)</enum><text>20 percent of such amounts shall be available to the Department of Defense for activities to support projects relating to—</text> 
<clause id="H890BF16528EF4A579887DC938C043DC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mining or processing critical minerals; or</text></clause> <clause id="HFB8F55A8AACB42FEAA327F0142E57DC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manufacturing of select derivative products.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF0E0CB1CD6445DCA345BD74FC5CA49D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>20 percent of such amounts shall be available to the United States International Development Finance Corporation to support international critical mineral projects in countries that are members of the Alliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8DBB84B2320495C963F3A88FEA08E42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude a person from seeking support for a project under both subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF6DEB4927DDF46AFBB2F6900C01A81D3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception from certain limitation under Build Act of 2018</header> 
<paragraph id="H9F3133A1DDFB4794B16BBF87042217A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of providing support for projects under subsection (d)(1)(C)—</text> <subparagraph id="H8C5CECA86B8F4D09924CB6A16C166B01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation may provide support for projects in countries with upper-middle-income economies or high-income economies (as those terms are defined by the World Bank);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC054553754AE4286826296A398DAACF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the restriction under section 1412(c)(2) of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9612">22 U.S.C. 9612(c)(2)</external-xref>) shall not apply; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA34E096D2D24D6E867BB8F0421A3CE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Corporation shall restrict the provision of such support in a country described in subparagraph (A) unless the President certifies to the appropriate committees of Congress that—</text> 
<clause id="HD76CD013C4FE45479493A5E98B23B52C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such support furthers the national economic or foreign policy interests of the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H1429E5B6A14348CAB3972014549B2613"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such support is—</text> 
<subclause id="H2ADB98BE08284F8E9C6BEFAF9F984D54"><enum>(I)</enum><text>designed to produce significant developmental outcomes or provide developmental benefits to the poorest population of that country; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H24493B43433B424981715AE1CEFCB697"><enum>(II)</enum><text>necessary to preempt or counter efforts by a strategic competitor of the United States to secure significant political or economic leverage or acquire national security-sensitive technologies or infrastructure in a country that is an ally or partner of the United States; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H095F805779B84CECAFA87D5E23208C8E"><enum>(iii)</enum> 
<subclause id="H4F1500FDDEA9404680919E3FD72676BC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a United States entity is participating in the project for which the support is provided; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCFE4026180074FECB9581D0FAA4CDDF3" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not less than 50 percent of the critical minerals produced by the project will be offered for sale to the Department of Defense and United States entities before being offered for sale to other entities.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D18FCF180A443B3A9A684AB50D5EF3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HCC2044CC9A804F3190F71DFE75FE9978"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H27F66787F104443ABBD6F14B03BE7404"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA87B880D8426426BBFED2323B0EE2CA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1EB9F16FF1A48349E9D1909F899FEA0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Less developed country</header><text>The term <term>less developed country</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1402 of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9601">22 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59375F6C32FC4319ACE774644A8FDF2F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>United states entity</header><text>The term <term>United States entity</term> means an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

