<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77A354F59DFD471980ECEF24C5B59FDB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8156 IH: National Parent and Youth Helpline Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8156</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260327">March 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a grant program to support the establishment of a national, toll-free telephone helpline to provide information and assistance to parents, caregivers, and youth to prevent child abuse and strengthen families.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF843EB4B5B164CECAE421EEAE79CAEFF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9EAF0B615EF046FAB76C11A3D5F16B38" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Parent and Youth Helpline Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1CB1052470FE4EDBBED2EBB5C4EAE6CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFEC21639BD941679E228BB52EF475D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There are approximately 174,000,000 parents, caregivers, and youth in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97156855433646749F7331C8E8DDA6B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many parents, caregivers, and youth often do not have an immediate connection to someone who can offer trusted guidance when facing personal challenges.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H780B0B387E15465280C0748CCC0878AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Parents, caregivers, and youth could benefit from an effective helpline that fosters the strengths parents have, which would improve family relationships, as well as community life and society overall to foster the future for American children and families.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54F934AF25AF477F9BBC68B633AEBFDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress recognizes that helpline prevention services will support parents and caregivers in positively addressing child development concerns and responding to child maltreatment, substance misuse, and other personal and family challenges.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29C4149D3EA342D388EF573237F173B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress recognizes that helpline prevention services promote safety and stability by reducing harmful influences and encouraging protective behaviors through weekly, trusted, and stable engagement programs.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H052F1CE9BFEE4B73A1E7D8DEAC58193A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant to establish a national parent and youth helpline</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5101">42 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 103 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HDD8BD65D18C544C1B0B77CACDD928D55" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H851D452B22BA451B9E39B74655998A61"><enum>103A.</enum><header>Grant to establish a national parent and youth helpline</header> 
<subsection id="H657EE899B32F4EE4BD222F5EFCDA4B30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant to one nonprofit entity to—</text> <paragraph id="H03A263357C894F65A5FA34751741DC7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for the establishment and ongoing operation of a national, toll-free telephone parent and youth helpline, as described in subsection (d), to provide personal guidance and trusted assistance to parents, caregivers, and youth to prevent child abuse and strengthen families through calls, texts, and live chats;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3726F9323F8D45C8BF94E0B2299A0B93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>create and maintain a website with vital information and resources for parents, caregivers, and youth to address a broad spectrum of family issues related to emotional, social, behavioral, and educational well-being; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5743AFF9663B48FE977D6B60095BFCE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and implement comprehensive outreach strategies to reach parents, caregivers, and youth nationwide.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3484FE7DAD9D4744ABFB000288607663"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding the grant under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an entity—</text> <paragraph id="HACD859FB35B34BDABD3455166B77851C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with experience in operating a national parent and youth helpline that provides guidance and emotional support to parents, caregivers, and youth; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F92AC79F21F49B2958D841669BDF17B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that operates weekly, evidence-based mutual support groups.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAC2C9B3BA6244927A3F30D8C6C865FDD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The grant under this section may be awarded for a period of not more than 5 years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6A2A83EF979D4AA7BFDD6669BDD368E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Helpline activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The entity that receives the grant under this section shall use the grant—</text> <paragraph id="H5023AAF1ED054A8A8F36858641CAA677"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish and operate a 24-hour, national, toll-free telephone helpline to provide (through calls, texts, and live chats)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB2722C2D921341B393AF352E448A89DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emotional support and assistance to parents, caregivers, children, and youth of all ages who are facing personal challenges, including emotional distress, substance abuse, peer relationships, and educational concerns related to their well-being; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE14562C06904056AAB7228DD9AC9D0A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">weekly, trusted mutual support groups held across the country to promote family stability and encourage skills that help strengthen households; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5316A32F8C134978B8F801D77CA80797"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to carry out activities in support of the helpline, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H07CAA00236FC4688AD80EEF05D145C42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implementing comprehensive outreach strategies to reach parents, caregivers, and youth nationwide;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H192C97A1EE804B9C8DB023AC8F326C2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">distributing relevant information and resources to parents, caregivers, and youth; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86C1055828994DC68FDAEE01641F3094"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintaining a website to provide information about the helpline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF4D3B4A4FF24FECBD76AB314E6B9C0C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Performance reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The entity that receives the grant under this section shall submit a performance report to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require. Such performance report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H7704B959C6834165B75CE5F9FB8A13C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the activities carried out with the grant;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECC63E5FE3DD42B0A58B4F67D00A87D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of such activities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB81A7DD56D54A4DADA7175D1B0D9CBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such additional information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H931FF146ECC04BFDBB162DA03A7EF451"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report addressing the implementation and effectiveness of the national parent and youth helpline funded with the grant under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H61B903F7A7584865A6CDE40D44BACD6A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

