<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCA41B29482B84D8A961DE73AA65E3819" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7206 IH: Farm and Family Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7206</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for economic assistance to agricultural producers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H74139EA6CF41433C9AF4D94F1562EDF7" style="OLC"><section id="HC380E1BE24C34D7DB6A4056D46CC17CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Farm and Family Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCAC81984ABC84D36AD1695ED8BB01163" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Economic assistance for families</header><subsection id="H2D568181195D424BB1BC6E8F618399E0"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Benefit cost-Shift delay</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(a)(2)(B) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2013">7 U.S.C. 2013(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                <paragraph id="H233ACA83724D442AA2516E014AF81B8D">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in clause (i) by striking <quote>2028</quote> and inserting <quote>2032</quote>;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6E3B639AE37C415890AC3C123C7AEDCE">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="H00FAD39F4ECA4A4E955488ECE19B7E55"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (I)—</text>
                        <clause id="HBE3DF10BC8EF48F9BEBB8D3AE3414101">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>2028</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>2032</quote>; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H844E90CEA9D64D6A8E5242E586DE84B6">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>2025 or 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>2029 or 2030</quote>; and</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HA4AE55C3074C468FA109BCE9F71F0E3A">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (II) by striking <quote>2029</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>2033</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HCC66D585DBAE4B16B0CC2580BE3D700C">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>by striking clause (iii).</text> </paragraph> </subsection><subsection id="H6FA686A725174F3187B55A6A40ACA8CB"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Administrative cost-Shift delay</header> <text>Section 16(a) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2025">7 U.S.C. 2025(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>through fiscal year 2026, 50 percent, and for fiscal year 2027</quote> and inserting <quote>through fiscal year 2028, 50 percent, and for fiscal year 2029</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H06C9258CCFF84546B684E3903397DE23"><enum>3.</enum><header>Economic assistance for producers of eligible commodities</header><subsection id="H0F0D9FA15F3D41B89102EF7B66E67433"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H4A5E0A557AC349D0BA21DEFFC7F06340"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Economic assistance payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the 2025 crop year, if the Secretary determines that the expected gross return per acre for an eligible commodity determined under paragraph (2) is less than the expected cost of production per acre for that eligible commodity determined under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, make a 1-time economic assistance payment to each producer of that eligible commodity during that crop year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H977F76EC0B824C72B47B738742348BF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expected gross return per acre</header><text>The expected gross return per acre for an eligible commodity referred to in paragraph (1) shall be equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H59A4436FE8CC4CA6A85E2F46C3F6D6AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, cotton, rice, and soybeans, the product obtained by multiplying—</text><clause id="HCBD0C0B062674215B5601C9B2F2DA264"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the projected average farm price for the applicable eligible commodity for the 2025–2026 marketing year contained in the December 2025 World Agricultural Supply and Demand Estimates published by the World Agricultural Outlook Board on December 9, 2025; and</text></clause><clause id="HD5D4F61D4298444B9C4261907FE48CC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the national average harvested yield per acre for the applicable eligible commodity for the most recent 10 crop years, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4D02D020047418F835DAC00BE948324"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of each eligible commodity not specified in subparagraph (A), a comparable estimate of gross returns, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73052539F82F4AD88F065536B09984E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expected cost of production</header><text>The expected cost of production per acre for an eligible commodity referred to in paragraph (1) shall be equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H8153DC0F6B0B4C5BA65A2C22330AA008"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in the case of wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, cotton, rice, and soybeans, the total costs listed for the 2025 crop year with respect to the applicable eligible commodity contained in the data product relating to such commodity and crop year entitled <quote>U.S. Commodity Costs and Returns by Region and by Commodity</quote> published by the Economic Research Service; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8586F02E322045BAA6BBD78B1234CF34"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Payment amounts</header><subparagraph id="H85620A0370284DADBBCAC64D03DB4D17" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of an economic assistance payment to a producer for an eligible commodity under paragraph (1) shall be equal to the difference between—</text><clause id="H6D97387A59C14A6F910C75FF1BA04245"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount equal to 65 percent of the product obtained by multiplying—</text><subclause id="H5DA231F2EADB42BE84A65CE8A020A68E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the economic loss for that eligible commodity determined under subparagraph (B); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCCD2C8587DC74ECFAC34B1BA98880393"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the eligible acres of that eligible commodity on the farm determined under subparagraph (C); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H13DDD548C9DD43C0B4B7460C542CA10D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of any payment issued by the Secretary to such producer with respect to crop year 2025 for such eligible commodity or such eligible acres on the farm under the Farmer Bridge Assistance Program of the Department of Agriculture as described in the press release of the Department of Agriculture on December 8, 2025 (Release No. 0239.25).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB69B5231955648E49779AFCBC5CCF945"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Economic loss</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the economic loss for an eligible commodity shall be equal to the difference between—</text><clause id="HD21B2B05B3F54F29A9E3D767C373C336"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the expected cost of production per acre for that eligible commodity, as determined under paragraph (3); and</text></clause><clause id="H464C50412C1045FAB1DB4FA3036F6430"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the expected gross return per acre for that eligible commodity, as determined under paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AB48DEF96824D99990EC03512282EB7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible acres</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i)(II), the eligible acres of an eligible commodity on a farm shall be equal to the sum obtained by adding—</text><clause id="H0D9CDC936E874E79A96F3DC042360FEF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the acreage planted on the farm to that eligible commodity for harvest, grazing, haying, silage, or other similar purposes for the 2025 crop year; and</text></clause><clause id="HCD313B441E5742E785FD8F4960F71D52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to 100 percent of the acreage on the farm that was prevented from being planted during the 2025 crop year to that eligible commodity because of drought, flood, or other natural disaster, or other condition beyond the control of the producers on the farm, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85341B77F1714706985D4CA1F224A0A8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Acreage planted</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (C)(i), the Secretary shall consider acreage planted to include any land devoted to planted acres for accepted skip-row planting patterns, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H036CF946286D4C67A75C3E1A077C08C3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Data</header><text>If the Secretary determines there is insufficient data to determine the comparable estimate of gross returns with respect to an eligible commodity under paragraph (2)(B) or a comparable total estimated cost-of-production with respect to an eligible commodity under paragraph (3)(B), the Secretary shall use data related to a similarly situated commodity for purposes of determining the payment amount under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A4B3B6CC9E24CE0A8811BC79B16986E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment limitations</header><paragraph id="H705D025309CB48EC95D9555FF3060389"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), sections 1001, 1001A, 1001B, and 1001C of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1308">7 U.S.C. 1308</external-xref>, 1308–1, 1308–2, 1308–3) shall apply with respect to assistance provided under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5036F89ED9A4442BD7F8D4086EB920A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The total amount of payments received, directly or indirectly, by a person or legal entity (except a joint venture or general partnership) under this section may not exceed—</text><subparagraph id="HFE66F128D6104660ABE4A37650932CBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$125,000, if less than 75 percent of the average gross income of the person or legal entity for the 2021, 2022, and 2023 tax years is derived from farming, ranching, or silviculture activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C70735117104A638657F2AB143638DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$250,000, if not less than 75 percent of the average gross income of the person or legal entity for the 2021, 2022, and 2023 tax years is derived from farming, ranching, or silviculture activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9D6C20DED9541F0AC2A41591F30943E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HAF62AA36E36D48D6A24798977CE9B537"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <term>extra-long staple cotton</term> and <term>producer</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1111 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9011">7 U.S.C. 9011</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46F490BB262F439CA087C9A80B23F499"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>cotton</term> means extra-long staple cotton and upland cotton.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBBF8116459A4EE58B73F207959E1493"> <enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE5ACEEC0445444879CCC48BE0268F91D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>The term <term>eligible commodity</term> means a loan commodity (as defined in section 1201(a) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9031">7 U.S.C. 9031(a)</external-xref>)).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H866D5AC465BA4151AE66532320611F12" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The term <term>eligible commodity</term> does not include graded wool, nongraded wool, mohair, or honey.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA119A988A0CC43EF90DB6DE183C6EE09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The terms <term>legal entity</term> and <term>person</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1001(a) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1308">7 U.S.C. 1308(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA371AC7AB23B4F3497702532151E7583"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>rice</term> means long grain rice and medium grain rice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7E26FBB0C0C4AAEA7E2FC55B642D7B7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The payment limitations under paragraph (2) shall be separate from annual payment limitations under any other program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H75457E5ED8464F7592B6CD0A1E15504A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Economic assistance for sugar beet producers</header><subsection id="H5D627A668DAD4384AB3401967CA72C07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H18B1A2A87A1A428E9ED11D2F5161EEFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Block grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated under subsection (c), the Secretary shall make block grants to sugar beet cooperatives to carry out economic assistance payments in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3AAAB24F0DF4B778F3E86C0D3D264BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A sugar beet cooperative that receives a block grant under paragraph (1) may only use the grant funds to make payments to members of such cooperative that are sugar beet producers for the economic losses incurred by such producers during the 2025 crop year for sugar beets.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H189AA33087854B5B9092E2513AF41E8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments</header><text>In carrying out the block grants under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H8CF5CE6A860143CF9F8651F9064733CC" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish, in consultation with sugar beet cooperatives, a per-acre payment rate for purposes of determining the amount and allocation of such block grants; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H313BA1AB42CC42A1B83454D8984B279C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce from the amount of a block grant to a sugar beet cooperative, as determined under paragraph (1), the total amount of assistance each member of such cooperative that is a sugar beet producer received for the 2025 crop year under the Farmer Bridge Assistance Program of the Department of Agriculture as described in the press release of the Department of Agriculture on December 8, 2025 (Release No. 0239.25).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68DB28CFC95F49619A0D28F437C5D217"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $330,000,000.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF6CE753BE2CD4FF0BC07EC4749A59EDD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Economic assistance for specialty crops</header><subsection id="HBDF64323101F4DD690A57B6EEFC93AD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and implement a program under which the Secretary will provide a one-time payment to eligible producers to aid such producers in—</text><paragraph id="H95D36BF5E83C41ABB74026C71FB2B2E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expanding domestic markets for the covered specialty crops of such producers; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90523D2BC9A64AB48DA1DDCA76CC020D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developing new markets for such crops.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD492E37AC48149618FC77A64D1C5DEAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible producer seeking payment under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF52B43CA54804BD7AB5116E376BABC61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of payments</header><paragraph id="H0F2D287852CD4F25AC8B7F84C103D414"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as specified in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall calculate the amount of the payment under this section to an eligible producer based on the producer’s sales of covered specialty crops in calendar year 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A0E5EFEC3C54431894E80B7CB7CCD72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New producers</header><subparagraph id="H7ECB3817C01745CC9D937288D1CD1575"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a new producer, the Secretary shall calculate the amount of the payment under this section using the new producer’s estimate of their sales of covered specialty crops in calendar year 2026.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69BFF02120834D68AABBFA03810C07D8"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Required documentation</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A new producer shall provide to the Secretary as evidence to support the estimate referred to in paragraph (1)—</text>
                        <clause id="HFB4260651FBC4B69A5F916D222907E3F">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a legally binding contract or agreement under which the producer has agreed to sell a covered specialty crop during calendar year 2026; or</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HDA7264875A3D4B47977BC43292040D22">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>evidence that, at the time of application, a covered specialty crop has been planted and is expected to be harvested and sold in calendar year 2026.</text>
                        </clause>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51AF234941C246538679C42AD7F1B1F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The maximum amount of the payment an eligible producer may receive under this section shall not exceed $900,000. Such maximum amount may be reduced if the amount of funds made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year is insufficient (as determined by the Secretary) to make all payments for which applications are submitted under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97F01B21803E4BFDAB1413967663BE92"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reduction of total payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the payment an eligible producer may receive under this section with respect to a covered specialty crop shall be reduced by the amount of any payment issued by the Secretary to such producer for such covered specialty crop (or acres on the farm planted to such crop) under the Farmer Bridge Assistance Program of the Department of Agriculture (as described in the press release of the Department of Agriculture on December 8, 2025 (Release No. 0239.25)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3FF851120EC461EBC12D6C933242398"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibition on duplicate payments</header><text>An eligible producer may not receive financial assistance under this section and under section 6 with respect to the same losses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1E08DA6C51E4E9596AFB04B9260DC93"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3B6C2B08EE9E482E948DF6EBA2E0CAFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered specialty crop</header><text>The term <term>covered specialty crop</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD5604FD741FA45C49A7994AB8EE38EDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a specialty crop;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD36FB5D408F42B6B0C8BCE119C25E3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dry edible beans and peas, mushrooms, and vegetable seed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3427231F209F451082200A631A38E933"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Christmas trees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD929D6E2AD6547E2B79DFD4EC07E7FA9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any culinary and medicinal herb or spice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CE7CAEFBE1D4C9788CCFFBEFF56EAC9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>honey, hops, maple sap, tea, coffee, turfgrass, and grass seed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E0EBCAD737541C293063DD4672262A6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other crop as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E45BDC90DF64BD59EF3144B65CCA612"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible producer</header><text>The term <term>eligible producer</term> means a producer of covered specialty crops (including a new producer) that—</text><subparagraph id="HFD74DEC9CF87421D9C22180DE109B3B6"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBDBE2F187E2E4412999B2CF2C882D740"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is in the business of producing covered specialty crops as of the date on which the producer seeks payment under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H0B07D4B3928440E095F91BCBD065E6F9" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is entitled to an ownership share and shares in the risk of producing a covered specialty crop that will be sold in the calendar year for which payment is sought;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0949F4BC13BF46268C28B9910524D4A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is—</text><clause id="HCF37FE2AD12740409CBA16E7D4548DC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a citizen of the United States or lawful alien (as defined in section 1400.3 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations));</text></clause><clause id="H599FCED789424523B25B21CDB86FE037"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or other organizational structure organized under State law;</text></clause><clause id="H11085A18571144A293511ADCB41D5DFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or Tribal Organization (as those terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)); or</text></clause><clause id="H1CC21882A0BC4414854562B1F5159B3B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a foreign person that meets the requirements specified in section 1400.401 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H533B597EC8924C62A59B7C1034D045AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has an average adjusted gross income that—</text><clause id="H96C59975DC394DC2B30E418D7CD3D0D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is less than $900,000 for the preceding three tax years; or</text></clause><clause id="HDF9E7018D6F24663874FB8A3EBFFF989"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>equals or exceeds $900,000 if the producers’s average adjusted gross farm income is at least 75 percent of the producer’s average adjusted gross income.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H148317AE108D4A149BC87987ACDFBD7D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>New producer</header><text>The term <term>new producer</term> means a producer of covered specialty crops who, at the time of application for payment under this section—</text><subparagraph id="HB0764B5837154D3DAD62B1F113066EE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">began producing specialty crops in either of the preceding two crop years but did not have sales due to the immaturity of the crop;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70AC8654DC7347BDB95F0E643E481588"><enum>(B)</enum><text>began producing specialty crops in the preceding crop year but did not have a complete year of sales; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD785B947A1F405591AA41A031C33553"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is beginning to grow specialty crops in the crop year with respect to which the application is submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B92B45B7A304FA5A7C926660F8034B8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Specialty crop</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specialty crop</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1621">7 U.S.C. 1621</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/465">Public Law 108–465</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A11859014234E8B9D07FC3EB50BCBE9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="HA4E993FB2C5A43F2B146C7D9657311D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated to the Secretary $5,000,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H804EAA8F97C74FE0BE36512587F36313"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduction based on other funding</header><text>In providing payments under this section, the Secretary shall use an amount equal to the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) reduced by any amount obligated by the Secretary for payments to eligible producers of specialty crops under the Farmer Bridge Assistance Program of the Department of Agriculture (as described in the press release of the Department of Agriculture on December 8, 2025 (Release No. 0239.25)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E4BC368CAEC45E2BA629314EEE38B20"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date that is the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, there is rescinded from the unobligated balance of the amount appropriated under paragraph (1) an amount equal to the amount under paragraph (1) reduced by the amount obligated by the Secretary for payments to eligible producers of specialty crops under the Farmer Bridge Assistance Program of the Department of Agriculture (as described in the press release of the Department of Agriculture on December 8, 2025 (Release No. 0239.25)) for such period.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB318AFDF8F604095A7FCCA4EDDD7AE2C" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>6.</enum><header>Financial assistance for qualified timber losses</header><subsection id="H48D6410FDEC54E3C9660C9C7DA657E24" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide to an eligible entity that submits an application under subsection (b)—</text><paragraph id="HB02BD7F45B9D481DA43A7C979AA0FCAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a one-time payment or grant, as determined by the Secretary, for qualified timber losses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE057F47C3F094F0DB503A82D289932DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a one-time loan or loan guarantee, as determined by the Secretary, for purposes of enabling the eligible entity to—</text><subparagraph id="H23E5B34519FD4193B891B71200B3B976"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address or offset increases in the timber-related business operating costs of the eligible entity during calendar year 2025 due to market and economic conditions, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D6163EE4A174C7DA16955556450A5AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish, reopen, expand, or improve the timber-related operations of the eligible entity; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C287915DC5D4BA2B55A28D01469364D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a payment or grant under paragraph (1) and a loan or loan guarantee under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2B594F945FD49808C5395720881AC80"><enum>(b)</enum><text>To be eligible to receive financial assistance under the program under subsection (a) an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H00F097751CCE419FAF2DAD515D12BCBC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H562C560FA6A84A618A21769373188B2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amount of a payment or grant the Secretary provides to an eligible entity under subsection (a)(1) shall not exceed the amount that is the lesser of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBFADB9F21D37492E8F08B46778CC4C97" indent="down1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The amount equal to $40,000 reduced by the amount described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34901D136A1D4D65B6F9E993D42458D4" indent="down1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount equal to—</text><clause id="HE5371D45017B440A841DEE2016BBAC10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount equal to 65 percent of the qualified timber losses of the eligible entity; reduced by</text></clause><clause id="H4E8B552BED56412FB228019EE37551A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount described in paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E4122D1773641D881EA82FB6A245EAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a loan or loan guarantee the Secretary provides to an eligible entity under subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed the amount equal to $5,000,000 reduced by the amount described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3C175FBBBB42288F3C95F58EBC949C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The amount described in this paragraph is, with respect to an eligible entity, the amount of any financial assistance the eligible entity receives with respect to calendar year 2025 under the Farmer Bridge Assistance Program of the Department of Agriculture (as described in the press release of the Department of Agriculture on December 8, 2025 (Release No. 0239.25)) for qualified timber losses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H499F7AF1AA8E4A72A8F0501AC05BCCF3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An eligible entity may not receive financial assistance under this section and under section 5 with respect to the same losses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB38A3979CD92481FA5B1B2A6C3AF5D09"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF92F508A93184BC9A62835ABC25FAE69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary $500,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7000845D0296414993796D2EAFEF1B77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Of the amount appropriated under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HB8ADBF46CAA44C059389B6B1A66D8B3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary shall use $250,000,000 to provide payments or grants under subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D160A3CAB93416B96911B494AA5607B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary shall use $250,000,000 to provide loans or loan guarantees under subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3296EFF67E404D1AAE3312E3F5BF9661" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines the amount of funds under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) is insufficient to provide the financial assistance specified in such subparagraphs, the Secretary may ratably reduce such assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB22BEBDA0E54F8192876D3BEE1A5C4B"><enum>(e)</enum><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4F93F929752C47388DACC25CFD6B5CC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H0F6D337282FB4DF882C942857E779B49"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB7B18B418E7340178E6FB92FE5413251"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is in the business of growing, producing, harvesting, transporting, or processing timber, including for lumber, pulp, and paper, as of the date on which the entity submits an application under subsection (b), and was in business during the prior calendar year; or</text></clause><clause id="H976EA268A0324B9792D9B1FCD9E69E8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is entitled to an ownership share, and shares in the risk, of timber production on private forest land in the United States relating to an application under subsection (b); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB11307DA82344C05994920A59B88D0DD"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCFE62E32BE36418D9A74D7CC269E94D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an entity that is an individual, is a citizen of the United States or lawful alien (as defined in section 1400.3 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations));</text></clause><clause id="H98238CF54A4C457496F95DA7E0F9C6C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a partnership, corporation, cooperative, limited liability company, or other organizational structure organized under State law;</text></clause><clause id="H0C8337891DCE4552B2E639E752FD813D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as those terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)); or</text></clause><clause id="HF47E5A23D0254457A0C890C18C5CE88C"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>is a foreign person that meets the requirements specified in section 1400.401 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DD8212F22B94FAD92ECC4C26806DB66"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified timber losses</term> means the timber-related revenue losses of an eligible entity that occurred during calendar year 2025 due to market and economic conditions, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H44A19EB481964DBB80B754E1D850EC4F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Office of Technology Transfer</header><subsection id="HFBD85BBBBCF04DF2AE17A09449F745DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Forest Service an Office of Technology Transfer (referred to this subsection as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC3E55EA1F7294BC4A33DAE4D4DA7D0E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the Office shall be—</text><paragraph id="HE15FBF75FF564D6480EA9A84CF88AB66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to expand the commercial impact of the research investments of the Forest Service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B74A02F45A54D4FA8EE9BA715F67C13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide for the commercialization of technologies that support the mission of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H222287D44DA0424D88B6EE84FF0C743D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chief Commercialization Officer</header><paragraph id="H939E2259E0334CB1810AEFB9361C6951"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be headed by an officer, who shall—</text><subparagraph id="H26FD58A797FB4DCD99AE41A6B91D94A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be known as the <quote>Chief Commercialization Officer</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4B72D83A50048D19D1F00B59D733250"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report to the Deputy Chief of the Forest Service for Research and Development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6A1F6DC0E91495BBFFB9A4F3B9CA183"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual appointed to the position of Chief Commercialization Officer shall be an individual who, by reason of professional background and experience, is specially qualified to advise the Chief of the Forest Service and the Deputy Chief of the Forest Service for Research and Development on technology transfer at the Forest Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H378DFD43F00F483B9CAC4A5907F9A743"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Chief Commercialization Officer shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF899A9BAEA944CB8AFDB9AE4219585CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oversee the expenditure of funds allocated for technology transfer within the Forest Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89F9A337F5184F98BC7AEE0D563D37DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>represent the Forest Service on—</text><clause id="HB6A66EB7EC2B4397A5A0AA2347E71478"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Laboratory Consortium for Technology Transfer established by section 11(e) of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3710">15 U.S.C. 3710(e)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="HA8CBAF37D95B43BCBCF7962EBF092BC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other similar interagency coordinating entities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE130184FB0964EE8934B1F3BF9A79234"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinate with—</text><clause id="H52CB1663CF954C13A99119EBB2131CF9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>other technology transfer and commercialization offices within the Department of Agriculture; and</text></clause><clause id="H0C0C94B1A5674A6EAF121B11FC9FBA1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other similar Federal entities, as appropriate;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D349BD86F2A4D19A26A450667DF167B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>oversee efforts to engage with private sector entities, including venture capital companies, on issues relating to technology transfer and commercialization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F1F9BB029348F6BBB1F7C97E9674AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinate efforts to patent or otherwise protect under title 35, United States Code, any inventions arising from a Forest Service laboratory.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A001199A2EE4B598C445C894A0A65B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technology transfer working group</header><paragraph id="HE34A75722DDC4484B1401196E017FA91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish within the Forest Service a Technology Transfer Working Group, which shall consist of—</text><subparagraph id="HC4291589B1FA4860851AB1A951E938C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Deputy Chief of the Forest Service for Research and Development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90515E4D2E21484085D5C53E37D24BB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chief Commercialization Officer appointed under subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1AE1FEA17F543DEA634710E0BC6EE36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>representatives from each research station within the Forest Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EEABB61294647C9AB6EEB4626A718FF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>representatives from other Forest Service entities with relevant expertise, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403832A67714468C8CBD12EC99942CE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Technology Transfer Working Group established under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HDC2E900567514B17B7652A564B6AA946"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assist with the coordination of technology transfer and commercialization opportunities occurring at Forest Service laboratories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23F769B06152454B8BA6700FBDA06A1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop and disseminate guidance to researchers at Forest Service laboratories on technology transfer and commercialization requirements under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3701">15 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>) and associated agreements to implement those requirements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D59F905A9D44B1B565BABE6F2F32C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop and disseminate to the public and prospective technology partners information about opportunities and procedures for technology transfer with the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0BC4CFBC15C409CA9D30E5F2DA95D28"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Technology Transfer Working Group established under paragraph (1) shall submit to Congress a report that describes—</text><subparagraph id="H1C27755335E04EE3935173C2352E221C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of cooperative research and development agreements entered into by the Forest Service under section 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3710a">15 U.S.C. 3710a</external-xref>) during the preceding 5 years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42F3F0DF438C46FD9E11A73F0E1113CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of agreements with partnership intermediaries entered into by the Forest Service under section 23 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3715">15 U.S.C. 3715</external-xref>) during the preceding 5 years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA164AAD6DA8C423C8BF0CFB07B7EDEBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of licenses and other use authorizations issued by the Forest Service for patents held by the Forest Service during the preceding 5 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1AC38AF69464151A55D14375D00ECAE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative, programmatic, or regulatory changes to support the mission of the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10A24FA7BED24D53A1B1494B4078E3EB" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall use to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5F7E8155E8D7436390DA6EC0375AC06B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Amendments to the International Forestry Cooperation Act of 1990</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The International Forestry Cooperation Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4501">16 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H02A59E46A02E4DCD9BDE2E5644FA0468" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE86D9E2E272641D9AAD8FFB8B4F89A06"><enum>612.</enum><header>Domestic market assistance program</header><subsection id="HDC5AD3B1B48044F3997CB86CF3084B59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary may undertake such activities as the Secretary determines appropriate—</text><paragraph id="HDB8EF79B2D804F6DA74FE1BB3A845443"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to access, develop, maintain, and expand international markets for United States agricultural timber products, including lumber, pulp, and paper; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9661592D69465584BC7D9ED70FBD47"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to promote cooperation and the exchange of information between domestic and international agricultural timber product market participants as a means of promoting the export and sale of such United States timber products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77D1E9B17AE448F58D6DBB70E6A37F92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Secretary for use carrying out this section $15,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HF53DA16B2A5246F3AD1AB28E09BE52B2"><enum>9.</enum><header>Termination of certain Executive orders imposing tariffs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Duties imposed by the following Executive orders, and any successor or substantially similar Executive orders, shall have no force or effect on and after the date of the enactment of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H545ED69ADDCE4B1F88E7556C8B7A79E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Executive Order 14257 (90 Fed. Reg. 15041).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C021B69C17B41B0BC7018AA030976A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Executive Order 14193 (90 Fed. Reg. 9113).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B3762D8630846538BD1DC76BEF25506"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Executive Order 14194 (90 Fed. Reg. 9117).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDA836566CA44F9DA4EB2122CEFB6C0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Executive Order 14195 (90 Fed. Reg. 9121).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFC762E0DBB864313A982E6D9612B2CA9"><enum>10.</enum><header>General provisions</header><subsection id="H99A83948C1034FC8AD73F6CE4C9EA866"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subsection><subsection id="H651DD9DEAE5E4C5A80128E9FC01905A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts provided under this Act are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/901">2 U.S.C. 901(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

