<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7DF6E21D76964A9BAD43C9965B801855" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9056 IH: Community Flood Resilience Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9056</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to allow certain recipients of the Flood Mitigation Assistance Grant, and other grants, to be used for the payment of premiums for a community-based, parametric flood insurance policy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBAA4AE0898DC437AB3107FB131378BF6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAE8412B0E5B2466590766B5B2793BBFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Flood Resilience Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H61F804A566F14EBDBCF69A4FF6705980"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1911A4ADB4E94F2A841AF28D5BFBDC56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>many communities with significant flood risk continue to experience chronically low participation in the National Flood Insurance Program, leaving households and small businesses financially vulnerable to flood events and increasing reliance on post-disaster Federal assistance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E483D76A02E44A5BD11FE910CE1E9E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there is a need to promote greater engagement with private flood insurance markets and improve insurance awareness in communities with elevated flood risk and historically low flood insurance take-up rates;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9829EF3168AC49A691036F38EAEF8E8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>community-based parametric flood insurance has the potential to provide faster, more transparent, and more flexible financial protection at a community level and can serve as a supplemental form of risk transfer alongside existing flood insurance coverage; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B292848E88545EFB61AAA84840317B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>community-based parametric flood insurance may help strengthen the financial resilience of communities undertaking flood mitigation and resilience investments by providing an additional layer of protection for households and small businesses.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDD50DD3383FB4F6D8FB24BEA66B5F86B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of flood mitigation assistance grant amounts for premiums of community-based, parametric flood insurance</header> 
<subsection id="HC618600E2F464C03A5ACD36BBA0F60F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Flood mitigation assistance grant eligible use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H82353753ECED443B90BCFB9656F5FC49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the period that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (hereafter referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall permit any State or community that receives flood mitigation assistance under section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>) to use not more than 15 percent of such assistance amounts each year for the payment of premiums for a community-based, parametric flood insurance policy that—</text> <subparagraph id="H8EECD31711FC436C826B13C849635DA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is offered through the private sector;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H772AF5EC807E427E91B2FABC592CBF33" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifies objective, predefined trigger conditions for payout based on measurable flood-related metrics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB10D513346F2412CB88A4741F6466749"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes timelines and disbursement terms agreed upon at the time of underwriting; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFACB6ABA4D04495BBF2C36F07F6F58BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides that funds shall be disbursed to the participating community promptly upon verification that a triggering condition has been met, without the need for post-event damage assessment or additional administrative approval by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF678C522AE245A78E6EA156FD24BC9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>In each year that a State or community that uses assistance amounts as described in paragraph (1), such State or community shall submit to the Administrator a report that describes how such State or community—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8A66C290FC7B4EC79E574AAFDD954084"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promotes National Flood Insurance Program policy enrollment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2601DE82A54446F843B155549DD5936"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educates members of the community about the limitations community-based, parametric flood insurance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H891B7602938140C98C746160683B4C00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encourages flood-risk mitigation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF343CD85F55F46CDB2F5F1EAA91AD6E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>uses community based, parametric flood insurance to—</text> 
<clause id="HF785534DB45F4F93900CBE70BCD9AC24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support households and small businesses; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF0BE36D21F174C1097E69A7107403816"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contribute to broader flood resilience and insurance awareness efforts; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8650D28400904277AE1AD69AE9B798CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages flood insurance take-up by improving public awareness of flood risk and promoting participation in either the National Flood Insurance Program or a private flood insurance offering.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H648B2F4A4F254A40A28D4D90BC8ACA49"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The permission described in paragraph (1) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, absent a reauthorization by the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7DBFE5029DF643B7B89EA96B07525891">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Promotion of community-Based flood insurance</header>
 <text>The Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE1A3A6833AAB46E79A33F9C713BEF14A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct outreach to communities to spread awareness with respect to community-based, parametric flood insurance policies and the eligible use described in subsection (a); and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H81BDED8B5E7D489183DEFC38FD7281E2" commented="no">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>notwithstanding any other provision of law, allow for the use of other grant amounts under the authority of the Administrator for the payment of premiums of community-based, parametric flood insurance policies by grant recipients for the 5 year period after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H26AEA6B1B57A4F3FBF4A6FEDB3FD5D99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure required</header><text>Any community based, parametric flood insurance policy for which premiums are paid as described in subsection (a) shall include a written dislcosure that explains—</text> <paragraph id="H17D972F9DA75487E85EDE1C6D150F40C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the specific trigger conditions under which a payout will and will not be made;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96030BFD5C9D4BD1BACD22B0285C66E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the circumstances under which a triggering event may occur but individual households or small businesses within the community may not receive financial relief (commonly referred to as the <quote>basis risk</quote>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA4E7AC3FA8F45D892F27BEFBD5A5DC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the parametric policy interacts with and differs from flood insurance provided under the National Flood Insurance Program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8DCEE4BFB6994282931D2E3CAE42231E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and on the dates that are 3 and 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Congress a report that contains—</text> <paragraph id="H0BB988E33E2D4A4F8DE9BE0DC2EBF065"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of any changes to the number of National Flood Insurance policies in communities that use flood mitigation assistance grant amounts as described in section 1366(c)(3)(k) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 and communities that do not use such grant amounts as described in such section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF5C468EC22949F2BA33A4855679EFB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the product types of community-based, parametric flood insurance policies that communities use, including the number of households covered by such policies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H836A3CF621074918AEF4B22C5E029AF4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the timeliness and effectiveness of claim payouts through community-based, parametric flood insurance policies for which premiums are paid for as described in such section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H370AD80C09E246CA8D19A63E8763FECA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of outreach and flood insurance awareness efforts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5971053235B4B518C7B122AE823E5F0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any legislative recommendations for the continuation or expansion of community-based, parametric flood insurance policies.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

