<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9770E360B33C447AAA5A3A377905BDCA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8297 IH: District of Columbia Firearm Freedom Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8297</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restore and protect the Second Amendment rights of residents and United States citizens who visit the District of Columbia by modernizing the District’s firearm laws, eliminating prior restraints on acquisition and possession, establishing concealed constitutional carry, prohibiting feature-based firearm bans, and facilitating lawful purchases through Federally licensed dealers in neighboring States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEE696045E74F419EB536320ADD5C2DBC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H375D53A72C694B60AF5AA5888ED8C848" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Firearm Freedom Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFE0C925311D14F3E9A00A40BDCBDC90D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBD872790ADB349D3AB61AC0F469885A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Article I, section 8, clause 17 of the Constitution grants Congress plenary legislative authority over the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E476570C50B478DB99FCB71028EEE7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Second Amendment protects an individual’s right to keep and bear arms, and the District must maintain laws consistent with that constitutional guarantee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FB9CEA966314CF4AD779D71BD53104D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>United States citizens visiting the National Capital and those who reside or work in the District should not have their constitutionally protected Second Amendment rights infringed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC3D38AC097F46F0A0F884E0E623DC8A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The District’s regulatory structure has imposed undue burdens on legal gun owners and residents wishing to be legal gun owners, prior restraints on purchasing and concealed carrying firearms, and feature-based restrictions that unduly burden lawful acquisition, possession, and carrying of firearms by responsible residents and visitors.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB23858DFA180442CBAE9CCFBCD31ED55"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H656C00F37D50493D827FA852899C9DC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>District</header><text>The term <term>District</term> means the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H170B25C4F40240D4B386D203E35F1C13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text>The term <term>firearm</term> has the meaning given that term in section 921(a)(3) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEC4B41DA3B94A1D9C0B492B27B2DE16"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Licensee</header><text>The term <term>licensee</term> means a person licensed under section 923 of title 18, United States Code (a Federal firearms licensee).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D719ABEA1594CA6A869E207AA35E797"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibited person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>prohibited person</term> means any person prohibited from receiving or possessing firearms under Federal law, including section 922(g) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> <title id="HE9418865623C4AA88AF429DF172DDEC2"><enum>I</enum><header>End Prior Approval and Registration System</header> <section id="H6A5D335D1D2C47A4B00CEFC87442D1BE"><enum>101.</enum><header>Prohibition on prior restraints for acquisition or possession</header> <subsection id="HE518440B09874B2AAAAE5A094A5C7473"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No law, regulation, rule, or policy of the District may require any person to obtain, before acquiring, receiving, possessing, or bringing into the District a firearm otherwise lawful under Federal law, any license, certificate, registration, approval, permit, or other authorization as a condition precedent to such acquisition, receipt, possession, or importation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B761906D4B547E9A0BED681933C3CAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No criminal liability for mere lack of prior approval</header><text>No person may be arrested, prosecuted, or subjected to criminal penalties under District law solely because the person acquired, received, possessed, or brought into the District a firearm without first obtaining District authorization described in subsection (a), if the person is not a prohibited person under Federal law.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H295BAB4A397741CDAB5935F8C9A67438"><enum>102.</enum><header>Repeal of district firearm registration system; conforming provisions</header> <subsection id="H44A8D43FF95A4D59B55DA4F4F11BF917"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of registration system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District may not require the registration of any privately owned firearm. Any provision of District law, regulation, rule, or policy requiring registration of a firearm, conditioning lawful possession on registration, or imposing any penalty for failure to register a firearm is hereby repealed and shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H39D6DA32BCCE48299A2775F685AD6DAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming repeal and premption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any District provision that—</text> <paragraph id="H5366D8F4D662439CA111EA0FF98FF69D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes or authorizes a registry of firearms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AF030B212B54D22A2282A6138059D44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requires a registration certificate, registration card, or proof of registration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24B77748E07F4BAE89D9D425A9ACA0C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>makes lawful possession, transport, storage, use, purchase, sale, transfer, carrying, or receipt of a firearm contingent upon registration; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01E7A04ABF3F40FB8BB627E4A0283208"><enum>(4)</enum><text>authorizes seizure, forfeiture, or arrest solely for a registration-related violation, is preempted and may not be enforced.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC9EC752E2BAA4A67834462CF171A5824"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on alternative registration schemes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The District may not establish or maintain any system that, in purpose or effect, functions as a firearm registration requirement, including any requirement to report or record firearm identifying information as a precondition to lawful possession, purchase, transfer, transport, or carrying, except to the extent such information is collected by a Federal firearms licensee as required under Federal law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB8957ACC311418DA40CD520F71AFA27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Records and data</header> 
<paragraph id="H386676F5794740F98508451EF241F25F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cessation of collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the effective date of this Act, the District may not accept, process, or require any registration application, registration renewal, or registration amendment for any firearm.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0532763984BB4134BA14F106FE0E9DD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disposition of existing records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the effective date of this Act, the District shall destroy each firearm registration record in the possession of the District, including database entries, paper records, and electronic files, except records that are evidence in a pending criminal prosecution or are required to be retained by Federal law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B1F940B71DB4CBAB00F7E17F5634B7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No use for enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No firearm registration record possessed by the District on or after the effective date of this Act may be used as a basis for probable cause, reasonable suspicion, or any adverse action against any person.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H41D571F57BDE4CF08867D389E2098733"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter Federal background check requirements under section 922(t) of title 18, United States Code, or Federal prohibitions on possession by prohibited persons under section 922(g) of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> </title> 
<title id="HD0836CBBAD804601A72140A6C1428A38"><enum>II</enum><header>Common Firearms Protection; Ban Feature-Based Prohibitions; Repeal of prohibition on large capacity ammunition feeding device</header> 
<section id="HF9D7AFE941AC469FB7E0B915E0C2D6C9"><enum>201.</enum><header>Preemption of feature-based and assault weapon bans</header> 
<subsection id="H4C8E09BC3CA8401889158206108AAE35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of District of Columbia law, no law, regulation, rule, or policy of the District may prohibit the possession, acquisition, sale, transfer, transport, or use of any firearm on the basis of—</text> <paragraph id="H483D2C9672B541378C5E18195C1DFC8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the firearm being semiautomatic;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2749A92DA9049798D55F88C3047B344"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the capacity to accept a detachable magazine; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB808E04845724F39A7CFD91017BAADD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any feature, characteristic, component, or configuration that is based on appearance, ergonomics, or other nonfunctional or commonly possessed attributes, including a pistol grip, adjustable stock, barrel shroud or handguard, muzzle device, threaded barrel, forward grip, or accessory rail.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE016A9FDE25741FFB36ABFEA9633C95D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit possession of firearms prohibited under Federal law, including items regulated under the National Firearms Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5801">26 U.S.C. 5801 et seq.</external-xref>), except to the extent Federal law otherwise permits such possession.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H16A5A03A21594448829F9DE3007DD790"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming preemption</header><text>Any District of Columbia provision defining or prohibiting assault weapons (or substantially similar term) in a manner inconsistent with this section is hereby preempted and shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0C3F440B508D46A7A54B74970E334B4D"><enum>202.</enum><header>Repeal of prohibition on large capacity ammunition feeding device</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 601(b) and 601(c) of the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975 are hereby repealed.</text></section></title> <title id="H8233736D50DD46D2AD23C9AA47C4AD0E"><enum>III</enum><header>Concealed Constitutional Carry</header> <section id="H3A761BF05DAF4344AF8B026F6E050FB2"><enum>301.</enum><header>Concealed constitutional carry</header> <subsection id="HCCD1FB1AACC843D7899844868BCAC08B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person 21 years of age or older who is not a prohibited person and can otherwise legally own a firearm under Federal law may carry a concealed handgun in the District without any District-issued license or permit.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H036EFA6F381E4750B0EE489046E38FB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No prior restraint</header><text>The District may not require any license, permit, training, fingerprinting, good cause, suitability determination, or other discretionary or nondiscretionary prerequisite as a condition to carrying a firearm concealed.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF89AB285E5104AA5A3CA5F0DE0B112FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sensitive places</header><text>The District may prohibit concealed carry only in locations where prohibitions are consistent with the Constitution and Federal law, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4BD1908CB9E24FCB816EFAB0CA5B3559"><enum>(1)</enum><text>secure areas of law enforcement facilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB355CFEFD5DD454893BDE374B41D994A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>courthouses and courtrooms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H290D0899439449D8AF1DD51B200F63C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>detention facilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F9FC536E843473984AC308BC8B17633"><enum>(4)</enum><text>polling places on election day (as narrowly tailored);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E7EBCC36A87450D82B90E43B2CB4F08"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a school zone, consistent with the terms of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/921">18 U.S.C. 921(a)</external-xref> and 922(q); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E4ADB7CDA3B47D288ECE9CF0DB220E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any place where possession is prohibited by Federal statute.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7BC79C5EA5F145AA9FE9A34FF91E96EB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the right of a private property owner to restrict or prohibit firearms on the owner’s property, provided that such owner shall give notice of any such prohibition or restriction by posting a sign at any publicly accessible entrance to the property or by express notice to individuals entering the property.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H309CA3028D074BE2AAF59985D491200C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Optional licensing</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the District from issuing a carry credential on an optional basis for residents seeking reciprocity in other jurisdictions, provided that such a credential is not required for any person to carry concealed within the District under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50EEB3A0951F430AB133B4D84B3E9656"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Open carry</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require the District to permit open carry. The District’s laws restricting or prohibiting the open carrying of firearms, to the extent otherwise consistent with the Constitution, shall not be preempted by this Act.</text></subsection></section> </title> <title id="H90FD56D5FC1E48AD977AF9CF03AF6475"><enum>IV</enum><header>Modernize Commerce: District Residents as <quote>In-State</quote> Buyers for Virginia and Maryland Federal Firearm License Purchases</header> <section id="H53A8DFA34C854AB8838095C2A6567C5B"><enum>401.</enum><header>Authority for licensees in Virginia and Maryland to transfer firearms to District residents</header> <subsection id="HFE55703B1A334B078F65CE65AF551618" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 922(b)(3) of title 18, United States code is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>, and <header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">(C)</header-in-text> shall not apply to the sale or delivery of a firearm by a licensee whose licensed premises are located in the Commonwealth of Virginia or the State of Maryland to a resident of the District of Columbia if <header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">(i)</header-in-text> the transferee appears in person at the licensee’s premises; <header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">(ii)</header-in-text> the transfer is completed in compliance with section 922(t) (including a NICS background check or a lawful alternative under Federal law); <header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">(iii)</header-in-text> the transferee is not a prohibited person; and <header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">(iv)</header-in-text> the sale, delivery, and receipt would be lawful if the transferee were a resident of the State in which the licensee’s premises are located, except that the District of Columbia shall not be treated as a <quote>State</quote> for purposes of imposing any additional restriction;</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H62D77E5AC5F44CA0822B3B50E5D00BF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="HA828996684154832BFD3B06C43FE1BCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>alter Federal prohibitions on possession or receipt of firearms by prohibited persons; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF99CFABE77FE471891F56E46313BBF03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>alter Federal requirements applicable to licensees, including recordkeeping.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HA38B26D66FD14EEFA1C095EFA7F40F33"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming guidance</header><text>The Attorney General shall, not later than 60 days after enactment, update any implementing guidance necessary to ensure NICS and licensee compliance for transfers authorized by this section.</text></subsection></section></title> 
<title id="H06A6022D89D147EE81D058E16A9DAC1D"><enum>V</enum><header>Preemption, Enforcement, and Effective Date</header> 
<section id="HD3251C5616FE4C9DB97028A94FA3CD7C"><enum>501.</enum><header>Preemption of inconsistent District laws</header> 
<subsection id="HB16F7E96BCC043C69EE0332628F920C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act supersedes and preempts any law, regulation, rule, or policy of the District that is inconsistent with this Act, and such inconsistent provisions shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H34E88D490742434ABA65B5075E7F0252"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Anti-Circumvention</header> <text>The District may not enforce any portion of a preempted provision by reissuing it under a different name, authority, or rulemaking vehicle.</text>
        </subsection></section> 
<section id="HD7A0B98BD48240398C1FC7FD4D5250D8"><enum>502.</enum><header>Enforcement; cause of action; attorneys’ fees</header> 
<subsection id="H3BF1D1545E854D54A658DF6C19F5D29F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>Any person adversely affected by a violation of this Act, or by the enforcement or threatened enforcement of a District law preempted by this Act, may bring a civil action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for declaratory and injunctive relief.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBA8B887FCBED4222B79FB3248E703D22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>In an action under subsection (a), the court may award appropriate relief, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B659EB48B584C19906E2A35A3911069"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">declaratory relief;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCF75F0C984F431A8EA9437567337BFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>temporary, preliminary, and permanent injunctive relief;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAE2DC50A79A4EA59656642D86A55792"><enum>(3)</enum><text>compensatory damages (where otherwise available); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E35681A39DF4CC1ADBE3F334692B176"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs to a prevailing plaintiff.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H07E8CC7A3CDC48349193DA43B517E01D"><enum>503.</enum><header>Effective date</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </title> </legis-body></bill>

