<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV26874-C1L-3H-V29"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 712 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate in support of general elections in Venezuela.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 712</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate in support of general elections in Venezuela.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the people of Venezuela should be free to elect their political leaders through a fair and democratic process;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a clear majority of Venezuelans have rallied around the democratic opposition, led by María Corina Machado and Edmundo González Urrutia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Maduro-Rodriguez regime does not have international legitimacy or the support of the Venezuelan people; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is in the national interest of the United States to have a democratic and free Venezuela, free of the corrosive influence of China, Iran, and Cuba: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it is the sense of the Senate that the United States should use all diplomatic tools to support internationally monitored, free and fair elections in Venezuela.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution>

