<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61F2B23C256E4A39AEED05A142C9DABC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8633 IH: Competitive Prices Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8633</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To specify the standards governing claims of consciously parallel pricing coordination in civil actions under the Sherman Act, and to clarify the meaning of contract, combination in the form of trust or otherwise, or conspiracy under the Sherman Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8DDAEE6D86314EBE9AB95CBADC4B2455" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1DAFA78AE57F404F864BD3401CD98217" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Competitive Prices Act.</short-title></quote></text></section> <section id="H9F220BDAAF3B407B81A7AA23D75915CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pleading an antitrust violation through parallel conduct and plus factors</header> <subsection id="H50B5CFBE95A64366B0E14FA3E064CB58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="H7FC3F858ABBA4E25911ED89317219723"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The term <quote>antitrust laws</quote> means the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, et seq.), the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>, et seq.), and the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref>, et seq.).</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5279ABA1272B496CB4686C414AAD7B39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>parallel conduct</quote> means two or more persons acting similarly to raise, lower, maintain, stabilize, or manipulate price, output, capacity, supply, or other terms of competition for reasonably interchangeable commodities or services. Parallel conduct need not be uniform and can be varied in timing, method, and amount.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DF95E83DE5F43D497456C76A423DE90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>person</quote> has the meaning given the term in subsection (a) of the 1st section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/12">5 U.S.C. 12(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E36D41A39EB45F1BB73A493F0747E9D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>plus factors</quote> means allegations other than parallel conduct supporting the inference of a conspiracy, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HDEA644A2B5B045C8A180AC6B089FC725"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a motive to coordinate efforts to raise, lower, maintain, stabilize, or manipulate price, output, capacity, supply, or other terms of competition for the purchase or sale of reasonably interchangeable commodities or services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF20CC8CBEC0495BA0E4B0A69A633E08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>actions that would be contrary to a person’s unilateral economic self-interest absent a conspiracy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD27B7EBE15104D3D83D596C680B08B1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>departure from prior pricing methodology and practices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H718863DB21DC474197F859CF1383C3A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>exchanges of competitively sensitive information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2071E07674EC4373805EA5BBFC9D94FA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>price or output levels unexplained by cost, supply, or demand;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6846298AC2E4ABEB858E7E0F76ED849"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an opportunity to conspire at industry events, conferences, trade association activities, or through any other meetings or venues;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDBD775CEC4441AC945108500E20DD8F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>past collusive practices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H683F449E59714377BECB76AC9BDD6333">
                        <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>an invitation to participate in a common scheme, including by public signaling of pricing, output, capacity, supply, or other competitive strategies, or offering of a method to engage in parallel conduct; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5A7DC4F4D0948D987F1543EB6DC6404"><enum>(I)</enum><text>market conditions conducive to coordination, including high market concentration, high barriers to entry, high exit barriers, inelastic demand, or fungible products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC1F8EFE7EB2474BA17BAC6688D909B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The terms <quote>State attorney general</quote> and <quote>State</quote> have the meaning given in section 4G of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/15g">15 U.S.C. 15g</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE29BB2CA4A94AB6AF2DF3046B01FDC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards of pleading and proof</header><text>In a civil action, including an action brought by the United States, the Federal Trade Commission, a State attorney general, or any person seeking damages or injunctive relief for violations of the antitrust laws—</text> <paragraph id="H0A5B563AC51849D0ADF6FEA0B6ED262E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>when opposing any motion to dismiss a complaint, motion for judgment on the pleadings, or any other motion challenging the sufficiency of the allegations, a claimant—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1057E2714B414768A31C654DFC1C920F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>plausibly states a claim by alleging parallel conduct and the presence of two or more plus factors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C019FCD09E24AE5AD965F87F6AC587B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>need not allege direct evidence of a conspiracy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAEF43ADE77044D483996AE2CEB5CAEC">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>need not allege facts tending to exclude the possibility of independent action; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H421F92D49B1047329112FD02A6254B9B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>need not allege a theory that is more plausible than one offered by defendants, as the court at the pleading stage must only consider whether the allegations are plausible, not whether an alternative explanation is equally or more plausible; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF89677F891FB4F6A8452A6EC11C03791"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when opposing any motion for summary judgment, motion for directed verdict, motion for judgment as a matter of law, or any other motion challenging the sufficiency of the evidence and permitting a ruling as matter of law, a claimant—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F961EC087254513A0309AF5D5BC4599"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrates a genuine issue of material fact by offering evidence, which may be direct evidence, circumstantial evidence, or some combination of the two, that is sufficient to allow a trier of fact to find that the defending party engaged in an unlawful conspiracy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DA643ED67044186BC17011E80F59ABC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>need not offer evidence tending to exclude the possibility that the defending party acted independently; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E778B4A26FA43138394B56F9F8C4340"><enum>(C)</enum><text>need not demonstrate that the weight of the evidence favors the claimant, as all evidence must be construed in the light most favorable to the party opposing summary judgment and the weighing of the evidence is an issue for the finder of fact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H523EDAA2C5C54A0BBB34F0431BDEF894"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to abridge or narrow the remedies available under the antitrust laws.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

