<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25A31-4PV-HT-089"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 S3493 IS: Carson City Public Land Correction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3493</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in Carson City, Nevada, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1028887F4E4C4DEB9CF7E17E1D2051CA"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Carson City Public Land Correction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida2599e4936454ba0a56193cfd2bb8979"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ida05019ccb80245f3928fe215f7e623f7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Account</header><text>The term <term>Account</term> means the Carson City Special Account established by section 2601(e)(1)(B) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1113).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb93ecfce21e45179b1ca16af918ddb0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>City</header><text>The term <term>City</term> means Carson City, Nevada.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31333bb6a9854d76b6216d9bb7ccc9c5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Carson City OPLMA Lands 2025</quote> and dated December 11, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32e9964ae2354352a38d7000b272b8d8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id555b41d102e34d88b7e4591110302f7b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idea1d25bf87fa47e59c0ba605f98b40ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to other Federal land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ide6727d8b935043bd9814af28378373cc"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conveyance to Carson City, Nevada</header><subsection id="idbfc1366dfa9e41d99e889b46871a5259"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1713), at the request of the City, the Secretary shall convey to the City, subject to valid existing rights, for no consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to approximately 1,288 acres of Federal land in the State depicted as <quote>Lands to acquire</quote> on the Map.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide0acae958c4742a38e1de368fc16b9bf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use</header><text>The City shall use the Federal land conveyed under subsection (a) for public purposes consistent with uses allowed under the Act of June 14, 1926 (commonly known as the <quote>Recreation and Public Purposes Act</quote>) (44 Stat. 741, chapter 578; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/869">43 U.S.C. 869 et seq.</external-xref>), including recreation and flood mitigation.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6b3ec039e00547babe09a5964f5f1296"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>Any costs relating to the conveyance under subsection (a), including costs of surveys, appraisals, and environmental response and restoration and administrative costs (including closing fees) shall be paid by the City.</text></subsection><subsection id="id24f4267a53d442089e86f0ba704e3709"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>If a parcel of Federal land conveyed to the City under subsection (a) ceases to be used for a purpose described in subsection (b), the parcel of Federal land shall, at the discretion of the Secretary, revert to the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="id626cd8c80c1b400aa28d8b68af16542c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Carson City street connector conveyance</header><subsection id="id350e1f3b3e1440ec89d700df727003d8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the request of the City, the Secretary shall convey to the City, subject to valid existing rights, for no consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to approximately .45 acres of Federal land depicted as <quote>Lands to acquire</quote> on the Map.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5cd8ce2027df4da4a58d09d694e25d7a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use</header><text>The City shall use the Federal land conveyed under subsection (a) for the expansion of a roadway.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcf2d5426903f4189a8e61e08aeb9c047"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>Any costs relating to the conveyance under subsection (a), including costs of surveys, appraisals, and environmental response and restoration and administrative costs (including closing fees) shall be paid by the City.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfee5734c32f2485cbd17b6676e0c6932"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public safety conditions</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the conveyance under subsection (a), the City, in consultation with the Secretary, shall construct a crosswalk across South Curry Street to allow for continued access to the Carson Ranger District Office of the Forest Service.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7aa3750972e8422e94e058bb2cfefa30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Environmental response and restoration</header><text>For purposes of the conveyances of the parcels of Federal land under subsection (a), the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="id7869993034864358ae92eee2e0e972b2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall meet disclosure requirements for hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants under section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6774089b8e3a47c3871f86bbe0191b7b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not otherwise be required—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefe349fc7a19460f87a44ee6bd930566"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to remediate or abate the hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8a13af5f34b4d97853776e1c6ccf97c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to remediate or abate the presence of solid and hazardous waste and materials that may be required by applicable Federal, State, and local environmental laws (including regulations); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63a72ff53af04919a67851dda9b30781"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to remove any improvements from the parcels of Federal land to be conveyed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id88358b64673e4222a4ac66ee77a83c31"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>The exact acreage and legal description of the Federal land to be conveyed by the Secretary under this section shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd6b9c0e131404401b36f0bb1d6f09608"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header><paragraph id="id04f8b21763ac4dac8a56ba842438c5d7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize maps and legal descriptions of the parcels of Federal land to be conveyed under section 3 and this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcddfcbd26b5f473da1c6c823057b81e0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions finalized under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management or the Forest Service, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6a8ae31ed694924aa338937197fa3a4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>The Secretary and the City may, by mutual agreement—</text><subparagraph id="id6df1dda9c9cc49f4a3e5288d86e8fb6a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make minor boundary adjustments to the parcels of Federal land to be conveyed under section 3 and this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ba0ec5138684b3caa4294985ce7215a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>correct any minor errors, including clerical and typographical errors, on the maps, the acreage estimates, or the legal descriptions of the parcels of Federal land to be conveyed under section 3 and this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7cd4739ced4f4378a19d87a9675ea6b9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Disposal of Federal land</header><subsection id="id8760ee452ca74263a963f914af0927c8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disposal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights and notwithstanding sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1713), the Secretary shall conduct 1 or more sales of the Federal land described in subsection (b) to qualified bidders.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida17b9a0ab57d472882493fd38bda3e54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of land</header><text>The Federal land referred to in subsection (a) is the approximately 360 acres of Federal land depicted as <quote>BLM Owned lands to dispose</quote> on the Map.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4e136ff1fb754948936edb871f5af0f3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>Any costs relating to the disposal of Federal land under subsection (a), including costs of surveys and administrative costs, shall be paid by the party entering into the disposal agreement with the Bureau of Land Management for the 1 or more applicable parcels of Federal land.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf8f68fe2c1a841a8b86a5075e255f1fb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>On disposal of the Federal land under subsection (a), the City shall retain—</text><paragraph id="id2224c0f1fdfe425d96fcacd2c2557d7a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an existing public utility easement concurrent with Koontz Lane and Conti Drive, which provides waterlines and access to the water tank and trailhead immediately east of the applicable parcels of Federal land; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93aa92d59816443ea6de763ebb5e7acd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an existing drainage easement for a future detention basin located on APN 010–152–06 depicted as <quote>Lands for BLM Disposal</quote> on the Map.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1405b81f224d45bc8d2282b1005ff182"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transfer of land to the United States</header><subsection id="id72cb4eaa51d349749faced81cf908753" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance</header><text>If the City offers to convey to the Secretary of the Interior all right and title of the City in and to the land described in subsection (b), not later than 1 year after the date of the offer, the Secretary shall accept the offer.</text></subsection><subsection id="id991eec2d3f6f469cbcc5a7b79c6cebd5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of land</header><text>The land referred to in subsection (a) is the approximately 20 acres depicted as <quote>Lands to Dispose</quote> on the Map.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf4e9974529de4a53a7bdb79087e6c48c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disposal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights and notwithstanding sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1713), the Secretary of the Interior shall conduct 1 or more sales to qualified bidders of the land conveyed to the Secretary of the Interior under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idfdc350a67fd04f05b2db6532c5c42820"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs</header><paragraph id="id691cc19bca7b4b578bb3659bd80e6a6c" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Costs related to conveyance</header><text>Any costs relating to the conveyance of the land under subsection (a), including costs of surveys and administrative costs, shall be paid by the City.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb7f7cc5d3f64873914c5c164833b6ae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs related to disposal</header><text>Any costs relating to the disposal of the land under subsection (c), including costs of surveys and administrative costs, shall be paid by the party entering into the disposal agreement with the Bureau of Land Management for the land described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id03386e03765b4643a13afd2610b0b509"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>On disposal of the land under subsection (c), the City shall retain—</text><paragraph id="iddab8475c41c94fca938bfce24d285073"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access and an existing public utility easement on APN 010–252–02 for operation and maintenance of a municipal well; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98e83014122d49bd8bb6797b86ec3e40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an existing public right-of-way for Bennett Avenue.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc528e6b6bea048d7bcf2dd243b271530"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Hazardous substances</header><text>The costs of remedial actions relating to hazardous substances on land acquired by the Secretary of the Interior under this section shall be paid by the entities responsible for the costs under applicable law.</text></subsection></section><section id="idd5f0ba8ac6bd495b84effc56710877c5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Disposition of proceeds</header><subsection id="id0f544863193b409b96a9b5e1e9f9e73e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disposition of proceeds</header><text>In addition to the amounts deposited in the Account under section 2601(e)(1)(B) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1113), the proceeds from the sales of Federal land under sections 3 through 6 shall be deposited in the Account.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18222ea3cec0434f90ed95c200c51b44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts deposited in the Account shall be available to the Secretary, without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation, for—</text><paragraph id="id1bf315a9af9c48ff950757778dfd4fb6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the reimbursement of costs incurred by the Secretary in preparing for the sales described in sections 3 through 6 and section 2601(e)(1)(B) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1113), including—</text><subparagraph id="id9482aa0680af47eea28784dee091e220"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs of surveys and appraisals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5e4b9ecb3514384b8454020033a3638"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the costs of compliance with—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56a86d02c2ae43daaf1fa2249137df90"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5a17a50578f476bab9eef549cf3d1fb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sections 202 and 203 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>, 1713);</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9534f71844eb4e2ea765257213c19fac"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reimbursement of costs incurred by the City in preparing for the sale of the Federal land described in section 3 and section 2601(d) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1112);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ee184ac6c04422f8bc4f54f80e5571e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the conduct of wildlife habitat conservation and restoration projects, including projects that benefit the greater sage-grouse in the City;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida9a9ab0ad50c4ac0ab2c8aa6259386be"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the development and implementation of comprehensive, cost-effective, multijurisdictional hazardous fuels reduction and wildfire prevention and restoration projects in the City;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida359a5994f254c1fa668bcff297b1bb8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the acquisition of environmentally sensitive land or interest in environmentally sensitive land in the City;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecf3f1122a7f40438ee9b4c69cc52614"><enum>(6)</enum><text>wilderness protection and processing wilderness designations, including the costs of appropriate fencing, signage, public education, and enforcement for wilderness areas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idddff466aad6d44a9824df1c1fc7c6506"><enum>(7)</enum><text>capital improvements administered by the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service in the City; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f16063fd50841679d0db44dc477a076"><enum>(8)</enum><text>educational purposes of the City.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide565c2e658b0420f979af41159ffdfce"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investment of account</header><text>Amounts deposited in the Account—</text><paragraph id="idc8153710780144f9bc85cced079be2c4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall earn interest in an amount determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, based on the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id455772de142c47c7b6dcd0245969507d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be expended by the Secretary, in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc841259600734b3d99d4e21985f6796b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management of Account</header><text>The management and procedures of the Account shall be determined by an intergovernmental agreement between the City and the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0C77F882C20F44839687DB160FFDBB9E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Amendments to the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009</header><subsection id="id0672e271eb8345e2b67a7c94a32992ec"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to reversionary interests</header><text>Section 2601(b)(4) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1111) is amended by inserting after subparagraph (D), the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb204de9ee77a48d4900d0865f990df1c"><subparagraph id="idaafb9f5fef364667ae59ca5ef54bf394"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Sale or lease of land to third parties</header><clause id="id878666761E2B4DA1840B641E9FDEE168"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The City may enter into an agreement to sell, lease, or otherwise convey all or a portion of the land described in paragraph (2)(B)(iv) to third parties for economic development, recreation, or other public purposes.</text></clause><clause id="idD68B5EF9E9A445C0976547AD994F1B23"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Condition</header><text>A sale of land under clause (i) shall be for not less than fair market value.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id0647679918e0418786fb718f390f0e85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Postponement; exclusion from sale</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2601(d) of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1112) is amended by striking paragraph (6) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18813E84E37F47C2AEE7FCA02F0C1583"><paragraph id="id29ab16c7f91e451e8939f8f0a4b549ba"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Deadline for sale</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Carson City Public Land Correction Act</short-title>, if there is a qualified bidder for the land described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2), the Secretary of the Interior shall offer the land for sale to the qualified bidder.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

