<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE259D97E46074563B536E099BE53A8BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8492 IH: Public Safety UAS Readiness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8492</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Transportation to establish a grant program for unmanned aircraft system pilot training, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB901B39894ED4C6AB3DF0B36A70E8EEA" style="OLC"><section id="HFB3DDAB037EE4769ACEA622C38BC84B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Safety UAS Readiness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8FE973E671BC45BE9CA17901434F34C0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system pilot training grant program</header><subsection id="HF351F418B63E4B3B89015379BADD2148"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall establish a program to award grants to covered entities to carry out activities to support training of unmanned aircraft system pilots.</text></subsection><subsection id="H342202DAE7C74D40851D3440D4A202C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity in receipt of a grant awarded under this section may use such grant—</text><paragraph id="HED5F684040B24F37AA98BA82B6C1BF67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish and develop an unmanned aircraft system training program, including curriculum design, instructional materials, and related resources necessary to carry out—</text><subparagraph id="H0E18B9A13B754FA89BAF51DB35F86E8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training of public safety personnel on aviation safety, Federal Aviation Administration regulations, basic airspace principles, and public safety mission profiles relating to the operation of unmanned aircraft systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15FDE18B5DC640A6BD30313EC079C5CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training of certified remote pilots on risk management, flight execution, data collection for unmanned aircraft systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F641AD4BBDE40DAB866DDE201927921"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specialized instruction for certified remote pilots leading unmanned aircraft system missions in complex, multi-agency environments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H220337BF0BD1457E8986E5E5CF16E73C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development and validation of public safety UAS instructors to serve as instructors in certain regions throughout the United States upon completion of such certification;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC73940C4108745F6AC0AFB75B1FF6598"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to purchase an unmanned aircraft system that meets all Federal safety standards and regulatory requirements for the purpose of carrying out the training described in this paragraph; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EA29D1D566240AF8F590CB184A9550D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for reasonable administrative costs directly associated with the delivery of training and program implementation under this section, including support services necessary to ensure student participation and program completion, expenses incurred due to staff attendance, including travel coordination, and local facility use.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC5C6CA6F61C4574A6550FEFF19213CE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a covered entity shall demonstrate the ability to manage Federal funds and submit to the Secretary a comprehensive plan describing how such entity will use such funds to develop and sustain unmanned aircraft system training and operations. Such entity shall include in the comprehensive plan information on—</text><paragraph id="HC9B12101692C471EA9FA74D97221BBC5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administration and oversight for any program proposed to be established using such grant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H519E9E7631DA4554B07A8645B4336419" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>risk management procedures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H535E13BFE73B452383AAD50522FF8F27" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>airspace coordination and safety protocols;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC063575490A5459EAFC094A879C877E8" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>certified personnel rosters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80131638A1F14BEFA2BFDE21CD8FC700" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>equipment maintenance schedules;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE325DFE065B84DA8A46CBBACDB7EED84" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>data and privacy protections; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E7BA6794BB4F5EAF8BDBBF7CF1EE35" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>legal compliance documentation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90E7D07D244340D3A4587043B2BA503F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>With respect to a training program established with a grant awarded under this section, a covered entity shall—</text><paragraph id="H76C2B27C4CC24DF4A095FF0D601A139E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operate or administer such program in accordance with applicable Federal law and regulations, which may include section 44807 of title 49, United States Code, or parts 91 or 107 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, as applicable, and—</text><subparagraph id="H7FDD28F7CBD744D0B1A0CBF3BFE1ED30"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">National Wildfire Coordinating Group Standard A–450 or S–373;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D175B9887DF4D93A29E8003C8741A98"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ASTM International Standard F3266, F3330, or F3370; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB3B4D6D2B1249F68CAFC3C55D42DB7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">National Fire Protection Association Standard 2400; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE8367CB614B40C9B658C72F8DFDAD2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure—</text><subparagraph id="HD78CC2EE56434371BF82520169F7E303"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the curriculum for such program is maintained by, or licensed through, a national nonprofit public safety organization or a nonprofit emergency response training entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D0F30B0C3FF42A7B9415238F6F57623"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that such curriculum remains consistent with operational standards and reflects mission specific public safety training needs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H064CCA7E1E3741C28E5DE2DFBF611B42"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that any modification to such curriculum is subject to the approval of the organization through which the curriculum is maintained or licensed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD936C08D202146B28C195C6E667D5100"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize selecting covered entities who—</text><paragraph id="H829FC10FDE934B71A5283D1E9C6C63A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engage in high risk operations or operate in underserved regions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3D302D8BC4B486AAEDA56BA03391E8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrate multi-agency or regional coordination;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FD7E2A94FDF4B4EBEBCE1102EBE384E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>propose to carry out training that is consistent with Federal Aviation Administration, National Wildfire Coordinating Group, and National Fire Protection Association standards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE727CDD9166E47E491A9AFB6FE6B1644"><enum>(4)</enum><text>lack the capacity for unmanned aircraft systems training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECC190440FD840E2A07DB9D7E0230B9E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HD27A405BA7B34333B6097C82D9D49816"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report by recipient</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each recipient of a grant awarded under this section shall, not less frequently than annually, submit to the Secretary a report containing the following information:</text><subparagraph id="HF9D307B291C744FD81649176BFD7E239"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and type of personnel trained using such grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H297C0AD0B7A24CDDAFFE2E0E223BE2E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of certifications of public safety UAS instructors under subsection (b)(4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1851AEE128534766832D470791998178"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of instructors participating in any training provided using such grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE8F9C3458948F791E4882F54BC8C36"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of unmanned aircraft system deployments carried out by such recipient after completion of training carried out with such grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7141C073DC04E7CBD4A30F2202FAC7D" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Challenges or recommendations related to a program established using such grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8F8A96B3CC64BB599C7304704CF2412"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report by Secretary</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the grant program carried out under this section that contains the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H89477ACBD966498782E26633DBF52E75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of grant recipients, disaggregated by region and type of entity receiving such grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58A94D729C6741F090EE8DC5FE357767"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A summary of progress made in building unmanned aircraft system training capacity across the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H271188D2EA7E484DA4CDED34A57F97A2" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any recommendations for improvements to training standards and the grant program established under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H277C29582BC94852851E1D4CBBAF030C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF60DFAAC42B44EC2AF9F403F07CC1EB4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certified remote pilot</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>certified remote pilot</quote> means a pilot certified to operate an unmanned aircraft system under part 107 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, or under a valid public aircraft operation or Federal Aviation Administration authorization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5263F42BA80E42C4BBFB82BFC7DCA096"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2D57068AD0E047398955B8EDA3CADF9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a governmental or nonprofit fire department, emergency medical service, or law enforcement agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4651A413AF84845BB873D6220FD1F6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State or regional public safety training academy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA814823A291F44588BE5269111EA6A2A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an interagency unmanned aircraft system collaborative; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC4923F92424B24B828DD7D95432DAA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a nonprofit public safety training organization that—</text><clause id="H6834EE4276D3409A940754AC891228DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has demonstrated a national presence in public safety education;</text></clause><clause id="HAB76C847F4514733A4BD3677AC5B9C5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintains a primary mission focused on emergency response readiness; and</text></clause><clause id="HE581A6193F884882B20859516458E3CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has a documented history of partnerships with Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, or local public safety agencies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EAEDEB8DAFB4C58A75DC1C52E1A0DAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emergency medical service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>emergency medical service</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>emergency medical services</quote> under section 553(e) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290ee-10">42 U.S.C. 290ee–10(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF63CBAD0941E4A0AA3D521B294954B38"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High risk operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>high risk operation</quote> means an unmanned aircraft mission conducted in an environment, condition, or for purposes where a loss of control, system, failure, or operational error could reasonably be expected to result in serious injury or death, substantial property damage, or disruption to public safety or critical infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H994BE1225733421194CE340B1B195057"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interagency unmanned aircraft system collaborative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>interagency unmanned aircraft system collaborative</quote> means a formal partnership, task force, or mutual aid framework involving 2 or more governmental or nonprofit public safety or emergency response agencies that jointly develop, operate, or coordinate unmanned aircraft system training and deployment to support all-hazards response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF943EFEF08E46C2A8CBDC637852CC04"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nonprofit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nonprofit</quote>, with respect to a covered entity, means an entity that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07047309596B447787D69816DF44A8C0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public safety UAS instructor</header><text>The term <quote>public safety UAS instructor</quote> means an instructor providing training for unmanned aircraft system operations conducted for the purpose of emergency response at or on behalf of a covered entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94F4D00525AE44DEB8F5B23898A7287B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The term <quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA38C48A702534513A8F7214B3E2C0CF5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

