<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26281-JKC-6V-3JX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 731 IS: Recognizing the 175th anniversary of the founding of Alpha Delta Pi Sorority.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 731</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 175th anniversary of the founding of Alpha Delta Pi Sorority.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Alpha Delta Pi Sorority was founded as the Adelphean Society on May 15, 1851, at Wesleyan Female College in Macon, Georgia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alpha Delta Pi Sorority was the first secret society for college women, founded at the first college chartered to grant degrees to women;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the recognized founders of Alpha Delta Pi Sorority include Eugenia Tucker Fitzgerald, Mary Evans Glass, Octavia Andrew Rush, Ella Pierce Turner, Sophronia Woodruff Dews, and Elizabeth Williams Mitchell;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas membership of Alpha Delta Pi Sorority stands at over 290,000 lifetime initiates as of the date of introduction of this resolution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alpha Delta Pi Sorority, headquartered in Atlanta, Georgia, has established chapters at over 220 colleges and universities across the United States and Canada and has 165 active alumnae associations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alpha Delta Pi Sorority is a private membership organization whose mission is to provide women with a meaningful lifelong experience that empowers them to reach their full potential through leadership, educational, philanthropic, and social opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the objects set forth by the Adelphean Society were the mental, moral, social, and domestic improvement of its members, and Alpha Delta Pi Sorority now recognizes the core values of sisterhood, service, character, and knowledge to be the guideposts by which all members live;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alpha Delta Pi Sorority, whose open motto is <quote>We Live For Each Other</quote>, whose collegians log over 300,000 community service hours annually, and whose platforms regularly educate members and the public about the dangers of hazing and the importance of sisterhood in relation to wellness and belonging, consistently raises over $1,000,000 per year for Ronald McDonald House;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alpha Delta Pi Sorority counts among its alumnae 1 Academy Award winner, 6 Emmy Award winners, 2 Grammy Award winners, 4 New York Times bestselling authors, 6 United States Olympians, 2 Pulitzer Prize-winning journalists, and 1 recipient of the Walter Cronkite Award for Excellence in Journalism and the Peabody Award for Journalistic Integrity, is home to 2 sitting United States Representatives and 1 sitting United States Senator as of the date of introduction of this resolution, and can claim several <quote>firsts</quote>, including the first Treasurer of the United States to be named National Director of the Savings Bond Division and the first woman to hold the highest education post in the Federal Government; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alpha Delta Pi Sorority will hold its 175th Anniversary Grand Convention in Palm Desert, California, from June 17 through June 20, 2026: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide95a2d896c6d4048912212e9f107e49f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates Alpha Delta Pi Sorority on the occasion of its 175th anniversary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id563631d11d534d0380a518aa3ac2502c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the contributions of Alpha Delta Pi members to education, science and technology, the arts, athletics, government, the military, business, and community service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e6289dc7e9f4b6891f9f34ee87aef19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the members of Alpha Delta Pi Sorority for their lifelong commitment to personal growth, friendship, and community enrichment.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

