<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF381D019A03B4ADB98AA6507D677DEF9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6626 IH: PFAS Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6626</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to codify a Federal cause of action and a type of remedy available for individuals significantly exposed to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, to encourage research and accountability for irresponsible discharge of those substances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H21AD8CF271AF487AA9AB8CB5214B4EB0" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB824EC0C04C441E2AC939C1E421ADD47"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PFAS Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB65D613D18D54001BE80094EBDE18EB4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds thatã</text>
<paragraph id="HA9397B7FB8EB41F18457693F54246064"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has detected numerous perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances (referred to in this Act as <term>PFAS</term>) in the blood serum of individuals in the United States, all of which come from manufacturing and use of PFAS by humans, as there is no natural source of PFAS in human blood;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F7B367ECA3D49598FBF8F68118FB216"><enum>(2)</enum><text>peer-reviewed studies by other organizations have detected PFAS in the drinking water of at least 200,000,000 individuals in the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H272CED989B224838ABABB56B8E80020B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>PFAS are introduced into the market every year, and little research is conducted to ensure the safety of PFAS for individuals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47871546CCD04AA59E0EF1F9BFB94550"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act, a Federal statutory cause of action does not exist for individuals harmed by the long-term effects of PFAS exposure; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFBCEA547ACD6462FB379E2744A5A8D1B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>PFAS exposure, even at low levels, has been linked to chronic diseases, including cancer, reproductive and developmental harms, and harms to the immune system.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H93B7E01D6FBB46B89009F2B7F1630617"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act areã</text>
<paragraph id="H20CED571CB8B465B90779CA4978B810E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to encourage PFAS research and provide accountability for irresponsible PFAS manufacturing and irresponsible use of PFAS in manufacturing by codifyingã</text> <subparagraph id="H1A5A2E30AE2845ACB9A1096E02A25D0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal cause of action for individuals significantly exposed to PFAS; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE4B7105CFFB244F98C9D062EC471ABD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a medical monitoring remedy for those individuals;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6E154909E774CE489F2C6CD20B1A63F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to help address harm to individuals significantly exposed to PFAS byã</text>
<subparagraph id="H81F304E2C83B42A68779D57C77C2F5CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">codifying that harm as an injury at law and equity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97657317F8A24F258365DC77E520AD43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shifting the costs of medical monitoring from those individuals to the parties responsible for the exposure; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADB742B40511408DA453D0849B628FDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide incentives for industry to fund PFAS safety research.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H77DAB0E201394A12A44F52DF81672349"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cause of action and remedies</header> <subsection id="HADEAB360A7104B348DA175E2798F097E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Toxic Substances Control Act is amended by inserting after section 24 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2623">15 U.S.C. 2623</external-xref>) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37292762D13340AE88CB4688612E7799">
<section id="H7C9DEB8236A44B798FDCECCB0ABAB3E0"><enum>25.</enum><header>Individuals exposed to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H811BD1DD0BB746609B3A872A669C090C"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of PFAS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>PFAS</term> means a perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance with at least 1 fully fluorinated carbon atom.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H106B4A74D2CE4FC6815503B5B8EC712F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>An individual who is significantly exposed to PFAS or has reasonable grounds to suspect that the individual was significantly exposed to PFAS may bring a claim, individually or on behalf of a class of similarly situated individuals, in any district court of the United States for appropriate legal and equitable relief against any person thatã</text>
<paragraph id="H8B83C833BBB641EFB99152C0E41615A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engaged in any portion of a manufacturing process that created the PFAS to which the individual was significantly exposed, including any telomer, fluorôÙoôÙsurôÙfactôÙant, or toll manufacturing process leading to the creation of the PFAS to which the individual was significantly exposed; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9842FBB4C6274BE1A78C4DDA3DEC45CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>foresaw or reasonably should have foreseen that the creation or use of PFAS would result in human exposure to PFAS.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H688C3B8B48A144EDB5185DCDDF322707"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medical monitoring</header>
<paragraph id="H2A16DF0A35AA4C26ABD76CA1EF20B959"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A court may award medical monitoring to an individual or class of individuals bringing a claim under subsection (b) ifã</text> <subparagraph id="H90A5F8324792405EA62ACED6120AD90A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual or class has been significantly exposed to PFAS;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD6E04CB442064BE6B09CDF1E5741E4A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as a result of that exposure, the individual or class has suffered an increased risk of developing a disease associated with exposure to PFAS;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H58A044A87DD143B19074D05D128BD08C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as a result of that increased risk, there is a reasonable basis for the individual or class to undergo periodic diagnostic medical examinations of a nature or frequency that is different from or additional to what would be prescribed in the absence of the exposure; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1695235AE7A44ABDBFCF74ED30012102"><enum>(D)</enum><text>those medical examinations are effective in detecting a disease associated with exposure to PFAS.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0247C4CCB7C942398B5BF2C3FF76A48C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Presumption of significant exposure</header> <subparagraph id="H409F613F7F04429896008B28EDDD2FCF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Individuals</header><text>An individual plaintiff shall be presumed to have been significantly exposed to PFAS under paragraph (1)(A) if the individualã</text>
<clause id="HE72B951DC87943CBBAAD08F2A20C39A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrates thatã</text> <subclause id="HA5AFE133EDE4420D84CB2714DA04F43F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the defendant engaged in any portion of a manufacturing process that created the PFAS to which the individual was significantly exposed, including any telomer, fluorôÙoôÙsurôÙfactôÙant, or toll manufacturing process leading to the creation of the PFAS to which the individual was significantly exposed; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE8D8273D3AA84289B8F41E8C0F535DC4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the PFAS described in subclause (I) were released into 1 or more areas where the individual would have been exposed for a cumulative period of not less than 1 year; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H59BAAE25198749A69E2748B35C5A48E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>offers testing results that demonstrate that PFAS or metabolites of PFAS have been or are currently detected in the body or blood serum of the individual.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE59F88C215F44E448CA3088D566997BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Class actions</header><text>In a class action, a presumption of significant exposure to PFAS under paragraph (1)(A) shall be established for the class byã</text> <clause id="H914064A171EB4CECA8432E050DEA832A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrating thatã</text>
<subclause id="H75445101B5984507A7CC91B02B2C5CBD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the defendant engaged in any portion of a manufacturing process that created the PFAS to which the class members were significantly exposed, including any telomer, fluorosurfactant, or toll manufacturing process leading to the creation of the PFAS to which the class members were significantly exposed; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD6FEF279F76A499C9D712D3E1D84544D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the PFAS described in subclause (I) were released into 1 or more areas where a representative portion of the class members would have been exposed for a cumulative period of not less than 1 year; or</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HC33C13CF76C64776B790CF5FC0FD30F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>offering testing results that demonstrate that PFAS or metabolites of PFAS have been or are currently detected in the bodies of a representative portion of class members that share sufficient common exposure characteristics with the class.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H627326A0AFFA4B319A10A845BEFFA98F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rebutting the presumption</header> <subparagraph id="HDEFBCD849E0A4067B0FA6680BC7BCDFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A defendant may rebut a presumption of significant exposure with respect to an individual plaintiff or class member for which testing results are not offered under subparagraph (A)(ii) or (B)(ii) of paragraph (2) by offering results for that individual or class member of testing thatã</text>
<clause id="H551BE61FBFBA46FD9CF13E98F82B8EB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>uses a generally accepted method for detecting the particular PFAS or metabolites of PFAS at issue;</text></clause> <clause id="H10E0BC51A2784779B24884A9E58EDC71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is performed by an independent provider agreed on by both parties; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3C13F125616B49D7A96F2142F4B6DEBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>confirms that the relevant PFAS or metabolites of PFAS likely were not present in the body of the individual or class member at the relevant time in a sufficient quantity to qualify as significant exposure under paragraph (1)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36C26851FE204F1FBC069EA37F2747B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>A defendant shall be responsible for the costs of testing under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A35FCCB756B4A06963C844270ABC1B4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Independent provider</header><text>If both parties cannot agree on an independent provider under subparagraph (A)(ii), the court shall appoint an independent provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E1FC9F2D84443F9923E48D740B83D54"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Increased risk of developing disease</header> <subparagraph id="H37B33628D0184E4FB86412FCC08D6C00"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If there is insufficient toxicological data to reasonably determine whether an individual or class has suffered an increased risk of developing a disease associated with exposure to any individual PFAS or group of PFAS under paragraph (1)(B), a court may lower the standard for scientific proof with regard to the increased risk of developing that disease until independent and reliable toxicological data is available with respect to that individual PFAS or group of PFAS.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE24E26311B3A4BB6928C2B67EE5B2EA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ordering studies</header><text>To make available independent and reliable toxicological data described in subparagraph (A) with respect to an individual PFAS or group of PFAS, a court may order new or additional epidemiological, toxicological, or other studies or investigations of that individual PFAS or group of PFAS as part of a medical monitoring remedy awarded under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD2063FFBE0124A7A80F52C3DC8B4A989"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that courts should encourage more reliable and independent research into the latent health effects of PFAS.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HCE002E08F0A14778A1785DECBFFF8C78"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect on State law claims and remedies</header><text>Nothing in this sectionã</text> <paragraph id="HC1248C97548D4FC6AFB53E7E4653C317"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preempts, alters, bars, or precludes any State law claims or remedies, including any State law claims or remedies for an injury addressed by this section; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H43C26466CD5544D9992AD1719BB8C6C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides an exclusive claim or remedy.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDED3043D080640E2BBE71761CAD6B1C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Toxic Substances Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/469">Public Law 94ã469</external-xref>; 90 Stat. 2003) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 24 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1827D0857076470E9E6C5F337D087317">
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H7C9DEB8236A44B798FDCECCB0ABAB3E0">Sec. 25. Individuals exposed to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

