<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C57E797B0E94A29BB189224F416CB1F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9355 IH: Don't Settle for Corruption Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9355</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to reform the process for payment of certain compromise settlements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6984086291AF49F2AB0372552668019E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H67E5228B71C2466E94A37C5B3157ABD5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Don't Settle for Corruption Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H89C2C572916E4F239579B1D61C4A4E1E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on certain payments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2414 of title 28, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H4A77977A53F24E159A99D5F4156C84B1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HF6B50645CBFB4456ABE194DED9C43EDF"><enum>2414.</enum><header>Payment of judgments and compromise settlements</header> <subsection id="H0B3572530A3E43EF82C4A707D88E25C6"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 41, payment of final judgments rendered by a district court or the Court of International Trade against the United States shall be made on settlements by the Secretary of the Treasury. Payment of final judgments rendered by a State or foreign court or tribunal against the United States, or against its agencies or officials upon obligations or liabilities of the United States, shall be made on settlements by the Secretary of the Treasury after certification by the Attorney General that it is in the interest of the United States to pay the same.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H552F77BF39C7462ABF4A2D69D3C39216"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever the Attorney General determines that no appeal shall be taken from a judgment or that no further review will be sought from a decision affirming the same, he shall so certify and the judgment shall be deemed final.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9ED68BE533FA47FABBAA1F709E17D34C"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by law, and subject to enactment of a resolution in the case of a covered settlement, compromise settlements of claims referred to the Attorney General for defense of imminent litigation or suits against the United States, or against its agencies or officials upon obligations or liabilities of the United States, made by the Attorney General or any person authorized by him, shall be settled and paid in a manner similar to judgments in like causes and appropriations or funds available for the payment of such judgments are hereby made available for the payment of such compromise settlements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF593A41AF476482DBEFBC5B8540EA2F3"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall expeditiously submit a report, bearing an identification number, setting forth the terms of a covered settlement to both Houses of Congress on the same day and to each House while it is in session.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEA597A86CDE945FAABE59FCCE899CD03"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No proposal for a covered settlement may be considered approved unless during the period beginning on the date on which the report under subsection (d) is received by Congress and ending 60 days thereafter a resolution described in subsection (f) is enacted.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2E76E678DDC45CB94B8048AC619C9B5">
                        <enum>(f)</enum>
 <text>For the purpose of this section, the term <quote>resolution</quote> means only a joint resolution of the Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That the____approves the covered settlement numbered___submitted to the Congress on____</quote>, the first blank space therein being filled with the name of the resolving House and the other blank spaces being appropriately filled.</text>
                    </subsection> 
<subsection id="H36F1C7DD33C44C90B0452DE508256192"><enum>(g)</enum><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered settlement</quote> means any compromise settlement for defense of imminent litigation or suit by the President or a former President against the United States, or against its agencies or officials upon obligations or liabilities of the United States.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

