<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC0770FFCD51648BE9D06BB9A76FD0829" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7054 IH: To require the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a notification of certain construction projects using nonstandard designs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7054</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a notification of certain construction projects using nonstandard designs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6AD9C7FFAB014938BA6092379F0F0A7B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC40BAD5BB37544BCBEC213573122990E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Notification required for nonstandard construction</header> 
<subsection id="H355FE48329AE4C8C973CB13F795727EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Bureau of Overseas Building Operations of the Department of State, or any successor office, shall, to the greatest extent possible, give appropriate consideration to standardization in construction, such that each new United States embassy and consulate starts with a standard design and keeps customization to a minimum.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5F22B1860EFB4AD5BB4428CA9E470B3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional notification required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may only carry out a covered project that uses a nonstandard design if, not later than 15 days prior to the obligation of funds for such project, the Secretary submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of such project, including the following information:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4CFB476E77904AAF988C6B6CDF8ABA05" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A comparison of the estimated full lifecycle cost of the project to the estimated full lifecycle cost of such project if such project were constructed using a standard design.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A646856C22647D0A9D2067C33779AD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of the estimated completion date of such project to the estimated completion date of such project if such project were constructed using a standard design.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C094CF7C4184E4792B38585A0F33AE5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of the security of the completed project to the security of such completed project if such project were constructed using a standard design.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA09BAC9942E540B7BA61091C37C754CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A justification for the Secretary’s selection of a nonstandard design over a standard design for such project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9E136230F7B4BD692DE4509D1C254DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Documentation to support the information required in paragraphs (1) through (4) or, if any such documentation cannot be provided, an explanation as to why such documentation cannot be provided. </text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H1468098DA1DD45D684FC28708DA28B9C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B60E47404504E399683C3F996E827BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H210C963A035C4195A09B53C707CD1C43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H95DB962106F144BB831452D5937BE1FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC08A0A6DB9C7473AB559033C45AC6C1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered project</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFC77A311D026481982C20D7D764B6C56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a project to construct a new United States embassy compound or new United States consulate compound; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE9182E407CD426EA650C8B4E76945BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes such projects that are in the design or pre-design phase on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

