<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H59BE070E8BAA4DFDAAC8AC9E49BED1B3" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 67 IH: Authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the lying in state of the remains of Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar, and of Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard, of the Iowa National Guard.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 67</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251215">December 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the lying in state of the remains of Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar, and of Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard, of the Iowa National Guard.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4F4F4D0C23B94244B7EF9B516702C58C"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H594C5E1A225F4519AB2FE980C6249F54"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That, in recognition of Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar and Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard, who served with distinction in the 1st Squadron of the 113th Cavalry Regiment of the Iowa National Guard, their remains shall be permitted to lie in state in the rotunda of the Capitol on a date to be determined by the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Architect of the Capitol, under the direction of the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, shall take all necessary steps for the accomplishment of that purpose. </text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

