<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-ELM26060-W84-D6-KJJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 793 ATS: A resolution congratulating the Johnson County Community College Cavaliers on winning the 2026 National Junior College Athletic Association Division I Baseball National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 793</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution congratulating the Johnson County Community College Cavaliers on winning the 2026 National Junior College Athletic Association Division I Baseball National Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Johnson County Community College Cavaliers baseball team won the 2026 National Junior College Athletic Association Division I Baseball National Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cavaliers finished the 2026 season with an extraordinary record of 67 wins and 3 losses, one of the most successful seasons in junior college baseball history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Johnson County Community College secured its first National Junior College Athletic Association Division I Baseball National Championship with an 8–5 victory over Blinn College at the Alpine Bank Junior College World Series in Grand Junction, Colorado;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in a memorable semifinal game, the Cavaliers overcame a 6–run deficit in the eighth inning against Midland College to advance to the championship game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cavaliers demonstrated exceptional perseverance, teamwork, and dedication throughout the season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Head Coach Eric Horner provided outstanding leadership in directing the team to the first national championship in program history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the accomplishments of the Cavaliers have brought great pride to Johnson County and the State of Kansas; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the student-athletes of the Johnson County Community College Cavaliers baseball team have distinguished themselves through their skill and sportsmanship: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id8f4f71bffbb44d70ac99a507bb3c48c2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Johnson County Community College Cavaliers baseball team on winning the 2026 National Junior College Athletic Association Division I Baseball National Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id060b303c07b0423497abeba4644d608a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the student-athletes, coaches, staff, and supporters whose dedication contributed to this historic achievement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id422b1a89c6f740259b0bf960fd1a72f6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>wishes the members of the Johnson County Community College Cavaliers baseball team continued success in their future endeavors.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

