<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9C2CA9356855432AB47B2D3CE378E3B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7503 IH: Housing for Heroes Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7503</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand the eligibility of properties for the Good Neighbor Next Door Sales Program for members of the Armed Forces, firefighters, and law enforcement officials, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC431A15D026F4387AA5C818F7A77AF0B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD5F13ECD5AB24AC8B7DD0FFF3B46BBF2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing for Heroes Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA6E8A1A8C33A46649EC264C4B07A4FD7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Eligibility of properties for members of the Armed Forces, firefighters, and law enforcement officers for Good Neighbor Next Door Sales Program</header> 
<subsection id="H57016BDC5E9847F387450AE2AF3DA731"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Armed Forces, firefighters, and law enforcement officers shall be eligible to purchase eligible properties under the Good Neighbor Next Door Sales Program of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, as provided under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF97E3839C4EE43859BCA9527AD79AF9F"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Eligible properties</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 204 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1710">12 U.S.C. 1710</external-xref>), part 291 of the regulations of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (24 CFR part 291), or any other provision of law, regulation, guideline, order, or notice, in carrying out the Good Neighbor Next Door Sales Program for single-unit properties acquired by the Secretary, properties shall be made available for purchase under the Program for members of the Armed Forces, firefighters, and law enforcement officers without regard to whether or not the properties are located in a revitalization area.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9023C30247EA43768D69872B4BD52D0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall amend the regulations of the Secretary as necessary to carry out subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

