<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1925E0E06F5945AD9346FD7A4042A15E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6687 IH: Data Rights for Information and Vehicle Electronics in Real-time Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6687</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require manufacturers of motor vehicles to provide motor vehicle owners with access to and use of motor vehicle data of motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9AB3A9EFF169409B83A3B73813603028" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9A86251BAB67458C9486E0AD33728843" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Data Rights for Information and Vehicle Electronics in Real-time Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DRIVER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB697F89AC17A40EE9FCA20AE0EF21B4B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Motor vehicle owner access to motor vehicle data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A manufacturer of a motor vehicle shall provide to a motor vehicle owner secure access to, and joint control of, any motor vehicle data of the motor vehicle of such motor vehicle owner as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC8079DB9CB584F659CABB1083B5A0E46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>At no cost beyond the purchase price of such motor vehicle.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8ED251D46C947119F2A1DBF45ECA4A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In real time.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87D7E508E1F344EA969814D3F65AE3DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Without any restriction or limitation with respect to the manner in which such motor vehicle owner, for any lawful purpose—</text> <subparagraph id="HCCEAAEE4811C4DFBB9678ABC1BA73637"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses such motor vehicle data; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H891B28CCC66243CEA5CE46AA106BE0CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorizes access to or use of such motor vehicle data by a third party, other than a person owned or controlled by a foreign adversary (as defined in section 791.2 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E63E2C2619E497790FB9DA09B87330E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Without a requirement that such motor vehicle owner pay a fee or purchase a license to decrypt such motor vehicle data or use a device provided by such manufacturer to access and use such motor vehicle data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H397ED9657EE14D0BAC6B44CB51670714"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Through a motor vehicle interface port (such as an on-board diagnostics port) of such motor vehicle and through wireless transmission of such motor vehicle data (to the extent such motor vehicle is equipped with technology to wirelessly transmit such motor vehicle data).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H33272EC792C14A6784581633AACACCE0" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a manner that facilitates the deletion of any user data stored in such motor vehicle.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1584AA7247B340DBB82740B8A92FAB79" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In compliance with any voluntary automotive industry cybersecurity standards requirements (such as ISO/SAE 24134).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H2A3908AA2C164348998BE8ADE2C43207"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional motor vehicle owner data access controls</header> <subsection id="H42DB822FF2BF43D6A73D985FE666D711"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vehicle owners’ data access control with respect to motor vehicle manufacturers</header><text>A manufacturer of a motor vehicle may not, with respect to a motor vehicle manufactured by such manufacturer, sell any covered data unless the manufacturer provides to the motor vehicle owner of such motor vehicle a clear and conspicuous opportunity to opt out of any such sale.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC04DB530968D4B2A85D0B9FABEBA0527"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fleet vehicle drivers’ data access control with respect to motor vehicle fleet owners</header> 
<paragraph id="H129DC221F0F44C3290C95D56160417A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A motor vehicle fleet owner may not, with respect to a motor vehicle that such motor vehicle fleet owner leases or in which such motor vehicle fleet owner has an ownership or contracted beneficial interest, sell any covered data, unless the motor vehicle fleet owner provides to the driver or operator of such motor vehicle a clear and conspicuous opportunity to opt out of any such sale.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAE4A52FE01F45E68DD04B2B57CF6D74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to provide an opportunity to opt out described in paragraph (1) does not apply if the relevant data is generated by a commercial or governmental fleet vehicle driven by a driver in the course of the employment of the driver, except if such driver behavior data is to be sold for the purpose of profiling in furtherance of decisions that knowingly cause negative legal or similarly significant harmful effects concerning the conduct of a person outside the course of the employment of the person.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H46900312D6304A94A4FD2DF24E62794F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National security</header><text>A manufacturer of a motor vehicle or a motor vehicle fleet owner may not knowingly sell motor vehicle data to any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H92BD7A351E404E92A9E5B35283BE75D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7072F1786C5B4D279AEF483235AE59E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EBA41DAD8E643EDB2E230F3B144685A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Russian Federation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DDD7AF22C4F46789690DCF8759FD147"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CA729E05BBB47CCA60F8CFEEA07B6E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H10E4D4FA70E24C5395267C301897B04A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>For purposes of this section, a sale does not include any of the following activities:</text> <paragraph id="H9225971E65E14FFEA097B96722323816"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Transferring covered data to emergency responders.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF38507C1F3FE4703A6288900C7D483C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Responding to an owner-initiated communication originating from within a motor vehicle or an app, where covered data may be transferred only to provide the response.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8715872914D74DCD8763DDBBADEAEFFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Responding to a vehicle-initiated communication related to the safe operation of a motor vehicle, where covered data may be transferred only to provide the response.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H025288B118C946D29F90F5837784A894"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Responding to a driver or user-initiated communication originating from within a motor vehicle or an app, where covered data may be transferred only to provide the response.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F7B398973B4436FA7283E6F8A3597FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Conducting research or efforts to improve, repair, enhance the safety of, or develop products, services, or technology.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44422EC176104E73B97F249B24953228"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Investigating or defending claims and losses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25E52E61E7444242A3FA63017AA33BDE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Conducting investigations of potential product quality, fraud, theft, or safety issues.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86E22D7C91D64BA18FD2F592D7AF9730"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Determining or effectuating vehicle field actions, including customer satisfaction campaigns, technical service bulletins, compliance recalls, and safety recalls.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2691530C210F4752B33B4FA07FFC5880"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Detecting or responding to cybersecurity incidents.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H721A67345EDC44E8A50092F625ADC968"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Administering and fulfilling motor vehicle warranties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FC6BE33E6C64DB4B75520E8D042BC20"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Performing diagnostics and prognostics of a motor vehicle or a component of a motor vehicle.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C47043D32DD48D18A94226DDD663C23"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying and addressing issues that impair functionality.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC0D336732144955B57A736FE86A2CC8"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disclosing covered data to a processor that processes such covered data on behalf of a manufacturer of a motor vehicle or a motor vehicle fleet owner.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE57CAFC864140FBBD63BCCA37D40039"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Disclosing or transferring covered data to an affiliate of a manufacturer of a motor vehicle or a motor vehicle fleet owner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF57310C3A59F48CA8B07E5E3450A254A"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Disclosing information that a consumer—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0EB4F9C012D6440489B39701894999EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intentionally makes available to the general public through a channel of mass media; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3BFD444B4974923B22B22A43F51DF4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not restrict to a specific audience.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DECA9B8A4FD4451ABA8D92FC987AA2F"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disclosing or transferring covered data to a third party as an asset that is part of a proposed or an actual merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or other transaction in which the third party assumes control of all or part of the assets of a controller.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9CA184F2675465D81D76C66D20E54FF"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Complying with a lawfully executed warrant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91DD38AEF1664142A9C441F24ABEF507"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Complying with a court order.</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H0DE316A9539649C8B53C82C9203F1085"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement by Commission</header> <subsection id="HE78E980AFC6742FAA49D822D63D02D84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of section 2 shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2F8A535EE614FB1AE4844077E91BBCC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce section 2 in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act, and any person who violates such section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H516A1EDD448E48D7A10EB10CCE85930B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Disclosure of confidential business information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 2, nothing in this Act shall be construed to require a motor vehicle manufacturer to divulge confidential business information (as defined in section 512.3(c) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations).</text> </section> 
<section id="H94C158E55FF74FFABF24D9CE353649A0" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No State, or political subdivision of a State, may maintain, enforce, prescribe, or continue in effect any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law that relates to section 2 of this Act.</text></section> <section id="H102C1E6BC3D54D57A662056708419B04"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1F430A3BF078457196CAA7CAC3B9DBED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biometric identifier</header><text>The term <term>biometric identifier</term> means motor vehicle data generated by automatic measurements relating to biological characteristics of an individual that are any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3CC1D37AC5EB4CD1A497DBB2E682E845"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Fingerprints.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H521FAFD9B8DB4BA782A0D7980F9B34D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facial features.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FA91329D5394AE59306E5E5DC465087"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Iris or retina patterns.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4850A65C30814073AFBE14E90B27786B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Gait.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32709A53878F42CB90C55DA25287365E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Voice.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE0AB34DB53843A398525F03D1FCFD4A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Body measurements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4ED139388FA403586A23E8269E3B499"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Weight.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B67DA11B5854B9C8C7A7CE3120ACC4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E96AA22BD6043FEA95D92506ADECF4C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered data</header> <subparagraph id="H0FB08741281B4728A0962E653731DE8A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered data</term>—</text> 
<clause id="HEC1291D450B34CCFBBA5DDA53CCBE0E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means personal data that relates to a biometric identifier, precise geolocation, or driver behavior with respect to a motor vehicle owner (or a driver or other user of a motor vehicle of such motor vehicle owner); and</text></clause> <clause id="HEB40DE07365B40AF8F466EA86A615FD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes personal data received by such motor vehicle from a personal device of such motor vehicle owner, driver, or other user of a motor vehicle.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA856B0A8A5EB42598359ED8FFE0C0234"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered data</term> does not include deidentified, pseudonymous, aggregate, or publicly available information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9964402A1F774978879CA4E8725DA299"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Driver behavior</header><text>The term <term>driver behavior</term> means motor vehicle data that is used for the purpose of profiling in furtherance of decisions that knowingly cause a negative legal or similarly significant harmful effect concerning the conduct of a motor vehicle owner outside the course of the employment of the motor vehicle owner.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H648744DE0A2D4434A5572D6D5A5566B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>motor vehicle</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HF7BAE3C187364C8ABB588B022ADDFD11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11184873303C4B0B8ABAF6AB8BC15FBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a motor vehicle trailer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01A69E45C8074853ACE6DED998785B38"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Motor vehicle data</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle data</term> means electronic data generated or processed onboard a motor vehicle, including data generated by sensors, receivers, computer processing units, and other components of the motor vehicle.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAFC56A0510F45AD92AC7E54077C9361"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Motor vehicle fleet owner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>motor vehicle fleet owner</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA5888F3C97547DBAC5196746371476B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a person—</text> 
<clause id="HDC65788B73C146F9863069F53A5F7ABA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with an ownership or contracted beneficial interest in 5 or more motor vehicles; or</text></clause> <clause id="HC7382E40600D42619494E9C7D8C1095C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who is the lessee of a motor vehicle under a lease agreement with a term of at least 180 days; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA906CE2021574EC9B04C4A236FA870CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a designee of a motor vehicle owner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CB3DC20AC2948529A1B42E9A7300CEC" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Motor vehicle owner</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle owner</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H04472896AD5D4FA897A61561BF9C0042" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an owner of a motor vehicle; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2F14E07C95F4F3EAFD43D4187D25681" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> 
<clause id="HF7AA9911DF0047B9BB2AD40AAB5F1939" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a designee of such owner;</text></clause> <clause id="H9EA03E604AE14E17A6AE8C1C297BC074" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a person with an ownership or contracted beneficial interest in a motor vehicle; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA3854A5190EA42848CBBC33A5196B125" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a lessee of a motor vehicle under a lease agreement with a term of at least 180 days.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5B361332C064CB7B51D1665CE611E16"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Personal data</header><text>The term <term>personal data</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H19FEA2ADC4BE44B8B4B1B44FC1650536"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any motor vehicle data that is linked to an identified or identifiable natural person; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76B296AE5A2E4E38BBFF9C6326E9C298"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include deidentified, pseudonymous, aggregate, or publicly available information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBB41921797E4AA48B1C0E5240C69F36"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Precise geolocation</header><text>The term <term>precise geolocation</term> means motor vehicle data that directly identifies the specific location of a natural person with precision and accuracy within a radius of 1,750 feet.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF48CDEB1211E4EBE8363754AE92C21AF" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Sell; sells; sale</header><text>The terms <term>sell</term>, <term>sells</term>, and <term>sale</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2DD91FAFC7B642908470517C5D59BBEB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mean the exchange of data for monetary consideration; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8137704223774666B77B228B6EE744C2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">do not include when a driver or user of a motor vehicle requests a specific product or service from a manufacturer of a motor vehicle or a motor vehicle fleet owner that is necessary for such manufacturer or motor vehicle fleet owner to disclose such motor vehicle data to a third party to provide such service or product to such driver or user.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D55215EC56041D9869C237569746055"><enum>(12)</enum><header>User data</header><text>The term <term>user data</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H8C50F0B6A9344C7F9E53958AEC7AFA12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means data transferred from a personal or external device to a motor vehicle by a motor vehicle owner or user of such motor vehicle; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82C88B602DBD44F7B21075B87B1D4490"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include motor vehicle data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

