<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDE5442C9417A49FDBA330F7F0F80D883" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6785 IH: Championing Local Efforts to Advance Resilience Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6785</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to make grants to States, territories, and Indian tribes to support local resiliency offices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H04A22073FF5147BF9C6D19A796DB4268" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1A3884EEA1514A23A204517E7D590AAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Championing Local Efforts to Advance Resilience Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAR Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCA78A3A666E44A8BAEBCAF63498C111B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Resiliency office grants</header> <subsection id="HE41BD32F7C3644CAA8D76E141B8A331D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior, may make grants under this section to States, territories, and Indian tribes that are eligible for such grants pursuant to subsection (b) for use in accordance with subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9DA572A0872D4DCDABFD1F7A68EAE810"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State, territory, or Indian tribe shall establish and maintain, or show a plan and ability to establish and maintain, an office specifically responsible for issues relating to resilience and that has among its duties the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD38D0B90EDB3426AAABF64C4E2DE6C71"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop and update, not less frequently than every 5 years, a resiliency framework, in consultation with vulnerable and impacted communities, that identifies current and projected risks and vulnerabilities due to extreme weather and other challenges, and provides recommendations to address such risks and vulnerabilities, in each of the areas of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAC234C52BEA046E2ABBEAD4BA574018C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>environmental and natural hazards;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5C213F02BF64920A4FC4EA5E9F28B7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the economy and workforce;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFCBB76ADF29A410780540B0E8D7A2CED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69952F25F632431585CA669103E3F683"><enum>(D)</enum><text>health and social services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4DC212161954E45A6B0D10609CA8D4E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE6DB88F1AFE4ABEB695FE4BEC51B615"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To implement programming to address risks and vulnerabilities identified in the resiliency framework, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H968C5BD6D8BB4CBE8DCD77B40953E8D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to local governments for the implementation of resilience planning;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7A5107BFC9A478DA544EF8F5720FCDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting State, territory, or tribal agencies in the implementation of resilience policies and procedures;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3ECDAE1A7CC14BB89EB01A954BFFF669"><enum>(C)</enum><text>integrating resilience criteria into existing competitive grant funding administered by such office or State agencies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55075C1D19334E6999C3A40C5640B369"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting long-term community pre-disaster mitigation and recovery efforts and facilitating access to resources before and after a disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48A93D2003EC4BE89259F3D8C2386023"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To improve coordination among State, territory, or tribal agencies and regional and local jurisdictions to support community and economic recovery efforts and address risk and vulnerability reduction.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H30D3AE241E864C7ABE2ADBAE2A50008C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts from a grant under this section may be used by the grantee, or any unit of local government that is a subgrantee of such grantee, only for—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAC6930567FA142ADA7EF94C799B5D4B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">costs of establishing or maintaining, or both, a resiliency office and implementing resiliency programming, developing resilience planning and analytic tools, enhancing community planning and capacity, enhancing coordination among State, territory, or tribal agencies and regional and local jurisdictions and stakeholders, and providing technical assistance, in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2615040AA3024D4FBAAEBCD262EFA817"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payment of any non-Federal share required in connection with a Federal program undertaken to carry out any of the purposes of subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF8D23CB704F43588DBAAFF0B5EAE2D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To apply for a grant under this section, a State, territory, or Indian tribe shall submit an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may prescribe for establishing a formula-based grant program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD42A05DF96444B4B918CC11D8FE81518"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section to States or territories, the Secretary shall give priority to applications that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9707E7A67C0D44F1AA55486820994E36"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate the greatest need for assistance under this section, as determined by the Secretary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF2588A34FC94778BECB126026215AC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify vulnerabilities and risks in disadvantaged communities and prioritize projects to benefit such communities and promote equity in resilience;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFADB9FF3BFED44AB90AC846295A0A133"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate a broad approach to resilience, as such term is defined in subsection (j)(3); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDAA8DA5E7F14891825F98FDACFFECD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for subgrants to entities that adhere to prevailing wage provisions as published by the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2AA618B502BF41E7BF5B93401DF0276F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The Secretary shall award formula grants in an amount sufficient to provide funding to a grantee to cover a minimum of 24 months of grant activities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H617DC336F0FE4F158AA4DF37A42440BF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Interior, and such other heads of Federal agencies as the Secretary considers appropriate, provide technical assistance to grantees regarding developing resiliency frameworks and implementing resiliency strategies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC547A68964140EC8E8CF05506431756"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of any amounts made available for grants under this section, the Secretary may use 1.0 percent for—</text> <paragraph id="H9415A938BF174E798592CD661208DA72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the costs of administering the program under this section for such grants; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA365A8E5ABC4F5D9C432D2802116581"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for providing technical assistance—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B14103DBB254C68B1F3545C23BB0E3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to applicants for such grants; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09677B5A3268456A8403BA73371A6796"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under subsection (g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H829722DBB3AA4539B6A78A92262B3AC3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports to HUD</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which a grantee receives a grant under this section, the grantee shall submit a report to the Secretary regarding the use of such grant amounts, which shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD2A68BF4D6AA4D9E9127EFB195E5D624"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the activities undertaken by the grantee using such grant amounts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39CBF73DF8F1454D885880CA7B792CA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identification of the costs of each of the services provided using such grant amounts; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18AA01BE7BCC4C0E906729843C708AF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assessments of the effectiveness of the grant program under this section and the programs carried out by the resiliency office of the grantee and recommendations for improving such programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5178FB8FAD804F798FF847A41F94B052"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6ECB9FF7E5E94166A70A3EEE05A23249"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disadvantaged community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>disadvantaged community</term> shall have such meaning as shall be established by regulation by the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, using such indicators and metrics as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4302D7946FFC45669D4F9A83479A86BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grantee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>grantee</term> means a State, territory, or Indian tribe to which a grant under this section is made.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57E52AE79D93408293DB1874EEF71F35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Native American Housing and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H017C228FD3F84CE8A9F8F7AF36AAFB4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>resilience</term> means, with respect to a community, the ability to rebound, positively adapt to, or thrive amidst changing conditions or challenges, including human-caused and natural disasters, and to maintain quality of life, healthy growth, durable systems, economic vitality, and conservation of resources for present and future generations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5DF0341218E47ADA214C9781FBECAF7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2A714AEFA27461CAFB6B65566B60137"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means a State of the United States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99DD67D835C94BC1AC617CD08DB6201F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Territory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>territory</quote> means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and American Samoa.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H41436C812BBA45D89DB6527E22B8CACA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="H7F4178405F8D4BF49A24AF461C671FB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for grants under this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D185107D38149FB8B4980717795B3FF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Set-aside for Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of any amounts appropriated for a fiscal year for grants under this section, the Secretary shall reserve 10 percent for grants to Indian tribes. The Secretary shall allocate such amounts reserved, among Indian tribes having applications for grants under this section for such fiscal year approved by the Secretary, on the basis of a competition conducted pursuant to specific criteria for the selection of Indian tribes to receive such amounts. The criteria shall be contained in a regulation promulgated by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, after notice and opportunity for public comment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

