<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA3615EDD7D814934BBA5110C148CDA69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9454 IH: Next Generation Shipping Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a program to support the research, design, development, demonstration, and deployment of zero-emission vessels and retrofit or replacement of existing vessels with zero-emission vessel technologies and charging infrastructure or fueling infrastructure, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF5F3DBB62B7049EEB90BC4815F655548" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H4DCB62D0ED064254A43AE26C136CEF27"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Next Generation Shipping Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H4D3FE44D51EC459E81D133EB82E501D2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0887033CB06E43A984AF8F76AC8E80BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Automated</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>automated</term> means any vessel or cargo handling system that performs any or all core functions without human operation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CA96C33A1454A51B515CC4F36888D22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Charging infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>charging infrastructure</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H502E18C1BDB345B9850E569381BEE633"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the physical systems, equipment, and facilities necessary to supply electrical power to vessels for the purpose of recharging the batteries or energy storage systems of such vessels; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60FF7E7A0B72498691FE3DC93B0D325C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes, with respect to zero-emission vessel technology, shore power facilities, onshore charging stations, and any associated equipment required to support the electrification of maritime transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DD4872367904C9B9B549051C77FDCA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clean alternative fuel</header><text>The term <term>clean alternative fuel</term> means a fuel or energy source that results in at least 90 percent fewer greenhouse gas emissions than a baseline of conventional marine fossil fuel on a life-cycle (<quote>well-to-wake</quote>) basis, measured in grams of carbon dioxide equivalent emissions per unit of energy, that is proven to be safe for people, communities, and the marine environment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A00FDCFC8B94AD2A9EB73F1A774A3EB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Committee</term> means the Next Generation Shipping Advisory Committee established under section 4.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11D838B3217E476EA00ECC8AC4AA2025"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Community benefits agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community benefits agreement</term> means an agreement signed by community groups and an eligible entity, identifying the community or labor benefits the entity agrees to deliver in return for community support or workforce availability for a project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBFC2232326E48429CA5C149BC1054A6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5085ADD19B2548ED9A745A9162F346DC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D781AAC1E9B41B5981B8CA45A0D0CC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means—</text> 
<clause id="HF5C6D5F1783F44C1A23AB09FD3789DE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an owner or operator of a vessel of the United States, as defined in section 116 of title 46, United States Code;</text></clause> <clause id="H576C766ACAEA47428054789A04F3AFEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a United States-based manufacturer of vessels;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEAEA4F13EBFC4299B517B8184AB3B6EC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manufacturers of components, technologies, or materials that support zero-emission vessels and clean alternative fuel vessels;</text></clause> <clause id="H9F3FBB8BFE6A497887391B53B9D56357"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a port authority;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC308D858C378401199CCCF37E78B0E00"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a terminal operator at a port;</text></clause> <clause id="H856D2DAE45494D4BB0B6B72B2095C6D6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>an academic institution or nonprofit entity in a joint application with an entity listed in any of clauses (i) through (v); or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EFF50D48F7E4AF1B8D1CC72F1F79793"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a nonprofit institution that—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC576466A66EE42A6B6D2B88AFC07B8B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is funded, in whole or in part, by a labor-management training fund established pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H637BB0D51CF34A1FACF0546F0319B4D5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is approved by the Coast Guard to provide training toward the issuance or renewal of a merchant mariner credential under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1235122C1F414F1EB3D86078C0DEB31F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provides training and education to individuals with merchant mariner credentials serving in licensed engineering or licensed deck officer occupations; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99F694FBE95440B0BF4BF5067B8A04D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">excludes any entity that is a foreign government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AF7DA82BA6D4624BA3F99059E4383CA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text>The term <term>eligible project</term> means a project to support the research, design, demonstration, development, and deployment of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE375FDEE75D845F9B0698CAB7B96AED8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">zero-emission vessels;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2AF784F0B23242BF9444C4C18A144980"><enum>(B)</enum><text>clean alternative fuel vessels;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC04C01DCEB54551B55F1F4A90D38586"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">vessel energy efficiency technology (such as wind assistance and systems that minimize underwater noise emissions);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1AA4694080334105969714DECE9BB0AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shore power and corresponding vessel technology; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7839D55232384C55AF8B9A541D0E462F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>zero-emission and clean alternative fuel vessel infrastructure, including bunkering and storage, for vessels.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB092065C2F2745688543713A346AD189"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Environmental co-benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental co-benefits</term> means the additional positive environmental impacts or advantages that arise as a result of implementing a particular policy, technology, or initiative.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2ADE6BD540124AC893E6709538732D2D"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Fueling infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fueling infrastructure</term> means the infrastructure and facilities essential for supplying, storing, handling, and distributing alternative fuels or energy sources used for powering vessels.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H417D56B9A14748E8AC67EC3552187E62"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Maritime decarbonization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>maritime decarbonization</term> means the process of reducing or eliminating carbon dioxide emissions associated with maritime transportation activities and involves implementing a range of strategies, technologies, and policies aimed at mitigating the environmental impact of vessel operations, including the adoption of alternative fuels, energy efficiency measures, operational improvements, and regulatory measures designed to promote the transition to zero emission vessel technologies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4D915BB93874AC1A94D348FF5D96987"><enum>(12)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13468C1DC7754BE588F7A1ED9E370FAB"><enum>(13)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program</term> means the Next Generation Shipping Innovation Program established under section 3.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1A9AF42AABF4348AA922C611C8FE25A"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Project labor agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <term>project labor agreement</term> means a pre-hire collective bargaining agreement with 1 or more labor organizations that establishes the terms and conditions of employment for a specific construction project and is described in section 8(f) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83724F22F92840D8A37879BA8C26A066"><enum>(15)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E9962F21B7648D7BF2D0DFFBBDDFD5C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Zero-emission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>zero-emission</term>, with respect to a vessel, means the vessel produces zero emissions of any criteria pollutant, precursor pollutant, or greenhouse gas, other than water vapor during its operation, typically by utilizing renewable energy sources, clean alternative fuels, and efficiency technologies.</text></paragraph></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE48F7BE0F554605826B813FA7241F3E"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Next Generation Shipping Innovation Program</header> <subsection id="H4EF7F62A0CAD4F02A06DB5FCEC85DFDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>Next Generation Shipping Innovation Program</quote> to support the research, design, development, demonstration, and deployment of zero-emission vessels and retrofit or replacement of existing vessels with zero-emission vessel technologies and charging infrastructure or fueling infrastructure.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB1161FBA63A4459A841FE8F7B0D2CF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mechanisms</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may provide eligible entities with finance mechanisms to support eligible projects, including grants, low-interest loans, and loan guarantees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H054CF57060014A359066C61B58FE7D11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall prioritize eligible projects that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H08AF7C92E14E455FA6C10FD316514D4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advance the efficiency and reliability, and reduce the costs, of zero-emission vessel development;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBEF66C52AEC4B4DA5987ACFD64F5635"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve the components, controls, manufacturing, materials, and infrastructure that support zero-emission vessels;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H446946789E3E46E486FBBF8330B312D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reduce underwater noise emissions from vessels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC16A33357D8447C28206E3B72559D5A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>emphasize technologies with environmental co-benefits such as biofouling reduction;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3041E83E6DE54CC7A37895A38BB844DA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>advance synergies between offshore renewable energy development and maritime decarbonization and ocean noise, such as through the deployment of zero-emission and quiet offshore wind support vessels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE8D68E4542E4FD0B12AF842C4DE4473"><enum>(6)</enum><text>utilize a project labor agreement or community benefits agreement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD55225EB55FB43479BA8FA5F1EC2F4CA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>advance environmental justice and engage communities affected by maritime transport in all phases of the project including the development, planning, and execution of the project; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFBD9AE2CFAB43F5B6C77494AB8F838B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>support workforce training and development for the research, design, development, demonstration, deployment, and maintenance of zero-emission and clean alternative fuel vessels and charging infrastructure or fueling infrastructure, including through—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBA52E04ED1A1436C8BD73BB3E26F30C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>centers of excellence for domestic maritime workforce training and education designated under section 51706 of title 46, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76DC123615984EFD9B313FF280F8E346"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nonprofit institutions described in section 2(7)(A)(vii), for the purpose of developing, updating, and delivering Coast Guard-approved training curricula, simulation technology, and certification programs for individuals who have, or are obtaining, merchant mariner credentials to operate zero-emission vessels or clean alternative fuel vessels, consistent with the applicable requirements of the International Convention on Standards of Training, Certification and Watchkeeping for Seafarers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0951754B38D845CA9CDD79BE93066852"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall make publicly available each year on the website of the Department applications submitted for funding mechanisms under this section, including applications selected and not selected for funding.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H05CCD4C7C3CC4E559C360374D2CA04AF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination and leveraging of resources</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</text> 
<paragraph id="H06475D9C54B044728D6B27E4EA00BABD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with each relevant office in the Department and any other Federal agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA42C39057BC41BC81B6AEBE786BAB6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leverage existing resources and programs of the Department and other relevant Federal agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F3D2F7F395B460C80F657071BC09D37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leverage public-private partnerships; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H815A09FA8D204441B23C81C7BD774FEE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>engage and solicit input from environmental justice communities and environmental organizations on project impacts and benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H91990CBAA9494289BFBB665A366FABAC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>The Secretary may use up to 10 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section for the administrative costs of carrying out the Program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H68A28BA2DFFB40A7A33014A76659F771"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Wages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All laborers and mechanics employed by a subgrantee of an eligible entity, and any subgrantee thereof at any tier, to perform construction, alteration, installation, or repair work that is assisted, in whole or in part, by funding awarded under this section shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction, alteration, installation, or repair work in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H302A10907CBD40F3AF04C6048B648473"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is authorized to carry out the Program under this section $1,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2036.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3651361458934E459BCCB63503EBBFEB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds made available to carry out this section shall be spent for the study, design, implementation, or installation of automated vessels, automated vessel operating systems, automated cargo handling systems on a vessel, or automated cargo handling systems for loading or unloading vessels.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H33400BF389E5453AA6551E91C54706BF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Next Generation Shipping Advisory Committee</header> 
<subsection id="HFE40371B71AB4F57AC61A8713D93EB0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Maritime Administrator, shall establish an advisory committee, to be known as the <quote>Next Generation Shipping Advisory Committee</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB6C691A1106F4720A7B18831BA2722CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="H189975A34F634DDC8B7A0625D31F2DD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Committee shall be composed of not fewer than 15 members, who shall be appointed by the Secretary, in coordination with the Maritime Administrator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36072425EA8E406EA174B4E934E03ECC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>Members appointed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HBD09A7EB4DA1405693544FD39D38EC2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative of each relevant Federal agency, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11EDA29973174CB398C229CCFF65997B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 2 representatives of labor groups;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D532D3C1AF84CC9A08167C29620AA3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less than 3 representatives of the research community, which shall include academia and National Laboratories;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H822C410ECEC5407483ABAEB2FA19CB1E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not less than 2 representatives of nongovernmental environmental justice organizations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4008B1E06D4242479DAD3D05B7A2C139"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not less than 2 representatives of nongovernmental environmental organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02BF1700E5F5458B8CEA724DA67F3ACE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>not less than 2 representatives of the maritime industry;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5EAADA820D0847E0BABA988280DD20B7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>not less than 2 representatives of the zero-emissions fuel industry;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E87443620294D9596504BB07A2AE1BC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative of a State government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADF63D5524E34ECEBB6BA69E2C126834"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 2 representatives from United States ports; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06AA53A5D0874BC3BB40CF5DDE7229CF"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other individual whom the Secretary, in coordination with the Maritime Administrator, determines to be necessary to ensure that the Committee is composed of a diverse group of representatives of industry, academia, independent researchers, and public and private entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE020F30F08514593B5ADCF28A1F89818"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Secretary shall designate a member of the Committee to serve as Chair.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H960012E6DBF2491BBDEC81D1B332E1DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall advise the Secretary and the Maritime Administrator with respect to the Program by—</text> <paragraph id="H6BDBCB58231C471DA8D1351E2D043CBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying and evaluating any zero-emission vessel technologies being developed by the private sector or other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86998BA3CB5E493D8EDB91DC6C13955B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying technology gaps in the private sector in zero-emissions vessels, and making recommendations to address those gaps through the implementation of the Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B1DD090050A4F109D29BD470C07517A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>surveying and analyzing factors that prevent the adoption of zero-emission vessel technologies by the private sector;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2EFE9514BCF4841B212A18FFF9E1E0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommending technology screening criteria for technology supported under the Program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H409277A5DEE149DB99EC17DD7B9F4DCB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>specifying near-term and long-term qualitative and quantitative objectives relating to the development of zero-emissions vessel technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1035CF9E3C1A4916A67F135E1ED0FEAF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header> 
<paragraph id="HB445A8BB1CD346ECA31ED5384A7FDB56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Committee shall meet not less frequently than 2 times per year, at the call of the Chair.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37493B4391F14986947B796FD8C8AD6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the members are appointed under subsection (b), the Committee shall hold a first meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44083124F288435EAE69D464F81B19C8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Committee report</header> 
<paragraph id="H53786C21350849C98A664AA59D95D754"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 3 years thereafter, the Committee shall submit to the Secretary a report on the progress of achieving the purposes of the Program described in section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H155D9BD894A149DE89FD4D5DDA239085"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HACFC7E1DBAB9421BB3DF47378943CF8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of any technology innovation opportunities identified by the Committee;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC6499A55C2D44939D76A6E6D5436B47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of any technology gaps identified by the Committee;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H704D07EEA3794E7584E430641774BF9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of the progress of the Program and the research, development, and demonstration activities funded through the Program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C5D29DB732F4411BA6B3277A6922F7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the extent to which progress has been made under the Program in developing commercial, cost-competitive zero-emission vessel technologies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H478EB4003F0147259D46AAA54853C61A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of the Program in coordinating efforts within the Department and with other Federal agencies to achieve the purposes of the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F2D92FAAD1340E1BAB60E340437EE67"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 60 days after receiving a report from the Committee under subsection (e), the Secretary shall submit a copy of such report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

