<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25E62-CCV-R5-KMS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3533 IS: Shadow Docket Sunlight Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3533</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the administration of justice by requiring written explanations by the Supreme Court of its decisions and the disclosure of votes by justices in cases within the appellate jurisdiction of the Supreme Court that involve preliminary injunctive relief, and other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shadow Docket Sunlight Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id958ad33b8bd94de4bd3f1e21369522cf"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supreme Court written explanations and disclosure of voting in cases involving preliminary injunctive relief</header><subsection id="id26e2ad5bbb0543ed8a26e2c351e15f24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/155">Chapter 155</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56e42aa00b6142f5bb2b279a5e35336e"><section id="idc92596a367954b9aa97bdbd9e21aec38"><enum>2285.</enum><header>Written explanations and disclosure of voting in Supreme Court cases involving preliminary injunctive relief</header><subsection id="idfed01911023c49598cf6b17f74a59f80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="id1946fd6a4476421eb5986c787d6e4549"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Supreme Court</term> means the Supreme Court of the United States, including any individual justice or set of justices when acting on behalf of the Supreme Court of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4c7430422fe4b3c9e152950720b2ddd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Supreme Court’s appellate jurisdiction</term> means all cases within the jurisdiction of the Supreme Court other than those within the original jurisdiction of the Supreme Court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2c9ea71984b24f8a8aec531f7ff90bf5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><paragraph id="idf80300f675664126a45d3e421e13ae78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written explanation and vote disclosure</header><text>In any case within the Supreme Court’s appellate jurisdiction, the Supreme Court may not issue any order granting, denying, or vacating preliminary injunctive relief or granting, denying, or vacating a stay of preliminary injunctive relief unless the Supreme Court publishes a written explanation of reasons supporting such order and indicates in writing how each participating justice voted regarding such order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13a94e11fb6d44a49d0fc09ccd3cfb8a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents for orders granting, denying, or vacating preliminary injunctive relief</header><text>The written explanation required under paragraph (1) for an order granting, denying, or vacating preliminary injunctive relief shall include an evaluation of the following criteria:</text><subparagraph id="id4c3a2938be234ebdb4ebc7bbf61ef082"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether an applicant seeking preliminary injunctive relief is likely to succeed on the merits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc0ce9d86290432aa45c874a80a6b92e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether an applicant seeking preliminary injunctive relief is likely to suffer irreparable harm absent such relief.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6afe46da619345809d8b621744d0c46a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the balance of equities tips in the favor of an applicant seeking preliminary injunctive relief.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9dff1b0821454ad8b9a259b3feddc415"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether preliminary injunctive relief is in the public interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id04cdf9bc0f6e44eeb4b8064428964518"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents for orders granting, denying, or vacating a stay of preliminary injunctive relief</header><text>The written explanation required under paragraph (1) for an order granting, denying, or vacating a stay of preliminary injunctive relief shall include an evaluation of the following criteria:</text><subparagraph id="id3607847f0eeb4545970c804954d91086"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether the stay applicant has made a strong showing of the likelihood of success on the merits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca0eb2f0292a4f0e8240e41f4fd712fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether the stay applicant will be irreparably injured absent a stay.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a12835330924dafa98d2266975cadd9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether issuance of the stay will substantially injure the other parties interested in the proceeding.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf7879e12f4f42399433e2c67d1c9181"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether a stay is in the public interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4dfdda4c12fd41da94be98c990de89cd"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Multiple opinions</header><text>The written explanation required under paragraph (1) may be made in 1 or more opinions representing a majority of justices participating in a decision, without regard to whether a majority of the justices participating in a decision publish the same written explanation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25b64bdc7eb6488bbcc93c7dc7aa26f3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administrative and scheduling orders excluded</header><text>The requirements of this subsection shall not apply to orders granting or denying applications that relate only to administrative or scheduling matters or petitions for certiorari and that do not grant, deny, or vacate preliminary injunctive relief or grant, deny, or vacate a stay of preliminary injunctive relief.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idec16e6670c594467a2e63671c8f8f05f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations and inclusions</header><text>In implementing this section, the following shall apply:</text><paragraph id="id5c4e4e3a8d8d43d3b1ae5c65486509e5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify the substantive standards applied by any court in deciding any case.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb88a7032679d4525b938b9c0570dfae0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify the jurisdiction of the Supreme Court under any other law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbec8532fcbe048edb8716aa607aabb1a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>This section shall apply with respect to orders issued in connection with a claim under chapter 5 or 7 of title 5.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d94e2800ec64bc0af6e4b3f8773efe1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/155">chapter 155</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="iddf15d644-2519-460e-9853-4c294148e90c"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc92596a367954b9aa97bdbd9e21aec38">2285. Written explanations and disclosure of voting in Supreme Court cases involving preliminary injunctive relief.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id85ad689c6a5547b49c0246bd5a89c82b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="id6a563404245644938ce60297c1c49097"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than April 1 of the first year that begins more than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and April 1 of every second year thereafter, the Director of the Federal Judicial Center shall submit to Congress a report—</text><paragraph id="id1f217abafa894123918a886839b77549"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assessing the extent of compliance or noncompliance with the requirements of section 2285 of title 28, United States Code, as added by section 2 of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbdc3e7bdec74069bad7b5016e34dee1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing any recommendations of the Director regarding ways to improve compliance with such section 2285.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id34d66393a5184870a7cfc27664696412"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional time</header><text>For the first report required under subsection (a), the Director of the Federal Judicial Center may submit the report after the date described in that subsection if the Director identifies in writing to Congress the amount of additional time needed for completion of the report.</text></subsection></section><section id="idcf623f83f9144179ad950979ea0edb04"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such a provision or amendment to any particular person or circumstance is held invalid, the remaining provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such remaining provisions and amendments to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

