<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H93097C9F0BDA436297E129C8263190C1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6293 IH: Housing Supply Expansion Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6293</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251125">November 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To update the definition of manufactured home, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H66FEB6CF9D36406CBF5C63DC0719BFA4" style="OLC"><section id="H505EED93F8FD46B592F66681CC67C6FA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Supply Expansion Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H75C98BDC20F84039B3E2286AADB64B3E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Updating the definition of manufactured home</header><subsection id="HFE853B5C418349FB9917658C37643BE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 603(6) of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402(6)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>on a permanent chassis</quote> and inserting <quote>with or without a permanent chassis</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3238D11740C44056A6D32A5D3064A5BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards for manufactured homes built without a permanent chassis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 604(a) of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5403">42 U.S.C. 5403</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H978F46A271DD48A4AA1536F42D82DBCE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H3A2FB08822C84ED1AA3FE8066288A147"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Standards for manufactured homes built without a permanent chassis</header><subparagraph id="HD196CA9E697948B6B2310E83AD3EC302"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall issue revised standards for manufactured homes built without a permanent chassis and shall consult with the consensus committee in the development of such, using the process described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6471184E15B5498B9DBC1735D53F286E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Creating final standards</header><text>The Secretary shall, after consulting and conferring with the consensus committee, establish standards to include manufactured homes without a permanent chassis have—</text><clause id="H10C294290EE34B17B5E0DFD0A0B9D5E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a distinct label to be issued by the Secretary distinguishing manufactured homes built without a permanent chassis from manufactured homes built on a permanent chassis;</text></clause><clause id="H39AA3A56F81B41BA814E04D7FCB158C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a data plate, as described in section 3280.5 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, distinguishing manufactured homes built without a permanent chassis from manufactured homes built on a permanent chassis; and</text></clause><clause id="H8765F80556584AAE88A5597A39E7D129"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a notation on any invoice produced by the manufacturer of a manufactured home that is distinguishable from the invoice for a manufactured home constructed with a permanent chassis.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC5F04BDD9DCE44AD96F64C812D555EDE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Manufactured home standards and certifications</header><text>Section 604 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5403">42 U.S.C. 5403</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA7A5469FF834C1C9474B381AFCF6B87"><subsection id="H2621800F14B646388E5FC1CEB9174AAB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Manufactured home standards and certifications</header><paragraph id="HADA702CCB7924E338A955D59BD11FBDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H83E2A8D434F24F259D3A6284E5BB169F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial certification</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Housing Supply Expansion Act of 2025</short-title>, a State shall submit to the Secretary an initial certification that the laws and regulations of the State—</text><clause id="HAD139E13F3C04E47ACE25EFB127A323D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treat a manufactured home, including a manufactured home without a permanent chassis, in parity with a manufactured home (as defined and regulated by the State); and</text></clause><clause id="H95289514A5674C81B988FEE330A67D91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject a manufactured home without a permanent chassis to the same laws and regulations of the State as a manufactured home built on a permanent chassis with respect to financing, title, insurance, manufacture, sale, taxes, transportation, installation, and other areas as the secretary determines, after consultation with and approval by the consensus committee, are necessary to give effect to the purpose of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB97F7450CA28484196C8739C623BBD43"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State plan submission</header><text>Any State plan submitted under subparagraph (C) shall contain the required State certification under subparagraph (A) or paragraph (3) and, if contained therein, no additional or State certification under subparagraph (A) or paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13046B40F3674A8EB0186E7398C3BF72"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extended deadline</header><text>With respect to a State with a legislature that meets biennially, the deadline for the submission of the initial certification required under subparagraph (A) shall be 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Housing Supply Expansion Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36FA45E6BE0A4EE4A8CF7CDADECB4CA7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Late certification</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9C72596B0D64DDD957AF1B4C6CCC1AF"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No waiver</header><text>The Secretary may not waive the prohibition described in paragraph (5)(B) with respect to a certification submitted after the deadline under subparagraph (A) or paragraph (3) unless the Secretary approves the late certification.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA04CA8C4BE14BB1B4B9F23D0E520953"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent a State from submitting the initial certification required under subparagraph (A) after the required deadline under that subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D2F317C3F7246E18C3891874323B3CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of State certification not presented in a State plan</header><text>The initial certification required under paragraph (1)(A), if not submitted with a State plan under paragraph (1)(B), shall contain, in a form prescribed by the Secretary, an attestation by an official that the State has taken the steps necessary to ensure the veracity of the certification required under paragraph (1)(A), including, as necessary, by—</text><subparagraph id="H2145BAC6680F4C40B31106EAAE213638"><enum>(A)</enum><text>amending the definition of <term>manufactured home</term> in the laws and regulations of the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC3FD7012A9447338B2C9032BD13087C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directing State agencies to amend the definition of <term>manufactured home</term> in regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE98C684703064548947A6B2EE3270E29"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual recertification</header><text>Not later than a date to be determined by the Secretary each year, a State shall submit to the Secretary an additional certification that—</text><subparagraph id="HD8F679110277414C8301DAB0873C0A21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>confirms the accuracy of the initial certification submitted under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H919627AB0CC34A0F9FCAE5187818A676"><enum>(B)</enum><text>certifies that any new laws or regulations enacted or adopted by the State since the date of the previous certification does not change the veracity of the initial certification submitted under paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F196ED97A5046D38414E8674E7F2394"><enum>(4)</enum><header>List</header><text>The Secretary shall publish and maintain in the Federal Register and on the website of the Department of Housing and Urban Development a list of States that are up-to-date with the submission of initial and subsequent certifications required under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9E3953B858140E383AF2FE20CF499D3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><subparagraph id="H81FDE897EB8B4B4483C5EFE97E74979F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered manufactured home</term> means a home that is—</text><clause id="H154267EFA96C47A99FBA212A7A50767C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not considered a manufactured home under the laws and regulations of a State because the home is constructed without a permanent chassis;</text></clause><clause id="H7D01E1659D0B47DFAF223F7BC4BC7557"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>considered a manufactured home under the definition of the term in section 603; and</text></clause><clause id="H2FE8F3E6084641D38B48B9918A9D943D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>constructed after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Housing Supply Expansion Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8571EA4C3D654C3788344632FC411F1C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Building, installation, and sale</header><text>If a State does not submit a certification under paragraph (1)(A) or (3) by the date on which those certifications are required to be submitted—</text><clause id="H2F51189AA3CF42039B66A7F22F8D418A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a State in which the State administers the installation of manufactured homes, the State shall prohibit the manufacture, installation, or sale of a covered manufactured home within the State; and</text></clause><clause id="H285F9E006BFA45D8BBF168A488E32F5A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a State in which the Secretary administers the installation of manufactured homes, the State and the Secretary shall prohibit the manufacture, installation, or sale of a covered manufactured home within the State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H18CF230425F8404D931CD72E5E10DEC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other Federal laws regulating manufactured homes</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may coordinate with the heads of other Federal agencies to ensure that Federal agencies treat a manufactured home (as defined in Federal laws and regulations other than section 603 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402</external-xref>)) in the same manner as a manufactured home (as defined in section 603 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402</external-xref>)), as amended by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4D998F8698AF425BA31624FFA4651DFC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assistance to States</header><text>Section 609 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5408">42 U.S.C. 5408</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5614AA04755943B5A6D3F2A71B10854C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4700B45F652D4A5A9F0D46E5694293DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC94E05557B63438DA31884CA8FEE1DA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2254F2F3B93044D0AD6853FDDA2D9FB7"><paragraph id="HBCDBE1CBDF024EF69036E6A8745E3FF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>model guidance to support the submission of the certification required under section 604(i).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68CBA8FBD5E448518BDC9A4EBFA54ED4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed as limiting the scope of Federal preemption under section 604(d) of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5403">42 U.S.C. 5403(d)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

