<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB9E8222F08F448E8BD5B9BBFF44314A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8222 IH: End Russian Oil Windfalls Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8222</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To nullify Russia-related General License 133, <quote>Authorizing the Delivery and Sale of Crude Oil and Petroleum Products of Russian Federation Origin Loaded on Vessels as of March 5, 2026 to India</quote>, and Russia-related General License 134A, <quote>Authorizing the Delivery and Sale of Crude Oil and Petroleum Products of Russian Federation Origin Loaded on Vessels as of March 12, 2026</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H709179809D824316B306F8650127D1C0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2F7892AF64C5415B899F6E92108A4008" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Russian Oil Windfalls Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H87B7B2ED9B554E14A703E0542A2EDFC2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nullification of Russia-related General Licenses 133 and 134A</header> <subsection id="HF5746B6A91D249D081CE5F39A4D885EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, Russia-related General License 133, <quote>Authorizing the Delivery and Sale of Crude Oil and Petroleum Products of Russian Federation Origin Loaded on Vessels as of March 5, 2026 to India</quote>, and Russia-related General License 134A, <quote>Authorizing the Delivery and Sale of Crude Oil and Petroleum Products of Russian Federation Origin Loaded on Vessels as of March 12, 2026</quote>, both issued by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury, shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5A7853787BE45A9B92B068D2CF399BF" commented="no">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Future licenses</header>
 <text>The Secretary of the Treasury may not authorize any transactions otherwise prohibited by law that are ordinarily incident and necessary to the sale, delivery, or offloading of crude oil or petroleum products of Russian Federation.</text>
            </subsection></section> 
<section id="H1E54F7CC82B34DC985F1D1DBACA4CB04"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header> 
<subsection id="HA64CE0E5D1524F65A7BB4B48F71AAF09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any Russian person that engages in the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE196905666E84CBE852C9177AE5A31D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Oil and gas extraction.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5AD8BD96E80A4F398591299A7BA575E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Oil and gas refinement or production.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H881C3CFAE8D347D5B391026E52A26B78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Maritime transportation of oil and gas or other petroleum products.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F5202CB49874761B2D1455CAB605155"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H02981037655E491FAC0F5A5A344FCC06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President may exercise of all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0303D8C63C346D2A44AD3520067A742" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3035743B75974AE9B56464161BACF8D1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, is described in subsection (a) is—</text> <clause id="HBA867674A39D460B92FECD00423C25DF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDC259C18DF84400185CF8620B4B62F2F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF1DF9A0639E64472979911E0B4B20F43" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8CB632270644504A2649E48B687FC7C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header> 
<clause id="H6B36385B8703489FA1A3E28283083093" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></clause> <clause id="H4EFB5D968AF44F17950A62E70E666A23" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text> 
<subclause id="H1B81C967A8C64FF8BBFCAB13DA8A936D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE4C353C64D234177A54F429CB7A79190" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE5B74D60A2944806BDB8BD273C4EE2CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<paragraph id="HE57916BAD28941FD92030078E3FDAEB1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE85E66EB450543F2A129AD5CDAD16016"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D0BE559663C4BC5B751EBD682F09D62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA6F4E927281489D9F039675F469DCD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2228D663B2A44222B5B4B9ED219E641C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE65EAAF8D00B4A82868F588DC159EA21"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H833407650F6A4419A95F447FE4E83AC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7E98AC08061E429C935764BF0F7014AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text>In any judicial review of a determination made under this section, if the determination was based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act) such information may be submitted to the reviewing court ex parte and in camera. This subsection does not confer or imply any right to judicial review.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FD931BB75DB409DBC304069DE75EA5C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header> 
<paragraph id="H776547EA50A8401EB4290BEE8912075B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B30A311D29147EFB446CCA978036E0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person who commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB9322B7604724D72987DFC3834571C92"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on Russian oil</header> 
<subsection id="H07065FFBDD45482FA6B0FE3E25B274D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 60 days thereafter for three years, the Secretary of State in consultation with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies as appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of Russian general license.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFF52301E478D40A7BC2827054B8B4231"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of the impact of Russia-related General License 133, <quote>Authorizing the Delivery and Sale of Crude Oil and Petroleum Products of Russian Federation Origin Loaded on Vessels as of March 5, 2026 to India</quote>, and Russia-related General License 134A, <quote>Authorizing the Delivery and Sale of Crude Oil and Petroleum Products of Russian Federation Origin Loaded on Vessels as of March 12, 2026</quote>, both issued by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury and any extensions or successors thereof on the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2B75EDDF0F574F5DB01574706663531C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The volume and sale price of Russian crude and refined oil product exports.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H800164BEAB1B4353BD9DA2E6DA04883B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The revenue earned by the Government of the Russian Federation or Russian Federation state-affiliated or state-owned entities through exports of oil products, including the premium earned on Russian oil as a result of the closure of the Strait of Hormuz and the subsequent fallout thereof.</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE09D758B052A4D0F9D4C4AE7C3B87CC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Russian oil production levels.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H69996C849E484DE49942AEF584924666"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H16E80E82897D4166B8E2A7E42167C61F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1615C3AD9454F16963B5BC364BC98D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC301D9FF2A9047D3A6A418CA1A56BF16"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on Russian energy companies involvement in abducting Ukrainian children</header> 
<subsection id="HB20CAE9C5C444F0A80C1C3885188B7EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for two years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies as appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on any involvement by Russian state-owned or state-affiliated energy companies in the abduction, forcible deportation, or indoctrination of Ukrainian civilians, including Ukrainian children.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5A5199D093584B2B9F82AD7FAB73A867"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2DF44845B2364D2CB024124CDA956919"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20662900C4BA4C6A978015D92F95691F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

