<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4B0EEEDBB9B48DFBA91D04B561EDFFE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8758 IH: Protecting Our Second Amendment Data Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8758</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require certifications related to the intentional, accidental, or otherwise knowing disclosure of personally identifiable information of persons involved in transactions related to possession of firearms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H165B5295EE114086A73618586C0F8FEA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H029F9C34391C437F991070C084D13C5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Second Amendment Data Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1DF55BFF17A34720A7A36111F4E6735F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 502(a) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10153">34 U.S.C. 10153(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H39F438B538434059BEC3705730454B79" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HC00E5929866146D6A823FE2D81F24FA6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification that during the previous fiscal year the applicant has not intentionally, accidentally, or otherwise knowingly disclosed personally identifiable information of a person involved in a transaction to register a firearm, apply for a concealed carry permit, apply for an open carry permit, or apply for a background check related to possession of a firearm.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H105429C290604233BAE6785ECDEE8AC2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Discretionary grants</header> <subsection id="HC8F5A6AC6C744C249EC122DC4900E418"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants to public agencies</header><text>Section 517 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10181">34 U.S.C. 10181</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCF1149889A28498FACEBDDFD05AFA394"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5F1D26CA9084FE2AFEDC983AE391F16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE7057AD694B4B948EE2E7753B06529A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HA2A99163034C4468B6CBBD60381AECD6" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE38178C00C5140E1A52DA545D5CA23DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies that during the previous fiscal year the applicant has not intentionally, accidentally, or otherwise knowingly disclosed personally identifiable information of a person involved in a transaction to register a firearm, apply for a concealed carry permit, apply for an open carry permit, or apply for a background check related to possession of a firearm.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF6447785BC2147C18B6F2B8E56675C42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants to private entities</header><text>Section 519(b) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10191">34 U.S.C. 10191(b)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, including a certification that the organization has not used, disseminated, or facilitated the use or dissemination of personally identifiable information of a person involved in a transaction to register a firearm, apply for a concealed carry permit, apply for an open carry permit, or apply for a background check related to possession of a firearm</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H13E0102036FC4AEDA8EECA54712A4251"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cops grants</header><text>Section 1701 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H76951EEC8C05453F82CA3965782B1092" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HE2D211E36A2749E9AB9F79C7DC62C4E1"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this subchapter, the COPS Director and the BJA Director shall require States, units of local government, and Indian tribes to submit a certification that during the previous fiscal year the State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe has not intentionally, accidentally, or otherwise knowingly disclosed personally identifiable information of a person or persons involved in a transaction to register a firearm, apply for a concealed carry permit, apply for an open carry permit, or apply for a background check related to the possession of a firearm. Such certification shall be made in a form acceptable to the COPS Director and the BJA Director.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H1FFAC765C5E3455AAE12F79E044C45B6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 901(a) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H040AE059FD55497C81CD817C80BF021A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (32), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC5918C8DE274ECF82297ED4F8B1BDC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (33), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E65F9CD15AD4657B5E66E0DBD64F8D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (33) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAF69B9A313594122814C5CA83F317F51" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H1A91C1229AD34D9395D1B4DC8EF45E13"><enum>(34)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>firearm</term> has the meaning given such term in section 921 of title 18, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H501C2C71219F440EAFF5252963B82667"><enum>(35)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>personally identifiable information</term> means information that can be used to distinguish or trace an individual’s identity, such as the name, social security number, date and place of birth, biometric records, home or other phone numbers, or other demographic, medical, or financial information.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

