<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR26209-030-3G-8L7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4345 IS: Marijuana Impact on Medicaid Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4345</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to collect data and report to Congress on the cost to the Medicaid program from hospital and emergency room visits related to marijuana use.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Marijuana Impact on Medicaid Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79031c5b4820474c97f4db888e6c22ba"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on cost to the Medicaid program from hospital and emergency room visits related to marijuana use</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a6b8fb9f4ae4bfc887e5d8f55263638"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall collect data relating to the amount of Federal and State expenditures under the Medicaid program established under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) that are attributable to costs incurred for providing medical assistance for inpatient hospital services, outpatient hospital services, and for services received at a hospital emergency room (without regard to whether such services are emergency services (as defined by the Secretary)) related to marijuana use (as defined by the Secretary).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48d4bd3fa5c74c5f9547b102125b06c3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report describing the findings from the data collection pursuant to subsection (a), together with any recommendations for legislation or administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

