<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-BAG25J89-8Y4-HD-SJ0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 566 ATS: Recognizing that care provided by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs is essential for meeting the health care needs of veterans of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 566</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing that care provided by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs is essential for meeting the health care needs of veterans of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, as of 2025, the Department of Veterans Affairs serves more than 7,000,000 patients;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, veteran trust in Department outpatient health care was nearly 92 percent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Department hospitals have out-performed non-Department hospitals in quality and patient satisfaction in the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services’ annual star ratings since 2023 when Department facilities began being included in the annual star ratings;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas recent studies have concluded that Department health care is consistently as good as, or better than, commercial health care in areas of quality and safety;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas veterans who are engaged in Department health care in Department medical facilities or through the Department’s community care providers should receive high-quality continuity of care and positive outcomes regardless of where they receive their care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department’s 2024 National Veteran Suicide Prevention Annual Report found that in 2022 there were, on average, 17.6 veteran suicides per day, of which 7.0 per day were among veterans who received care from the Veterans Health Administration in 2021 or 2022, and 10.5 were among other veterans.</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department is the largest educator of health care professionals in the United States, with more than 70 percent of practicing physicians having completed at least some of their training at a Department medical facility;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than a century, Department researchers have made countless medical breakthroughs, which have benefitted not only veterans, but all people of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department has a statutory <quote>fourth mission</quote> to support national, State, and local emergency efforts in times of war, terrorism, natural disasters, and public health emergencies, while continuing service to veterans: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0432e756367b44848a44d2435e35c939"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the Department of Veterans Affairs is essential in meeting the health care needs of veterans, training the medical workforce, conducting critical research, working to end veteran suicide, and improving public health and the preparedness of the United States for emergencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id496487c22e4e47b899e326305b03dd00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the Department to support all it’s employees, respect their expertise and experience, and empower them with appropriate resources to serve veterans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b8e757e54564c4db0c87d1e64ebc604"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the Senate to ensuring that every veteran has timely access to high-quality, affordable, and veteran-centered care, whether provided in Department medical facilities or through Department community care providers when direct care is not available or in the best medical interest of the veteran.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

