<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR26539-5MT-7Y-061"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>110 S4738 IS: To implement reforms relating to foreign intelligence surveillance authorities, protections relating to warrantless queries for the communications of United States persons, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4738</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To implement reforms relating to foreign intelligence surveillance authorities, protections relating to warrantless queries for the communications of United States persons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section section-type="section-one" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a042fe16bd344caaf8fb82251a8f2bc"><enum>1.</enum><header>Protections relating to warrantless queries for the communications of United States persons</header><subsection id="id332ae8ad0a1047bd807ec189afedbc27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 702(f) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idf6020a67ca42439b956cb8588b9eb3c7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by inserting <quote>and the limitations and requirements in this subsection</quote> after <quote>Constitution of the United States</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c81ea1949e84358ae797e566ba87f81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><subparagraph id="id7a63081333c8482d88c92bcf0d942e51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B), and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91a8901d28a34f2c8011a54b0367b20a"><subparagraph id="id67cfec841ed640d480315876f15757eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>covered information</term> means—</text><clause id="id715f2c1b37ac490999d062db49c6a818"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communications content; and</text></clause><clause id="ide3ffb018f3b148b0b960c24abcd51a25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information, the compelled disclosure of which would require a probable cause warrant if sought for law enforcement purposes inside the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb61809c76bab46f195e07debd3c8c23c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means—</text><clause id="idf8e62e5d5dc34b3c81b8e93c8f5fafeb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a United States person; or</text></clause><clause id="id707d2f34d4044d98944a7a61ec2be9c2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a person reasonably believed to be located in the United States—</text><subclause id="id6aeac855870f47d396140ee3315c3de5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at the time of the applicable query; or</text></subclause><subclause id="ide2b2f9af967447149cc8164858b9f654"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at the time of the communication or creation of the information subject to the applicable query.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2cc4203b6d4c48b78559e429d72b36cd"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>covered query</term> means a query that is conducted—</text><clause id="id7061c6bfeb3d409d888ab40d30648598"><enum>(i)</enum><text>using any terms associated with 1 or more covered persons; or</text></clause><clause id="id5f74c40eec4b490cb326244faa12f799"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for a significant purpose of detecting or retrieving information of or concerning 1 or more covered persons.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idffd79625919d4c7193409e0cdccf1c71"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The term <term>query</term>—</text><clause id="idd4157cc250eb4e3096cec873129f3cd7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means the use of any technique, whether manual or automated, to detect or retrieve information obtained through acquisitions authorized under subsection (a) from within a system, collection, or assortment of information, or a subset thereof; and</text></clause><clause id="id5ef0a2473e08450698faa8f401b360c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include the manual observation of retrieved information.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id810aa119740541f78d1c2ebb9b579abd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59adfe61acdc440b89d0cb770242fc89"><paragraph id="id4615fa1d66bb4d43931185430a1c32f8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on warrantless access to the communications and other information of United States persons and persons located in the United States</header><subparagraph id="ide73d30c27768436a8256d435f402782a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), no officer or employee of the Federal Government may access covered information returned in response to a covered query.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id598b63e7ab4c4ce3b84c0079d244c98b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions for concurrent authorization, consent, emergency situations, and certain defensive cybersecurity queries</header><clause id="idac95bd6e808a49d38215b246e9f35d19"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if—</text><subclause id="id65d157075acf4d8bb28e8bbe4ab6a982"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the covered person to whom the covered query relates is the subject of an order or emergency authorization authorizing electronic surveillance or physical search under section 105, 304, 703 or 704 of this Act, or a warrant issued pursuant to the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure by a court of competent jurisdiction, if—</text><item id="id5780230f5cc546b3ba6a4cd753ac81d5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>such order, authorization, or warrant is active at the time the covered query is conducted;</text></item><item id="idfccdb5b1573847e7be1ebf43ee2e3b0c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the covered query is conducted and covered information is accessed in compliance with all use, dissemination, querying, retention, and other minimization limitations required by the order, authorization, or warrant; and</text></item><item id="id1de82f64436340cab16aaab1e3dc6779"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>with respect to an emergency authorization, the Attorney General makes or has made an application to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court in accordance with section 105, 304, 703 or 704, as applicable;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id9d9217e297df48db943e72d33acad353"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idaa58b0755f9d45b0944d07fb927e193f"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the officer or employee accessing the covered information has a reasonable belief that—</text><subitem indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1dcaa81e90d46d4b86aa51b5fdf52da"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>an emergency exists involving an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm; and</text></subitem><subitem indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbddc78d525334e82b3c9cddef76946f5"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>in order to prevent or mitigate the threat described in item (aa), the covered information must be accessed before authorization described in clause (i) can, with due diligence, be obtained; and</text></subitem></item><item id="id347eee96da6246d59f9e83ca7c11b048" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the covered information is accessed, a description of the circumstances justifying the accessing of the covered information is provided to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court, the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="ida3a9fd9d0a074bcd94c614a8ebe7252c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the covered person to whom the covered query relates or, if such person is incapable of providing consent, a third party legally authorized to consent on behalf of such person, has provided consent for the access on a case-by-case basis; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idf7e2eae54f6549f38fae21326dceb95b"><enum>(IV)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id05c8ac8fb0c24320b4e22148d3747bb0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the covered information is accessed and used for defensive cybersecurity purposes, including the protection of a covered person from cybersecurity attack;</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89677b39256749a4bb4ec7580a5a8bf6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>other than for such defensive cybersecurity purposes, no covered information is accessed or reviewed; and</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dd476e3e6304b29b39a021c7eea6c7d"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the covered information is accessed, a description of the circumstances justifying the accessing of the covered information is provided to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court, the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="iddec15a7dbe2a4bf08eff8ec82e673765"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Matters relating to emergency queries</header><subclause id="idcb7e992f41114082b919ae018088f9f8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Treatment of denials of applications after emergency authorizations</header><text>If the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court denies an application described in clause (i)(I)(cc), the restrictions set forth in section 105(e)(5), 304(e)(5), 703(d)(4), or 704(d)(4), as applicable, shall apply.</text></subclause><subclause id="ide89a24fbf66f4978a65481342fcdcf35"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court review of emergency exception</header><item id="id0cf8145124b64457921a78f8735a93c6"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 7 days after receipt of a description provided under clause (i)(II)(bb), the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court shall determine whether the criteria set forth in clause (i)(II)(aa) were met.</text></item><item id="ide0adfe40a35a45cd87ec235f6fc4902a"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court may require the submission of any additional information the Court considers necessary to make the determination described in item (aa).</text></item><item id="id5bf2b46786924b2d913ee381a62ee037"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Criteria not met</header><text>If the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court determines that the criteria set forth in item (aa) of clause (i)(II) were not met, no information obtained or evidence derived from the accessing of querying results shall be received in evidence, or otherwise disclosed in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, office, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or political subdivision thereof, and no information concerning any covered person acquired from accessing of the results of the covered query shall subsequently be used or disclosed in any other manner by Federal officers or employees without the consent of such person, except with the approval of the Attorney General if the information indicates a threat of death or serious bodily harm to any person.</text></item><item id="idc8cc0b0d555146ea8ba45da1d4ed6792"><enum>(dd)</enum><header>Submissions to Congress</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the determination described in item (aa) is made, a copy of such determination shall be provided to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id25a3a145955f4851852a90e44240fa6f"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Assessment of compliance</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Attorney General shall assess compliance with the requirements under subclauses (I)(cc) and (II)(bb) of clause (i) and subclauses (I) and (II)(cc) of clause (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide1fa913bdd6a4605b73dc085c18dc9f0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Foreign intelligence purpose required for queries</header><clause id="id4fb2d1c0b7494cc196692ea6ed9becd1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), no officer or employee of the Federal Government may conduct a query unless the query is—</text><subclause id="id4ce22b7cfc814a2096ca27ac9cd5192e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reasonably likely to retrieve foreign intelligence information; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ida1c665cc0eeb4652a772b3109e5f8590"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is made with a significant foreign intelligence purpose.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id1b8d074c1e374f988217d2560f1520db"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>An officer or employee of the Federal Bureau of Investigation may conduct a query if—</text><subclause id="id6d2dc1fb72eb429f98ffbee449b88584"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idb111b6b9ebe94662bc2e7a757ffd2aaf"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the officer or employee conducting the query has a reasonable belief that—</text><subitem indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67bac8dd4ffa48f7a44abfc3125ed9ed"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>an emergency exists involving an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm; and</text></subitem><subitem indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id700279959bc8418ab24385661b8e3ba4"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the query could reasonably be expected to assist in mitigating or eliminating that threat to life or serious bodily harm; and</text></subitem></item><item id="id42b19f24f6d64f2ab11e917f1b37ce50" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the query is conducted, a description of the query is provided to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court, the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id892310abf7714a0a995ba2cfd620ac4d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the query is necessary to identify information that must be produced or preserved in connection with a litigation matter or to fulfill discovery obligations in a criminal matter under the laws of the United States or any State.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0910d7820819477986704a302773ebbe"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to limit any oversight or training activities required under any other provision of law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id35516e3b16304c3c87f2a77b0ccdd68b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required documentation and query record system</header><subparagraph id="id1a7e2fa242414dbf936923de81599cb1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>No officer or employee of the Federal Government may conduct a query, or access covered information returned in response to a covered query, unless an electronic record is created that includes—</text><clause id="id205502a5d57349b2a47d8a53ee64d3fe"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each query—</text><subclause id="id88a464c57e7341e49f9b5ae246812ee5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>each term used for the conduct of the query;</text></subclause><subclause id="id929a10a33fe44986aada4aa98b5c34d9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date of the query;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide03002b994254bb9b737ea4307380529"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the identifier of the officer or employee who conducted the query; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ided7975b5a14f4a348f1e097f9d78fa27"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a statement of facts justifying that the query is reasonably likely to retrieve foreign intelligence information and the significant foreign intelligence purpose for the query or, if an exception under subparagraph (D)(ii) applies, a description of the basis for such exception; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6e883b181f4144e6aed1f2da4f29c11b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each access—</text><subclause id="ida797dcff533f47ba903df17d05655698"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date of the access;</text></subclause><subclause id="idca35a727f5a14a7cac71cccd21bb30bd"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the identifier of the officer or employee who did the particular access; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id3b787af3bf47422a9eaaebcc622a81a0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a statement of facts showing that an access is authorized by an exception under subparagraph (B).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f5e9383a9e14b42b7b44abe023287e0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Query record system</header><text>Each head of an agency who is authorized to conduct a covered query shall ensure that a system, mechanism, or business practice is in place to maintain the records described in subparagraph (A), including ensuring that any queries or accesses to covered information returned in response to covered queries, that are conducted by automated means are attributed to the officer or employee who was the proximate cause of such query or access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb2edb890434144e690c285c0c789f205"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on compliance with query record system requirement</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each head of a Federal agency described in section 702(f)(3)(B) of such Act, as added by subsection (a), shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on the compliance of the Federal agency with the requirement of such section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5b5139e3d7424a56b975aa63124323c6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 702(f) of such Act, as amended by subsection (a), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="id5423c6b4e011420bb021a5a1c9e5686f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the headings for subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1), subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2), and subparagraph (A) of paragraph (3), by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">United States person</header-in-text></quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">covered person</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0a1732c26774d75a94bb732deebf075"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text><subparagraph id="id91dbd8248daa4822b8263e8fa263b797"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">non-United States persons</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="paragraph">noncovered persons</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb546c3f860b3447f98605d838b6ed676"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>non-United States persons</quote> and inserting <quote>noncovered persons</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id74507241dee04caaa66a6c73107910ca"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraphs (1) through (6), by striking <quote>United States person</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>covered person</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2fc4b475129f48a5be7fd3b9439c3454"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nine-month extension of section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act</header><subsection id="id81a49f98c1b2464bafff56b6063fb35a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of repeal date of title VII</header><text>Section 403(b) of the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/261">Public Law 110–261</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idbb48715fd602436ba569a44a6ad9a197"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881">50 U.S.C. 1881</external-xref> note), by striking <quote>June 12, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>March 12, 2027</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idacf5c535dbb447c3b0917076a2dd7331"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2511">18 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref> note), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>June 12, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>March 12, 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id49d8a03141b84628a0f31471878293f0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall take effect on the earlier of the date of the enactment of this Act or June 11, 2026.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

