<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H03BBF842599542E48443D33DDEFB0923" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9418 IH: Access to Innovative Treatments Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9418</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide a review process for adverse national coverage determinations with respect to drug coverage under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA55ED24D08F1404C948F8F023167D6A0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCE21199AE6994D229D09B8DF0323047F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Innovative Treatments Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2CB7D55061A2460186B237CC2E4F3E03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Providing a review process for adverse national coverage determinations with respect to drug coverage under the Medicare program</header> <subsection id="H6E5FDEB747794859830D8E422547B816"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1862(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8AA83C728C6144BE92C6B869197E1A0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) and (6) as paragraphs (7) and (8), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27DFFEC27B8A4098B64B9546CDB7EFB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H337458613E9248FC9AC361164022330A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H87D1E1AE167D4263B26A9881CE8778A2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Review of national coverage determinations for drugs and biologicals</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFB289799255D475991FDE4C9461F2184"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (D), not later than 90 days after receiving a request for a review of a specified national coverage determination (as defined in subparagraph (E)), the Secretary shall initiate such a review in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBDDE01656FC14C45B70826D881758C82"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><text>Beginning on the date of the initiation of a review of a specified national coverage determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide for a 30-day public comment period as to whether such determination should be affirmed, reversed, or otherwise modified.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB856947B8EFE4F44ACAABE8D8DC34CD4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Final decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the conclusion of the 30-day period described in subparagraph (B) with respect to a specified national coverage determination, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H52E976151D964CAC9C05B340BA84D8F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make a final decision as to whether such determination should be affirmed, reversed, or otherwise modified;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8F007EF7F3E845ED9512FF9FA586BB93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include in such final decision summaries of the public comments received and responses to such comments;</text></clause> <clause id="H13E1D7FD9C8943F5A414FDFF8B223E8C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make available to the public the clinical evidence and other data used in making such decision when such decision differs from the recommendations of the Medicare Coverage Advisory Committee; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H403109D299154F06B29BFE6EAC65AAF8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a final decision under clause (i) to reverse or modify such determination, the Secretary shall assign a temporary or permanent code (whether existing or unclassified) and implement the coding change as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCD8586052DD476A89C70E3AEB682E41"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on successive reviews</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a request for a review of a specified national coverage determination if the Secretary has made a final decision with respect to a previous review of such determination under this paragraph during the 2-year period ending on the date of the receipt of such request. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to review or reconsider a national coverage determination if determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3AD649B5D5E4574A31823C142013453"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Specified national coverage determination defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <quote>specified national coverage determination</quote> means a national coverage determination made with respect to a drug or biological approved under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act under which coverage of such drug or biological under this title was denied or otherwise limited in a manner inconsistent with such approval or licensure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB77C617A56AF4FDF8FABCD125B1FCD52"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition on application of certain existing national coverage determinations to newly approved drugs and biologicals</header><text>The Secretary may not, with respect to a drug approved under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or a biological licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act, apply a national coverage determination that was made prior to the date of such approval or licensure (as applicable) to the extent that such application would result in a denial or other limit of coverage under this title for such drug or biological in a manner inconsistent with such approval or licensure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6CAA3CE96E2B47DCACB61AFE176FC04F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonreliance on certain NCDs under part D</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–2(e)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(e)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In determining whether payment would not be made with respect to a covered part D drug if section 1862(a) applied to this part, a prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan may not base such determination on a national coverage determination made with respect to such drug if such determination is a specified national coverage determination (as defined in section 1862(l)(5)).</quote>.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

