<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD0DDC9CABF8349578A3C622DC5207833" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9539 IH: Online Accessibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9539</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to include consumer facing websites and mobile applications owned or operated by a private entity, to establish web accessibility compliance standards for such websites and mobile applications, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBD085554CE344F448C065D6078B5C34F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H49EC1495DBE64494930E1FD2F14CFAC7" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Online Accessibility Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAE1FD75D9F8743ABB8CF9EC53EAAC557"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 relating to consumer facing websites and mobile applications owned or operated by a private entity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H93F67CB36AF545A785C1DCDAB55DF67C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<title id="H5BB72475F42446DCB41E735303348CD5"><enum>VI</enum><header>Consumer Facing websites and Mobile Applications Owned or Operated by a Private
            Entity</header> 
<section id="H3634FFCD30E645DD9A4653DFB5A269D8"><enum>601.</enum><header>Requirements for consumer facing websites and mobile applications owned or operated by a private entity</header> 
<subsection id="HDBD92BB71404410987FB9A78A7CC2503"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No individual, by reason of a disability, shall be excluded from participation in or be denied the full and equal benefits of the services of a consumer facing website or mobile application, or be subjected to discrimination by any private owner or operator of a consumer facing website or mobile application.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A8FCC03844044068DF25C3B4BC7D905"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standard for compliance</header> <paragraph id="H780E5331C1204DCA981EB9DEBC9F6507"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A consumer facing website or mobile application shall be considered compliant under the requirements of this section if such website or mobile application is in substantial compliance with the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (referred to in this title as WCAG) 2.0 Level A and Level AA standard established by the Accessibility Guidelines Working Group, or any subsequent update, revision, or replacement to the WCAG 2.0 Level A and Level AA standard published by the World Wide Web Consortium or successor organization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4CB53B90F3A4920BD35AB04AEF609AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative means of access</header><text>A private entity that owns or operates a consumer facing website or mobile application that is not in substantial compliance with the standard set forth under paragraph (1) shall provide an alternative means of access for individuals with disabilities that is equivalent to access the content available on such website or mobile application.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H70E6794F099A4EC7BD750C501F47FA37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulation</header> <paragraph id="H97331215B70E4943A34AB8F39BEFA093"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access Board</header> <subparagraph id="H23C6B243235C4A4690E8B14FC8F09108"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board (referred to in this title as the <quote>Access Board</quote>), shall issue and publish standards setting forth—</text> 
<clause id="HB6A972AD63DF4104AE5F97134C02B1CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for purposes of this title, a definition of <quote>substantial compliance</quote>, <quote>alternative means of access</quote>, and <quote>consumer facing website or mobile application</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H90ECA45E10CE4F8685B32AD08B3D40F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>regulations necessary to implement the standard set forth in subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04E5CB3DD471433795C41B5941DEB879" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing of regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title:</text> <clause id="HB107134E585A42A68DC48EC996E61BBE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Access Board shall promulgate a notice of proposed rulemaking.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9889A913743F4DBFAC54F9317D8612EA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Upon issuance of the notice under clause (i), the Access Board shall solicit comments from the public on such proposed rule for a period of 90 days.</text></clause> <clause id="H5C7C67CF9D054CDC870CCFD62AE35B56" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>After the Access Board has reviewed the comments solicited under clause (ii) and revised such proposed rule, the Office of Management and Budget shall conduct a regulatory assessment of the rule for a period not to exceed 90 days.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H12C94C013B934F6DB516A29BD6C7FBF9" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Not later than 365 days after the Office of Management and Budget has completed the regulatory assessment under clause (iii), the Access Board shall issue final regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38458166857C4C24A6CE36DC8827C516"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review and amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Access Board shall periodically review and, as appropriate, amend the standard required under subsection (b) to reflect technological advances or changes in electronic and information technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9712E4287FB643EEB196B5E2466C26C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Justice</header><text>No later than 365 days after the end of the comment period under subparagraph (B)(ii), the Attorney General shall establish a procedure for receiving and investigating complaints filed under this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H172F51ACB8EF44BEABD3BB1B377FC2A2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Flexibility for small business concerns</header><text>Regulations established under this section shall include flexibility for small business concerns to comply with the standard under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE613E19AA96242369695F8963C67998A"><enum>602.</enum><header>Administrative remedies</header> 
<subsection id="H391A0E02FC284028AD0A4A77BD320671"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exhaustion of administrative remedies</header><text>No individual may bring an action before a civil court to enforce the provisions of this title until all administrative remedies under this section have been exhausted.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H83AC4855920A4F5DA559A012FE1ABB4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice to owner or operator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to filing a complaint with the Attorney General under subsection (c), an individual must first notify the private owner or operator of a consumer facing website or mobile application that such website or mobile application is not in compliance with the standard for compliance under section 601 of this title.</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC57DB624C14414CAD03A926F6629B99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If within 60 days of receiving notice under subsection (b) the owner or operator of a consumer facing website or mobile application fails to bring such website or such application into compliance with the requirement under section 601 of this title, an individual may file a complaint with the Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE47A69BF1F584274B8B598F4C702981C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual files a complaint with the Department of Justice (referred to in this title as the <quote>Department</quote>) under paragraph (1), a copy of such complaint shall be provided to the owner or operator of a consumer facing website or mobile application.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D1C1CCD27EA4C2384D0873EEC9AB2F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting of violations to Attorney General</header> 
<paragraph id="H63EC264DA8B44AFAA9454E76888FB6FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline to file complaint</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual files a complaint with the Department, such complaint shall be filed within the 90-day period beginning on the date after the 60-day period under subsection (b)(1) has terminated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54C3432EF596411B81A3A96B271332DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation by Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving a complaint of an alleged violation, the Attorney General shall complete an investigation within 180 days to determine whether a violation exists.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A9402E1CF4841A0805698D7CE9A6DB8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final agency determination</header><text>The Attorney General shall be considered to have made a final determination on a complaint if—</text> <subparagraph id="H732279181D5B43B18EFD2D7959D11282"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the 180-day period after a complaint has been filed with the Department, the Attorney General determines the owner or operator of a consumer facing website or mobile application is not in compliance with the standard set forth under section 601; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDDDE3E9CADCD4F348AA4E0AA43FC473B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 180-day period expires without the Attorney General having made such a final determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD24906E8B0DA4205B27498A7E71F6F3B" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement by attorney general</header> <paragraph id="HC0A5A82B705B478293E26B17412FB49F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Denial of rights</header> <subparagraph id="H98604EC4D7FB45EAA1D79823199A638E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duty to investigate</header> <clause id="HEC4421824C894F188A5CDFCF89FC2A76" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall investigate alleged violations of this title, and shall undertake periodic reviews of compliance of consumer facing websites and mobile applications under this title.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H48205B7C84BC47FDAE39AE0926EA6747" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Attorney general certification</header><text>On the application of a State or local government, the Attorney General may, in consultation with the Access Board, and after prior notice and a public hearing at which persons, including individuals with disabilities, are provided an opportunity to testify against such certification, certify that a State law or local ordinance that establishes accessibility requirements that meets or exceeds the minimum requirements of this Act for the accessibility and usability of consumer facing websites and mobile applications under this title. At any enforcement proceeding under this section, such certification by the Attorney General shall be rebuttable evidence that such State law or local ordinance does meet or exceed the minimum requirements of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17CFCF486650439C9999ECD37BCD5649" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Potential violation</header><text>If the Attorney General has reasonable cause to believe that—</text> 
<clause id="HBD6D7CAED7F8423D8276513275819426" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any person or group of persons is engaged in a pattern or practice of discrimination under this title; or</text></clause> <clause id="HCDDB21A5CEF240AB88D697A5D39A2C71" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person or group of persons has been discriminated against under this title and such discrimination raises an issue of general public importance,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">the Attorney General may commence a civil action in any appropriate United States district court.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC809A5CA905A4D57B9ACC29E9612A9CE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority of court</header><text>In a civil action under paragraph (1)(B), the court may—</text> <subparagraph id="H6DBC164EAC6045198CC9036ABF88F42D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grant any equitable relief that such court considers to be appropriate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6303170BD08343D2B11BB0F90A7F207A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">order monetary damages to persons aggrieved when requested by the Attorney General; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7829E15A870247DA947FC4E1B75F30D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assess a civil penalty against the entity in an amount—</text> 
<clause id="HDBF65E8E232A4E04A15EA9745482C609" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not to exceed $20,000 for a first violation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8C1CB49D629147F39997C99B142B6D5D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not to exceed $50,000 for any subsequent violation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAD283FD7A734F0DBDBBC8F3B74E914D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Punitive damages</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (2)(B), the term <term>monetary damages</term> and <term>such other relief</term> does not include punitive damages.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF17A7A6FB6A8434884066A0073946DF1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Single violation</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (2)(C), in determining whether a first or subsequent violation has occurred, a determination in a single action, by judgment or settlement, that the consumer facing website or mobile application has engaged in more than one discriminatory act shall be counted as a single violation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63C9616791244EEEAC20A3F68DEE35D7" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Judicial consideration</header><text>In a civil action under paragraph (1)(B), the court, when considering what amount of civil penalty, if any, is appropriate, shall give consideration to any good faith effort or attempt to comply with this Act by the entity.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HDF0374855BCE4AD5B3916E8A2759AA2D"><enum>603.</enum><header>Private right of action</header> <subsection id="H78D24CDA42954751BF70CAF9DDE1AAD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon exhausting all administrative remedies under section 602, any individual aggrieved by a violation of this title may commence a civil action in any appropriate court of the United States against the owner or operator of a consumer facing website or mobile application that engages in such a violation, unless the Attorney General has instituted an enforcement action under this title. A civil action under this title is the sole and exclusive remedy for any person aggrieved by the failure of any consumer facing website or mobile application to meet the requirements of section 601. In any action filed under this title, the complaint shall plead with particularity each element of the plaintiff’s claim, including the specific barriers to access a consumer facing website or mobile application.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCB2660EB178F4E808B125A04F73B3994" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tolling</header><text>With respect to the running of the statutory periods of limitation for such action, the running of such statutory periods shall be deemed suspended during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending 180 days after the date the Access Board has issued final regulations under section 601.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H09D8B7515F6744DBAFCD3B740DE70428"><enum>604.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9EAAD90079584B82BD1925059CD6AEDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consumer facing website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>consumer facing website</term> means any website that is purposefully made accessible to the public for commercial purposes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10731578ED6248E7BBC6C836EDAEFDB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mobile applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mobile application</term> means a consumer facing software application that can be executed on a mobile platform, or a web-based software application that is tailored to a mobile platform but is executed on a server.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H107A078E87CE47CBAC06616202AB6599"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Small business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HDA89EEDB1651417E8A2E3B0A28909FD4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 515 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8CD3636F65F244AB8E31087E3323D86C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="title">Title VI—Consumer Facing Websites and Mobile Applications Owned or Operated
            by a Private Entity</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 601. Requirements for consumer facing websites and mobile applications owned or operated by a private entity.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 602. Administrative remedies.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 603. Private right of action.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 604. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

