<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI26149-KMS-X9-XR8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4032 IS: Gas Prices Relief Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4032</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a gasoline tax holiday.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="ida495f4873c734f7685a9581e3c2ffea2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gas Prices Relief Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id87262CCBD91F4189BFB5DAE72C9A4752"><enum>2.</enum><header>2026 gasoline tax holiday</header><subsection id="id01294D4C0A7C40338E522CFF73151696"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of gasoline removed, entered, or sold on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and before October 1, 2026—</text><paragraph id="id94632953B68F43AC849E7CCDC67389E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the rate of tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4081">section 4081(a)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be zero, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBC6B120CA05C47CB81082CA1EDA8E85C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate under section 4081(a)(2)(B) of such Code shall not apply to gasoline to which the rate under paragraph (1) applies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE1A83B97B572419F92D06AEE848FAB8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to Trust Fund</header><paragraph id="idFC043ECEF37C4B769787F12700A86B83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the general fund to the Highway Trust Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund established under section 9508(a) of such Code amounts equal to the reduction in amounts credited (but for this subsection) to each such Trust Fund by reason of subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id84A8152F3E9245C58BA9365FAEF26A0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination rules</header><subparagraph id="id17578F54A4EA465ABC9FE3A3FBE37AA9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund under paragraph (1) shall be treated for purposes of sections 9503(b)(1) and 9508(b)(2) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8012605B7A924897B25B48B00A4CCDEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Highway Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Highway Trust Fund under paragraph (1) shall be treated for purposes of section 9503(b)(1) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code which are not attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id34152704a576480fab510de5b704639c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Benefits of tax reduction should be passed on to consumers</header><paragraph id="id7a6ba80c8d874b9f87d6716d66ce659b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It is the policy of Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="id89496c6fa72641a48c0c1e5b8656ac2b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consumers immediately receive the benefit of the reduction in taxes resulting from the application of subsection (a),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ad5924d90ec49bd98ad727f22540cf9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transportation motor fuels producers and other dealers take such actions as necessary to reduce transportation motor fuels prices to reflect such reduction, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53a44d4d1cce4d6c858a942d3bc48040"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transportation motor fuels producers and other dealers that fail to reduce transportation motor fuels prices to reflect such reduction shall be subject to monetary penalties which are not less than the amount of the reduction in taxes which should have been passed on to consumers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id88ffa5c5ae8f4f55be53c161961db22f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall use all applicable authorities to ensure that the benefit of the reduction in taxes resulting from the application of subsection (a) is received by consumers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

