<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7445093A9FA64EDFBF6E7194ED2DE12C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6384 IH: Defense Health Agency Prevention Services Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6384</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to brief the Armed Services Committee of the House of Representatives on the feasibility of consolidating covered prevention services into a single facility for each military installation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7C5FE4B395E646BFA142913CE63526A4" style="OLC"><section id="H69BC2C8985144DF192541367749F7BBF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Health Agency Prevention Services Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H70015338DB7542DF994A25B001A6251B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Briefing on consolidating covered prevention services</header><subsection id="H52E4EBDFBA6740A4BFB8A7A375D797AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Briefing required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with each Secretary of a military department, shall provide to the Armed Services Committee of the House of Representatives a briefing on the feasibility of consolidating covered prevention services into a single facility for each military installation (as defined in section 2801 of title 10, United States Code) located in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF4D1A22913714BFC84F4688DB95B0BAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The briefing required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HAFF093D8299F46A5A0C8DA2E242163D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the feasibility and advisability of consolidating covered prevention services into a single facility for each military installation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA131F1D822834E25B9ADF98E27C2D493"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A cost estimate for such consolidation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3415F3D59F7F457E838D1F9E1AB669C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the efforts of each Secretary of a military department to consolidate covered prevention services into a single facility for each military installation under the jurisdiction of such Secretary and successes and lessons learned from such efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB25EE2D37DD84FFA967CD9961D29ABDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered prevention services defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered prevention services</term> means services offered by the Secretary of Defense or a Secretary of a military department to a member of the Armed Forces or a dependent of such member relating to—</text><paragraph id="H632B82614AD444F292D3F3679E69DB0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preventing sexual assault, suicide, harassment, domestic violence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53DFDA0DD6BE4F73B2461A859A958909"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other related community-based prevention services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

