<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82645B2466D0402CAC83957033803503" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7092 IH: Raising Awareness for Youth Suicide Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7092</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies to include mental health and suicide prevention information on student identification cards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2B84E969B3FA4337AE6189E4FD13BCCF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCEC7F70F22AF40038576A5FFF8097E71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Raising Awareness for Youth Suicide Prevention Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RAYS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD20D01E9A94B4C5E9E6CD2D09449BEAC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mental health and suicide prevention information on student identification cards</header> 
<subsection id="H513381A20B714BE4BD7874BFB984C423"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart 2 of part F of title VIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7901">20 U.S.C. 7901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB5732992EA06476880CE8080682872EA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H9DBC33CD877F41E581DC717203E08495"><enum>8549D.</enum><header>Inclusion of mental health and suicide prevention information on student identification cards</header> <subsection id="HCAAF9A3CA4194F8C83BA75DDC59D64A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required information</header> <paragraph id="H0A9D5E8B0BFB40FE872B6BEAFBACCD7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ID Cards</header><text>Each local educational agency that issues identification cards to students in secondary schools shall ensure that such identification cards include contact information for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H19B337A4D7A3485097537429E26255CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 988 Suicide and Crisis Lifeline (or an alternative service designated by the Secretary under subsection (c));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE598D6E8BB4B4B3DAA75C8E3FE75B0D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Crisis Text Line (or an alternative service designated by the Secretary under subsection (c)); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H318A194EE91944ECB55427DA158492D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State or local suicide prevention hotline selected by the agency, if available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E3CDC83088948F3947021493757E7C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other methods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each local educational agency that does not issue identification cards to secondary school students shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDCA242AEF2A04F0A94126136FB350506"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prominently publish the contact information specified in paragraph (1) on a publicly accessible website of the agency; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF27A1FF3779462A8CC30903911E9AF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include such information on computer portals and software platforms regularly used by secondary school students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8AFB73040B0549AD8B99D5D4C5FAD4DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Method of inclusion</header><text>The information required under subsection (a)(1) may be included on identification cards using any method the local educational agency determines appropriate, which may include—</text> <paragraph id="H16C3692E0CC844BA8CEEFEF0DDA163B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>printing the information directly on the cards;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36AAC623AF974B0D9A17E5C74EC4BBE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affixing a sticker to the cards that contains the information; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1154561AF81C40098D3B61ED00CAA4D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other such methods.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5B08D3BAFBF84A7E9983EA8B11512D22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation of alternative services</header> 
<paragraph id="HB3E6D9514FB3431D8C2CD650AB8CB26E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event a service described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) becomes unavailable or ceases to operate effectively, the Secretary may designate an alternative service that provides equivalent or comparable mental health resources to be included on student identification cards as required under such subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6910A1F023F743EFA0C22B699310EE35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 60 days after designating an alternative service under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0B66CC78EB9B486082FF2409493CAB57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify local educational agencies of such designation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB9DC668D8254196BB465EDE68A095B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide such agencies with the contact information for the alternative service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A5DC5DD48724E519ABCC9A82AA6E529"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Optional information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the information required under subsection (a), a local educational agency may consider—</text> <paragraph id="HC6E8A8BA506F47668168CDE4247B58D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">including information on additional mental health resources, such as contact information for school counselors or school mental health resources, on student identification cards; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE796D1B1488C45CDB11CF7384D70E29D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adding the information described in subsection (a)(1) to identification cards issued to teachers, administrators, and other school personnel.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5F8645570E1D4AF7AAC166B292548475"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the heads of other appropriate agencies, shall conduct outreach and awareness campaigns to inform students, parents, school personnel, and the public about the mental health resources described in subsection (a). Such outreach efforts shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H28B80D0C917749F1BCD7030AB1E76318"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include the dissemination of information through school-based programs, websites, social media, and other communication channels; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09E1E4B1CF654285B89BF27CC74EAC9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide information in a manner that is accessible to students and community members with physical, developmental, and intellectual disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0C7F0F7E25A4D3F935245EB7E9B7E33"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header> 
<paragraph id="HFDC419E8E1414005A4439D6A4F8FD867"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Physical ID Cards</header><text>The requirements of subsection (a)(1) shall apply with respect to student identification cards issued by local educational agencies for school years beginning after the effective date of this section. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the modification of a student identification card issued before such effective date.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5624FC9945FD409D92F8CD474A363C01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of subsection (a)(2) shall apply beginning 60 days after the effective date of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA29B7FAABF64EC98BC98AFF4B810593"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>local educational agency</quote> means a local educational agency that receives Federal funds.</text></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H00CF42BE89BE47478CED7D6B53EBA5BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect one year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

