<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H076CBAEE02D54F6ABF9F2B18FD006978" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6605 IH: Secure Our Skies Drone Safety Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6605</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to report on the use of unmanned aircraft systems and on systems developed to counter such unmanned aircraft systems by Federal, State, local, and Tribal agencies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B551E86C1E845A6B0BA45F6A2FDF91C" style="OLC"><section id="H73368954AA28413CA36CDF33969AF9A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Our Skies Drone Safety Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H08C3C0CE527C4AC5B069D7E4FDA323A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete a study, and submit to Congress a report thereon, on the use of unmanned aircraft systems (hereinafter in this Act referred to as <quote>UAS</quote>) and on systems developed to counter such unmanned aircraft systems by Federal, State, local, and Tribal agencies. Such report shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H08B3851EBC244CBF8A0C9E68AF7D2449"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recommendations for the following:</text><subparagraph id="H51277ADB8FFC4CB6B5611835488F5502"><enum>(A)</enum><text>What, if any, legal authorities and what policies need to be changed to improve the ability of such agencies to successfully counter threats from such UAS.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07B0C2C40B2E46E1B02C49785BB30BDA"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>What actions need to be taken to bolster the capabilities of the United States and its allies to manufacture UAS and to simplify the procurement process for UAS.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBD872746B3E4D06A461C85EF738C811"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information about the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4B43E7623A164DA6A8C542E08FA9B156"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of UAS deployed by Federal, State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies as of the date of the report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10889E09A83D44CC8A17DE6B3802C6B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For State, local, and Tribal agencies, the number of UAS purchased from entities operating within an adversarial nation (including any countries included on the list set forth in section 791.4 of title 15 of the Code of Federal Regulations).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D5332432A004DB18B12452E4A1B5FA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>How many UAS are domestically produced.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEED38FD972CC41DCA0B9A90AB21B2BEE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any cost restrictions that prevent law enforcement agencies from expanding the use of UAS produced in the United States or a nation other than one referred to in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B0936798A4147FA871A72D108670DD9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>How frequently UAS are used and for what purposes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D91095D228B435BA2599E79F1BDABDB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Whether the operators of UAS are trained or certified in any way.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4ADF915CA2747DB984E8E4047821D40"><enum>(G)</enum><text>What authorities, policies, or protocols govern the use of UAS.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5972DD81EF9A4C2ABD3DFBF1111602C4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>What privacy protections or expectations are there regarding the use of UAS.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67D062D175B6401DBAA3B9C2F8BB31FC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">What countermeasures or strategies exist to counter UAS, and to what extent is there a training or certification in their use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

