<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM26022-46S-06-XWW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3628 IS: Real Emergency Access for Aging and Disability Inclusion for Disasters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3628</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260113">January 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure that older adults and individuals with disabilities are prepared for disasters, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Real Emergency Access for Aging and Disability Inclusion for Disasters Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REAADI for Disasters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id17613adca2c146129779938e3a8e1b95"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header><subsection id="id4578c4ec42224eac991320a6c1891cb9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id1aaa25776b364fe88e108ba4b5ede59e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the United States, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, there are more than 70,000,000 adults who are individuals with disabilities and, according to the Bureau of the Census, there are more than 54,000,000 adults age 65 or older.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2ceb1ad47104becbb4b887944ffe31f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There have been nearly 400 emergencies declared under section 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>) related to hurricanes and tropical cyclones during the period beginning January 2000 and ending December 2024. These declared emergencies have directly resulted in at least 1,442 deaths in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id09adaa31f4ec4e639ac73937f45d9b8a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration estimates that—</text><subparagraph id="idbb22ae75ec9f40a7bf3ccfff6fd72caf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cumulative damage from weather- and climate-related disasters in 2022 cost the United States over $182,700,000,000; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id844eac1ef8bf4649b6b630ddd078cdcc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>27 of the disasters in 2024 cost over $1,000,000,000 each.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4650f47bf97741b7bee88977c0098bbd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Individuals with disabilities and older adults have been found to die at higher rates, compared to the general population, during disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd383e8d94c67476f9d31df55b9d3f3bb"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in 2024, the United States experienced a total of 108 major disaster and emergency declarations under sections 401 and 501, respectively, of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>, 5191), which resulted in more than 4,000,000 individuals applying for assistance through the Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1cf2931cba7e4c52b2f984a16c112dd2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in 2022, the United States experienced 90 major disasters declared under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>) affecting more than 54,000,000 people, and more than 16,000,000 of those people were adults with disabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id84207408c6864d748a8a7aee6074d11b"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Failure to provide accessibility for, or plan for accommodating, individuals with physical or sensory disabilities, chronic illness, or mental disabilities decreases the ability of those individuals to evacuate prior to or during a disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a404a8fdac8485484cc3ff39ab16e6d"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Households of individuals with disabilities are more likely to need assistance and are less likely to be able to evacuate in advance of disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9389ba4378cd4d549ebb83202a0aaf68"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Less than a third of individuals with intellectual disabilities and individuals needing personal care attendants have planned with their personal care providers what to do in a disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9926cdec3ed541588f9fbd066d00ceb2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Evacuation information, including orders, is not uniformly communicated in ways and via media that are accessible to individuals with disabilities, including being communicated in ways that lack use of American Sign Language, captions, and plain language on websites, instructional materials, and television and radio announcements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f619fb3b729482f9f6919eaae173a0e"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Displaced individuals with disabilities served in general population shelters have better access to information and material resources than individuals with disabilities in specially designed shelters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb60a81864a9429e8005955575b24b8f"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Despite the better access to information and resources provided at general population shelters, personnel in general population shelters often do not have the resources or training to address the needs of individuals with disabilities and older adults.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1894233689ed421ea0c5d4732e514e75"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Public shelters often do not have disability-related accommodations, often forcing individuals with disabilities and older adults to be segregated, sometimes apart from their families and natural supports during disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ab7b85e6dc948a1aa533ff6350f5def"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Households with individuals with disabilities sustain more costly property damage from disasters than households without individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68c812775c0346d1ba94c49e24910e4a"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Historically, disaster-related recommendations for individuals with disabilities and older adults have been typically aimed at caregivers and service providers, not individuals with disabilities and older adults themselves.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43a39de4832244b09882ea9aa97dcbaa"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Thousands of individuals with disabilities have been denied their civil rights because they do not receive accessible notice during disasters—</text><subparagraph id="id0eb40ae0e79a4a12b97f30cfedd796b0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of spoken instructions via phone or video; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id052b1e3cb941459a939c99daf40ebdb2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>of instructions regarding evacuations, sheltering, and other procedures during disasters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id544803d944354b94b3f8a4d76da4915e"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Disaster shelters and services do not routinely have American Sign Language interpreters nor procedures written or presented in plain language.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id136b93f275b4441abe9e95a7a46329d6"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Individuals with disabilities and older adults are more at risk for loss of life, loss of independence, or violation of civil rights than the general population during times of disasters, response, and recovery.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida81390948f6d495aa909a8507cd901c4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="idb4bffd29318446d792cbbfb23faa172d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities and older adults should be supported during times of disasters, and during disaster preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation, in order to—</text><subparagraph id="idbec5456cfd6744adb2776680fcbf1439"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure maintenance of and access to services and supports; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb52586445b8641f9a28f9a802038c1d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enable those individuals and adults to return to their communities in a timely manner as compared with the general population;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a3e5861d8c64e23bf25faa0a11b6a7f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during the recovery and mitigation phases of disaster response, all buildings and services should be designed, and constructed or reconstructed, according to principles of universal design and to the standards established by the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board in order to ensure access for individuals with disabilities, older adults, and all individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6001995eb5314bf89574b29a10cd1c72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities and older adults should have access to shelters and other services during disasters in the same locations and settings as the general population;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b432eba50d840faa2c30ede7aaa024f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities and older adults should receive information about preparation for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters in formats accessible to them, including in American Sign Language, Braille, and plain language, as well as captioned video messages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c9b1182a0874196b50d47ea1a8c7f4d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities and older adults must be included as key speakers, essential stakeholders, and decisionmakers in the preparation (including planning), response, recovery, and mitigation phases of disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9bc0de3cd6ef4ee684377f22c7b76e78"><enum>(6)</enum><text>local, State (including territorial), Tribal, and Federal disaster planning must include robust representation of individuals with disabilities and older adults; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c23ec7e065a4fecbf5d617a754a2e67"><enum>(7)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities and older adults must be included in the evaluation of governmental, VOAD, and other nongovernmental preparation (including planning), response, recovery, and mitigation of disasters.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id975ff5cc4e6945df97421b49c0b1c190"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text><paragraph id="id14f6e1950a5940b1866493ee9332f917"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the inclusion of individuals with disabilities and older adults in the preparation for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id240a76df120248b8a2fd5f97c077c228"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that individuals with disabilities and older adults with disabilities are free from discrimination on the basis of disability or age in programs and activities and are protected during, and included in, all phases of disaster preparation, response, recovery, and mitigation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c7f7457a0cc4ece8dc2c4a18be25f2d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, and other disability laws during preparation for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40ad1a46dd6b4dacb84cb35c1d8a7a20"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve coordination among the communities of individuals with disabilities and older adults, including multiply marginalized BIPOC and LGBTQ+ communities, government agencies, centers for independent living, VOADs, and other nongovernmental organizations, including organizations that represent and are comprised of covered individuals, in preparing (including planning) for, responding to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59d2d78d99d9482da4e4f4c38dc26134"><enum>(5)</enum><text>improve outcomes for all individuals, including individuals with disabilities and older adults, who are affected by disasters, and increase community resilience in responding to disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4639d4f648d4c75a2580c67036666f4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establish dedicated Federal funding for capacity-building and rapid response to support Federal, State (including territorial), Tribal, and local entities, and public and private human services entities, to support activities to address the needs of at-risk individuals before, during, and after a disaster; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb285b5a87e5945f5a698e9a38cf9609c"><enum>(7)</enum><text>enact into Federal law standards of care and standards for protection of civil rights, for older adults and people with disabilities, to be applied for disasters and public health emergencies.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id4f8caf8a7ec04bb79198987f228baec1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="iddb4be8e3900a4e968a3134b981ccfeab"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access and functional needs</header><text>The term <term>access and functional needs</term>, used with respect to an individual, means an individual with needs such as—</text><subparagraph id="idb70df09114004bf988ea589567679642"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual with a disability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id343e1fb963d04d8fb3cbd482bce67c35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an older adult;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c8c6703f6c94bf39840377c4ae7b418"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual with limited English proficiency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14c12b1badb245ff8c4777a456c9d1f2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an individual with limited access to transportation that would enable the individual to prepare for, respond to, recover from, and mitigate a disaster; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14dbe412649f407a814c917514d78d86"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an individual with limited access to the financial resources that would enable the individual to prepare for, respond to, recover from, and mitigate a disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb0beaa342a141d0a5b94af91b7f307e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>At-risk individuals</header><text>The term <term>at-risk individuals</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1306c0fb5ce94741a1cc19a0538f3219"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given the term in section 2802(b)(4)(B) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300hh-1">42 U.S.C. 300hh–1(b)(4)(B)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7abe1f585467443688937f2594af3f39"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd1c6452f5b44087812ef84831f2225d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">older individuals, individuals with disabilities, and children; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8257ba65a054e36b2a480fd875c8ee7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">members of families that include individuals described in clause (i) or subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ddc16250dbe4cfd9a58a231c4e7f85d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civil rights</header><text>The term <term>civil rights</term>, used with respect to an individual, means the existing (as of the date of enactment of this Act) legal rights of an individual to be free from discrimination on the basis of disability or age in programs and activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id087db06d8d2d42afb271ec7717a1afcc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual with a disability, an older adult, and an individual with access and functional needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf1be91cbdc7420e87867dff7902ff93"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc94e7cf95ab4c69892b2b9b89cf1b25"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b61758f01984065b22bbbf2b928ba8e"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Disability inclusive emergency management experience</header><text>The term <term>disability inclusive emergency management experience</term>, used with respect to an individual or entity—</text><subparagraph id="idc02fb9edf069494893cf1a92198f3901"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual or entity that has—</text><clause id="idc651df14bef747518df6f61beb60f874"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrated disability leadership experience, including working with nongovernmental entities; and</text></clause><clause id="id6c7dd63a84ee4c63a6ce74cc3808e4bb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject matter expertise in leading disability inclusive preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation initiatives that focus on meeting the civil rights of covered individuals who are affected by disasters, to be free from discrimination on the basis of disability or age in programs and activities; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b92b0bd6988415698205fca402d9282"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an individual or entity that has demonstrated favorable outcomes that measure the effective communication access, physical access, program access, health, safety, and independence of individuals affected by disasters and their communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6bd26c59ec543eb8263f72885e0ac05"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Disaster</header><text>The term <term>disaster</term> means an emergency or major disaster (as such terms are defined under section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>)) that results in severe property damage, deaths, or multiple injuries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida960a91d2a11486ba519a1fe234d3879"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Disaster services</header><text>The term <term>disaster services</term> means the process of responding to a disaster and providing humanitarian aid to individuals and communities who are affected by a disaster.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6389241a94cc4bddb775781fe32a5b65"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Disproportionately affected</header><text>The term <term>disproportionately affected</term>, used with respect to a group, means a group of individuals with protected status, including individuals with disabilities or older adults, who are excessively adversely affected by disaster-related harms.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03d5eb9dc34c4360a91cc12abb4ea31d"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Disaster Human Services Emergency Fund established under section 7.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7fbb87b7e1ed4c1398032f36722cd13f"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Human services</header><text>The term <term>human services</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc66801a0119745a591fbed4654628a17"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means programs and activities designed to aid individuals, families, and communities to prevent or remediate problems or events that destabilize lives and undermine the ability to meet basic needs in the immediate aftermath of a disaster and medium- and long-term needs after a disaster; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c6889e417094f85894e2925f8b62f3f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f06c45cd5bb470fbfbdc1cc704cf586"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preparedness training and capacity-building;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6976e45b3c314041bdd95f9460ac1c98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">peer support;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0a0509a8da6434d91e3a8589d3e1745"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">child care;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0ecbdbbb04645bc9303ad3b9510688f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nutritional services;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b19f3668ec9458288cb3b1daf1b8246"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">home and community-based supports and services;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec62a1ea350b49b891b1bc26c271e69e"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">personal care;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf0cdbcf5b624a11861bf3154004fafd"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">case management;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67426f62e5fe402ca50fc3939bbfb59c"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">behavioral health and psychosocial support;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe7d8c7a50304050a0517fd5f07e676b"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance with accessing home repair and modifications;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c18aaceb01e49659740faefd915b3e7"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accessible housing;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1cf16626d7214326bc7169865bd102f2"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">food, home, transportation, communication, and language access;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8b3b339d41d44d79986b825545ca360"><enum>(xii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">helping prevent institutionalization or helping transition individuals to community living;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b59901d69624d5c8f24161294ca91ff"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">helping with evacuation; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id308a94ed435d48d0b1c148b3d314f5f9"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting at-risk individuals in accessing durable medical equipment or other equipment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idA797039F8DCC4F7CA0277935420A4D2F"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Indian Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribal government</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribal government</term> in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5383a55c5f6c4b3bafb0ee0225934549"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Individuals with disabilities</header><text>The term <term>individuals with disabilities</term> means more than one individual with a disability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ebddbd456f24d6986ccf60297e5af60"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Older adult</header><text>The term <term>older adult</term> has the meaning given the term ‘older individual’ in section 102 of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3002">42 U.S.C. 3002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcffe5e1b34e04474b90df0994e3da115"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Public health emergency</header><text>The term <term>public health emergency</term> means a public health emergency declared under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94e981cd23e44cf7b6c02996d7972a44"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Resident</header><text>The term <term>resident</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id5751E770A6BB469187C62CA00E21F160"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an individual receiving assistance through an Indian Tribal government or other Indian entity, a resident of an area or member of a community governed by an Indian Tribal government; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73C9F8A80A6C4B22B24CB1EB014E2961"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an individual not described in subparagraph (A), a resident of a State that is not an Indian Tribal government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f73fd1b88a04e1c8694b75014cba087"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b81d8614edb4a6898f02911798abdd5"><enum>(19)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any of the 50 States, an Indian Tribal government, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbbee14f9f3674ad88fbf58f2cb7847e6"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Visitability standards</header><text>The term <term>visitability standards</term> means standards for Type C (Visitable) Units under the Standards for Accessible and Usable Buildings and Facilities (ICC A117.1–2009), or any successor standards, of the American National Standards Institute.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16abf17f4499484fad2f48d79c3ee60c"><enum>(21)</enum><header>VOAD</header><text>The term <term>VOAD</term> means a nongovernmental organization assisting in disaster preparation, recovery, response, or mitigation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id5C7500967445460396AE8A4A7B9C2B91"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use of disaster response funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 615 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5196d">42 U.S.C. 5196d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idDD58550FE6154C07AA4B3069FA640C0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Funds made available</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85ACD909B06E409EA8DD10A7B60F9B73"><subsection id="id27704CD8D10F40C58399EDFD4E7A7F76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idC9AC91E4768446AB904E1F3718D48DDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access and functional needs</header><text>The term <term>access and functional needs</term>, used with respect to an individual, means an individual with needs such as—</text><subparagraph id="idD8576D29472B40A2A4F47E3DD6A22784"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual with a disability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80DF6E88AFDA459F9F1A96D0BCE48599"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an older adult;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96A09A02A0594A8CAEC1FC0630B2CB46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual with limited English proficiency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB437D523D1BB4F80AC48FEB7398A7776"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an individual with limited access to transportation that would enable the individual to prepare for, respond to, recover from, and mitigate an emergency or major disaster; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB64A37830CE6406FBA8E7D9158DFB42F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an individual with limited access to the financial resources that would enable the individual to prepare for, respond to, recover from, or mitigate an emergency or major disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2FE676F126DE47EC9D88322A68CDF1BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Center for independent living</header><text>The term <term>center for independent living</term> has the meaning given that term in section 702 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/796a">29 U.S.C. 796a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4BDC98D669DC4B399C21F643D0753147"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered recipient</header><subparagraph id="idD459AD19B6964B68A952793614391704"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered recipient</term> means a direct or indirect recipient of funds made available under this title for a covered use of funds.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0954FCE7E59E42D6A43B5A71CD882617"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>covered recipient</term> does not include individuals or households.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC57A7114964D452589ADE0506134AB1C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered use of funds</header><text>The term <term>covered use of funds</term> means the use of funds for the preparation for, response to, recovery from, or mitigation of hazards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB05C6B6045A64948B4B8C5CBD154B9DC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Individual with a disability</header><subparagraph id="idFEB916198C254D1F9AC3E2417CD22E38"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Single</header><text>The term <term>individual with a disability</term> means an individual with a disability, as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A518670D4134A7BBE1EB98E57733D15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plural</header><text>The term <term>individuals with disabilities</term> means more than 1 individual with a disability, as defined in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7E348DE4282B4B3B8CAE00BCFD032E08"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Older adult</header><text>The term <term>older adult</term> means an individual who is age 50 or older.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7166102DA9234275B7A33ECCBC16E5EB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Visitability standards</header><text>The term <term>visitability standards</term> means standards for Type C (Visitable) Units under the Standards for Accessible and Usable Buildings and Facilities (ICC A117.1–2009), or any successor standards, of the American National Standards Institutes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF9D556D554BB4480A521F6D34E82F0A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds generally</header><text>Funds made available</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id45D469C940F4414BA5BDFF9C20120C9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2780D14586A5486AA5AF0D10655282DB"><subsection id="idAC458BBC5E7847558B073A412E97BDCD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory committees</header><text>A covered recipient shall ensure that an advisory committee that includes individuals with disabilities, older adults, and other individuals with access and functional needs shall oversee the use of funds made available under this title to the covered recipient.</text></subsection><subsection id="idA64677B25DF34212A3EBB8E191FD15BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance with disability laws</header><text>A covered recipient shall use funds made available under this title in accordance with the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id515ECEC5EA914923A08F4ECE9F2D1CE9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Centers for independent living</header><text>A covered recipient may contract with 1 or more centers for independent living to—</text><paragraph id="idEAF15817CB9B4FCD930E992CAE7E3036"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare for hazards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1521F718024D4B029312FCF5C41575EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide personal assistance services during response and recovery periods;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8D9DAB62792D4446A4F4C4568F0D9124"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify accessible emergency shelters and adapt emergency shelters to be accessible;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD04139A29191431FA244F298DB5FFC3D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop accessible media, including media using American Sign Language; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id775BE3191FEC4DABB25FC788F399BAF9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>meet other needs for individuals with disabilities, older adults, and individuals with access and functional needs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB5DFDBE8B6B04DF18048525BF015DD1B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Contractors</header><text>A nongovernmental organization that enters into a contract with a covered recipient relating to a covered use of funds shall comply with the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) in providing property or services under the contract.</text></subsection><subsection id="idDE2F4C585EAB450ABD22D3F4BECDF815"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Communications</header><text>Communications relating to a covered use of funds by a covered recipient shall be made available in languages, including American Sign Language and other sign languages, used in the communities receiving the communications.</text></subsection><subsection id="id594E622D8600428F81DDF94D75BCC2AA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text>A covered recipient shall ensure each facility or service made available in connection with a covered use of funds is accessible to individuals with disabilities, older adults, and other individuals with access and functional needs, including—</text><paragraph id="idEB18B9436C054A7B82830F894EB64D8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notifications relating to a hazard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id442D3DB109294677A4BEAF3E0267D957"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evacuation notifications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89AFF3EECCA743919974C03A4F01D590"><enum>(3)</enum><text>notifications relating to disaster services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB315C0B58436435B89D0D68D0B10F2C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>emergency shelters.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id86E0011658114EB38CFA5BC154A7DD50"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visitability</header><text>A covered recipient that, as part of a covered use of funds, constructs or prepares dwelling units (including sleeping units) shall ensure that the dwelling units meet visitability standards.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="idb25b956adea9459a8b7d59a1e3cd3d8c"><enum>6.</enum><header>Training, technical assistance, and research disability and disaster centers</header><subsection id="idf5f926e7a5cf49878945e14a6192cfa0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to provide financial support to eligible entities to create centers through which the eligible entities will—</text><paragraph id="id938cb68580d845fcb15410e4e5c2fcc2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide training and technical assistance to State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster relief, public health, and social service agencies in the implementation and enhancement of systemic and effective engagement policies, programs, and activities that ensure—</text><subparagraph id="iddcfdd1d241bc4b37bf5a89d12505679d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the needs and civil rights of covered individuals are addressed and implemented throughout all phases of disaster preparation, response, recovery, and mitigation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38ed9459503f4dd1a9801ddf29242ebe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the inclusion of covered individuals in the development of all State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster preparation plans;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fc0133dd2d24745bea200cf841854b7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster relief agencies in the coordination and integration of Federal, State (including territorial), local, and Tribal services and programs to serve covered individuals in the least restrictive environment appropriate to their needs during a disaster;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id939ac260f572441bbbf91aa81e10c738"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct research and expand knowledge about covered individuals and their experiences during the preparation, response, recovery, and mitigation phases of disasters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1053898bca3471fa59d508cf08f9c15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>discover, through research, and disseminate knowledge about, the most effective methods for—</text><subparagraph id="id2e8dbee73d964de0852a51a96b0ec5e2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protecting the civil rights of covered individuals during times of disasters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id199a19dceb0c473d98537bd74b088184"><enum>(B)</enum><text>including covered individuals in all phases of disaster preparation, response, recovery, and mitigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5534f06f31f04dfd901256b0a929c356"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reducing their deaths, injuries and losses from disasters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fd5e1600df34972b01101b17d38f7cc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reducing the displacement and disproportionate effects of relocation after a disaster, including financial and social effects, on covered individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b3295bd1b61406d8ca84c74261d03c0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ensuring covered individuals are participants in the research, development, and distribution of evidence-based information regarding disasters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd831c9babee64affa7b469a95dbd89ce"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id07cf8ea2d4014473a3292a1cc37e293d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity or partnership of entities that—</text><subparagraph id="id2aa78551aba64b2f93658581dbe62d0d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submits an application to the Secretary in accordance with subsection (e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc99e6f5933b40a7a67e62d36635395f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is or includes an institution (which may be an institution of higher education), or a nongovernmental organization, that focuses on—</text><clause id="id7b4b742a8d6e45868de539db6f4ea9ed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serving the needs of individuals with disabilities; or</text></clause><clause id="ida1f9fe5477e443bfa64d43004d5c8bd2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serving the needs of older adults;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id901ccc5aa9a84cde8d2a9a3bca971730"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of an entity or partnership with a disability focus, has a cross-disability service focus;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a2a31535f01489eb59abc36455e0c64"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has experience in conducting training, technical assistance, and research pertaining to consumer-directed community support services for covered individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id300e48fdcba947d48ec305871d2e9a63"><enum>(E)</enum><text>includes covered individuals in positions of leadership in the planning, management, and operation of the programs of training, technical assistance, and research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0dc1550c2e3450b8294cb6aabdde454"><enum>(F)</enum><text>has knowledge and experience pertaining to the implementation and enhancement of systemic and effective engagement policies, programs, and activities that promote the inclusion, needs, and civil rights of covered individuals in preparation for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e91a2f85ae74477bab2814678168397"><enum>(G)</enum><text>has, or will establish, an advisory council or similar entity, of which at least 51 percent of the members are covered individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9be4dd3818e4aa8aa91f4ebb4aaf836"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf117965b62574e81aae8704057a22f0d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholder group</header><text>The term <term>stakeholder group</term> means a group of individuals and organizations that—</text><subparagraph id="idf7f253ae81d34d20ac5aa0312b8f4fab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is committed to disability inclusive and older adult inclusive disaster management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2285e77d55be421fb7291e2848794c06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes covered individuals throughout preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d39b13c64334edb8e9c9f7c89613669"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has leaders that include covered individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb03d1c77b943416499cefac96ee82c03"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has a governing or advisory board, of which at least half of the members are covered individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id577dd64245d2407a9b35b27c5e376787"><enum>(E)</enum><text>has a mission to inclusively serve covered individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb7a4a918af874a8dbcd060b771601ea4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority for grants</header><text>The Secretary may award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities, to provide for—</text><paragraph id="id10a7f99808c04ad98e27c9bd4177f0de"><enum>(1)</enum><text>activities that include covered individuals in the preparation (including planning) for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide132050429884b89812cb3b6384d4cbf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>except as described in subsection (d)(2), research related to disasters and covered individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id647b05a090524535b2671963926ad68b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount and period of grants</header><paragraph id="id4cd5d403addc495d9d4a50f1e30e675e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, award a grant to an eligible entity in an amount that is not less than $2,500,000 and not more than $10,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a9625d990604110b2d445e838c163de"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall award not fewer than 2 of the grants in each of the 10 Federal regions of the Department of Health and Human Services. At least 1 grant in each region shall be awarded to an eligible entity exclusively to conduct training and technical assistance described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id67d90cae2ccd478e8ad8aae107146b4e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Periods</header><text>The Secretary shall award the grants for periods of 5 years, through an open competition held at the end of each 5-year period. Eligible entities that receive grants under this section may reapply for such grants at the end of the periods.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8d6e9681c7704c928e74cb3deba7ec2f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header><paragraph id="id60ed33051d074ea580ac75b3ca96885a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submissions</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80cb591e0c714541bfca6960f8a56ac5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each such application shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text><subparagraph id="iddee448c6f1474fafbe10e9c083be2a97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the applicant’s demonstrated experience in providing training, information, and support to individuals with disabilities in preparing for, responding to, recovering from, and mitigating disasters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1d6a993facc424bbeff41d1f6fbdf36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the applicant’s demonstrated experience in providing training, information, and support to older adults in preparing for, responding to, recovering from, and mitigating disasters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20ed6346768341a48d82ea2d4dea29f6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the applicant’s demonstrated experience in working with Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial government agencies in preparing for, responding to, recovering from, and mitigating disasters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05e5110c80ee45be8c99764f5af80809"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the steps the applicant, acting through the center, will take to target services to low-income individuals and individuals identified as disproportionately affected in disasters, including those individuals at greatest risk of institutionalization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id636f2e943a2b45519a30843b97a656a6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assurance that the applicant, acting through the center, will—</text><clause id="idc36bc23350b448408232e15f580b483a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>work with State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster relief, public health, and social service agencies to determine the best means for delivery of services to address the needs of covered individuals;</text></clause><clause id="ida7e4361b53c8434db55872d6dcbe4f7e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist in establishing State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster plans to address the needs of both rural and urban populations;</text></clause><clause id="id754c7a171dc841a4a48fa8cc20697c16"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in carrying out activities under the grant, conduct sufficient outreach to centers for independent living, VOADs, and other nongovernmental organizations, including organizations that represent and are comprised of covered individuals;</text></clause><clause id="id818c612155cb4d538574b19de60afe9f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>include covered individuals in a meaningful way in the development and execution of activities carried out under the grant;</text></clause><clause id="id5633e3e63b3e4803be55465caa24df03"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provide adequate staff, including staff who are individuals with disabilities, to carry out the activities under the grant; and</text></clause><clause id="id3af8ef3f56c14037a9e7ccca6682ca30"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>communicate information on the programs and systems developed under the grant, in accessible formats and languages, including American Sign Language, of the communities being served.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idecd614acd1d747238b60bb1f125bbfc5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants for activities described in this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text><paragraph id="ida8c3037cedfb4476a9444550aa733e83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrate a minimum of 3 years of experience in actively conducting disability inclusive and older adult inclusive disaster management;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40641c23a4604a54aefc232f04cb07ad"><enum>(2)</enum><text>propose activities to address the preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation needs of covered individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78e6915e20ed4a72b7033e385a41472d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>propose activities to address leadership development in State, local, Tribal, and territorial agencies and covered individual advocacy organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fd9de3c4410434c912e8d0ee5aa4e34"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes covered individuals in positions of leadership in the planning, management, and operation of the activities carried out under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1be76cb8afdd4f6c891a09c32747e9b1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>demonstrate ability to provide training that prevents bias due to disability or age, and that uses experiential approaches and does not rely on simulations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc63fe3637574bc9bd83d66af3230924"><enum>(6)</enum><text>demonstrate expertise concerning the obligation to prevent discrimination against covered individuals on the basis of disability and age in programs and provide activities and specific plans for achieving and maintaining physical access, program access, and effective communication for covered individuals throughout all grant activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f13c342ca684101b7e41bb4e984f728"><enum>(7)</enum><text>demonstrate that the eligible entity involved will use measurable collaboration and partnership strategies with State, local, Tribal, and territorial agencies, centers for independent living, VOADs, and other nongovernmental organizations, including organizations that represent and are comprised of covered individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3bfc04f4e3f4cc39fd088f1e573442e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>demonstrate that the eligible entity will use measurable disaster outcomes strategies in carrying out grant activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76bd47214c89472fae3d3272e3c1d0bb"><enum>(9)</enum><text>demonstrate the ability to quickly create products, such as videos, fact sheets, guidelines, and checklists, to be used in disaster management;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4f02a9b12f64322891215dc559f3ab7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>employ constituents of the entity in decisionmaking positions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ba20b27540246d58ffa07c1805de108"><enum>(11)</enum><text>provide disability inclusive and older adult inclusive disaster management leadership skills development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida677beafc67b45ebabf1d52e860dcf56"><enum>(12)</enum><text>demonstrate awareness of available resources in the community for meeting the preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation needs of covered individuals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32d02ea8a41148ce99a57af10d72f0c5"><enum>(13)</enum><text>demonstrate expertise in promoting the use of universal design (as defined in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>)), the philosophy of independent living (within the meaning of that philosophy in title VII of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/796">29 U.S.C. 796 et seq.</external-xref>)), intersectionality imperatives, and the social model of disability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id68e81113b72446d4b2c7cc27cb5015a3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="id1161222f814b4bb19bb78703b37527f4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Grant funds made available under this section shall be used only for activities described in and approved by the Secretary as a part of an application submitted under subsection (e), to carry out—</text><subparagraph id="idd58e08e366774374921995fcead3d50b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a strategy designed to ensure the inclusion of covered individuals in the preparation (including planning) for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0450c1bc89c94eff8a08fe184053ec47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>research to enhance the activities described in subparagraph (A), using not more than 25 percent of the grant funds to carry out that research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida40977f9b0bd42d0a8ce920cf50f266e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Such activities may include initiatives that provide comprehensive training, technical assistance, development of funding sources, and support to State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster relief, public health, and social service agencies and stakeholder groups, in order to ensure that, in carrying out disaster management planning and programs, the agencies and groups address the inclusion, civil rights, and needs of covered individuals by—</text><subparagraph id="id15c7b463a70642659e2523050f86f12c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hiring personnel with direct knowledge of and experience with meeting the civil rights of covered individuals to be free from discrimination on the basis of disability or age in programs and activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b75eb772b5340cea9299586e7a54217"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training staff of State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster relief, public health, and social service agencies on the needs and civil right of covered individuals, preferably through training by experts who are, collectively, individuals with disabilities and older adults;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6ffca65a7e843a08771192e1d51b5a5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>creating partnerships between eligible entities, State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster relief, public health, and social service agencies, centers for independent living, VOADs, and other nongovernmental organizations, including organizations that represent and are comprised of covered individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id83f7adf0c6364d10ba59409cd0ddbb4f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assisting in the development and implementation, in partnership with State, local, Tribal, and territorial disaster relief, public health, and social service agencies, of plans that will provide for a continuum of services to remove barriers to full engagement for covered individuals during a disaster and in preparedness (including planning) for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of a disaster;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc16caf1217d14d7da87f685f867c0a9d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assisting in the creation of standards and identification of funding sources for rebuilding disaster-damaged housing and new housing that is accessible, affordable, and disaster-resilient;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfec3c324651044beb01358d96635b8d1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>assisting in the creation of standards for homeowner and flood insurance coverage for rebuilding disaster-damaged housing and new housing that is accessible, affordable, and disaster-resilient;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1a321ef3e5ee4b1d83f703040dc9c926"><enum>(G)</enum><text>establishing universal design and accessibility standards, and establishing specifications for visitability (based on the visitability standards), for achieving and maintaining equal access for covered individuals throughout hazard mitigation and disaster resilience activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf84f66c0e6ca47909b614de9a356f274"><enum>(H)</enum><text>establishing initiatives to increase new and transferred technology and innovations to solve notification, evacuation, health maintenance, and other barriers for covered individuals before, during, and after disasters; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd848f20ef670440fbfb6fea51450e6a2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conducting research, in partnership with covered individuals, that will contribute to knowledge and strategies to—</text><clause id="id1181bed172b94b3c8b624de9b273d46f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>decrease injuries, deaths, and harm to covered individuals;</text></clause><clause id="id34957f2760444ee28e8b95dd3329cbc5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>create inclusive disaster preparedness, recovery, response, and mitigation strategies for State, local, Tribal, and territorial agencies, centers for independent living, VOADs, and other nongovernmental organizations, including organizations that represent and are comprised of covered individuals;</text></clause><clause id="id2643fb969f4849a081b03ce9945f3c19"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>preserve community living options and access to needed services and supports for covered individuals during post-disaster periods; and</text></clause><clause id="id8369da695f4844e3abd58d5ad400fc32"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>conduct longitudinal studies that create and maintain datasets to assist in the understanding of Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial policies designed to reduce the negative impact of disasters on covered individuals and protect the civil right of covered individuals to be free from discrimination on the basis of disability or age in programs and activities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2747ffb4cfa342c88f40aed2d3a25db0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Standards and guidelines</header><text>The Secretary shall establish standards and guidelines for activities supported by a grant under this section. Such standards and guidelines shall be developed with the input of stakeholder groups. In a situation in which a refinement or adaptation of the standards or guidelines is made necessary by a local circumstance, the Secretary shall enter into negotiations with an eligible entity applying for such a grant for a project in the affected area, to refine or adapt the standards and guidelines for the project.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5fc1c8d09105457e9364c53a4e9a1bf6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Individual rights</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, no entity, agency, or group assisted under this section shall take any action that infringes in any manner on the civil right of covered individuals to be free from discrimination on the basis of disability or age in programs and activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1e4bc5b278be41408e28ee860d054cd2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than January 31 of fiscal years 2028 and 2030, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the activities carried out under this section during the preceding 2 fiscal years.</text></subsection><subsection id="id422f87067c554452b9339a68aeb9de87"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><section id="id69f90777b4d7484e8da34894dd0ee171"><enum>7.</enum><header>Disaster Human Services Emergency Fund</header><subsection id="id6e86252653a24ba5939ee961b33f4c6d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62503408ec7849f69d31e98ba1b86828"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idf4a8db13ae1847f7841c67265fc07bd5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State or local government agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0d18e41750e4739abe044d1048252a2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id105285fa2b2043c49fbb9ee2ccc82009"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization, including a public or nonprofit provider of services</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fef8342b44f40138bbbb03d5f4c1651"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Major disaster</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major disaster</term> means a disaster that the President has declared is a major disaster or emergency under section 401 or 501, respectively, of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>, 5191).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb27b32b512cf48feabe233097115d0fd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disasters Human Services Emergency Fund</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9a74a600f044af187e7b45f6df479a5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the general fund of the Treasury an account, to be known as the <quote>Disaster Human Services Emergency Fund</quote>. The Fund shall be administered by the Secretary, in accordance with this section, to rapidly respond to the immediate human services needs resulting when—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8552628c5f2241a18cf0206f6b308685"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public health emergency or major disaster has been declared; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8718dc38e204b64bb6e1459bf1c79fe"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines there is significant potential for a major disaster or public health emergency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddccac60b0d604e3d90f86a31b43c119c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts available in the Fund shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id70d724993e3c4f85b397f61282096cdd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use amounts in the Fund to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id599ed579601c41619f67c45da1ffd4ec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate coordination between and among—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde6e99d653a74a1a871fbdac2d9d966e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal, State (including territorial), Tribal, and local entities; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb75ac87211704290aa62bdb51c5f5c1f"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public and private human services entities that the Secretary determines—</text>
                            <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id472de3354770404b980e1536aed45a21">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be affected by a major disaster, public health emergency, or potential major disaster or public health emergency; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2ad7bf76fea46c5af2e267ce3871136">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve at-risk individuals;</text>
                            </subclause>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idec15a70ce57e4d47bd625995284de5b2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make grants or awards to, or enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, eligible entities for projects that provide human services to at-risk individuals impacted by a major disaster or public health emergency, or prevent impacts from a potential major disaster or public health emergency, including through peer-to-peer support and person-centered case management services to address the needs of disaster survivors from preparedness and response through recovery, in accordance with subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idf61c9801a5ac4fe9b4d111736a4a23b4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carry out activities of the Department that support the provision of the services described in subparagraph (B) to at-risk individuals, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bdad56e6d994f2f85975537d27247dc"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs of necessary staff salaries and expenses and other administrative expenses, including information technology; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf62c7d173ee24685b84700862ef17a43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preparation costs that are not readily attributable to a single major disaster or public health emergency; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idd7771d5d12114aa1ace3938f4d842826"><enum>(D)</enum><text>carry out other activities, as the Secretary determines applicable and appropriate, to address the needs of at-risk individuals during public health emergencies, major disasters, and potential public health emergencies and major disasters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf163031811fb41aaadf4a86d6a24865c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc503ebd6e824705a17ffd23e0bee61b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants, awards, contracts, and cooperative agreements</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id3baf4a0b8640451e822c305730e2fee0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants or awards to, or entering into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities using amounts in the Fund, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that, directly or through a contractual arrangement, will—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id01aa9c26a92a418f8995842e5158189d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide accessible human services to at-risk individuals and communities to prepare for and mitigate the impacts of a potential major disaster or public health emergency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id4f6cf416f9bc43808a48a34b7e2840f9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide accessible human services to at-risk individuals impacted by a major disaster or public health emergency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idc33db88ac7e84225a0214413dc3a7046"><enum>(C)</enum><text>restore human services agency functions that were diminished or lost due to a disaster or public health emergency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda73964e742c4c2aa4a9cdbef7018b38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expedited delivery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall plan and take such steps as are necessary to enable the Secretary to expedite the delivery of funds under this section to appropriate agencies and entities that support at-risk individuals due to a major disaster, public health emergency, or a potential major disaster or public health emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbdc46f5885de470a9c9543497b06ff60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant or award, or entering into a contract or cooperative agreement, under this subsection shall carry out 1 or more of the following activities:</text><subparagraph id="id38eca0fc4e3b41b1820cb8318d02586f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Case management assistance for at-risk individuals, including—</text><clause id="id5e91a7c214c841d38b5caf2d5456fd26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing disaster-related application assistance, including—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe8abcee666a40d28177f49081dc6941"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligibility pre-screening;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6accec2509b649bca583eb45618e81ac"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance completing an application for disaster-related assistance;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8f4bfac38a94799baec9cd8adf0ffe4"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">translation services for such application; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id339bcaa51f42473799760cefc522cc7f"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that applications for disaster-related assistance are accessible;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idc61dc26badc34860a49c5fd0f4fdc35e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing person-centered case management services to address the needs of disaster survivors from response through recovery; or</text></clause><clause id="idf8ff109f51674ec9b6c6f4da038144fc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing other case management services and activities approved by the Secretary that address the human and social service needs of the impacted population.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51b5ab28886c4512baf270cae407dd28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Targeted efforts to support community living options for at-risk individuals before, during, and after a disaster or emergency, including—</text><clause id="id4e2e67a03e334202b68517774ff8da8f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing services and engaging in activities to prevent individuals from entering or relocating to institutional settings;</text></clause><clause id="id89796cede5a944cfa932070b4cc600f0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying individuals who have been relocated to acute care and institutional settings because of a major disaster or public health emergency;</text></clause><clause id="idfd7ab6a5a73d461e9aea368bc6c383f7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing services for individuals who were relocated to acute care and institutional settings because of a disaster or public health emergency and engaging in activities to return such individuals to a home or a community-based setting;</text></clause><clause id="idac9d883c5c7b40458a05cee2820e729a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinating among emergency management services and human services providers to ensure the accessibility of emergency responses, including the establishment of accessible emergency shelters;</text></clause><clause id="id9468398c41a041a2942663f6610e2c01"><enum>(v)</enum><text>providing legal assistance to support at-risk individuals in their recovery from a major disaster or public health emergency;</text></clause><clause id="ide45683c007e34a6ba00ae33aa9ef0404"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>engaging in activities that improve accessibility of disaster recovery and response efforts for at-risk individuals, including by providing accessible information and communications;</text></clause><clause id="idff43d41cc67a4a008d7d28cfc30a136f"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>replacing, repairing, or acquiring equipment, materials, or supplies to support community living, including such items that were lost or damaged due to a disaster or emergency; or</text></clause><clause id="id1bde87a7744b4ea3a472c8f5845bb3ef"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>providing other disaster relief or public health emergency services approved by the Secretary that address the human and social service needs of the population impacted by the major disaster or public health emergency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf03abd643dfa40f58194c2a127d8c4c6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Accessible home and community-based services and supports for at-risk individuals in connection with a major disaster, public health emergency, or potential major disaster or emergency, including—</text><clause id="ide8a5523208484328bad19d96d94ba24b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing accessible transportation services to support at-risk individuals before, during, and after a major disaster or public health emergency in obtaining necessary supports and services;</text></clause><clause id="id79a445c4390a4cf4b104932e7408f6ab"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing accessible and tailored nutritional services during a major disaster, public health emergency, or potential major disaster or public health emergency;</text></clause><clause id="idd1a6ac9508514cafba45d63c98f36184"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing accessible housing before, during, and after a major disaster or public health emergency;</text></clause><clause id="id68bb619b31ca40a9b597440977d9cd49"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>providing trauma-informed counseling and support before, during, and after a major disaster or public health emergency;</text></clause><clause id="id06fa302cc7754c8bbe6d2862f2699049"><enum>(v)</enum><text>providing personal care before, during, and after a major disaster or public health emergency;</text></clause><clause id="idc3aff8ed6c924d9083f5b7cf72c42d2c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>supporting at-risk individuals in accessing durable medical equipment or other equipment; or</text></clause><clause id="idb4dc9b02265a4bf99e6a071425425654"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other major disaster relief and public health emergency services approved by the Secretary that address the human service and social service needs of the impacted population of at-risk individuals.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2200709f2f864288a060d1ea8f18b8a8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><subparagraph id="ide9c28dbe16a74dc4981da4e710e33a6e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant, award, contract, or cooperative agreement under this subsection shall participate in data collection and reporting, as required by this subsection and other law and in the manner required by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id592cd1aed27b46959d331452d489002e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>External evaluation</header><clause id="id715ff923127b4ad8abd95c61b8bfd590"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Reservation of funds</header> <text>Each eligible entity shall reserve not less than 5 percent and not more than 10 percent of the total award amount for an independent, third‑party evaluation of the activities carried out with funds made available under this subsection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id204efbd754ae4941bffdae459ac12dc3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Evaluator qualifications</header><text>An evaluation described in clause (i) shall be conducted by an individual or organization that—</text><subclause id="id96b25656176c437399b39a0263b1cfc0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is independent of the recipient entity; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6f2fb6fd9cd5489da545dc4f15fb3bc6"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>possesses demonstrated expertise in program evaluation, cost‑benefit analysis, and community‑based human services delivery.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id6721fa31ab3b4b06a2a6852069f2851f"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Evaluation scope</header><text>The evaluation shall, at a minimum—</text><subclause id="id8236bce47b5c4df0a05c14be6592d08f"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>measure the program outputs and outcomes of the activities supported under the grant, award, contract, or cooperative agreement, including the ability of varying groups of at‑risk individuals to access services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id3ccad2b5764b48579a39118996054a6d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>quantify the cost savings or cost avoidance attributable to such activities; and</text></subclause><subclause id="iddbf2aebf18f3438bb375e493b44654f1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>assess the community impact of the activities and the sustainability of the activities when the grant, award, contract, or cooperative agreement ends.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ida5c90c9ac37144849743f2aa719d85c4"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Reporting to the Secretary</header><text>The recipient shall submit the final evaluation report to the Secretary not later than 90 days after the end of the project period.</text></clause><clause id="idb4016dcd10744bc79c815cbd6debf6b5"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make evaluation reports received under clause (iv) publicly available in an accessible format within 60 days of receipt.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id68186962444e4b2f8daac5110fa35c62"><enum>8.</enum><header>Disaster preparedness grants</header><subsection id="id589d6d52ed08498e95b04cf60e2ec991"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the disaster preparedness grants and related technical assistance supported under this section are—</text><paragraph id="ide47f21382d0d4d9197b8713371695d8c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish authority to award capacity-building grants for accessible disaster preparedness and response efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfccb597a603a4223a991e03a559210d3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to foster multi-sectoral approaches and partnerships across human services networks to ensure coordinated and accessible disaster preparedness and response efforts for the public, including among at-risk individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id287190b0ea454499a3574b5f0d17a961"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of eligible entity</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><paragraph id="ide9fa238ec1b64038b23b2770211082d0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State or local government agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59380ea1776f4f07aa470cd7da3870ae"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e0dff1babbf4e0291bd112f5323a474"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization, including a public or nonprofit provider of services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idea17589596fc4a008e374077abb06e2c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disaster preparedness grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts made available under this section, the Secretary may award grants or contracts to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, eligible entities in order to provide for—</text><paragraph id="id5746a756f5874f6e8b1827c4dfa00bcc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>activities that prepare for disasters or public health emergencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb96d724f892e4cd6ae1a85f82164e018"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the development of partnerships among human service public and nonprofit organizations and public health and emergency management agencies at the State (including territorial), Tribal, and local levels;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65f27c7d921f4c0ca1cf76c207199515"><enum>(3)</enum><text>activities that improve the ability of human service agencies and organizations to mitigate and respond to disasters and public health emergencies and support the accessible human service needs of at-risk individuals impacted by disasters and public health emergencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide919175a344041f18adf52c8fc0aee96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>dedicated staff or staffing salaries and expenses for State (including territorial), Tribal, or local organizations that have demonstrated expertise in the disaster and public health emergency needs of at-risk individuals, to enable such organizations to work with, and be part of, State and local emergency management efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0961498889f247d9ae016c5c4c7a2b18"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application submissions</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f023ae7c5534a97ae379045ca72674d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Award basis</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out subsection (c) in a manner that distributes funds to appropriate agencies and entities that support at-risk individuals and can support disaster preparedness capacity-building initiatives.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36d0b69fae8144b2b9598641ed393d62"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve not more than 3 percent of the funds made available under this section for such year for the administration of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcf1b80a3402f4ef98ffce56003954cd9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $300,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><section id="id494e7161af2a4814a3c8ff1e663f9817"><enum>9.</enum><header>Projects of national significance</header><subsection id="id4ad72c187f064b54b33fc6beab491b99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id24be9e5ec0b942f2869769c40559600a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity or partnership of entities that—</text><subparagraph id="idf01b4e347fce43bfa1205d3838a13f73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submits an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb62f921655374299a0e69f7ed181b3f8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is or includes an institution (which may be an institution of higher education), or a nongovernmental organization, that focuses on—</text><clause id="idb88d6cfd2a034b8ebf67b2de43a6d926"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serving the needs of individuals with disabilities; or</text></clause><clause id="id40ad506f79e34c37b0b8bdd11fa5a7a9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serving the needs of older adults;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb30fedec41243c1a0d5111f76ac89ce"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of an entity or partnership with a disability focus, has a cross-disability service focus;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a6b21b0b2204383990ba1b489c0e2bf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has experience in conducting training, technical assistance, and research pertaining to consumer-directed community support services for covered individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97d7ee43a87b44a7b49444678c8966d1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>includes covered individuals in positions of leadership in the planning, management, and operation of the programs of training, technical assistance, and research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccc9ef747534454cb182006803551917"><enum>(F)</enum><text>has knowledge and experience pertaining to the implementation and enhancement of systemic and effective engagement policies, programs, and activities that promote the inclusion, needs, and civil right of covered individuals in preparation for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9040e7b251c24efe82b88a56fe19f748"><enum>(G)</enum><text>has, or will establish, an advisory council or similar entity, of which at least 51 percent of the members are covered individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id11baa8c8d345417b829f36b1b6ac9df8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id096dc94019f34dc9b787a59e4cfb2f27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements</header><paragraph id="id0036ccb6505f470c9d81c29a5453b84d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities on a competitive basis to carry out projects of national significance that—</text><subparagraph id="id98cf703eb1214c53af4323873eb71187"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create opportunities for individuals with disabilities and older adults to directly contribute to improving preparation for, recovery from, response to, and mitigation of disasters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3a6bf82813d4f2281dda6585b8cb2ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support the development of State, local, Tribal, and territorial policies that reinforce and promote the inclusion of individuals with disabilities and older adults in Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial community preparation for disasters; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20bdbcdff7a24f4f91cb400bd4694c94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support research that—</text><clause id="idfdbc45299ac345a0bd9f115ee88c6cee"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tracks, in the short-term and long-term, the effects of disasters on individuals with disabilities and older adults;</text></clause><clause id="idd9114930b3ce4cf19c3b4e1852d82990"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifies evidence-based practices that enhance inclusion of individuals with disabilities and older adults to participate in and lead preparation for disasters at Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial levels;</text></clause><clause id="id3f5a3190159c42729b776d97de336eeb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>leads to the creation of strategies and procedures to implement community level practices that decrease deaths, injuries, and harm resulting from disasters to individuals with disabilities and older adults;</text></clause><clause id="id186a13d5dbaf49809e16c9cd4c885df5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>contributes to the protection of the civil right of covered individuals with disabilities and older adults to be free from discrimination on the basis of disability or age in programs and activities, and self-determination of those individuals and adults, while also promoting their safety and well-being during and following disasters;</text></clause><clause id="id2e370d7fff594fcfafe8ddac489a949f"><enum>(v)</enum><text>contributes to the development of Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial policies that enhance collaboration among governmental entities, centers for independent living, VOADs, and other nongovernmental organizations, including organizations that represent and are comprised of covered individuals, to improve the inclusion of covered individuals in preparation for, response to, recovery from, and mitigation of disasters; and</text></clause><clause id="idd52f0f44951447a08c0b9f2b30a97bf5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>contributes to other efforts, as determined by the Secretary, to advance the purposes of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0abc6b21fe34d51a12628d0f3e68671"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount, quantity, and duration</header><text>In awarding grants or entering into contracts or cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="id7089e8c1972e46fa8839642da9d4a3ff"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, ensure that each such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement is for an amount that is not less than $2,500,000 and not more than $10,000,000;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida30f7012107f4ee7ae2ff9c4c7307f67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award or enter into not less than 4 grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c54a3ed69464197a6e9aa019d63f0e0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that each such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement is for a period of not less than 3 years and not more than 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="ide6b94bef340f47649d310ff94528a9f7"><enum>10.</enum><header>Crisis standards of care and civil rights laws</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7998d2d22d8f480eb35757ce744620d7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Standards of care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and local governmental entities shall develop crisis standards of care for implementation during the period of a disaster or public health emergency pursuant to the nondiscrimination requirements under—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0389d54799746ac8cfd85f96c301d08"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d548ac14ae1403f8dc63dbe22240254"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaea429e5dedb47499dc6827a008c0f5c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and implementing crisis standards of care in accordance with subsection (a), States and local governmental entities shall comply with:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93594db36dac4059a1bc89d33bb8acf0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The crisis standards of care described in the guidance issued by the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services entitled <quote>Bulletin: Civil Rights, HIPAA, and the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID–19)</quote> and dated March 28, 2020, and any best practices developed by the Office of Civil Rights pursuant to such guidance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5d00873545645279fc8a6b93b31007b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following requirements:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf637a42720a45728624caf02ab9fa28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and local governmental entities may not develop or implement potentially discriminatory policies that negatively affect covered individuals or children. Such policies may address the application of crisis standards of care in resource-constrained settings during disasters and public health emergencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde9f2f6b009a4d25833c7b002dac6736"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During disasters and public health emergencies, civil rights may not be suspended or waived.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3795a8a91b06408cb3d1f38a34685055"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Crisis standards of care shall reflect that every human being has fundamental and inherent dignity, equity, and worth, and has a right to be treated equally and fairly in the provision of health care services under Federal civil rights laws.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a3c6f3d6ab947eb9a3102e7493ebcee"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Crisis standards of care shall be sufficiently clear to allow practitioners to apply such standards of care, especially when stewarding of scare resources means withholding or withdrawing critical care services. Such standards of care shall reflect the values, wishes, and interest of all patients, especially covered individuals and children.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40325a7d86b746ba969d745e339c5860"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and local governmental entities shall partner with, and work to ensure strong public engagement of, community and provider stakeholders, with particular attention to the needs of covered individuals and children.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fb115cce95143c78b1a3ebc02e8a445"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and local governmental entities shall use ethically and clinically sound planning to secure equitable allocation of resources and fair protections for covered individuals and children.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c4c59570ae64c7a89f66d440388b1ab"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and local governmental entities shall develop specific response measures to meet the needs of covered individuals and children.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9aa73e988594a0fb2815bae320b234c"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and local governmental entities shall seek to eliminate the use of class, race, ethnicity, neighborhood, disability, and age in decisions relating to access of care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id36d1c9970d784791b4de810c5bad257b"><enum>11.</enum><header>National Advisory Committee on Individuals with Disabilities and Disasters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2811C of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300hh-10d">42 U.S.C. 300hh–10d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id49BD2E44CC794D11A73F8C72668F3AC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="id263a7cf801384b1e8bdc47fb1304291c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>17 members</quote> and inserting <quote>45 members</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ab17810767448568f22bc391c4b285f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5b0bd12c9424193a6c69d0090bcc53c"><subparagraph id="idff27f2871b08470db4a1967b72cc870a"><enum>(N)</enum><text>11 members, representing the disability community and reflecting the diverse characteristics of its members, who shall—</text><clause id="id4f3b74fa932e45cc9ed14ba674998829"><enum>(i)</enum><text>represent individuals with disabilities with a wide variety of disaster experiences, including cross-disability representation;</text></clause><clause id="idd7fa174486e54b2bae267f91c4296b4a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be geographically diverse;</text></clause><clause id="id596910d38f47414780e727f042089e5f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be ethnically and racially diverse;</text></clause><clause id="id4b189bdc71864a368a413797dd1e1dce"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>be of diverse ages, and include older adults;</text></clause><clause id="id52b0bc4f7804425896a2399ea88a9f34"><enum>(v)</enum><text>represent both genders, and include members that represent a variety of sexual orientations and gender identities;</text></clause><clause id="id0ce136e5d1854491aec154e69a8e65a3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>include veterans; and</text></clause><clause id="id110f2f2f795b405a9e3e52c4bdd22a07"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>be linguistically diverse.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe15158b0947425e9bfd4559c84c29f8"><enum>(O)</enum><text>1 representative from each of—</text><clause id="iddcd7aae28b024202ab5eca23977104a1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a coastal State emergency management agency with an employee in a position with established duties relating to integration of individuals with disabilities or to addressing access and functional needs;</text></clause><clause id="id16d6c25e757f495e82c5d52254f5472b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a noncoastal State emergency management agency with an employee in a position described in clause (i);</text></clause><clause id="idc41ad283025e4179a0795f26d440b9f0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Tribal emergency management agency with an employee in a position described in clause (i);</text></clause><clause id="ide48d42b9351348f2b06f6192f4a15c68"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a territorial emergency management agency with an employee in a position described in clause (i);</text></clause><clause id="idf52e101b17674069ba2007f3c5ff825a"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a nongovernmental organization providing disaster preparedness and response services;</text></clause><clause id="idc45a8c36943541dbb87b7dd5132350c8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a local urban disaster management entity, which representative has disability inclusive emergency management experience;</text></clause><clause id="idd1c76ab7bd26446785d3e1cbc6d29231"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a local rural disaster management entity, which representative has disability inclusive emergency management experience;</text></clause><clause id="id5029778d9a2247fd99f4ae8087965d97"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a local disability organization with a cross-disability focus;</text></clause><clause id="id235ddfaf96604cab886c660ada6fa078"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a State disability organization with a cross-disability focus;</text></clause><clause id="id23c54da7de3044fca5a859c50d6c1a10"><enum>(x)</enum><text>a national disability organization with a cross-disability focus;</text></clause><clause id="id69aed571d9c44691b66aa2204ec27e3f"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>a national older adults organization;</text></clause><clause id="ida6c336cb603f41b4a43df6f38af100fa"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency;</text></clause><clause id="id97e075eb487f409e978b47f62b749019"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>a low-income housing organization, who has expertise in the civil rights of disaster-affected covered individuals; and </text></clause><clause id="id6296911d54d340d1879c1cfe22363732"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>a representative of a legal services agency with expertise in the civil rights of disaster-affected covered individuals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id88bb8cc3775a4ba8bc4f668e4c953e40"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The Secretary of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id907920b3aae0496bbc6517e44c177565"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The Director of Disability Policy for the Domestic Policy Council.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11A46A04B45246BDB890F3C89D55FDF8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76B6ADA283FA457498596F1311F9DA72"><paragraph id="id79D3F0C9DCC846D096DBDE9B0CBDF9FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>access and functional needs</term>, <term>civil rights</term>, <term>covered individual</term>, <term>disability inclusive emergency management experience</term>, <term>disaster</term>, <term>individuals with disabilities</term>, <term>older adult</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 4 of the <short-title>REAADI for Disasters Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF0E4D7BC644D45A1B300FA700B555F0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAFE5DC607B49477AB551BE11C612A3AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F89334228034294980DCF117C8E1388"><subsection commented="no" id="id7b11fdcc45a44451a70b16fae2801cd6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id11FDA5699C444272993046613D64B68E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idAE7999BC1A594BAF988525B285D5252B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>on September 30, 2025</quote> and inserting <quote>4 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>REAADI for Disasters Act</short-title></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7794E5745CB74FD9B6BA778A92D3E1C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>October 1, 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>REAADI for Disasters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id7658f4568391479c9c47165b9d9aeeab"><enum>12.</enum><header>Review of settlement agreements related to disasters and individuals with disabilities and older adults</header><subsection id="id9730857aa5ac4308ac5650b882d56d13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id183f543243f4496c90d3d98063f661c9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chief of the disability rights section</header><text>The term <term>Chief of the Disability Rights Section</term> means the Chief of the Disability Rights Section of the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id880d079316d44a9dbd6e7b3cc30560ec"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committee</header><text>The term <term>Committee</term> means the Disability and Disaster Preparedness Advisory Committee established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f083f1280b54413931984639e058b78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered committee of congress</header><text>The term <term>covered committee of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id7b1d9e70fde145738530b653dce3f17a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70bd2c8329d14ea4bbbb5c546a517df7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Education and Workforce, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b2fb9d09e5b47cda2129cf29f67fbc4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered settlement agreement</header><text>The term <term>covered settlement agreement</term> means a settlement agreement—</text><subparagraph id="iddbde4802b93a482e85a383e5b6cc4235"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entered into by the United States during the period beginning on January 1, 2005, and ending on the first December 31 after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfea03d59bcd44709b9d2b781b81f3540"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that relates to a potential violation of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) in connection with the preparation for, response to, recovery from, or mitigation of a disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb3fe38da07fe423192ee06b36af7c4f7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of committee</header><text>There is established an advisory committee, to be known as the <quote>Disability and Disaster Preparedness Advisory Committee</quote>, to review covered settlement agreements.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida671e0c7a1914bb18865276b874cd9c3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="id9d8296d1fe674c1aaed6d8cc83ba86a8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall appoint the members of the Committee, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id07d0081b91e64d5fa13b630a43eb1a6e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employees of the Department of Justice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17f569dc23034df28b2421dfee48d3a9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 3 disability rights advocates who—</text><clause id="id96b4c9231cb4439e9bcdf42d7585ff73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are not employees of the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="id19ce5d15927c44a3b92986692be12dce"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are individuals with disabilities; and</text></clause><clause id="ided94c990b3054f6199248340d78c6b1d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have disability inclusive emergency management experience.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id60fdf35515804192a7e01c08ee10f3b3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of appointment; vacancies</header><subparagraph id="idc3a34f7a78f8424cb1d666cdf4e632a2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Committee shall be appointed for the life of the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3230a0ec43a4451d885986e91d971218"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Committee—</text><clause id="id22f8b0420ca6497cafb43829cf71411a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Committee; and</text></clause><clause id="id5f4c7af139c543acaa965405d298e439"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd04fc893eee24309a744e2d250e8947b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson and vice chairperson</header><text>The members of the Committee shall elect a Chairperson and a Vice Chairperson from among the members, not less than 1 of whom shall be a member appointed under paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83cbac90ce3741848da1f9df238a8196"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="idfdc7db2cf71a493aa63718664ef859af"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chairperson.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id690652a206fe4166aa554ac6dee32394"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Committee shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6e12d09ad6a0422f920dca76f7af080c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall—</text><paragraph id="idbcf078e0a434475ca1f21d9039717392"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of each covered settlement agreement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7e080a8baef48388485c3f2a3a05145"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review annual reports and recommendations provided to each covered committee of Congress relating to addressing the needs of covered individuals in the preparation for, response to, recovery from, or mitigation of a disaster;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba5f97b76c43451ca4c403a4f9bb3eb2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report containing the findings and recommendations of the Committee to—</text><subparagraph id="id26a29e7c7aef479a96178497404cb15e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each covered committee of Congress;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6239473bd6bb41508d179330d8ce03d5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other entity of Congress with jurisdiction over matters relating to addressing the needs of covered individuals in the preparation for, response to, recovery from, or mitigation of a disaster;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d5017dc59ed4edf9f0955d26cd83c54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Attorney General;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58ef93cd241049638602ebf6827ac0cc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2196d8985ece4e5b8d5ef163e5338b0d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a2d674d623542b581db00744b437a33"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31da32f8ec4948c8b4c324347950e04e"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Secretary of Transportation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb622236967de45b3b79fab9e86f3f9a4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the President, through the Director of Disability Policy for the Domestic Policy Council; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d7e5a9b1006420083df2c7db1bd42c6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide the comments and recommendations described in section 13(b)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id68c694572d5d4159a9edc8ba814d3afd"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Powers of committee</header><paragraph id="ida27dd03170084116b0a8f5fcac4fb36a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Committee may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Committee considers advisable to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42395b8f55ad428ab3752a8081546fbe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header><subparagraph id="id9fd54f003e2f47e9b986d1100502e501"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Committee considers necessary to carry out this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd713bb18a3d045d6b0c74f85e4d0a49d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Furnishing information</header><text>On request of the Chairperson of the Committee, the head of the department or agency shall furnish the information to the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id915ee91c4b4b417195b78eb8b95045b7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disability rights section</header><text>The Chief of the Disability Rights Section shall submit to the Committee a report on the oversight of covered settlement agreements a sufficient period of time before the date specified in subsection (d)(3) to allow the Committee to review the report and include the report of the Chief of the Disability Rights Section in the report of the Committee under subsection (d)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id897afcbb7c5d4b5d9d9bd80463457338"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Committee may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3645205e482b465fa2b1edd21d152459"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Committee personnel matters</header><paragraph id="ida4821b0504a8426b96c87a3957af9c6b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><subparagraph id="idaea895966e874bfaaa4ce5af1c2bfbc7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Committee who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3358804805ac49d9b441285258ee120f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal members</header><text>A member of the Committee who is an officer or employee of the United States shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for service as an officer or employee of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0740636713524cd09a0e4cb4e7353b86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their home or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79ee4ad583af44ccb206ecf8a3274be5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Staff</header><subparagraph id="id7548907dfb244883bf21e2b5b8f81642"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chairperson of the Committee may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Committee to perform the duties of the Committee, except that the employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b16582c14ab4749a47b23ef95795274"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Chairperson of the Committee may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id37058b63bef54982afadeb2c900255e3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>Any Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Committee without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c5266aac9414a8f8db61464d964b92e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</header><text>The Chairperson of the Committee may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals which do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf8c5abbbd7fa4c6ca3c64ef1dd397b5c"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination of committee</header><text>The Committee shall terminate 90 days after the date on which the Committee submits the report required under subsection (d)(3).</text></subsection><subsection id="id89ab41d2c0a74d469170b8e06f064539"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports by disability rights section</header><text>On and after the date on which the Committee submits the report required under subsection (d)(3), the Chief of the Disability Rights Section shall publish an annual report on the oversight of settlement agreements relating to disaster preparation, response, recovery, and mitigation activities.</text></subsection></section><section id="idb5d75bf1c2364517a8abd98fc2da2a37"><enum>13.</enum><header>GAO report on past use of disaster funds</header><subsection id="id85f64505f80d49ea98a1e149bf715242"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall begin to conduct an investigation of whether, on or after January 1, 2005, Federal agencies have complied with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>), in expending Federal funds to prepare for, respond to, recover from, or mitigate disasters, including whether and, if so, how such funds were used to ensure accessibility to services and supports for individuals with disabilities and older adults.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcabe5c64a5a04c40a509a5d836e746bc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="idb642c887f55649b4a41afd76646ec207"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall, in accordance with paragraph (2), issue a report on the investigation conducted under subsection (a), along with recommendations for remediation of any misexpenditures identified.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87d9283a505143bebd64f270ee6541a0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><subparagraph id="id7079fafe431e461c88e211514ccf90e0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to issuing the report under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall obtain comments and recommendations on a draft version of the report, including the recommendations described in subparagraph (B), from the National Advisory Committee on Individuals with Disabilities and Disasters established under section 2811C of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300hh-10d">42 U.S.C. 300hh–10d</external-xref>) and the Disability and Disaster Preparedness Advisory Committee established under section 12(b) (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>Committees</quote>), and any other agency determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfcd14045345d4524a9ba1d73794d82f8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Committee recommendations on additional sources</header><text>The recommendations obtained under subparagraph (A) shall include recommendations from the Committees regarding additional sources the Comptroller General may interview for purposes of the investigation under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

