<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL25A64-TH2-VV-CTL">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3059 IS: Boosting Benefits and COLAs for Seniors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3059</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251027">October 27, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr.
                    Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr.
                    Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms.
                    Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on
                Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend title II of the Social Security Act to require the Commissioner of
            Social Security to use the Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers for purposes of
            determining cost-of-living adjustments under titles II, VIII, and XVI of the Social
            Security Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Boosting Benefits and COLAs for Seniors Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HB1FC8703243E4218A8B3B621C7CD77FB">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>More accurate cost-of-living adjustment</header>
            <subsection commented="no" id="H7967DBE1B35042A8A48E6261750806D7">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
                <paragraph id="HECF8A0FADF404C328AF0EAB69F6ABA10">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Section 215(i)(1)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/415">42 U.S.C. 415(i)(1)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Consumer Price Index</quote> and all that follows through <quote>such index</quote> and inserting <quote>Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers (CPI–W, as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor) or Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI–E, as published by such Bureau) (whichever such index results in the higher percentage under this subparagraph) exceeds the same such index</quote>.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H581CBE277D1449A087A493D072D50524">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Conforming amendment</header>
 <text>Section 215(i)(1)(G) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/415">42 U.S.C. 415(i)(1)(G)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>applicable for purposes of subparagraph (D)</quote> after <quote>Consumer Price Index</quote>.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97E7E41134484581B9A304766881C912">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Application to pre-1979 law</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H19441437142A4260808F1B3B9DA34428">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Section 215(i) of the Social Security Act as in effect in December 1978, and as applied in certain cases under the provisions of such Act as in effect after December 1978, is amended—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3D3F85CDB1514A419099FB7FF80C530D">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>Consumer Price Index</quote> and all that follows through <quote>such Index</quote> and inserting <quote>Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers (CPI–W, as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor) or Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI–E, as published by such Bureau of such Department) (whichever such index results in the higher per centum under this subparagraph) exceeds, by not less than 3 per centum, the same such Index</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA47531F96F11474DA735AF88676D2189">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H30B707782310466A99C0FC948BFD5533"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by striking <quote>Consumer Price Index for such cost-of-living computation quarter</quote> and inserting <quote>Consumer Price Index applicable for such year under paragraph (1)(B)</quote>; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" id="HA9A42E0E3F3F4EDC81958C01A850AC9D">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C)(i), by striking <quote>Consumer Price Index as published for any month exceeds by 2.5 percent or more the level of such index</quote> and inserting <quote>Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers or Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers as published for any month exceeds by 2.5 percent or more the level of such index</quote>.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H6AA896DDE1B8436D89300CBC2ACB3A7C">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Conforming changes</header>
 <text>Section 215(i)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/415">42 U.S.C. 415(i)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fa467185ef14c1897a4bb29ef0975c0">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and by section 9001</quote> and inserting <quote>, section 9001</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1bd67ff55ad48328fb9aa2d16aff09e">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>and section 2 of the <short-title>Boosting Benefits and COLAs for Seniors Act</short-title>,</quote> after <quote>1986,</quote>.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC55C9DC2AC54B26A762934E66199734">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>No effect on adjustments under other laws</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 215(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/415">42 U.S.C. 415(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H092928A012A14B6392B637F55DA969B8">
                    <paragraph id="HBC75BD37B3754A43B8C9AC5DB819B585" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any provision of law (other than in this title, title VIII, or title XVI) which provides for an adjustment of an amount under such provision of law in the same percentage as a cost-of-living adjustment applied to benefit amounts under this title, such provision of law shall be applied and administered as if the percentage of such cost-of-living adjustment applied to benefit amounts under this title were determined without regard to the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) of section 2 of the <short-title>Boosting Benefits and COLAs for Seniors Act</short-title>.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H5A5C4DD33CE54258A63CB00CBBF9F37A">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Publication of Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers</header>
 <text>The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor shall prepare and publish an index for each calendar month to be known as the <quote>Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers</quote> that indicates changes over time in expenditures for consumption which are typical for individuals in the United States who have attained age 62.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H22324D2389D340A1A8C2FCE9A6B75797">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Transition rule</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to the publication of the Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI–E) pursuant to subsection (d), the reference to such index made in each of the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall be deemed to be a reference to the research price index prepared by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor known as the Consumer Price Index for Americans 62 years of age and older (R–CPI–E).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H403A605FEC7D46E58BF81936943DDB01">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to determinations made with respect to cost-of-living computation quarters (as defined in section 215(i)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/415">42 U.S.C. 415(i)(1)(B)</external-xref>)) ending on or after September 30, 2026.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

