<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-GAI26067-L5F-2S-GP3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 611 ATS: Authorizing the use of the atrium in the Philip A. Hart Senate Office Building for a Bipawtisan Doggi Gras Pawrade on February 25, 2026, from 4:00p.m. to 6:00p.m.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 611</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of the atrium in the Philip A. Hart Senate Office Building for a Bipawtisan Doggi Gras Pawrade on February 25, 2026, from 4:00p.m. to 6:00p.m.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas President Harry Truman stated, <quote>If you want a friend in Washington, get a dog.</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 65,000,000 households in the United States are enriched by having a dog in the home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas dogs have a unique ability to bring people of the United States with different backgrounds and beliefs together; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate welcomes canine companions on a regular, <quote>bipawtisan</quote> basis: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="id1e22869075b9494196e0b0105f93b1c5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of the atrium in the Hart Senate Office building for a Bipawtisan Doggi Gras Pawrade</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The atrium in the Philip A. Hart Senate Office Building is authorized to be used on February 25, 2026, from 4:00p.m. to 6:00p.m., for a Bipawtisan Doggi Gras Pawrade.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

