<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE8D0194E97E644A883E43F893E2E8895" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8174 IH: To amend title 31, United States Code, to prohibit the issuance of United States currency and securities containing the signature of the sitting President.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8174</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260402">April 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to prohibit the issuance of United States currency and securities containing the signature of the sitting President.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF52129F0D674C1781B0394F9FCA27EB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAF8A901620A544769DD5C939DB642780" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibiting the President’s signature from appearing on United States currency or securities</header> 
<subsection id="H65586A51C24545D8B997CFDA548D52E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5114(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>United States currency or securities containing the signature of an individual may not be issued during any period in which such individual is serving as President.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9EC31247BE374514A0B5EF49C528D81D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Explicit statutory waiver</header><text>The prohibition contained in the amendment made by subsection (a) may only be waived by the enactment, after the date of the enactment of this section, of specific statutory authorization for such activity that explicitly waives the application of such prohibition by reference.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

