<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9F81D0AD6E874AF5842376CD7CFA6F9B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1081 IH: Raising awareness for the sarcoma cancer chordoma.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1081</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Raising awareness for the sarcoma cancer chordoma.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas chordoma is a slow growing, yet aggressive bone cancer of the skull and spine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it strikes people of all ages and affects more than 25,000 individuals worldwide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, each year, thousands of people are diagnosed with chordoma including about 300 people annually in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas chordomas are among the most complicated tumors to treat due to involvement of critical structures such as the brain stem, spinal cord, and important nerves and arteries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas surgery or radiation performed by a skilled treatment team can be curative for some patients, but even with the best care possible, the recurrence rate remains high; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas no drugs are known to cure or effectively control the disease, meaning that patients whose disease progresses after exhausting surgical and radiation options have little hope for a full recovery: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0AA3F34706CE4121AE92043E6FA9B599"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC00A8939FA60483498A737D1DACEF64F"><enum/><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that chordoma patients and families need increased funding and support for—</text><paragraph id="H552FE9B86DC141AF958391AAA7EF462A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accurate and early diagnosis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H521C78D18BDE4C198E5D479F32E5AEAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the development of new treatments, diagnostics, and cures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4588654E01D348E8A63ABCC204F74B98"><enum>(3)</enum><text>fewer hurdles between research and new treatments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H285FD76D615E47539ED2E06EABFF57FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>patient-centric approaches to drug discovery and development.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

