<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26945-07V-WS-V3K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4899 IS: Securing Partner Supply Chains Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4899</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of State to establish the Initiative on Foreign Investment Screening, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H38F34BECADF443EB815E43420AA6425F"><section section-type="section-one" id="H09B9F4766605429785276220CA5C5002"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Partner Supply Chains Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H521DA7F2142344E59E5ED455CAC6D9F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Initiative on foreign investment screening</header><subsection id="H131080CA7CFF46CFBE7C0452FB0C83D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H218E7C642F5F4BEF9818132401A79178"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Foreign investment can be beneficial to economic growth, but also presents risks to national security if critical infrastructure, sensitive technology, or supply chains are compromised.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3F03486D7794899ADBAABA77F71DCC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Many foreign countries lack robust regulatory frameworks to screen foreign investments for national security risks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43394752D9E44C5ABB66351044ADD95D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Strengthening investment screening mechanisms worldwide supports United States national security by enhancing the resilience of allies and partner countries against malign foreign influence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2113DD904D26486FB9DCCC110E47F16F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States has expertise in investment screening that can be leveraged to assist allies and partner countries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA17F77D270F64F95BCDCA53BFBC88BD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initiative on foreign investment screening</header><paragraph id="H6E019BC013F9419592A76E13B528CB8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall establish the Initiative on Foreign Investment Screening (in this section referred to as the <quote>Initiative</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H463F6ECCF122419CB9BFDC47C8369C01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the heads of other United States Government agencies, as appropriate, in the establishment and activities of the Initiative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD346EEBD074D25ABB9F5BC9FB5DFED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designated official</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall designate the Under Secretary for Economic Affairs or a designee of the Under Secretary to lead the initiative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C7E259E431540CCAB5913E64D2AA185"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Initiative shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3219EBFBB37642E1A1FC1586709F7749"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide technical assistance, training, and advisory services to foreign countries regarding best practices for screening foreign investments for national security risks to such countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H744B52B6B63243B1AEC0D51BFA5B2C48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate coordination among United States Government agencies, the private sector, partner countries, and civil society to promote security standards for foreign investment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF02EB10C5D8346F88B5981E82B61C389"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the development and implementation of foreign investment screening mechanisms in partner countries through regulatory guidance and information sharing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D70995FBC0A4A14B322FA193F798551"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess the progress of partner countries in establishing robust foreign investment screening mechanisms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAE1E69CB1F24CD698C48A85CCDAAB0E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>conduct outreach and capacity-building efforts to enhance global awareness of the national security risks of foreign investment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf50b95ddab5b4e2d86c6add104dd382b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Initiative shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Initiative is established under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF99429E484E49B09DBCF46C7260052B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the activities of the Initiative, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2D23F79D30BD4A6A874FB6772A02CD16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of technical assistance and training provided to foreign countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H273BC4118D714CAE92B3E72FB475DDED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of progress made by foreign countries in implementing foreign investment screening mechanisms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC70C549F16CD4ED184DB816D4E232DE8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of emerging national security risks related to foreign investment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4250B36C16BF45768C387F1DDC12054A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for further United States engagement with foreign countries regarding screening foreign investments for national security risks to such countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E836D87867E4A0EB20840A05DEB2CC9" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each country determined by the Secretary to be a partner country pursuant to subsection (c)(4)(C) during the year preceding submission of the report, a detailed description of the reasons for such determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EC5E0445355481BB46ACBD6708FFB8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H92AF0E07C0AC42BCA6D013E65C7AB3F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBC1055219455423B9A60A142389A4AC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99C0B7AB80C044C5B484BAAE4559ADAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5900AC367E5A4F069CE7C0712123A269"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign investment</header><text>The term <term>foreign investment</term> means direct or indirect investment in the economy of a country by—</text><subparagraph id="H61FB56641E49426896A2117D6AE2B502"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is not a citizen or national of such country; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E2D0A41CA9440BBA68D89C7C8288CC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity that is not organized under the laws of such country or any jurisdiction within such country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE6316D920754681A42443869AA24566"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National security risk</header><text>The term <term>national security risk</term> means a risk related to critical infrastructure, sensitive technology, supply chain vulnerabilities, or malign foreign influence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD41498C5D53845538B758A5F0E7C2F03"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partner country</header><text>The term <term>partner country</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H0FBAC9ED9E794E81A56869D8520D161E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A country with which the United States has in effect a bilateral or multilateral free trade agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC480B7A0FA3403ABE3FA7C301E78580"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A country with which the United States has in effect a treaty for mutual defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7B261BD608A44278EE8238613BD3C0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any other country or jurisdiction, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

