<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDD519D23F01A42CE994049ED4E73D72E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6572 IH: Launching X–Labs for Breakthrough Science Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6572</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the National Institutes of Health to carry
            out a program, to be known as the <quote>X-Labs Initiative</quote>, to support
            breakthrough biomedical research at innovative research institutions, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBFA8811C92E84933B0B77BCCF275FE2F" style="OLC"><section id="H7831061EBB2140F6B8BDFEF35AB98737" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Launching X–Labs for Breakthrough Science Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H277582FA43C1482B91512DCD00762F97"><enum>2.</enum><header>NIH institutional awards for breakthrough biomedical research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/281">42 U.S.C. 281 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H78348308C96E478398B46067C20ED43A"><section id="H6A526393F269449CA462269895BFE61B"><enum>404P.</enum><header>NIH institutional awards for breakthrough biomedical research</header><subsection id="H1B79C61C0BEC492B947880634937EA18"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>X–Labs Initiative</quote>, to provide long-term institutional awards to eligible entities in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D38443B2F2F4DE096DBC57F8144916E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of the program shall be—</text><paragraph id="HE16B300C22EA4FEB86C5C3846033CC67"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enable and catalyze innovative research institutions to conduct breakthrough biomedical research; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3006F51A0E934BC9B417315D9F95F1B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist such institutions in the acquisition of R&amp;D plant, as necessary, to complete such research.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H117911ED58564340BA169AEBCECDCBA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Institutional awards</header><paragraph id="H0940BBB10E4A42EAAABE93AAF3601B21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Director of NIH shall, acting directly or through the head of an NIH institute or center, make institutional awards to eligible entities on a competitive basis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3324DCC9E6C435F9B126E41487493D4"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>XL‑series activity code</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall designate the <quote>XL‑series</quote> as a distinct NIH activity code available to all NIH institutes and centers making institutional awards under the program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C6661A8E58040A79C9942E4DEAB5FE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Categories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institutional award under the program shall be made within one of the following categories:</text><subparagraph id="H951125CB19A34262A586B0A8C46EF197"><enum>(A)</enum><header>XL01 funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Awards of XL01 funding to support basic science research institutions whose principal activities, or proposed principal activities, are directed toward advancing foundational scientific discovery. The purpose of such awards shall be to provide such institutions stable, long-term funding and minimal budgetary reprogramming requirements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61E96ECAE01E45C78FD13FEF72714F5C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>XL02 funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Awards of XL02 funding to support science institutions whose principal activities, or proposed principal activities, are directed toward developing new scientific resources, including datasets or measurement tools or techniques, with deliverables that are clearly defined at the beginning of the award.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC1C1F0273504BE0B15702F57F95CABC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>XL03 funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Awards of XL03 funding to support nonprofit institutions that award focused research organizations, individual researchers, or research collaborations or centers funds to conduct breakthrough biomedical research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H642DFCB0EAAE49AF99F4749F63FAD36A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>XL04 funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Awards of XL04 funding to support the formation and planning of new scientific institutions that will be eligible for XL01, XL02, or XL03 funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H167EF91201764BBE8A154DB3398BB1D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rules applicable to XL03 funding</header><subparagraph id="H9CF89628CA884740879760C789874681"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regrants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives an award of XL03 funding described in paragraph (3)(C) shall, subject to the terms of the award, make regrants using funds from the award to support research teams, early-stage projects, or innovative scientific initiatives consistent with the purposes of this section. Such teams, projects, and initiatives shall be located in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB18D80E088F94BF5BD30788D25725682"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An eligible entity that receives an award of XL03 funding described in paragraph (3)(C)—</text><clause id="H5594C2E43DF544D6A21662FD94B20B2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall use such funding to provide assistance, through regrants described in subparagraph (A), to organizations (in this section referred to as <quote>regrant recipients</quote>) that the eligible entity determines are unlikely to receive support through traditional NIH grants despite the breakthrough potential of the research to be conducted by the regrant recipient;</text></clause><clause id="H798C7F1662B74350B3956038653C1676"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall use innovative methods to identify, fund, and evaluate the research to be conducted using such assistance; and</text></clause><clause id="H33E8B29290204711A29435478FB150CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than one year after the date on which the eligible entity provides such assistance to a regrant recipient, shall make available to the public a summary of the method by which the eligible entity identified, funded, and plans to evaluate the regrant recipient.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H154600855BF44717B571D4CED2915107"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Amounts</header><subparagraph id="HCFC3117697E44BF18DC025883AB64144"><enum>(A)</enum><header>XL01, XL02, and XL03 funding</header><clause id="H72A9ADD0CC964EEAB3B37C122A487C70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall structure an award of XL01, XL02, or XL03 funding such that the award totals not less than $5,000,000 and not more than $50,000,000 per fiscal year for a period of 7 consecutive fiscal years. The amount of such an award shall be determined based on institutional scope, scientific ambition, and programmatic needs.</text></clause><clause id="H74462D32EF0642C8AB8B98F4F6C09149"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Renewals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH may renew an award described in clause (i) for not more than one additional period of 7 consecutive fiscal years, subject to—</text><subclause id="H70A4F4F92DFA405C84880A13C80F258C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a competitive review of institutional performance and scientific impact over the previous period;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9F207A5F74CC42559ADAB0A82EB9BEFF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the availability of appropriations; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB982FE43C33C47C89984AD0305045CAD"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a programmatic cap on the proportion of institutional awards eligible for renewal, to be determined by the Director of NIH, to ensure regular entry of new institutions into the program.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H083CB7058F374BA3AAF18F5D2761DCE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>XL04 funding</header><clause id="H41C52427DA374B19B982D1A9FF49F23C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH shall structure an award of XL04 funding such that the award totals not less than $1,000,000 and not more than $5,000,000 per fiscal year for a period of 1, 2, or 3 consecutive fiscal years, as determined by the Director of NIH.</text></clause><clause id="H1DFBF645076D47709102FD8697E1A782"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition on renewals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH may not renew an award described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H224FEE1B2E974771A87C90E7BF99ED18"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity seeking an award under the program shall submit to the Director of NIH an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Director of NIH may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63648064579443559FFB017581299AEA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Maintaining eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To remain eligible for an institutional award under the program and remain in good standing with respect to an award, an eligible entity shall not compete for or receive any other Federal research funding in the form of a research grant, excluding a training grant, during the award period of the entity for XL01, XL02, or XL03 funding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H420ACBF74ED44EBD980F6BBDB7F3145B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Early termination or suspension</header><subparagraph id="HF3AA9D383E49433790BB940B1EA59EF6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of NIH may terminate or suspend an award made to an award recipient under this section prior to the expiration of the applicable period of the award described in paragraph (5) if the Director determines that the award recipient—</text><clause id="HEDE6ABC2E2CA4E1D9A12285DF8FD9EC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not meeting the deliverables referred to in paragraph (3)(B), if applicable;</text></clause><clause id="H055CCE65AECF42819A51004F08E08ED8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is no longer an eligible entity; or</text></clause><clause id="HE766DD8BF6C34375A6A909731BBF4F9E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is otherwise failing to comply with the terms and conditions of the award.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H729007653227443BB45C7052B6F0560D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revocation of funds; reallocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon a determination to terminate or suspend an award under subparagraph (A), the Director of NIH may revoke any remaining funds from the award and reallocate such funds to new awards under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB245E51E79B490D9D92B2689A248CD0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="HCD2201C73767444196273B7E4F5FA8D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program shall be administered by the Director of NIH, in coordination with the heads of relevant institutes and centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56E37753A4444689ADFE57A1A7692D3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institute participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any institute or center within the National Institutes of Health may utilize the program to fund institutions within their areas of scientific focus, subject to coordination with the Director of NIH and the availability of funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E79281C61264F47867F58078AFE7E0A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other transactions authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of NIH may use the authorities available under section 402(n)(1) or other applicable transactions authorities to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99D658D553B7437AA5C19D5B7F3C434A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="H326A7A9B3ACD42FFA65F0E8DFA98D97F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 2 additional years, the Director of NIH shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing—</text><subparagraph id="H6AD976E4764F49848E9A27BBC5BAB3BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the progress made in establishing the program, including the development of application processes, review criteria, and award categories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EF8F67241844C22B333C165BC4CEB1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and types of applications received under the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC90010156C24488F8B2400DC69A7508E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number, type, and amount of awards made under the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5E7A02BBB254057BC69103694807DCC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any challenges or barriers encountered in the implementation of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD993BDA69DD140F78B7E4673A24572A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the first award under the program, and once every 5 years thereafter during the term of the program, the Director of NIH shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report evaluating—</text><subparagraph id="H12CEEE2089164776B756ACEC467881B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the scientific impact and outcomes of institutions receiving support under the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H054D63FB6ADB4E12B392A65B1AC9FB6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the program in advancing the purposes described in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3246776D720B4E24AF714DB0EC2EE905"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lessons learned from implementation of the program and recommendations for program improvement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD8991CA4A54426385B136A6CB60F132"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which the program has reduced administrative burden and enabled research that is high-risk and high-reward.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CBE4BE00103453FB6B8EB6C4EB00975"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD57C65EE662A4FB680062F811240C813"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H751D2EC7E0104227AD2BB70B2AA15D0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E9949A7AB9644D1A614D7089620C2BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB595A7E856014B338C9E66E0E2562229"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basic science research institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>basic science research institution</term> means a research institution conducting systematic study directed toward greater understanding of fundamental principles or phenomena of nature without specific applications in mind.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8429D8E2095F4382BCA03290D8CB1C03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Breakthrough biomedical research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>breakthrough biomedical research</term> means scientific research that has the potential to create substantial, field-defining advances in knowledge, methods, or technologies that enable significant improvements in human health or scientific capability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE3D3A7DA45845148DC9B53B2F10C546"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H864CD65C34644A2995B10D5E461C9B00"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit research organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B3ADA49D0274DABAA297331CDB33BA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB5A93F21AFD4C6FA95090462B218643"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a for-profit entity with nonprofit subsidiaries dedicated to scientific research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52DD535C54B6413D91F8471B2192ECDE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an individual with plans to establish a nonprofit research organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E612D128974ECE95D2B73F2216F557"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other research organization that the Director of NIH determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A3E7D7AA7A449699C993DD9FF061217"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Focused research organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>focused research organization</term> means a time-limited, goal-oriented nonprofit entity that concentrates resources and talent on achieving a defined scientific or technological objective not sufficiently pursued within existing academic, corporate, or government structures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7694FD583ABC4B0D9E3AF758B89DDBCF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foundational scientific discovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foundational scientific discovery</term> means research that produces broadly enabling scientific knowledge, methods, or tools that support subsequent applied or translational advances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H941F45E21E39488F91D7E9C8297FB6BB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institutional award; award</header><text>The term <term>institutional award</term> or <term>award</term> means an award of funding made under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFEC0FBE51BC4F349BF44A197E9A1A77"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Institutional scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institutional scope</term> means the size and organizational capacity of an institution to undertake research activities, including the breadth of its scientific research, number of personnel supported, and physical research infrastructure relevant to the proposed award.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D2479635E0F4412970889AC7599B55D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>NIH</header><text>The term <term>NIH</term> means the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ED09FF7FEA04758A7C3F0CCB766C146"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Nonprofit research organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonprofit research organization</term> means a domestic public or private organization exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 that conducts or supports scientific research as a primary purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1B2A6F3B8224ED5A9CF894815B66F97"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the program authorized under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61FFC507B27840C38416965CBB774CF8"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Programmatic needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>programmatic needs</term> means the degree to which an award would advance the strategic research priorities and unmet needs of NIH and its institutes and centers, as determined by the Director of NIH.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73DFD40038A040449CFE24A5EA43A1F8"><enum>(13)</enum><header>R&amp;D plant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>R&amp;D plant</term> means fixed assets used primarily for research and development, including the construction, expansion, leasing, or modernization of research facilities and the acquisition of major movable research equipment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0717932F077E4FB9AF2EBED2650EAFC0"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Regrant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>regrant</term> means the provision of a subaward or other financial assistance by an award recipient under the program to carry out research activities consistent with the purposes of the original award.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA57224850E0F4116895901ED83DBA0B0"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Scientific ambition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>scientific ambition</term> means the scale, novelty, and transformative potential of an institution’s proposed research agenda under an award, as measured by the significance of the scientific questions addressed and the potential to advance fundamental or translational understanding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F9D2F91CE82454C9A1EE1EC905C4E86"><enum>(16)</enum><header>United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States</term> means the States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0666B95B83AE4CCA9E94B47357EC5D57"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

