<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26479-RJY-GM-22H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4142 IS: Securing Help for Immigrants through Education and Legal Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4142</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Attorney General to provide grants to States, units of local government, and organizations to support the recruitment, training, and development of staff and infrastructure needed to support the due process rights of individuals facing removal.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8A27F75FB551423A95A0471C5D4B11D0"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6D7133625CAC4BBB8B7E31D9245FB6D9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Help for Immigrants through Education and Legal Development Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHIELD Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBADB5EC302574519970C01082301D388"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H83DA08C60D9C4BDDA7D2D9F6F35A1DBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individual facing removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>individual facing removal</term> means an individual in a proceeding under section 235(b), 238, 240, or 241(a)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)</external-xref>, 1228, 1229a, and 1231(a)(5)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D40202B29704D2DB7A09801B0F437D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service area</header><text>The term <term>service area</term> means the jurisdiction or geographical area in which an entity carries out activities using funds awarded under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C670458721248D9B548A4082D4D70AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8A977C172914C17B4A6B50B9014153B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Unit of local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unit of local government</term> has the meaning given such term in section 901(a)(3) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6A79AD4415FA4035B94FEBA3EC79D0FC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Immigration legal services staff and infrastructure development program</header><subsection id="H74B00343327441258AEB3E9C180392FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office for Access to Justice, shall award competitive workforce development and capacity building grants to eligible entities that are seeking to expand access to representation for individuals facing removal by increasing the workforce and strengthening the legal services infrastructure needed to provide such representation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H806DF6EEF42B4129BA4805BF6CF58DD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility criteria</header><text>An entity is eligible to receive a grant under this section if it is a—</text><paragraph id="HA9C1B3192728431FBE65934EABB50B22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State or unit of local government that has allocated public funds towards the provision of immigration-related legal services, including legal representation, legal assistance, community navigation, and related services, to individuals facing removal;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDEC0477FB28485B8DF8518E75F2C5A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community-based organization, nonprofit organization, or educational institution that provides or coordinates immigration-related legal services to individuals facing removal; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CE12C0E1A9D4C0599C4FC905E0F17F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community-based organization, nonprofit organization, or educational institution that recruits, trains, or mentors individuals who provide or will provide immigration-related legal services to individuals facing removal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H407630495C424E82A1BAC5292FA89B8C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Director of the Office for Access to Justice an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may reasonably require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7AF56CADE1E84EE5983D9AA853F39665"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds awarded under this section shall be used to develop a workforce scaled to meet the representation needs of all individuals facing removal, grow the immigration-related legal services infrastructure, and enhance long-term capacity to provide high-quality, holistic, and linguistically appropriate legal services, which may include—</text><paragraph id="H643FCA52B9924F5BBB7C5833B2E246F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>workforce recruitment and training programs, such as educational, fellowship, clinical, job recruitment, and job training services aimed at increasing the number of lawyers, accredited representatives, social workers, and community navigators entering the immigration legal services field;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8228EB4C92C349E9904AD37560B73EFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>technical assistance services, such as—</text><subparagraph id="H23F1FE7A5224434795AC1F989766653A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>substantive and technical skills-based trainings to improve the quality of representation provided to individuals facing removal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FC2CF9641E847549F1CB4EC07FA1776"><enum>(B)</enum><text>language training to ensure legal staff are equipped to provide linguistically appropriate services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB16B7F4262BF4B0B9F6CC0DC828D2EF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>specialized legal support to support representation in complex defense cases, including representation in Federal court and State court; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H081F2E08CF1D4CE58B5234D5E97488E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>leadership development, including management training and establishing appropriate supervisory systems;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD23DC1F3EA3A41069866B659782B9A36"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local or regional coordination services to ensure a coordinated and efficient delivery of legal services to individuals facing removal;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H880BBC9187C94B5F86EB8464B4303556"><enum>(4)</enum><text>retention improvement strategies to ensure sustainable growth of the immigration-related legal services field, including strategies to address caseload management, burnout, and organizational systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CA6A40F4A0D43629C1ABA313112397E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recruiting and retaining legal staff from underrepresented backgrounds and promoting diversity within the legal services field;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1174E6BC31E74910A3843B8A140288A5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>growing legal services infrastructure and representational capacity in locations with a significant unmet need for legal representation and with significantly less immigration-related legal services capacity in their service area than national averages; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9317E0390719467BA83119A4313A1F95"><enum>(7)</enum><text>physical, administrative, and technological infrastructure resources in coordination with a use of funds described in paragraphs (1) through (6).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13D0F7E7E94B4E13854AA3289C5671BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracts and subawards</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this section may, for purposes authorized under subsection (d), use all or a portion of that grant to contract with or make one or more subawards to one or more—</text><paragraph id="H4C5F4B308FFA4931A3A98AC4E13E3A23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>community-based organization, nonprofit organization, private organization, or educational institution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B31C6A1DBB8435E9324E4E17CFF77FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>units of local government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H095C8D3A9F6A472DB199A0852C066627"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall—</text><paragraph id="H97704732577D4C30AF88C75EBF19C275"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the Attorney General a certification that the proposed uses of grant funds by the entity—</text><subparagraph id="HD83ACBDB515F4C6AB0949FBBD8B775ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are consistent with this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6636B249321142B3AFBCDFE15708FAAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meet the criteria determined by the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Office for Access to Justice; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0963C403E3E74524A0184B66D8AD7797"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which an entity receives grant funds under this section, submit a report to the Director of the Office for Access to Justice that describes—</text><subparagraph id="H927633F4591E451A95F2A4C40F5F0AB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the types of services being provided under the grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19BF21AEEBCE45348D9188D4A79ABC49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the service area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1E43C07363E4C4EA1B1C7EBF929022C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of individuals recruited or retained through services funded under the grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H536EC164EA4247BEA2C21333B4716EFD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the impact that staffing recruitment and retention has had on organizational capacity to represent more individuals within the service area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ED89440F3D344DCA09E42C08D3D680F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the actual expenditures made in connection with the grant, including personnel and staffing structure and indirect costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68A7889FF75C429093D1112EB454626E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the outcomes of services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE57A0B027B414537A7E87976247D4E41"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of the continuing unmet representation needs of individuals facing removal in the service area and recommendations of supports and resources needed to meet them.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EE8FDE27CB74949B9195722ACCD052E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Grant term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a grant under this section shall be 4 years, which may be renewed.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD5920C2E7054745A6E68029550DDE86"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Supplement of Non-Federal Funds</header><text>Any Federal funds received under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, Federal or non-Federal funds that would otherwise be available for activities funded under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA1318EF39BB144C39EB4D37B1D8C558C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authority and duties of the administering agency</header><subsection id="H1DEC88CF295E4918BE2F4D32C9A9397C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties of the Director</header><text>The Director of the Office for Access to Justice may promulgate such rules, policies, and procedures as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out the grant program under this Act, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H3C8E148550C1432EACC4C05D640DDD6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Establishing competitive grantmaking procedures to identify grant recipients.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H635538D061A842FE807174447A93D290"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Targeting grants in a manner that best accomplishes the following objectives and priorities:</text><subparagraph id="HAA7675B95DE7439F85896C6B3B49FBD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Advancing a legal services workforce trained and equipped to implement an independent legal defense for individuals facing removal that ensures high-quality, independent legal representation, regardless of ability to pay, prior contact with the criminal legal system, or the nature or perceived strength of their legal defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E27B6DFA40341F4847D67BC63915428"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A national legal services infrastructure scaled to meet the representation needs of all individuals facing removal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EFA3F68D8C94C4C865A7E7661E74581"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Long-term growth of organizational or programmatic capacity to provide high-quality, holistic, and linguistically appropriate legal services to individuals facing removal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H025ECBF8645447D1B4E2AF7BB9B674E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing support to State and local governments that have taken leadership and developed expertise in providing public funding for the legal defense of individuals facing removal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B45F916F5B6445785B94408D06D3520"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Addressing the crisis of lack of representation in parts of the country where such publicly funded programs have not been established.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB0F23B1326647578A26F816EDC1FF82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Independent implementation</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office for Access to Justice, shall exercise the authority under this Act in an independent manner in order to advance the primary objective of increasing access to representation for individuals facing removal, and without regard to other priorities of the Federal Government related to immigration enforcement.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6D1565A7F02547F9A565095DD8EEFD33"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports and accountability</header><subsection id="HD1E59F0828EA418C87162DACCBC2B37C"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Reports and evaluations</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year, each grantee under this section during that fiscal year shall submit to the Attorney General a report on the effectiveness of activities carried out using such grant. Each report shall include an evaluation in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require. The Attorney General shall specify the dates on which such reports shall be submitted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H93B5561F11044DF68B954C15887937A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accountability</header><text>Grants awarded under this Act shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:</text><paragraph id="H4950C6779B684D239BD013358548F3E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Audit requirement</header><subparagraph id="H810F1B6B158A4659BBB1ABE34A1C48FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>unresolved audit finding</term> means a finding in the final audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice under subparagraph (C) that the audited grantee has used grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved within 1 year after the date on which 1 final audit report is issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66345DB74BB74395BD0938E267761EEC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>Beginning in the first fiscal year beginning after December 13, 2016, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of grantees under this section to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds by grantees. The Inspector General shall determine the appropriate number of grantees to be audited each year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E83538A78EC45BCB56AECA6EE284BFB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Final audit report</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall submit to the Attorney General a final report on each audit conducted under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80D58232CA0746EEB98B23400AD3286C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a grant under this section that is found to have an unresolved audit finding shall be eligible to receive prompt, individualized technical assistance to resolve the audit finding and to prevent future findings, for a period not to exceed the following 2 fiscal years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFED4475D36D74787B12E37AD5FFDCA42"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Attorney General shall give priority to applicants that did not have an unresolved audit finding during the 3 fiscal years before submitting an application for a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51F26A13F1C5464EBD553A05EA14A831"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonprofit agency requirements</header><subparagraph id="H4E3FA44679404258818DC4B86DBF4EB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph and the grant program authorized under this section, the term <term>nonprofit agency</term> means an organization that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D6B450CDED642D7A908AA87C8105AA8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may not award a grant under this section to a nonprofit agency that holds money in an offshore account for the purpose of avoiding paying the tax described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/511">section 511(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H431A79E42BE34758AA59F300C6BBDD46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Each nonprofit agency that is awarded a grant under this section and uses the procedures prescribed in regulations to create a rebuttable presumption of reasonableness for the compensation of its officers, directors, trustees, and key employees, shall disclose to the Attorney General, in the application for the grant, the process for determining such compensation, including the independent persons involved in reviewing and approving such compensation, the comparability data used, and contemporaneous substantiation of the deliberation and decision. Upon request, the Attorney General shall make the information disclosed under this subparagraph available for public inspection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H455B330FC31A4C6BB6BABDF9EC0ACAAA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conference expenditures</header><subparagraph id="HEC86A7DE5A4245FAA5B7848FE6192CEA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than $100,000 of the amounts made available to the Department of Justice to carry out this section may be used by the Attorney General, or by any individual or entity awarded a grant under this section to host, or make any expenditures relating to, a conference unless the Deputy Attorney General provides prior written authorization that the funds may be expended to host the conference or make such expenditure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E7505BEE1124B4B8DC5D160A7DC8820"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Written approval</header><text>Written approval under subparagraph (A) shall include a written estimate of all costs associated with the conference, including the cost of all food, beverages, audio-visual equipment, honoraria for speakers, and entertainment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E220BFD60274D39A7DFD6F09C4215BF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Deputy Attorney General shall submit an annual report to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives on all conference expenditures approved under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D2E39707EC41E5A94049FE1A9FA606"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Annual certification</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit an annual certification to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00" >Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that indicates whether all final audit reports issued by the Office of the Inspector General under paragraph (1) have been completed and reviewed by the appropriate Assistant Attorney General or the Director of the Office for Access to Justice.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDFCFEC692BF24A70B836BE51CD498365"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Justice to carry out this Act $100,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2027.</text></section><section id="id5d9bfa49404b4a1db4a40af036016d48"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to preclude the ability for a respondent to obtain counsel at no expense to the Government pursuant to sections 240(b)(4) and 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229a">8 U.S.C. 1229a(b)(4)</external-xref> and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

