<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26333-9KG-0K-WW9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4065 IS: Sanctions Targeting Aggressors of Neighboring Democracies with Taiwan Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4065</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260311">March 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the imposition of sanctions with respect to the People’s Republic of China if the People's Republic of China threatens the security of Taiwan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="idF192559E3A99428A937E598BE8EB04F6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2be6003238d64b3aa0582697777d8cab"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanctions Targeting Aggressors of Neighboring Democracies with Taiwan Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STAND with Taiwan Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42344cf9c69949f884e8371bbb634afd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="idF192559E3A99428A937E598BE8EB04F6">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id2ac38719a2474d7793b374356d9376cf">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc1929135336c42d482d2b1c5d960fa7f">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id5FE33B30ACB6436FB219DBC07EB04D22">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id83a6e5f0ca414cd98a5d66b4a6a2f377">TITLE I—Sanctions and other measures in response to significant threats to security of Taiwan</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc80bcb0e96f64dcd91fbf787d1ce658b">Sec. 101. Covered determinations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id116688815b1b4a1783cd817f62409ca8">Sec. 102. Imposition of sanctions with respect to officials of the Government of the People's Republic of China and members of the Chinese Communist Party.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id28de38862b0f4b8bb717c67293463f3a">Sec. 103. Imposition of sanctions with respect to financial institutions affiliated with the Government of the People's Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id59A86A535689457ABFC32C9EBAFD6CAE">Sec. 104. Imposition of sanctions with respect to entities owned by or affiliated with the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id057a59788d61465089c18e6f1f4033f4">Sec. 105. Prohibition on transfers of funds involving the People's Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id11b8011316d147dfa6af4b7a8c62afc1">Sec. 106. Prohibition on listing or trading of Chinese entities on United States securities exchanges.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idd36d804346b64972b1a109db8a9d0e5e">Sec. 107. Prohibition on investments by United States financial institutions that benefit the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id5b0081f604e34487aa82e7ad5d99d35f">Sec. 108. Measures relating to energy sector of the People's Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4c6d76ed3f9741e5ac75d47f6f21a7fa">Sec. 109. Prohibition on purchases of sovereign debt of the People’s Republic of China by United States persons.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id8dbf6b10a9a14911840de103e98cc071">Sec. 110. Prohibition on provision of services to sanctioned financial institutions by international financial messaging systems.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id96bc62bb4abd449e87319c4cd228fccc">Sec. 111. Increases in duties on goods imported from the People’s Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id227b135b1f244980bd78b2ee0a380375">Sec. 112. Increases in duties on goods imported from countries that support the People's Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idcb32717347734b6b935b0302e2d3cfe7">TITLE II—General provisions</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb4a0b3d3c9064ce1b48922a987b61a6a">Sec. 201. Sanctions described.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idd061d620791a42b2ad7bb6408ebe7dda">Sec. 202. National security waiver.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id42a0ba54967b4321b1443a9a0509f8c3">Sec. 203. Exceptions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id28362a005f0e486b938ba5c8e4428a30">Sec. 204. Implementation; penalties.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7953c4fe461f470ca407d34fb9806236">Sec. 205. Termination authority.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id2ac38719a2474d7793b374356d9376cf"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id040aae4d79254755af45b1914f382ddf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Taiwan is a free and prosperous democracy of nearly 23,000,000 people, an important contributor to peace and stability around the world, and continues to embody and promote democratic values, freedom, and human rights in Asia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80cb467e797d43c0af47e73ac1b0af63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The policy of the United States toward Taiwan is guided by the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id626274aabac04f91ae48680b48e77703"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Under section 2 of the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref>), it is the policy of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="id0d3b8c802c4544179fc46bea612d7e8c"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>to preserve and promote extensive, close, and friendly commercial, cultural, and other relations between the people of the United States and the people on Taiwan, as well as the people on the China mainland and all other peoples of the Western Pacific area</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0039294c13dd45a7865b0bef8f9f2c48"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>to declare that peace and stability in the area are in the political, security, and economic interests of the United States, and are matters of international concern</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4a907fea6384cbeb00b7a62f19e6c84"><enum>(C)</enum><text><quote>to make clear that the United States decision to establish diplomatic relations with the People’s Republic of China rests upon the expectation that the future of Taiwan will be determined by peaceful means</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e899cb7a10147e8a9c4c8d16c53b75d"><enum>(D)</enum><text><quote>to consider any effort to determine the future of Taiwan by other than peaceful means, including by boycotts or embargoes, a threat to the peace and security of the Western Pacific area and of grave concern to the United States</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id266240b920a34115bbc18b530049b6ab"><enum>(E)</enum><text><quote>to provide Taiwan with arms of a defensive character</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d14a380f0434511939ff5bf3d8d93ad"><enum>(F)</enum><text><quote>to maintain the capacity of the United States to resist any resort to force or other forms of coercion that would jeopardize the security, or the social or economic system, of the people on Taiwan</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id37832d62d16248b6b1615a0c9c030352"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For decades and increasingly since the election of President Tsai Ing-wen as President of Taiwan in 2016, the Chinese Communist Party has employed a variety of coercive military and nonmilitary tactics short of armed conflict in its efforts to exert existential pressure on Taiwan, including through diplomatic isolation, restricting tourism, cyberattacks, spreading disinformation, and controlling the ability of Taiwan to purchase COVID–19 vaccines from other countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42879e65ef7f4bf48f3025b9ec3d5a30"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to Taiwan’s Ministry of National Defense, the People's Republic of China undertook live-fire military exercises in the Taiwan Strait April 1 and 2, 2025, vowing to maintain combat readiness and prevent any attempts by Taiwan to gain independence from the People's Republic of China. The exercise reportedly involved Chinese 76 aircraft of the People's Liberation Army, 15 naval ships and four official ships of the People's Liberation Army Navy, with 37 sorties crossing the median line of the Taiwan Strait and entered Taiwan’s northern, central, southwestern, and eastern air defense identification zone.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14f0df3c6cad42c2877007b87901b5f5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to Taiwan’s Ministry of National Defense, 29 Chinese warplanes and drones crossed the median line of the Taiwan Strait on February 19 and 20, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide26d0ea913d44682b1ae03186350b070"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In March 2021, then-Commander of the United States Indo-Pacific Command, Admiral Philip Davidson, testified that the threat of a military invasion of Taiwan by the People’s Liberation Army <quote>is manifest during this decade, in fact in the next six years</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ae7139676574049a88b29b761390170"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In October 2024, the People's Republic of China employed a record 125 aircraft, as well as its Liaoning aircraft carrier and ships, in large-scale military exercises surrounding Taiwan and its outlying islands, simulating the sealing off of key ports. As part of that exercise, 111 Chinese aircraft reportedly crossed the median line, entering Taiwan’s air defense identification zone. That action followed remarks by Taiwan’s president rejecting Beijing’s claim of sovereignty over the self-governed island.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc1929135336c42d482d2b1c5d960fa7f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="idb6195a88853442ac990d2748ea1b3f76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it is in the interest of the United States to maintain a free and open Indo-Pacific region, with peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait as a critical component;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id56fe0360eb15477fa1a6f0c2f4ca1a1d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efforts by the Government of the People's Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party to unilaterally determine the future of Taiwan through non-peaceful means, including threats and the direct use of force, military coercion, economic boycotts or embargoes, cyberattacks, and efforts to internationally isolate or annex Taiwan—</text><subparagraph id="idb5221b8fafe14cfa8e111d9dbc5066d7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>directly undermine the spirit, intent, and purpose of the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70c329cc272f4b35a23931c9e605a402"><enum>(B)</enum><text>undermine peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcefb6999d6f5461ca98cc5e9a3fc3b5e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>limit a free and open Indo-Pacific region; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaad68c319e34791a8ba53f7e63c735b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are of grave concern to the Government of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2e36e11fba14acd83c280f2a28a14e1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the initiation of a military invasion of Taiwan by the People’s Liberation Army would—</text><subparagraph id="ide98e1395f6d04acea9e3881fe8136a44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constitute a threat to the peace and security of the Western Pacific area and threaten the peace stability of the entire globe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06037b9d53d44fd7aafdea7a9649d2c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>undermine the core political, security, and economic interests of the United States at home and abroad; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70ae45bed52a464988d359afa30931b7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as an important deterrent measure against a military invasion of Taiwan, the Government of the People's Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party must understand that initiating such an invasion will result in catastrophic economic and financial consequences for the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id5FE33B30ACB6436FB219DBC07EB04D22"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id3d700b3cde1243d1b30e36025b1af269"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Account; correspondent account; payable-through account</header><text>The terms <term>account</term>, <term>correspondent account</term>, and <term>payable-through account</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 5318A of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ida03ac01f99d24160a2a48f36500defd8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admission</term>, <term>admitted</term>, and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id016975DA698D4FE59E76C6809B1B2A10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id258b1a4915ed4b1280e40530309eca15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91a1d8ac185a4c99a7abecf9cb097482"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id741d470b414d4ff985c41c9bacbb0a46"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Armed Forces of the People's Republic of China</header><text>The term <term>Armed Forces of the People’s Republic of China</term> includes, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="id31a71db6d9864006882168a7ac6a84a5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Aerospace Force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfbb5e37ad8b0401db7acc2bc0c5db149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Cyberspace Force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a7ebb072190402ebf041d8ba80b2e6e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Information Support Force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idedf7ea7bbfc94a368d526e208913cd81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Joint Logistics Support Force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b7df2a6b9804324aa7d4b95af9789c3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Air Force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b3bedf2348d40f1ab31e84c1c2c6e47"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Army;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41e0715596e541e3b31ffe8a0e4082e6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Navy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc40d4a66105b485f829bf30edc73f1b2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Special Operations Forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe61ff9ec64745d29c248bbceef4205e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army Rocket Force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc4c8d5f06924cc2a486cf4cee93cee4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Joint Staff Department of the Central Military Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4dff56d2344e4bc18de7e5c4825094f9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the China Coast Guard;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca66fb7d9f2a49d4a865df96c58a3259"><enum>(L)</enum><text>paramilitary forces, including the Maritime Militia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf32b7e7c2dd4417a16339c911fb756c"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the People’s Armed Police; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd784ac8d8fa54cc58b7bdb30e73441cf"><enum>(N)</enum><text>any successor entities or proxies of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (M).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id379271AFEA994C95BF6B549DF38AAF8C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered determination</header><text>The term <term>covered determination</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86bd205808074a3ab7a883d1598afecd"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><subparagraph id="ide9662f9193644e6aae5fc6746fb3f55e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>critical infrastructure</term>, with respect to Taiwan, means systems and assets, whether physical or virtual, so vital to Taiwan that the incapacity or destruction of such systems and assets would have catastrophic regional or national effects on public health or safety, economic security, or national security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3bdcd449f4bc4f3ab9766b6a1e0e10ff"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Included sectors</header><text>The term <term>critical infrastructure</term> includes assets in the following sectors:</text><clause id="id706967012cc447b292450371a199448e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Biotechnology.</text></clause><clause id="id3fc85e21dea94aa7a1281d127384d0f1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Chemical.</text></clause><clause id="id944fa25963204cf09a6dd51021c2182f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Commercial facilities.</text></clause><clause id="id311df3c851bd416ba39edcd21945ce09"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Communications.</text></clause><clause id="idf9e744edf9da4898873a997de0d4653b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Critical manufacturing.</text></clause><clause id="id3ef48911e4a04f85bf31e9273b4302fc"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Dams.</text></clause><clause id="ide21cff63cecf4637a4926979013d8cae"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Defense industrial base.</text></clause><clause id="id25386fdebe2b49cd909fb76b72793bbb"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Emergency services.</text></clause><clause id="id2e7df2b437354a3883d777f857d15aee"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Energy.</text></clause><clause id="idb190286d2b7b4d46806c8427e91a2519"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Financial services.</text></clause><clause id="id95840291ac2a47bc98802ffbea087da1"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Food and agriculture.</text></clause><clause id="idbc23cafa19df4187967fa2af4b5e0314"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Government facilities.</text></clause><clause id="id34cfa39f64624827a21c7a033f95e4ba"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>Healthcare and public health.</text></clause><clause id="idb2b14cae3b894384ae3cd46b51c13d60"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Information technology.</text></clause><clause id="id2529f5292c9048f7a35b7da0811ac2ea"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>Materials and waste.</text></clause><clause id="idb5550f8d276749f0af7b8b2dddea930e"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>Nuclear reactors.</text></clause><clause id="idee0362abaf3f468c8f887e673d968163"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>Space.</text></clause><clause id="id7a3abb143e37434fbff02078b6b1b534"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>Transportation systems.</text></clause><clause id="id687630aa6ef441619b60821920a111c0"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>Water and wastewater systems.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id26f6642206d24731897c0f0d6f645820"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> means a financial institution specified in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), (J), (M), or (Y) of section 5312(a)(2) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id30175c7a8d2542cba386d3ee2289ce0f"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf158ef08064845b7925f674de04b65d0"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term> with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person had actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c34220945d248999ae2577bc9b13f1f"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Sanctioned person</header><text>The term <term>sanctioned person</term> means any person with respect to which sanctions are imposed under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab6d05f6f2874764bbf9432a75b7c842"><enum>(11)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Top decision-making body</header><text>The term <term>top decision-making body</term>, with respect to the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party, includes—</text><subparagraph id="id0326d4da22304b5994b41b0fee28312e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party Politburo Standing Committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31b8eb7760274e8b847d7937cfcd3198"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party Central Military Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd34f62f836b468c98886c9a9da538e9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party Politburo;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94e43665ceea47f0a230ac160660ef84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party Central Committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id266d6a376de643c194d5f72bf383210d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party National Congress;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a8a291107a14e4197cafb668618d6db"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the State Council of the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3565f17d5caf4e69a1709bb9350b6aa9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the State Central Military Commission of the People's Republic of China; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1649f18b389468997cc36754724059e"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any successor entity or proxy of an entity described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (G).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id33362f43698d40cf8cd09c2423359807"><enum>(12)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ide5c7a78e8cdf4362a0eafd35968d4d1c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida72442293b6d49a69db53654651c8278"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><title id="id83a6e5f0ca414cd98a5d66b4a6a2f377" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Sanctions and other measures in response to significant threats to security of Taiwan</header><section id="idc80bcb0e96f64dcd91fbf787d1ce658b"><enum>101.</enum><header>Covered determinations</header><subsection id="ide7010d8dade44f9bb8e67d5e0600ef51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Covered determination defined</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>covered determination</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idC6B57ACBA8DA448C8952B20E2642B622"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a determination by the President under subsection (b) that an actor described in paragraph (1) of that subsection has engaged, is engaging, or is planning to engage imminently in an act described in paragraph (2) of that subsection; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4127FCEC80A84239AA847D12782A6BCA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the enactment of a joint resolution pursuant to subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd144b105ceae4e04b84b19dfb7722530"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determinations by President</header><paragraph id="idaf2135e11f024c8882f2759cd187c8ca"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than every 30 days thereafter, the President shall determine if any of the following actors has engaged, is engaging, or is planning to engage imminently in an act described in paragraph (2):</text><subparagraph id="id8016b48ec3f14a549b9f6b799929db79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45ea30300f4e46cea1f86150aa074785"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Chinese Communist Party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id83b3e2c792e74c00bbbde1bdb8961aff"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any proxy of the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1759d6586fbd4fd88651559e29d3995c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any individual or entity controlled by or acting at the direction of the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide1af58fdaf884d499c6553681dfa82dd"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>Any individual who serves on any top decision-making body of the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8748b94be5424984b735d9d83cf53673"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any person described in section 102 or 103.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9f43adcf00b4411b90cd99c222db517"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acts described</header><text>An act described in this paragraph is any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id9d978f57e4a04ee1bd155ca17d3e54cb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Overthrowing or dismantling the governing institutions in Taiwan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d643a7baf5e4cdfa8811f05cc70b91f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Occupying any territory controlled or administered by Taiwan as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2cffcf90837424cbbcb8d7c17c2cebe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Violating the territorial integrity of Taiwan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7cbfce7efa1a45b79083ff5e02589c42"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Taking any of the following actions:</text><clause id="id92933764c0f44080a301402cd1c96fff"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Creating a naval or aerial blockade of Taiwan.</text></clause><clause id="id912df93a6a294a648308a631618680c7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Seizing the offshore islands of Taiwan.</text></clause><clause id="id4d1e7cfe41d14f32b1de6ad2e9aef187"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Initiating a military attack, including—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75c3a09a34cc4f929432948d11609ed0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amphibious landing or assault;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id054d1ee29d2645709c5d26ffbf1464ce"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an airport operation, air assault, or aerial bombardment;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0774f3a530cb4570aaeb90800bcf9743"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">missile attacks; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd42cd270c3e04fe8882a027b6541d9ce"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">naval bombardment.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ide286080cc7e448ada6641c507972cd5b"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A debilitating attack on the critical infrastructure of Taiwan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id6DC1D06586D54968BADB3F4AE1EA000B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determinations by joint resolution</header><paragraph id="id677976BFAF074E7784BE40EFE6C4F1AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered joint resolution defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered joint resolution</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress determines that an actor described in paragraph (1) of section 101(b) of the <short-title>Sanctions Targeting Aggressors of Neighboring Democracies with Taiwan Act of 2026</short-title> has engaged, is engaging, or is planning to engage in an act described in paragraph (2) of that section.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe5b27e920ec4ec4a916d5c2f811e8d0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>A covered joint resolution may be introduced—</text><subparagraph id="id36d0654e03aa418187f89e0ed813798b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives, by the majority leader (or the majority leader's designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader's designee); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca4d474d56224bdfacf41d2949417af3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the Senate, by the majority leader (or the majority leader's designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader's designee).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idddd39f53e95a4b5086470b849e938238"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Floor consideration in House of Representatives</header><subparagraph id="idA83164D6C1B14C9182EC406B75F99AD7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Discharge from committee</header><text>If a committee of the House of Representatives to which a covered joint resolution has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 2 calendar days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, the committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0b798f55b92f43be9a79bdf33306faab"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Moving to consideration</header><text>At any time after a covered joint resolution has been placed on the appropriate calendar, it is in order for the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) to move for the consideration of that joint resolution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddda70ebe61bc45a390f67f375d7f4b7b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Points of order; motions</header><text>All points of order against the covered joint resolution and its consideration are waived. If the motion under subparagraph (B) is agreed to, the joint resolution shall remain the unfinished business of the House until disposed of, except as provided in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c604f9a1c1441bd9413f9269f636840"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No amendments</header><text>A covered joint resolution shall not be subject to amendment in the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id160d6abda53047988e6eaae9d1c1d977"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Debate</header><text>General debate on a covered joint resolution shall not exceed 4 hours, which shall be equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25ebbdefb9014bfc9c5ff254f915050a"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Final passage</header><text>At the conclusion of debate, the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution, and the House of Representatives shall vote on final passage without intervening motion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc99d19daa2845e29334bfa86fa5057c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration in the Senate</header><subparagraph id="id17e6da629bf24df1b4cc27af4d76ca2b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the committee of the Senate to which a covered joint resolution was referred has not reported the joint resolution within 2 calendar days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ec86dbbe60543ef8c9539b4cbe19ce0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the committee of the Senate to which a covered joint resolution was referred reports the joint resolution to the Senate or has been discharged from consideration of the joint resolution (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef639dc012ee4042afe0b8b507cc4ef0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No amendments</header><text>An amendment to a covered joint resolution, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit a covered joint resolution, is not in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3361a4296be9423a8b997d344e8483f0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Consideration</header><clause id="id83e301f8e4564b3388e51adc81118e6d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation on debate</header><text>Consideration in the Senate of a covered joint resolution shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader, or by their designees.</text></clause><clause id="id207faf67d0cd45c5a5a420340780ac66"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Vote on adoption</header><text>Whenever all the time for debate on a covered joint resolution has been used or yielded back, the vote on the adoption of the resolution shall occur without any intervening motion or amendment, except that a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the Rules of the Senate may occur immediately before such vote.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd46b978730b14c15942fe46378ce3398"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a covered joint resolution shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78904cf580ff4c5c94321257688c3443"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to a covered joint resolution, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with the joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id479ab79c6ce2410da4ccac25f06164e5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rules relating to Senate and House of Representatives</header><subparagraph id="idf517200784ce45f4aee054bcdd45f259"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Treatment of Senate joint resolution in house</header><text>In the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply to a covered joint resolution received from the Senate (unless the House has already passed a joint resolution relating to the same proposed action):</text><clause id="id323b0332fa704f7796e0156d289bf8b4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be referred to the appropriate committees.</text></clause><clause id="idb04c831e29394b2a8886f27cd5010d1a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If a committee to which a joint resolution has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 2 calendar days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text></clause><clause id="id1e04becd7f3846cc8704ed4f48e2a92d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after the committee to which a joint resolution has been referred reports the joint resolution to the House or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed on the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></clause><clause id="id44189f3c4c73460b8fc7ba3b589c8507"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except 4 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e3b2d5e12ad472fa126fa022a50631f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of house joint resolution in Senate</header><clause id="idf0042932440945f6bf6cd71c4d1c5a19"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Receipt before passage</header><text>If, before the passage by the Senate of a covered joint resolution, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply:</text><subclause id="id26af377fe3d040c49ff150da428d9ac4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>That joint resolution shall not be referred to a committee.</text></subclause><subclause id="idee40417046284999bc86d8bcb8a6d95c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>With respect to that joint resolution—</text> <item id="idd5cef6581abd48c782d79f0f8db12b57"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>the procedure in the Senate shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the House of Representatives; but</text>
 </item><item id="id837247caff96427084735aca0f3252d7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the vote on passage shall be on the joint resolution from the House of Representatives.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id3762f88924d0401899d1c184973210b7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Receipt after passage</header><text>If, following passage of a covered joint resolution in the Senate, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, that joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate Senate calendar.</text></clause><clause id="id9aa2d2003ab44daf830a1be9e809bc88"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>No companion measure</header><text>If a covered joint resolution is received from the House, and no companion joint resolution has been introduced in the Senate, the Senate procedures under this subsection shall apply to the House joint resolution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7b2a03c8e33479086899316f39c868e"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to revenue measures</header><text>The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply in the House of Representatives to a covered joint resolution that is a revenue measure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id42fe2f725eba48eabe4cc39072fca2df"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Rules of the House of Representatives and Senate</header> <text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text>
                        <subparagraph id="id4ccf846a9d2e4b94ae6277cae9a6592a">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id3e297fd036ec4460a13b0c133acdd151" commented="no"
                            display-inline="no-display-inline">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id116688815b1b4a1783cd817f62409ca8"><enum>102.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to officials of the Government of the People's Republic of China and members of the Chinese Communist Party</header><subsection id="id7010c4f4d42f4755af00419b5f8c8c52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 days after a covered determination is made, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="id5396ff648e244bd982c5109081012077"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>impose the sanctions described in section 201 with respect to the persons described in subsection (b), to the extent such persons can be identified; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id28a5506ef1e348a08f6865dc863183ce"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit any United States person (other than an official of the United States Government acting in an official capacity) from engaging in any transaction with a person described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8b5eaff34da94466883f4c3ad22a783f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>The persons described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="idfa576a6110b54462a5c7b8bb250a3fd9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The following officials of the Government of the People’s Republic of China:</text><subparagraph id="id3ecb5ee799e2463aaea17141958f1345"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The General Secretary of the Chinese Communist Party and all members of the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7d56b69bb2d4c0287cad1e44ceaa8ef"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The President of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1636003fb4564093958178256c83cb9d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Vice President of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb33e8b73c60542a89cbff1bec0e611b6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Leaders of the State Council of the People's Republic of China, including the Premier, Vice Premiers, State Councilors, and the Secretary General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72d7737b98a6489dac0598707bf48fa1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the State Council of the People's Republic of China, including all Ministers and heads of all constituent agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63ae91765b2548e2a096bb570a78fb38"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Minister of National Defense of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e74a9be56a74449b0d53f23782ce819"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Members of the Central Military Commission of the Chinese Communist Party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1bd8d902d2b479cbe7d15278bdc598d"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The commanders of the People’s Liberation Army, the People’s Liberation Army Navy, the People’s Liberation Army Air Force, and the People’s Liberation Army Rocket Force.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b5b590a6f5b41fdbd28c3af5c2e81fe"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Commander of the People’s Armed Police Force of the Central Military Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd7c29b23d3b4ee08e6ee21291d5e723"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Commander of the People’s Liberation Army Reserve Force.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1013594a0504a36bdd4e9f8c5908aa4"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Commander-in-Chief of the People’s Liberation Army Aerospace Force, Cyberspace Force, Information Support Force, and Joint Logistics Force.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id965e9b32069d42fdb1e4eea236926494"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of the Central Commission for Foreign Affairs of the Central Committee of the Chinese Communist Party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf75fd0600e144d459570739da95fa8fa"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The Chair of the National Development and Reform Commission of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7085e2d0ed5e43e1870e7a0fcb5ec7cb"><enum>(N)</enum><text>The Minister of Agriculture and Rural Affairs of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e87444131c84f19bd2acbde3696d4e1"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The Minister of State Security of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c490247cc01464f92bbbc33ce7969d3"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The Minister of Public Security of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e99da6f825c477cbfbb4045f8048f08"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Any foreign person serving as a member of the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf084d4be1920478f9e4d99718996a68f"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Any foreign person serving as a member of the State Central Military Commission of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfdb826f94e354cc3baf244312e86a21f"><enum>(S)</enum><text>The Chief Justice or Grand Justice of the Supreme People’s Court of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c0fc1d3c45840ceb6279f309fda5364"><enum>(T)</enum><text>The Prosecutor General of the Supreme People’s Procuratorate of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27c4454660e041bd81e2120ff22b562e"><enum>(U)</enum><text>Any foreign person serving as a member of the State Council or any organ composing the State Council of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbddde3f4838d44029ec522a41b0d8228"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any other official of the Government of the People’s Republic of China that the President determines should be subject to sanctions under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf07bcb4f6e624a549e2918d4d8e0abb9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any foreign person that—</text><subparagraph id="id39517fb71b5842ba9c29090e35f9d683"><enum>(A)</enum><text>knowingly sells, supplies, transfers, markets, or provides defense articles, equipment, goods, services, technology, or materials to the Armed Forces of the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbea0369ea5cf41d18b630494b7a33267"><enum>(B)</enum><text>knowingly conducts a transaction with the Armed Forces of the People’s Republic of China (other than a transaction of an official of a foreign government acting in an official capacity);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id577ab7775647425a8b2de1fddc8aa371"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has engaged in or attempted to engage in activities that—</text><clause id="id2c5cbae943f845e1b6cb2ca1429bf95e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>materially undermine the military readiness of Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="idf001383251e74a22a2c7b91ef7310741"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>seek to overthrow, dismantle, or subvert the governing institutions of Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="id096f6ecef6284709935e976e249ef233"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>debilitate the critical infrastructure of Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="ide894ed228521499e805a73b23ea55c68"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>debilitate cybersecurity systems through malicious electronic attacks or cyberattacks on Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="idd632088a463d48f7a14a179cac875568"><enum>(v)</enum><text>undermine the democratic processes of Taiwan; or</text></clause><clause id="idfe0d9f2a35664427849fc1db17549536"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>involve committing serious human rights abuses against citizens of Taiwan, including forceful transfers, enforced disappearances, unjust detainment, or torture; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8269c93829394951965419ada72c8391"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged or attempted to engage in, for or on behalf of, or for the benefit of, directly or indirectly, the Government of the People’s Republic of China—</text><clause id="id976583bcdd0c48239ef2fb07900efe14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>transnational corruption, bribery, extortion, or money laundering;</text></clause><clause id="id0bd08acccac54b3ab7204c81b7985167"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assassination, murder, or other unlawful killing of, or infliction of other bodily harm against, a United States person or a citizen or national of an ally or partner of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id242cbb61396d430ebd43fd84eb3e03c4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>activities that undermine the peace, security, political stability, or territorial integrity of the United States or an ally or partner of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="ide852a909ec2a408d8361c2413efe88ec"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>deceptive or structured transactions or dealings to circumvent the application of any sanctions imposed by the United States, including through the use of digital currencies or assets or the use of physical assets.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7edf4f98a6474e3d9f32a0910c1cff45"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any agent of any person described in paragraph (1) or (2), or any other person, if the sanctioned person transferred property or an interest in property to the agent or other person—</text><subparagraph id="id285bc7e24c044dfcac627ddd3318625b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>after the date on which the President imposed sanctions with respect to the sanctioned person; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id902046f4ae6449e9a05ce3223d8fd8fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before that date, if the sanctioned person did so in an attempt to evade the imposition of sanctions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id28de38862b0f4b8bb717c67293463f3a"><enum>103.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to financial institutions affiliated with the Government of the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="id4c887e585ab741ada6611280ef3d74c2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 days after a covered determination is made, the Secretary of the Treasury shall—</text><paragraph id="id0310734E919A4881B303C9186D764DD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a8d81cdc64f40a6afb0189bc0aa3581"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the People's Bank of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e7d4aa898e743ad9550dc8c009f558d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any state-owned bank;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9f5b207a1d144dd902f09d306974f3d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other financial institution organized under the laws of the People’s Republic of China and owned in whole or part by the Government of the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd35df16383314166a610c64a467a4df2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any subsidiary of, or successor entity to, any of the financial institutions described in subparagraphs (A) through (F); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8153e52f3719438c87d08d06a706648d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any financial institution that engages in transactions with any of the financial institutions described in subparagraphs (A) through (G);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id982942ecad064a81bb721839dbec6b3b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose the sanctions described in section 201 with respect to any directors of, officers of, officials of, and shareholders with an interest in, a financial institution described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b8c0bd57ad64401bbc8111b462587fa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prohibit any United States person from engaging in any transaction with a financial institution described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7F9B4EE930ED47C0A1F9788B24A5568B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="id131e69af1be3460a96de40c6b9c377f2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><subparagraph id="idDBBDFEB0289C4383BDB3665016FB994F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a financial institution subject to subsection (a)(1) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9edf756bf5f54d60a265d9e395d42aad"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inapplicability of national emergency requirement</header><text>The requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply for purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id757f8b37f4c045e3879e51165e2d736e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictions on correspondent and payable-through accounts</header><text>The President shall prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States of a correspondent account or payable-through account by a financial institution subject to subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida58757c91be94d4bbf6cbb9705959bfb"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>State-Owned bank defined</header> <text>In this section, the term <term>state-owned bank</term>—</text>
                    <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="id41f9e0cc60424c708eefe6a917f9358b">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a bank that—</text> <subparagraph id="idf5345d2798e945ebb275a77ea1ddfb60"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>is incorporated in the People’s Republic of China; or</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id1888fc1c45fd49819bd8ab2eb300b753">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is owned in whole or part by the Government of the People’s Republic of China; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="iddb5e433f7f044462a36e90f6d6258c75">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>includes—</text> <subparagraph id="id66d6a1b3e0cf4ab0944e88e8086fffbc"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the Export-Import Bank of China;</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id0f3f9d903aa1431abab8d9ef05d3706d">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the China Development Bank;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id301d11c6ae1e4f169ad5f990ab08ab02"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the Agricultural Development Bank of China;</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id259dd5b3b2074488970810dfe0da7d74">
                            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ideef74276b9454e46962641ef38d35ea6"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>the China Construction Bank;</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="iddc08261a46c04007b5bfc8476a0db2f5">
                            <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>the Bank of Communications;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id2da91bc6b3cf4324bdac535de055a813"> <enum>(G)</enum> <text>the Agricultural Bank of China; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="idb2c379a1db374a75952730a6ebd5e780">
                            <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>the Bank of China.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection></section><section id="id59A86A535689457ABFC32C9EBAFD6CAE"><enum>104.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to entities owned by or affiliated with the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 days after a covered determination is made, the Secretary of the Treasury shall impose the sanctions described in section 201(1) with respect to any entity engaged in commercial activities on behalf of the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party, in which the government or party has an ownership stake and exercises ultimate control over business decisions.</text></section><section id="id057a59788d61465089c18e6f1f4033f4"><enum>105.</enum><header>Prohibition on transfers of funds involving the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="id5CDC7D9C3C8D46E4B62C634260DBC2A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by subsection (b), not later than 3 days after a covered determination is made, a depository institution (as defined in section 19(b)(1)(A) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/461">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>)) or a broker or dealer in securities registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>) may not process transfers of funds—</text><paragraph id="id073BF5F25EE24CC4BD38493C53C4DD27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to or from the People's Republic of China; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3DBB94BBDD0E4CE7BF24999CB266A3A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the direct or indirect benefit of officials of the Government of the People's Republic of China or members of the Chinese Communist Party.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id969399155D834142981AE39EDC3EB8B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A depository institution, broker, or dealer described in subsection (a) may process a transfer described in that subsection if the transfer—</text><paragraph id="idE84326E5AC90400C97DC4D99EC5054A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>arises from, and is ordinarily incident and necessary to give effect to, an underlying transaction that is authorized by a specific or general license; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE724259B935148BFA8DD2763C71D09CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not involve debiting or crediting a Chinese account.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id11b8011316d147dfa6af4b7a8c62afc1"><enum>106.</enum><header>Prohibition on listing or trading of Chinese entities on United States securities exchanges</header><subsection id="id153e26514d10463fbc211fd8371db548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Securities and Exchange Commission shall prohibit the securities of an issuer described in subsection (b) from being traded on a national securities exchange on and after the date that is 3 days after a covered determination is made.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2b396f51604d46b6a47c847f011304b7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuers</header><text>An issuer described in this subsection is an issuer that is a security listed with the China Securities Regulatory Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="id49b75f223ff446f393c97509f2e4368f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id4d76bde822124c8383675b7c7d03dc20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuer; security</header><text>The terms <quote>issuer</quote> and <quote>security</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60350612e66845a786f8a1e442049f0e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National securities exchange</header><text>The term <term>national securities exchange</term> means an exchange registered as a national securities exchange in accordance with section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd36d804346b64972b1a109db8a9d0e5e"><enum>107.</enum><header>Prohibition on investments by United States financial institutions that benefit the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party</header><subsection id="id780d05ae30d441f58b0ed27d2d26b723"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 days after a covered determination is made, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prohibit any United States financial institution from making any investments described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id33421b0f2eaa4ba7b5f70a57f6594438"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investments described</header><text>An investment described in this subsection is a monetary investment—</text><paragraph id="id46ade1c0dad546d3b7a421b7518fe97e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to—</text><subparagraph id="idd3771bd1cb0443308be454975e645d62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity owned or controlled by the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaae09c8a8e834f9aa9f58a0df8b178eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the People’s Liberation Army; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a8ca32265a64dd49ac06478c9b6d636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the benefit of any priority industrial sector identified in the <quote>Made in China 2025</quote> plan or the <quote>14th Five Year Smart Manufacturing Development Plan</quote>, including—</text><subparagraph id="id4066d62bdf694d009f4c975f6f1a2ba5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agriculture machinery;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05c4bad33fe14e2e964e1cf6b2a7f0be"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id449ea4dfc948412d8215fd67d98e288d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>artificial intelligence, machine learning, and robotics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fca17a8ba5247dc9f1b02875bf74ad3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>green energy and green vehicles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id639bd67b7bdf4040ab52f7797d2685fe"><enum>(E)</enum><text>aerospace equipment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida97ccf4f530047f0b39616b875e8569a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ocean engineering and high tech ships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id047998eabc6a4f33b124f538c6183a63"><enum>(G)</enum><text>railway equipment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57ff558ce8a34d4da788b3b6a992c853"><enum>(H)</enum><text>power equipment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ae883fc4ebe4258af14b231efb7e8b1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>new materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5a81dd0bf5744f4bb766373d76ae052"><enum>(J)</enum><text>medicine and medical devices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3b0af5079fb4cda9423368e947df5fe"><enum>(K)</enum><text>fifth generation and future generation telecommunications and other advanced wireless networking technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19ecfc71514c42cdb0c1fef1d0fd8e0c"><enum>(L)</enum><text>semiconductor manufacturing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74fcd42f03124b8880ea1ea23ceb343d"><enum>(M)</enum><text>biotechnology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc346b7a82f645bf96b15dc89be867b2"><enum>(N)</enum><text>quantum computing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85fa880fb50845e8923a3e9b8272100a"><enum>(O)</enum><text>surveillance technologies, including facial recognition technologies and censorship software;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b15d3d0dfa54979a37736eaf2ae11c7"><enum>(P)</enum><text>fiber optic cables; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62f38bef8f1f46a5a5ed00093b1c3c23"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>mining and resource development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb022be05a210409fabf68e476d10e5f8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United States financial institution defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>United States financial institution</term>—</text><paragraph id="id7E52979276BA42EE999E1C477980B635"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means any financial institution that is a United States person; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1A2D9022B6EF469A838A9EBE3C37749C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes an investment company, private equity company, venture capital company, or hedge fund that is a United States person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5b0081f604e34487aa82e7ad5d99d35f"><enum>108.</enum><header>Measures relating to energy sector of the People's Republic of China</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id440a77465844422bb7b45d60e35defe7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on exports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date that is 3 days after a covered determination is made, the Secretary of Commerce shall prohibit, under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), the export, reexport, or in-country transfer to or in the People's Republic of China any energy or energy product produced in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7af32f8e0d7e4345be9786f3f6a662a8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on investments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date that is 3 days after a covered determination is made, a United States person may not make an investment in the energy sector of the People's Republic of China.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc6c73ac2e33c428698697de97455c76e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>The President shall—</text><paragraph id="idc70228cd5c7147389ad037f628d83398"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose the sanctions described in section 201 with respect to any foreign person that the President determines knowingly sells, supplies, transfers, markets, or provides goods, services, technology, information, or other support that facilitates the maintenance or expansion of the production of oil, uranium, natural gas, petroleum, petroleum products, or petrochemical products for use by any person subject to sanctions under section 102, 103, or 104; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc940244451db4fe1b0e1abec4e00f8cb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit any United States person from engaging in any transaction with a person described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id399e1337d8aa4b11be99c7caab647fbb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>export</quote>, <quote>in-country transfer</quote>, <quote>reexport</quote>, and <quote>United States person</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 1742 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="id4c6d76ed3f9741e5ac75d47f6f21a7fa"><enum>109.</enum><header>Prohibition on purchases of sovereign debt of the People’s Republic of China by United States persons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On and after the date that is 3 days after a covered determination is made, the purchase of sovereign debt of the Government of the People’s Republic of China by any United States person is prohibited.</text></section><section id="id8dbf6b10a9a14911840de103e98cc071"><enum>110.</enum><header>Prohibition on provision of services to sanctioned financial institutions by international financial messaging systems</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 days after a covered determination is made, the President shall impose sanctions pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to—</text><paragraph id="id3b91965ed0494b48a182413283c94673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any global financial communications services provider that does not terminate the provision of financial communications services to, and the enabling and facilitation of access to such services for, any financial institution subject to sanctions under section 103 or any other provision of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a7d90022b5941d5a62b6ea39d849996"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the directors of, officers of, and shareholders with a interest in, the provider.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id96bc62bb4abd449e87319c4cd228fccc"><enum>111.</enum><header>Increases in duties on goods imported from the People’s Republic of China</header><subsection id="id7055d8271c1847509e9d9069515e9716"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days after a covered determination is made, the President shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law, increase the rate of duty for all goods imported into the United States from the People’s Republic of China to a rate of up to 500 percent ad valorem.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide378eb784c8f4e3ca4784a8a8e149cf8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duty rate in addition to antidumping and countervailing duties</header><text>The rate of duty required under subsection (a) with respect to a good described in that subsection shall be in addition to any antidumping or countervailing duty applicable with respect to the good under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1671">19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="id227b135b1f244980bd78b2ee0a380375"><enum>112.</enum><header>Increases in duties on goods imported from countries that support the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="idf7955ff47a9e4cdda0c294b86f3a5f26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days after a covered determination is made, and every 90 days thereafter, the President shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law, increase the rate of duty for all goods imported into the United States from a country described in subsection (b) to a rate of up to 500 percent ad valorem.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4cdd10d654d14bc1a0697e8c88b81bad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Countries described</header><text>A country is described in this subsection if the country—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc59ff07dc3e476483bfde9e3bf71a44"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly sells, supplies, transfers, or purchases oil, uranium, natural gas, petroleum products, or petrochemical products to or from the People’s Republic of China; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6abd828254e42109e709707d1066107"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly sells, supplies, transfers, or purchases products, material, or financial support to or from the People’s Republic of China for its military-industrial capacity or for any act described in section 101(b)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id029bdf656e9c447a9060bdc670d64b3e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duty rate in addition to antidumping and countervailing duties</header><text>The rate of duty required under subsection (a) with respect to a good described in that subsection shall be in addition to any antidumping or countervailing duty applicable with respect to the good under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1671">19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id37a3e361796a4ec9a58c52ee72595e8e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on waivers for certain countries</header><text>The President may not waive under section 202 the application of subsection (a) with respect to—</text><paragraph id="id4c61dfe4a658434da9a1d4ad868c83a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism (commonly referred to as a <quote>state sponsor of terrorism</quote>), for purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="id6a83729b06274dc5b4b838ab96f21c3f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae067e72eac14e53836feb723ce13438"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23a0defa5d8b4442a5f9cba79b4b3d31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ef35f18fd0d4e8982c57b9401f1c2c4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id26fa48c8be36415e864108e5794246de"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a country specified in section 4872(f)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1b20e1f74466434db9bdeb49b54a617c"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Military-Industrial capacity defined</header> <text>In this section, the term <term>military-industrial capacity</term> means the capacity of a country to produce and supply the equipment, technology, weapons, training and deployment of personnel, manpower, and systems necessary for military operations.</text>
 </subsection></section></title><title id="idcb32717347734b6b935b0302e2d3cfe7" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>General provisions</header><section id="idb4a0b3d3c9064ce1b48922a987b61a6a"><enum>201.</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The sanctions described in this section are the following:</text><paragraph id="id83ed0119f6314dce9ee425507c52928c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><subparagraph id="idFE6C833228A143FCAE57B54B681AA6FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the sanctioned person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id602ea25ebe0a47cc9ecfd8dc6a5ef698"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inapplicability of national emergency requirement</header><text>The requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply for purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id847f56559ac343bcaaf4ca809de2cf46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="id2d7993b0a36b4342819d1de62d977a60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>In the case of a sanctioned person who is an alien, the alien shall be—</text><clause id="ide648164c1beb47f8ba0ced7d6fa024cc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id41d4086e90154f7f863c7a0704913976"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="idda2eb8fed4324eb081fc113944fd15ad"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7ea53613df8499da19afb3f55c02ebe"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="id5a0d108062d448cab48968e3bb70092a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subparagraph (A) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause><clause id="id039ead28f3c7409da9b0c8c8f60a71ff"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="ida8f9dad9e3b646689c132b0056b63cca"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id185d6a9fc4f049b3afd271f3c8ce077a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idd061d620791a42b2ad7bb6408ebe7dda"><enum>202.</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided by section 112(d), the President may waive, for successive periods of not more than 90 days each, the application of sanctions, prohibitions, restrictions, duties, and penalties under this Act with respect to a person if, for each such period, the President—</text><paragraph id="id8154e38b757e4b5d980d60d0e12c0dc7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide36a3aee641b4a2688c8cc50c2d34540"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in the national security interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21be2c35b85c48a28eed2085fccf4d43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supports the enduring security of Taiwan and a return to the disposition of forces that prevailed before the act that led to the applicable covered determination; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4186cfbfd894fc5aa52dc24f8818175"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of the waiver and the reasons for the waiver.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id42a0ba54967b4321b1443a9a0509f8c3"><enum>203.</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subsection id="id74f3b9d82bfc48d1a6949882a3a957b3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Support for people of the people’s republic of china</header><text>This Act shall not apply with respect to efforts to promote democracy in the People’s Republic of China.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4ec5c04991c14162935dfc992c4fb532"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>This Act shall not apply with respect to activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id562a59e4b493458fb97a154a634486ce"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Exception To comply with international obligations</header> <text>Sanctions under this Act shall not apply to the admission of an alien if the admission of that alien is necessary to comply with United States obligations under the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, under the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967, or under other international agreements.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idaa60e3c1f8774bc1b538adf7f627b463"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><paragraph id="id57b0ae54a4d44080ba7703dd85ea0e86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this Act shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfde07eba4f05465da272cf9219775c73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id28362a005f0e486b938ba5c8e4428a30"><enum>204.</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><subsection id="idc3161040db0b4e0a9406df376025dcd0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this Act (other than sections 111 and 112).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd50f254ab4d43359328db9c8fec16e7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of any provision of this Act (other than section 111 or 112) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out any such provision shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection></section><section id="id7953c4fe461f470ca407d34fb9806236"><enum>205.</enum><header>Termination authority</header><subsection id="id07e3621972b643a084be0cb1c6e3a0fa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may terminate the application of sanctions, prohibitions, restrictions, duties, and penalties under this Act if the President submits to Congress a certification that—</text><paragraph id="id4cabe4fea22e4b9f8959ee8bac205209"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all actors described in paragraph (1) of section 101(b) have verifiably ceased engaging in acts described in paragraph (2) of that section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2560397ec1848b19a5bc01d38fa3dbe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party have renounced engaging in any such acts in the future.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4b5d5661deca4c608591c768b450e31d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimposition</header><text>If, after the submission of a certification described in subsection (a), an actor described in paragraph (1) of section 101(b) engages in an act described in paragraph (2) of that section, the President shall immediately reimpose all previously terminated sanctions, prohibitions, restrictions, duties, and penalties imposed under this Act, in addition to new sanctions, prohibitions, restrictions, duties, and penalties under this Act.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>

