<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF827E515D93B42AAA4AFF500ED742DA8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7248 IH: Maintaining Access to Recreational Industry and Necessary Adjustments Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7248</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Corps of Engineers to take certain actions with respect to rental amounts and administrative fees charged to certain marinas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C778DE8596E48A7A4C8B264F494798E" style="OLC"><section id="H36B9B035B9A14B40BDDE6687E9673358" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maintaining Access to Recreational Industry and Necessary Adjustments Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MARINA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H53F302C580564A249DFFC9CCBAF0D89B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD60EC1F07A4F44CC96C6210B6918071F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Marina concessionaires, individually and collectively, allow the Corps of Engineers to fulfill their responsibility to enhance public usage and enjoyment of Corps of Engineers facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB1B46341EFB4744A9AB6784B5E4088C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Leases for commercial concession purposes provide a direct benefit to the public and the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H708E1FF7F4574D10BD8C6D4811EF6912"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Corps of Engineers lacks a coordinated schedule or assessment for charging administrative fees to concessionaires across all Corps of Engineers districts.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H81420A848E544EC29308190ADA5FDC63"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rental amounts, fees, and lease periods for covered marinas</header><subsection id="HCAECCC7812384CB7A48A8724F2439497"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on rental amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the amount of rent charged to the operator of a covered marina for a covered lease, the Secretary shall, for purposes of applying the Revised Graduated Rental System—</text><paragraph id="HFE4780118D304158AC00510DC6D31E20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exclude from the total gross receipts calculation the combined covered receipts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFACF6EE41124C1FA7580B073A4C4FB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a percentage rate applicable to such combined covered receipts of not more than 1 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F62575A1D7F4A99982BCE460A9E7012"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fee schedules for administrative fees</header><paragraph id="H873DE61CC3C749919821697DFD0AF211" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish, for covered leases, a standardized fee schedule for administrative fees assessed to operators of covered marinas, applicable to all Corps of Engineers districts, that specifies under what circumstances and at what time such a fee is to be assessed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H745956CA70E84D87819AA4FFD0AE1EF7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="HA01ABF62BC0B47E9A4A4F891883DB14C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may assess, for a covered lease—</text><clause id="H82CF13E5C3764F31AC20F3C01D4D5DED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an administrative fee of not more than $50,000 to the operator of a covered marina only for—</text><subclause id="H55BE4C8047134FA9A89CFBCC15DAE540"><enum>(I)</enum><text>activities involving land disturbances that require a major review effort, coordination and concurrence with State agencies, other Federal agencies, or Tribal governments, and review and approval at the headquarters level of the Corps of Engineers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H039DCF62B12D48C49F3741CE6AA6F59B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>activities relating to lease area expansions of 100 acres or more;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H854226B192DC415E81BE6E572E812605"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an administrative fee of not more than $5,000 to the operator of a covered marina only for activities (not involving land disturbances) that require a moderate review effort, which may involve coordination and concurrence with State agencies, other Federal agencies, or Tribal governments; and</text></clause><clause id="HDEC9A07C9B0C4881952E433A2D5D9D20"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an administrative fee of not more than $1,000 to the operator of a covered marina for any other activities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B6716BFBF394E30B1B9892482B92CB2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not assess, for a covered lease, an administrative fee to the operator of a covered marina for a standard lease renewal, an extension of lease terms, or activities relating to lease transfers or sales to an entity other than a covered marina.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H497C78C843C04A69858BC776CD79D6C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall post the fee schedule established under paragraph (1) on a public website of the Corps of Engineers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E9C4E57DF05436EB5EC9F7A74B48D78" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lease periods</header><text>Section 4 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460d">16 U.S.C. 460d</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(which shall be not less than 50 years for an initial lease or for the first renewal after the date of enactment of the <short-title>MARINA Act</short-title> of a lease in effect on such date, and not less than 25 years for any subsequent lease renewal)</quote> after <quote>at water resource development projects for such periods</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA055BB6F9F564A1D9DD46DDF14EDC1E3" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Wage provision</header><text>Except as required by section 6703 of title 41, United States Code, the Secretary may not require, as a condition of a covered lease, the operator of a covered marina to compensate the employees of the operator at a rate higher than the Federal minimum wage established under section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF22C67C03DE541F99F1213F346EBFD65" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue a final rule to carry out this section and the amendment made by this section, which final rule shall take effect not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAF0E15102A9942C4930AA490B8B698FE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect on existing leases</header><text>Nothing in this section authorizes the Secretary to modify a lease in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, except as necessary to implement the requirements of this section and the amendment made by this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA672E84AE9004CC69746BB8581F72404"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9486A54C438242CCA5AE8BC1E4546309" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Combined covered receipts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>combined covered receipts</term> means the combined receipts, from business operations conducted at a covered marina, of the operator of the covered marina and all entities operating pursuant to a contract with such operator, from prepared food, beverages, fuel, boats, and expensive, boat-related items, such as boat motors and boat lifts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61B7B0B63E3A4F3C9AB86FAE5260F128" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered lease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered lease</term> means a lease for commercial concession purposes under section 4 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460d">16 U.S.C. 460d</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H901971D200FB4322B5AA65237E2AEB76" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered marina</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered marina</term> means a marina operating pursuant to a covered lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H892CE677FD1A4DC681A8F621DC21BE33"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revised Graduated Rental System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Revised Graduated Rental System</term> means the Revised Graduated Rental System established in Engineer Regulation 405–1–12, or any successor rental system used by the Secretary for purposes of calculating rental amounts for covered leases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD4A4FDB309142FB8E686FC3302A2BC7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

