<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-ROM26015-CVW-NR-XGR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 580 ATS: Directing the Architect of the Capitol to prominently display, in a publicly accessible location in the Senate wing of the United States Capitol, a plaque honoring the members of law enforcement responding on January 6, 2021, until the plaque can be placed in its permanent location.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 580</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108" legis-day="20260107">January 8 (legislative day, January 7), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Directing the Architect of the Capitol to prominently display, in a publicly accessible location in the Senate wing of the United States Capitol, a plaque honoring the members of law enforcement responding on January 6, 2021, until the plaque can be placed in its permanent location.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States owes its deepest gratitude to those officers of the United States Capitol Police and the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, as well as officers from other Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies and protective entities, who valiantly protected the United States Capitol, Members of Congress, and staff on January 6, 2021;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas section 214 of division I of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2131">2 U.S.C. 2131</external-xref> note prec.; 136 Stat. 527) directed that a plaque be placed on the western front of the United States Capitol to honor the extraordinary individuals who bravely protected and defended this symbol of democracy on January 6, 2021; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas their heroism should never be forgotten: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Architect of the Capitol shall prominently display the plaque produced pursuant to section 214 of division I of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2131">2 U.S.C. 2131</external-xref> note prec.; 136 Stat. 527) in a publicly accessible location in the Senate wing of the United States Capitol until such time as the plaque can be placed at a permanent location on the western front of the United States Capitol.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

