<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09D16DF3A2944C788C523E9EB5629DFA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6571 IH: Responsible and Ethical AI Labeling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require disclosure of the use of content by Federal officials that is created or manipulated using generative artificial intelligence in their publications, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HED9DB85C87C34A53AB896F412CC0383F" style="OLC"><section id="H713AFC8B6C56467E9A08018AEA17ABEF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Responsible and Ethical AI Labeling Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REAL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4D5B36D9F03941DF8730B9F1507D5E74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure of content created or manipulated using generative artificial intelligence</header><subsection id="HB5710EABBFB848C0981670EECC1589A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure requirement</header><paragraph id="H048BA12E2DF04D27A4819D211B077CD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on Non-Disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal official may not publish, disseminate, or otherwise release content created or manipulated using generative artificial intelligence unless such content includes a disclaimer described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC02521C60B6D44ACA24F158A0B9FA3BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclaimer requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The disclaimer described in this paragraph—</text><subparagraph id="H0B513313C80745798FE3D6D074E62584"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>is clear, conspicuous, and prominently displayed or communicated with the content;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2919EC1164454FCEB87E7EDBC8D08149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is written in plain language that is easily understandable to the general public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7E8618772F842579DED014C749A0135"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes the following:</text><clause id="H488BF89B18454E538E9E5B8F145F1B34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A statement that informs the reader the content was created or manipulated using generative artificial intelligence.</text></clause><clause id="H7127DA00D6C54D8DA32597DFBC13E6E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A brief explanation of how the content was generated or altered.</text></clause><clause id="HCBF9F7A936584A088D721B5721CEBE24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A brief explanation of the technology or method used to create or manipulate the content.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C3EE82C23B74675B5F57CA9D78722BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>This subsection does not apply to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8BF8BB306125485C958E6E0BD1BA0088"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any communication not intended for public release.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13D6A2D4C7F54DBB8198E7BA5976EE52" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Content created for any classified purpose, if a summary or description of the content that complies with this section is retained by the publishing agency to accompany any unclassified publication of the content.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EBAD1A372DC45A0996A97F8CF1F0F9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Content that includes any basic graphic or visual element, such as a text overlay, formatting, or other minor adjustment to visual media (such as brightness, contrast, or cropping) that does not materially alter the meaning or context of the content and the content does not otherwise contain content created or manipulated using generative artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A2E7B92EFD247B2954C9AE873990746"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any routine textual draft or other text-based document prepared using a digital tool, including text drafting software enabled by generative artificial intelligence, if such tool is used to enhance efficiency and the draft or document is reviewed by agency staff prior to publication.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEB2DA94F29E4BF59FA27F4F0E2AD3C6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any content published, disseminated, or otherwise released by a Federal official, if such content is—</text><clause id="HAFA3F4859089417BB47C6C8691CA2F0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not related to the official duties of the officer or employee; and</text></clause><clause id="H23DA4D20A5824F148A1A84FB3C5A0479"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is so published, disseminated, or otherwise released on a personal, non-Government social media account or other medium.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22D9D89880BC4EE49890F886F938C51E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation and enforcement</header><paragraph id="H07CBBDE6B2294483A6177E5F344720FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall issue regulations or policies—</text><subparagraph id="H556EAFB7788848BE8ACC9747994B3570"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with this section by Federal officials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02FC16BAD1B74764A5CD7ED6BE05739C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that establish specific guidelines for the formatting, placement, and wording of the disclaimer described in subsection (a)(2) across various media formats.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B658F96B9B24758B0D66418925BE032"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audits and Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President, Vice President, and the head of each agency shall submit to Congress and make available on, with respect to the President or Vice President, a public website of the White House, and with respect to an agency, the public website of the agency, an audit that describes compliance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4087857AFE5C49DEADD777B5547EC93F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Correction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President, Vice President, or the head of the agency, or the Comptroller General, determines that the President, Vice President, or any officer or employee of an agency has published content created or manipulated using generative artificial intelligence in violation of this section, the President, Vice President, or the head of the agency (as the case may be) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HA12088EEA4C8438780044DE514048842" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the greatest extent possible, retract such content; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2A22E22CB3140C2A3F0EDF11C69F6BA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue a communication that includes—</text><clause id="H54E0D0112487454CB0B31C8D4C64D379" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a statement that indicates the content was issued in violation this section;</text></clause><clause id="HB03A9387E31147CBA9B20CD35DE8F7F7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of factors that led to the publication of the content; and</text></clause><clause id="H5A89E8C710E64850B31F5784B66FC7DB" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if appropriate, a version of the content that has been revised to be in compliance with this section, which shall be made publicly available on the applicable website and disseminated, to the extent possible, to the same audience as the initial content.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA49FC9676954C49887835DB41EABFE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><paragraph id="H24013E4A6B264F7C9DF94DD768E20FA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Compliance</header><subparagraph id="H6B1F40D78B684B6AB097C8E33CFE098D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Corrective action plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which an individual is found by the Comptroller General or an Inspector General to be in violation of this section, the President, Vice President, or head of that agency (as the case may be) shall submit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and Congress a plan that outlines the corrective action that will be taken to ensure compliance with this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0BD2107D20B4FD8B68BAEA9A643101D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a plan is not submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A), or a Federal official does not comply with such plan or is in violation of this section after implementation of such plan, the Comptroller General shall review the internal controls and procedures of the President, Vice President, or applicable agency and, not later than 30 days after the date of the violation, issue corrective actions that shall be carried out not later than 30 days after the date of issuance of such corrective actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE29AA122B24C4065858B68FFFF029F4F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accountability</header><subparagraph id="H14235684B9B64047A021FF9541A5CCAB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal official who violates this section may be subject to appropriate disciplinary action, including disciplinary action under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H129224431BF64A0EA1F573E06D08BBAE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal contractor responsible for non-compliance with this section may face disciplinary action, including restriction on public-facing communication, contract termination, or other corrective action, as determined necessary by the head of the contracting agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2771E810B84A4423977EC262620414C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H18ACF669A4C1405AA88BCCB73339FF6B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, and includes the Executive Office of the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BAC63DCC7234F8B8BB75F5646A7B3E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal official</header><text>The term <quote>Federal official</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H001993700F194EA38B1DB2675C4EDECA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President and the Vice President; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H953D82E6DADF4101A27864714788C897"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any officer or employee of an agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA120E04D1ECA4DF2B3BA9FD9998DA109"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Generative artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>generative artificial intelligence</term> means any algorithmic system that uses parameters derived from previously observed or generated data to non-deterministically create or modify digital content, including text, image, video, sound, or any combination thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70BBCB04DC024C7CA982C0ECB35DCD5E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

