<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25H21-Y84-SD-CVL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3445 IS: To require the provision of alternative drinking water to households whose private drinking water is contaminated with perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances from activities of the Department of Defense.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3445</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the provision of alternative drinking water to households whose private drinking water is contaminated with perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances from activities of the Department of Defense.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="HD6FFB3AA2445422F8CA8128C2D276D50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Provision of alternative drinking water to households whose private drinking water is contaminated with perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances from Department of Defense activities</header><subsection id="H5A9CC9A1CBDC484E83980067B52AFEB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall offer alternative drinking water to a household if—</text><paragraph id="H300D5957789D48CE9AACCD1770FBC7DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the household is downgradient from a military installation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H067AD402CA9340FDBBA76B9C54B1718A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the household receives water from one or more private drinking water wells where contamination from detections of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances resulting solely from activities of the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary, carried out at such military installation has, at one point in time, exceeded the maximum contaminant level for such substances established by the Environmental Protection Agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9AFE016E22544668F81193E8847506E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as of the date of the enactment of this Act, another household located in the same community was eligible for alternative drinking water provided by the Secretary by reason of contamination from detections of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances resulting from activities of the Department carried out at the same military installation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63CBF4B6A6BA4FA49A1C206D7B2B4CA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with other authorities</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this section in a manner that is consistent with the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) and the authorities of the Secretary under environmental law, including by prioritizing and coordinating the efforts of the Secretary under subsection (a) with other efforts to address releases of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0860F1F2354648D4991C1E23EFA18B6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary is not required to offer or provide alternative drinking water to a household under subsection (a) if—</text><paragraph id="H76C25CCA55CA42BA8C46360F676B1C1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the household is part of a community, as determined by the Secretary, where all the households in the community that have been affected by contamination from detections of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances resulting from activities of the Department have been connected to a municipal drinking water distribution system; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81FC8623CAC04E178EAA346352ABF643"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary has otherwise taken action under the Comprehensive, Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) to reduce drinking water exposures, including by meeting the relevant Federal or State drinking water standards for perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD46F0A739F2842D190E27EF04214E3E5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H89A4D87CF5EB418BB4B318A71D63C4AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>alternative drinking water</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H554E766B28E4448FAF0BB8E0271F2879"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provision of bottled water;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91E66B7E0CB747A887CAA03CD5BD908D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>connection to public water systems for members of the public using private wells; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED2A9209B81C4B0B95CCDEABA276B2B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provision of filtration systems for private residences.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02D89607B39442B58638451DE3ECC2B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Federal drinking water standard</term> means an enforceable Federal standard for drinking water, as described in section 121(d)(2)(A)(i) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9621">42 U.S.C. 9621(d)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H435AD3308C4245B08A83EA13E7AD8491"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The terms <term>maximum contaminant level</term> and <term>public water system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0A80480B12F42349880F067564A3BAF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>private drinking water well</term> means a drinking water well that is not a public water system and is not connected to a public water system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECCBC5D957E047CDAA3C9AB33C65F47E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>State drinking water standard</term> means an enforceable State standard, in effect in that State, for drinking water, as described in section 121(d)(2)(A)(ii) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9621">42 U.S.C. 9621(d)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

