<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HF0E9D4233EC048BBBF7462A9BD52A482" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6916 : Federal Program Integrity and Fraud Prevention Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6916</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to prohibit Federal Funds from being provided to individuals convicted of certain Federal felonies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF400A00FD39A4457800B636E0C2C22BD" style="OLC"><section id="HE324C99D7EEC456C827262B808508BE6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Program Integrity and Fraud Prevention Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6CCA915910C34EDA9F94BA071BF0A63B" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal Funds from being provided to individuals convicted of certain Federal felonies</header><subsection id="HEA3A67A0275B4A618FDE9E3BC70D0C2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H96C3635C5FC140FCBFAB4A4D68083B9D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HFBE5C9C9864E463B907E15DE0F882CF4"><enum>3337.</enum><header>Prohibiting Federal Funds from being provided to individuals convicted of certain Federal felonies.</header><subsection id="H4667BC0B54E349158F0BA294025D334B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="HEF6454C9D20242BE88BF44CF02DB05A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency may not enter into, renew, or extend a Federal contract, or provide a grant or other Federal financial assistance to, an individual convicted of a covered felony arising out of any Federal contract, grant, cooperative agreement, loan, or other financial assistance, or to an entity of which such individual is a beneficial owner, during the three year period following the date of the conviction. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AED77348F064CFC94D585B2F55F444E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to an individual convicted after the date of the enactment of this section. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53E919D0561A46589A37F675DDF1277E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="HB08865658EA24266B79EA67B27EDC6BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The head of an agency may waive on a case-by-case basis the prohibition under subsection (a) with respect to an individual or entity described under such subsection if the head of the agency determines such waiver is justifiable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2323CE7A1394A9ABC236B3CAA816DC4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Written Congressional notification of waiver</header><text>Immediately after making a determination to issue a waiver under paragraph (1), the head of an agency shall provide to Congress a written notification of such determination that includes the justification for the waiver. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C5C511EFF464EAF82C14F741179A666"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each individual convicted of a covered felony arising out of any Federal contract, grant, cooperative agreement, loan, or other financial assistance—</text><paragraph id="HB355BBFCF407404CBA9572B495D9F310"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall notify the Administrator of General Services in a timely manner of such conviction; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43DE0D369F984C43AC6314C6B6D438B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Administrator shall promptly update the System for Award Management Exclusions list described in part 9 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, and part 180 of title 2 of such Code, or any successor regulation, to include such individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91AF7BC2F8F4466CAF0BA28F5CA8E3FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall issue guidance for the implementation of, and compliance with, the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1EAA377AD484F10AC6B60C371FEFC52"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal acquisition regulation</header><text>The Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be revised as necessary to implement the provisions of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE4516FA3576C49098CDF5C347D2DE8E5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="H55FF97B115A04BCE8A59ED7DFC3B32D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal interests</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit an agency from seeking or taking any other available criminal, civil, or administrative action to protect Federal Government interests, including the proposal or implementation of suspension or debarment actions pursuant to subpart 9.4 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, and part 180 of title 2 of such Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA171807216E24E5DBB2AE5FC8E20188C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Nothing in subsection (b) may be construed to affect any other statutory or regulatory waiver authority related to an exclusion. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05CB64D456424C1BA5F3D3C045608C39"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE8E2A2C7E4C444D78A418C2197436E91" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0DE372919D134AE384FA53A351B699E0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an Executive department (as defined under section 101 of title 5);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CDF542F60FD4AFFAEF0B8DDD558F9F8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a military department (as defined under section 102 of title 5);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2214134EE6F4384B8CD8B0071B8DAB3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Government corporation (as defined under section 103 of title 5); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BE75172701A48F09E477FC8BE4461EC" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an independent establishment (as defined under section 104(1) of title 5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08B374F1468A4B3FAEC65092B76ABE18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Beneficial owner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>beneficial owner</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H1C683DD4FBF74477B03C07D6B831D454"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means, with respect to an entity, an individual who, directly or indirectly, through any contract, arrangement, understanding, relationship, or otherwise—</text><clause id="H1E5B06729B54453C94BDA6D87AC9CDAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exercises substantial control over the entity; or</text></clause><clause id="H3FD540C29FFD4C24AC5B1AC3B3808E3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>owns or controls not less than 25 percent of the ownership interests of the entity; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF50D3072B4DF4A57B3697E4D0D285A20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="H561D57BF992241B98FAF9A9D8A8A4A63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a minor child, as defined in the jurisdiction in which the entity is formed, if the information of the parent or guardian of the minor child is reported in accordance with this section;</text></clause><clause id="H60CFD21D651C4FFDB434DE3747F967F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual acting as a nominee, intermediary, custodian, or agent on behalf of another individual;</text></clause><clause id="HBDB3CB6E796B433086212EA6ACF8C75F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an individual acting solely as an employee of a corporation, limited liability company, or other similar entity and whose control over or economic benefits from such entity is derived solely from the employment status of the person;</text></clause><clause id="H2535BEAF9C7146109053A083578645A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an individual whose only interest in a corporation, limited liability company, or other similar entity is through a right of inheritance; or</text></clause><clause id="H2175FEE8B6724FE8AB634BE322C188CE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a creditor of a corporation, limited liability company, or other similar entity, unless the creditor meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91A8FC98E8BD4589A3533E64E462D247"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Convicted</header><text>The term <term>convicted</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1BBB8E90D4594A09ABFD05D72162F40A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A judgment of conviction has been entered against the individual by a Federal court, except for any individual whose conviction has been reversed or vacated. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F3017C429674DF2B9ED3C6F7654D4BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plea of guilty or nolo contendere by the individual has been accepted by a Federal court, except for any case in which the conviction entered as result of such plea has been reversed or vacated. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DF08D145A8041E4A8F04C068831187D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The individual has entered into a first offender, deferred adjudication, deferred prosecution, or other arrangement or program in which the individual admitted guilt or responsibility to the underlying offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F18F22A125499A8C7A52FA89B67BCE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered felony</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered felony</term> means a felony described under section 286, 287, 371, 508, 641, 666, 1001, 1002, 1014, 1017, 1028, 1028A, 1030, 1031, 1040(a)(2), 1341, 1342, 1343, 1344, 1345, 1349, 1956, or 1957 of title 18 or section 16 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/645">15 U.S.C. 645</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H51D6B4CBCDBE48C1838DDA13578D5A1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HE280577455E547D991F48CFC57F454F9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">3337. Prohibiting Federal funds from being provided to individuals convicted of certain Federal felonies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260608" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 8, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

