<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF0E9D4233EC048BBBF7462A9BD52A482" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6916 IH: Federal Program Integrity and Fraud Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6916</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251219">December 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 41, United States Code, to identify individuals who commit certain Federal felonies implicating Federal programs as an excluded source on the System for Award Management Exclusions list, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF400A00FD39A4457800B636E0C2C22BD" style="OLC"><section id="H33D07A4EE7464FCE84B56A3EDD2525A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Program Integrity and Fraud Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H87A248D837184580ACBC4219813953B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusion of Felony Fraud Convicts to Protect Federal Funds</header><subsection id="HA99C722607EB484C99C93C054D3FEA41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procurement integrity</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/47">Chapter 47</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H8C56C6A602D04A159E33EE9E2509CD59" style="USC"><section id="HA4B16F1FB4BB4ACB8FAF34D93335F7D5"><enum>4715.</enum><header>Protecting Federal funds from individuals convicted of certain Federal felonies</header><subsection id="H2914C09101174710922DC6B369404C3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H946F8A2D26A44660A72B092182CA9C66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), an individual who is convicted of a covered felony arising out of any agency contract, grant, cooperative agreement, loan, or other financial assistance shall be identified as an excluded source on the System for Award Management Exclusions list described in part 9 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, and part 180 of title 2 of such Code, or successor regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3AA312B005B47A2A02F9A8C017BCB6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification of conviction</header><text>For each individual convicted of a covered felony, the Attorney General shall notify the Administrator of General Services in a timely manner of such conviction and the Administrator shall promptly enter the 3-year prohibition for such person into the System for Award Management, or any successor system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1039FC2B2D4941789E808E81B1256611"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), the agency head may exempt an individual described in subsection (a)(1) from the prohibition under such subsection for a case in which the agency head determines in writing that the exemption is warranted. The agency head shall transmit a copy of each such written exemption to Congress immediately after making such determination.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF41FAF2E2DE342B9AC728DD6215AD5ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H6A9CD9E9E59D4F44BD6D15D783686E98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> means an Executive department (as defined under section 101 of title 5), a military department (as defined under section 102 of title 5), a Government corporation (as defined under section 103 of title 5), and an independent establishment (as defined under section 104(1) of title 5).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE987BA6F5EA430F89AC09ED0627FC2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Convicted</header><text>The term <term>convicted</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H58F834D1A2294885B6C5C5B2BF80E88A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a judgment of conviction has been entered against the individual by a Federal court;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22B6FC9C1BCB4C67BF59C56C7C3ECFD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there has been a finding of guilt against the individual by a Federal court;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H350D291C29A74B8FB9B0B35811CC792A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plea of guilty or nolo contendere by the individual has been accepted by a Federal court; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1E8F1A29340412B98D23690B5FF91D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the individual has entered into a first offender, deferred adjudication, deferred prosecution, or other arrangement or program in which judgment or conviction has been withheld.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88FA0856A361481EA2088B8AF766C752"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered felony</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered felony</term> means a felony described under section 286, 287, 371, 641, 666, 1001, 1014, 1017, 1028, 1028A, 1030, 1031, 1040(a)(2), 1341, 1343, 1344, 1345, 1349, 1956, and 1957 of title 18 and section 16 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/645">15 U.S.C. 645</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D33B379BCAC4303B084875BD2BE260A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="H80B8B59646614FF095CDC85A9FACF273"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal interests</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit an agency from seeking or taking any other available criminal, civil, or administrative action to protect Federal Government interests, including the proposal or implementation of suspension or debarment actions pursuant to subpart 9.4 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, and part 180 of title 2 of such Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E854BFBD2D94E6687889948B52FC85A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Nothing in subsection (b) may be construed to affect any other statutory or regulatory waiver authority related to an exclusion.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA746EBDD474E4D57A3C1B21820C58CD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/47">chapter 47</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H81FDFD6950EE4BA6A91C543C5AC7BDB4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">4715. Protecting Federal funds from individuals convicted of certain Federal felonies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HA45520073B2243DE8B6254C2281EABB5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, shall issue guidance for the implementation of, and compliance with, the requirements of section 4715 of title 41, United States Code, as added by section 2.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

