<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0A1EAF13A5E24C6C945A06532D852A45" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9771 IH: Stopping Foreign Influence in Elections Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9771</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260718">July 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose penalties on political committees that accept foreign contributions.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H30BD9F9A25374B478BDDCC0E074AF7F3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H92C42285F2254348ADA07E8E94B4B097" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Foreign Influence in Elections Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H4ED399974B1441B6A75D8A68AD6185ED" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Penalties with respect to contributions to political committees from certain tax exempt organizations that accept contributions from foreign nationals</header> 
<subsection id="H0AFFD555E189446F945DA7D9AE6F6405"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part I of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/68">chapter 68</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD0C6B5E27164487984FD1758CD3F497"> <section id="H798F008F16A649A2A04BF963426BA636"><enum>6720D.</enum><header>Contributions to political committees from certain tax exempt organizations that accept contributions from foreign nationals</header> <subsection id="HA89EC06B49F6420A8641F71AA7919AF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any specified tax exempt organization that makes any disqualified political committee contribution shall pay a penalty equal to twice the amount of such contribution.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCEDD7E9292F44B80A2F1C617B0F0F37E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disqualified political committee contribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H197D8A7326904D10BB35C025528E6324" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>disqualified political committee contribution</quote> means, with respect to any organization described in section 501(c), any contribution made by such organization to a political entity if such organization received, during the testing period, any contribution or gift (within the meaning of section 6033(b)(5)) from a foreign national (as defined in section 319(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC674E658FD9847F8B8FE2DA284F12003"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Political entity</header><text>The term <quote>political entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF67DD728B1024C9982C84300E18EBEE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a political committee (as defined in section 301 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971), or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H50F60AA96CD1459C8DE90CA5306FAF0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any organization described in section 501(c)(4) and exempt from taxation under section 501(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1952D458895648A3BC564D76D498010B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Testing period</header><text>The term <quote>testing period</quote> means, with respect to any contribution by an organization described in section 501(c), the 2-year period ending on the date of such contribution, except that such period shall not include any period before the date of the enactment of this section.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE4DBB99E7824D2F846C00AAD70E4C37"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reliance on representation</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), an organization may rely on the representation of a donor as to the nationality of such donor unless such organization knows or should have known that such representation is false.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0E64E5A33DE948BC8496B9FDC15B67C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specified tax exempt organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>specified tax exempt organization</quote> means, with respect to any taxable year, any organization described in section 501(c) which is required to file an annual return under section 6033(a)(1) for such taxable year if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H11BF1422489F488488C92D38ABAF717F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the gross receipts of such organization for the preceding taxable year equal or exceed $200,000, or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FA7F83F481F44C8971ED87560C72C7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the assets of such organization (determined as of the close of such preceding taxable year) equal or exceed $500,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3ABE28A3A604C288B165647501A044F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of organizations making disqualified political committee contribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 501 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FD9BB2D7BAA46F080ABA28E8A9F4816"> <subsection id="H2994DD7F1CFC4B99B5435FFCE237F637" commented="no"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Treatment of organizations making disqualified political committee contributions</header> <paragraph id="H259FA2F703D64E1CB9CF096CED9E00C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any organization described in subsection (c) which makes a disqualified political committee contribution—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAE3252AF9FDF47D1A3FB138E2BCE2133" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if such contribution is the first disqualified political committee contribution made by such organization, there shall be imposed a tax on such organization of an amount equal to 100 percent of such contribution,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE77FBE59AF54A73807F81E50AC5D95E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such contribution is the second disqualified political committee contribution made by such organization, there shall be imposed a tax on such organization of an amount equal to 200 percent of such contribution, or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H33BE23C935B34325B191588B4F3C29DB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if such contribution is any disqualified political committee contribution subsequent to the second disqualified political committee contribution made by such organization—</text> <clause id="H1CD493D81D3646EABEA812F5DAB3C2EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there shall be imposed a tax on such organization of an amount equal to 200 percent of such contribution, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H61A8A4EC21394F668B05A4AE24C969FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such organization shall not be exempt from taxation under subsection (a) during the 2-year period beginning on the date on which such contribution is made.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC97422249C4475388F254038DE1F633"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of application for organizations not making disqualified political committee contributions for 2 years</header><text>In the case of any organization described in subsection (c) which does not make a disqualified political committee contribution during any 2-year period, any determination of the number of such contributions made by such organization for purposes of paragraph (1) shall be made without regard to any contribution made before such 2-year period.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3EB0CD76301450F95E8A7FCC0BA0B1B">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
                            <header>Disqualified political committee contributions</header>
 <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>disqualified political committee contributions</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 6720D(b).</text>
                        </paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72B3BD22CF3944CCACD093AFE7D60362"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part I of subchapter B of chapter 68 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB13721310E574DF8BFCA72F0753DD40B"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section" idref="H798F008F16A649A2A04BF963426BA636">Sec. 6720D. Contributions to political committees from certain tax exempt organizations that accept contributions from foreign nationals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H2EA11D8B85964BFF9EFD62C4B1CAE547"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to contributions made after the date which is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

