<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26314-LPY-86-942"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>100 S3902 IS: Reviewing Every Check and Each Invoice Purchasing Troops’ Supplies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3902</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for auditable financial statements for the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reviewing Every Check and Each Invoice Purchasing Troops’ Supplies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RECEIPTS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id785ae4ccdb35436592e6a7a2c42d335b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id0153ecb647fb4541ae88178d5685bba7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 9 of Article I of the Constitution of the United States requires all agencies of the Federal Government, including the Department of Defense, to publish <quote>a regular Statement and Account of the Receipts and Expenditures of all public Money</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id856ee8aba3564a099cdc713bc6136730"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 3515(a) of title 31, United States Code, requires the agencies of the Federal Government, including the Department of Defense, to present auditable financial statements beginning not later than March 1, 2003. The Department has not complied with this law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcaf0cdc270974148adcdfa44e008db0e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Financial Management Improvement Act of 1996 (title VIII of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3512">31 U.S.C. 3512</external-xref> note) requires financial systems acquired by the Federal Government, including the Department of Defense, to be able to provide information to leaders to manage and control the cost of Government. The Department has not complied with this law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe2d2fdae6a746adb928a69bb6d1c73e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The financial management of the Department of Defense has been on the <quote>High-Risk</quote> list of the Government Accountability Office, which means that the Department is not consistently able to <quote>control costs; ensure basic accountability; anticipate future costs and claims on the budget; measure performance; maintain funds control; [and] prevent and detect fraud, waste, and abuse</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id619d77d24d7d4af68646510bc9fa0788"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2005, the Department of Defense created a Financial Improvement and Audit Readiness (FIAR) Plan, overseen by a directorate within the office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), to improve Department business processes with the goal of producing timely, reliable, and accurate financial information that could generate an audit-ready annual financial statement. In December 2005, that directorate, known as the FIAR Directorate, issued the first of a series of semiannual reports on the status of the Financial Improvement and Audit Readiness Plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d3205271a7f4be2992fb471fcefe408"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 1003 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 2439) required regular status reports on the Financial Improvement and Audit Readiness Plan described in paragraph (5), and codified as a statutory requirement the goal of the Plan in ensuring that Department of Defense financial statements were validated as ready for audit not later than September 30, 2017. In addition, section 1005 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>) required that the statement of budgetary resources of the Department of Defense be validated as ready for audit by not later than September 30, 2014. The Department of Defense did not meet these deadlines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7939bed845e4069b329b6f0182889e2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>At a June 2025 hearing in the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, the Department’s Acting Comptroller committed to audit-ready budget statements for the Department of War by 2028 by stating, <quote>Within the next three years, under the secretary's guidance, the remainder of the department will achieve the clean audit opinion.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idb2d2f86a54994d8ca8323b58047ac860"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhanced reprogramming authority following achievement by Department of Defense and military departments of audit with unqualified opinion of its financial statements for fiscal years after fiscal year 2028</header><subsection id="idf13693f20dc44ddb86dcd08e8adde2b9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Defense generally</header><text>If the Department of Defense obtains an audit with an unqualified opinion on financial statements for any fiscal year after fiscal year 2028, the limitation on the total amount of authorizations that the Secretary of Defense may transfer pursuant to general transfer authority available to the Secretary in the national interest in the succeeding fiscal year shall be the greater of $10,000,000,000 or 1 percent of the total budget authority available to the Department of Defense for that succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="idec00b798aa0443d190b86dcea1993088"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Military departments, defense agencies, and defense field activities</header><text>If a military department, Defense Agency, or Department of Defense Field Activity obtains an audit with an unqualified opinion on its financial statements for any fiscal year after fiscal year 2028, the thresholds for reprogramming of funds of such military department, Defense Agency, or Department of Defense Field Activity, as the case may be, without prior notice to Congress for the succeeding fiscal year shall be deemed to be the thresholds as follows:</text><paragraph id="idf37e2d1fdccb4c848d3a3d1c39348feb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of an increase or decrease to the program base amount for a procurement program, $60,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id54b5913f65c4429f8f1daf177f6bbe4b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of an increase or decrease to the program base amount for a research program, $30,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4605d3bab2d84faf88386659d48b4f21"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case of an increase or decrease to the amount for a budget activity for operation and maintenance, $45,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe7fc6a5340241fb821a84aa614b1998"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the case of an increase or decrease to the amount for a budget activity for military personnel, $30,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id02ac95dbfe7549d98af070d42aaab025"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or revise any requirement (other than a threshold amount) for notice to Congress on transfers covered by subsection (a) or reprogrammings covered by subsection (b) under any other provision of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0f472e216d7e41c484e3a767f33ade37"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>program base amount</term>, <term>procurement program</term>, <term>research program</term>, and <term>budget activity</term> have the meanings given such terms in chapter 6 of volume 3 of the Financial Management Regulation of the Department of Defense (DoD 7000.14R), dated March 2011, or any successor regulation.</text></subsection></section><section id="id68861c46c02e4f09b50b3397b2bc4fdd"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cessation of applicability of reporting requirements regarding the financial statements of the Department of Defense after obtaining a clean audit opinion</header><subsection id="id84a0a3bda5234b3ca2e0d042c8da118d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cessation of applicability</header><paragraph id="ide5c913df37dd41c798b3c4cd0b7ec971"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Military departments</header><text>The financial statements of a military department shall cease to be covered by the reporting requirements specified in subsection (b) upon the issuance of an unqualified audit opinion on such financial statements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d35c7bf6b594bd1919031d37b39b3b3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Defense</header><text>The reporting requirements specified in subsection (b) shall cease to be effective when an unqualified audit opinion is issued on the financial statements of the Department of Defense, including each of the military departments and the other reporting entities defined by the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id638a9f46ff124f5d8612dae73653cbf1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>The reporting requirements specified in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="iddb346607acc5447e98b2c01269670bbf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The requirement for annual reports in section 892(b) of the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/383">Public Law 111–383</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 4311).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25bd0fed258c46519bd6a8a10029318f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The requirement for semi-annual reports in section 1003(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 2440).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id347178206e29411193f8add9273599aa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The requirement for annual reports in section 817(d) of the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/314">Public Law 107–314</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 2610).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c15003683f54fe69b4d8cbe859213f5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The requirement for periodic reports in section 908(b) of the Defense Acquisition Improvement Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/500">Public Law 99–500</external-xref>; 100 Stat. 1783–140; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2326">10 U.S.C. 2326</external-xref> note) and duplicate requirements as provided for in section 6 of the Defense Technical Corrections Act of 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/26">Public Law 100–26</external-xref>; 101 Stat. 274; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2302">10 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide94f9e71e95249688ea5a92dc61d28c6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Additional duties and qualifications for failure to obtain audits with unqualified opinion of fiscal year 2028 financial statements of the Department of Defense</header><subsection id="id22009629996d411eaadbf6138ac55424"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Department of Defense fails to obtain an audit with an unqualified opinion on its financial statements for fiscal year 2028 by December 31, 2028, the following shall take effect on January 1, 2029:</text><paragraph id="id468282473e824f6bbf2791a1ad582d2f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional qualifications and duties of USD (Comptroller)</header><subparagraph id="id4206060b28534bfd8fe5ad52aadf9809"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Any individual nominated for appointment to the position of Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) under section 135 of title 10, United States Code, shall be an individual who is a Certified Public Accountant (CPA) and has served—</text><clause id="id3985d29fef1d4ae080dbdef573921402"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a Federal or State agency that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such agency's financial statements during the time of such individual's service; or</text></clause><clause id="id8367f737a24f416d89aee823d2e64b28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a public company that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such company's financial statements during the time of such individual's service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0c95ba5f41d4e4993ef38fcaf69811f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties and powers</header><text>The duties and powers of the individual serving as Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) shall include, in addition to the duties and powers specified in section 135(c) of title 10, United States Code, such duties and powers with respect to the financial management of the Department of Defense as the Deputy Secretary of Defense (acting in the capacity of Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense) or a successor official in the Department of Defense (acting in such capacity) may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id28aebd780a37416ca9dbfc19c4117a12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional qualifications and responsibilities of ASA for Financial Management</header><subparagraph id="idf6cfe5078858425b9e9debfd135fa5ef"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Any individual nominated for appointment to the position of Assistant Secretary of the Army for Financial Management under section 7016 of title 10, United States Code, shall be an individual who is a Certified Public Accountant (CPA) and who has served—</text><clause id="id9264cbd6f8814412923f85e8e2f20b75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a Federal or State agency that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such agency's financial statements during the time of such individual's service; or</text></clause><clause id="id0c0bb330292e468eaa3e970e20041a33"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a public company that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such company's financial statements during the time of such individual's service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf51e95e250f84ffba08a54ce72bfb3f0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of the individual serving as Assistant Secretary of the Army for Financial Management shall include, in addition to the responsibilities specified in section 7016(b)(4) of title 10, United States Code, such responsibilities as the Deputy Secretary of Defense (acting in the capacity of Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense) or a successor official in the Department of Defense (acting in such capacity) may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id35d0f90631b745bd89eec2b7ca215f37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional qualifications and responsibilities of ASN for Financial Management</header><subparagraph id="id4214fd4b0cee4ee6849129fda128c819"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Any individual nominated for appointment to the position of Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Financial Management under section 8016 of title 10, United States Code, shall be an individual who is a Certified Public Accountant (CPA) and who has served—</text><clause id="id0a0724b5b62e4ae09c0859af1bda6420"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a Federal or State agency that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such agency's financial statements during the time of such individual's service; or</text></clause><clause id="ida785abc65c6a467b9da5f8e779c608d4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a public company that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such company's financial statements during the time of such individual's service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0892ed5510964b35a0006109cfbb9221"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of the individual serving as Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Financial Management shall include, in addition to the responsibilities specified in section 8016(b)(4) of title 10, United States Code, such responsibilities as the Deputy Secretary of Defense (acting in the capacity of Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense) or a successor official in the Department of Defense (acting in such capacity) may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide75f367d39f54a549d74c6eeddad5c28"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional qualifications and responsibilities of ASAF for Financial Management</header><subparagraph id="id1ee164a566cf4c6e8249e553f2090065"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Any individual nominated for appointment to the position of Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Financial Management under section 9016 of title 10, United States Code, shall be an individual who is a Certified Public Accountant (CPA) and who has served—</text><clause id="id144568332dc5408a94242982ee98b42d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a Federal or State agency that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such agency's financial statements during the time of such individual's service; or</text></clause><clause id="idd1364dcb554b4d6d848c99f91be101b2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as the chief financial officer or equivalent position of a public company that has received an audit with an unqualified opinion on such company's financial statements during the time of such individual's service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id64581d4ad8f540f59a47535b9c949994"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of the individual serving as Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Financial Management shall include, in addition to the responsibilities specified in section 9016(b)(4) of title 10, United States Code, such responsibilities as the Deputy Secretary of Defense (acting in the capacity of Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense) or a successor official in the Department of Defense (acting in such capacity) may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb6b42b6da19f4f6c81afcb5fca45ac11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public company defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>public company</term> has the meaning given the term <term>issuer</term> in section 2(a)(7) of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7201">15 U.S.C. 7201(7)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="id690adf4f58804d3e8a21ea9365e619f8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Requiring the Secretary of Defense to transfer non-defense operations of the Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) after failure to obtain audits with unqualified opinion of fiscal year 2028 financial statements of the Department of Defense</header><subsection id="id4563b243b74f496aa35a3c00f32d0eed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Department of Defense fails to obtain an audit with an unqualified opinion on its financial statements for fiscal year 2028 by December 31, 2028, the Secretary of Defense shall, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), transfer the non-defense payroll and finance services performed by Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) to another payroll and finance service in the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="idaff56629dcce403c89682c637f05e5bb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <term>non-defense payroll and finance services</term>—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e132cf8f7f44ae787f38dfc7b5b9067"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refers to services DFAS provides for other Federal agencies other than the Department of Defense, including the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf602fc7f4c8c47b3935da45e657ddf2e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not refer to any payroll and finance services provided for military retirees, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or the Executive Office of the President.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id35a44c16cc7c415ebef0fe8d832a6f46"><enum>7.</enum><header>Change in mission statement for DFAS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall direct DFAS to amend its mission statement and vision to incorporate the following principles:</text><paragraph id="id9d190c8c9793482d91b95aeeb1b8e885"><enum>(1)</enum><text>DFAS is a critical part of the United States military’s financial management and accounting team and is not solely providing a pay and finance service to the military services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6a8c00fb9084c8c83c7f38a493547c6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>DFAS is jointly responsible with the military services for—</text><subparagraph id="idf027108f39e24688959e5979cca553a4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accounting for military spending by accurately and timely recording, analyzing, summarizing, and classifying military service financial transactions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id188f9c4dfbf14db59643755d6fc4c83d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring military service financial transactions are recorded in the military services’ financial statements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id411532fcf32744bda1f2ec998c5f31c2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>achieving an unqualified audit opinion for the Department of Defense’s financial statements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id06f6327ef0614ebdb361cfb4d9bf3051"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization for artificial intelligence, including agentic artificial intelligence, to obtain audits with unqualified opinion of fiscal year 2028 financial statements of the Department of Defense</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98d55091c7d34aec8e03561412ed2153"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Department of Defense should, to the maximum extent practicable, utilize technology and software to automate its efforts to prepare and audit its financial statements and minimize the use of additional contractor personnel for this function.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa2a939f1afd43b7bcd67e77dcbe7fad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense the following sums:</text><paragraph id="id72a662ab67d243669e6265817a543a14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$150,000,000 for the deployment of automation and artificial intelligence to accelerate the audits of the financial statement of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35c1ba9a536e456cae8981c7a86d4c7b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$150,000,000 for business systems replacements to accelerate and improve the accuracy of the financial statements of the Department of Defense pursuant to chapter 9A and section 2222 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide4ef075dc0f34b28974ea94c92756dd4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Offset required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall terminate for convenience existing contracts for contractor support for consulting services regarding the audit and preparation of financial statements in amounts equal to amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="ida37fb461c1e24a04b47f54326eb420e6"><enum>9.</enum><header>Establishment of Department of Defense Audit Committee and amendment of Department of Defense Inspector General role in audit of financial statements</header><subsection id="id785b3ab3df184f4381933a0025c5d78c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a committee to be known as the Audit Committee to select and oversee the audit of the financial statements of the Department as performed by an independent external auditor.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcf809ba50716440fbd24ebf81d43e14b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Audit Committee shall be composed of the following members:</text><paragraph id="id65845b0fdc254a88a7ddb9bf84cdca74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Deputy Secretary of Defense, who shall serve as the Chairman of the Audit Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18c053eee1934f42987ff4d27569404d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2b87bb4c6314e98909825d03aa6bf90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Deputy Inspector General (Audit) of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idede182af940c4c7fbcbd064858018e82" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An individual appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id440dbaee838145448c626595356623a7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An individual appointed by the Ranking Member of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ce16188c4584d909f1191b77b761225"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An individual appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb91a6cbe59924dbb9488f08a03882ec1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An individual appointed by the Ranking Member of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91d62bd6514140efa112e0c1baf9dca3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An individual appointed by the Secretary of Defense from the Defense Business Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id16952c0fe4d945a3a44437ba545112ef"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Excluded individuals</header><text>The Audit Committee shall not include the following individuals currently serving in the following roles:</text><paragraph id="id747161b97e1447be9ff79fe56f3b8543"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller)/Chief Financial Officer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a166d92e21c4970964f5448226b631e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Deputy Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1401ddab854346aba9241786b627ac97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Director, Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida8ff0d956b234a04ade4190580cb2176"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Audit Committee appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives shall be appointed to the Commission from among individuals who are Certified Public Accountants (CPAs) and who have demonstrated knowledge and experience in the audit of Federal agency financial statements.</text></subsection><subsection id="id41627b768f9247bdba60fefe98f3b7f2" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Audits by agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3521(a) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d6c9caf27d746ec91b091f8f22ccbcb"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(a)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53a742994f6047c1a7e7e4b413b98754"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="id9B5280FF95E54D8D8A448716B224F0FD" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph indent="up1" id="idF6DC191446CE4BCEA9FB08D93271F705"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The audit required under paragraph (1) for the Department of Defense shall be performed by an independent external auditor.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

