<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H33A05548AC0C4981BD30E4DCD3255B33" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>110 HR 6568 IH: Lower Yellowstone River Native Fish Conservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6568</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reaffirm that the Bureau of Reclamation retains exclusive ownership, operational control, and financial responsibility for the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel, ensuring long-term conservation of the endangered pallid sturgeon and other native aquatic species in the Yellowstone River while protecting the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project and District from undue financial and operational burdens, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC16807FA08FD445283EABE3D9A7E24F4" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HAF1B866AE4F4443F8A6C91B4E808B3E5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lower Yellowstone River Native Fish Conservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9E725097A7244149B81A8ED9BD1AAD64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HE382C37CABA140AA90667758D5056314"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel—</text><subparagraph id="HA9C4E07D29684C19BC3B2EAD27C22837"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was authorized under section 3109 of the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/114">Public Law 110–114</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 1135) as a Federal mitigation measure for impacts on the pallid sturgeon (Scaphirhynchus albus) under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CC32A3561CE44608EB858AC5A97D3D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was designed and constructed by the Corps of Engineers and the Bureau of Reclamation using funds from the Missouri River Recovery Program and other Federal appropriations specifically allocated for ecosystem restoration and endangered species mitigation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AA75B0A45F040D6BB9649CD0719610E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is located outside the physical and operational boundaries of the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project and the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2357B903BFB648588C3B146EFBF86738"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau of Reclamation retains sole ownership, operational jurisdiction, and maintenance responsibilities for the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel and related infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02501FDCDBBF480284647E68770A3AB3"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project was federally authorized in 1904 under the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093), to provide irrigation water to agricultural land in eastern Montana and western North Dakota;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD95E0CB089284DBCB806F346DE259181"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, established under Montana and North Dakota State laws, has never had ownership, operational responsibility, or maintenance obligations relating to the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel;</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF804CA2CDB2849389E293BBDC4C7B1FE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) mandates Federal protection and recovery actions for listed species, including the pallid sturgeon (Scaphirhynchus albus);</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H97E28E7975C14921B3B51FB7109C40E0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">endangered species recovery, including construction of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel, is solely a Federal responsibility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFFA3474D544EEBAA0308DF6C0F0F22"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Bureau of Reclamation opted to construct the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel to comply with the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) because the Intake Diversion Dam is federally owned and operated, rather than owned or operated by the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project;</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC856F88300B84AB69FD5260B94F2480D"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project cannot and should not be burdened with financial or operational responsibility for a federally mandated environmental mitigation project;</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09A7B28FA008458E8A6E2A786E8BD238"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel is legally separate and distinct from the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project and the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7726CCC4EE44A70AFE18270B4AC96FD"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without legislative clarity, future administrative actions could inappropriately attempt to shift the burden of operations and maintenance costs of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel onto the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, which is a scenario that contradicts the original intent of the authorization for the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel under the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/114">Public Law 110–114</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 1041).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD1394F78B8E24DA29E3F36DE905EF68E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC536981E68934B74BC8FF3140A8FFC77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel</term> means the 2.1-mile-long engineered fish passage channel constructed near Intake, Montana, designed to facilitate the migration of pallid sturgeon (Scaphirhynchus albus) and other native fish species around the Intake Diversion Dam located near Intake, Montana.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC4D9E56DFC84167AF87C988805ECCEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District</term> means the local, State-chartered water management entity responsible for operating and maintaining the irrigation components of the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H197988BFA6244DD0AD14CCCC55713C67"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project</term> means the Federal irrigation system—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD696660B94BE4F75B897524CDF29E6C3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized in 1904 under the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H958B97A63F644F90A04926DC8A4C44A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operated in partnership with the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District for agricultural water delivery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85572ED6387F48E79669D8D16E5D3231"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Operations and maintenance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>operations and maintenance</term> means all actions, costs, and labor necessary to operate, repair, upgrade, and maintain the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BC06E1518E84EA7B6844967C91CF5E0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA3A8FDAF18C248ADB5089D619F41FFAA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reaffirmation of Federal ownership and responsibility</header><subsection id="HBB9768A8DB484D7CA9D928F801F77B4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sole ownership and control</header><paragraph id="H5D4FE4994D4C473688E56FE08A45CE89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall retain full ownership, operational authority, and financial responsibility for the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel in perpetuity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A53CB1B4AE440A1848800C104B2075D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative actions, agreements, or transfers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No administrative action, agreement, or transfer shall alter, diminish, or delegate to any non-Federal entity, including the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, the responsibilities and authorities described in paragraph (1) with respect to the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H439859D60297496DBE4428C9B63922FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act prevents the Secretary from retaining the authority to enter into agreements with, coordinate, or otherwise work with the head of any other Federal agency, including with respect to funding, planning, or implementation of activities authorized under this Act or any other Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DF9D5A028084078BCA88061EC1A1401"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance obligations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall be solely responsible for funding, operating, and maintaining the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel, including any repairs, modifications, or adaptive management strategies.</text></subsection><subsection id="H632D740B76CD41678262BE3592C7B332"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition of cost transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal agency may impose, mandate, or require the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, or any other non-Federal entity to assume financial or operational responsibility for any aspect of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A5B541D63344F47AFDE220A0CCF3705"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship to the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act alters, amends, or otherwise affects the authorized purposes, water delivery obligations, or operational responsibilities of the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDD5D206A773D4611958D21B2624B1F99"><enum>5.</enum><header>Preservation of Endangered Species Act obligations</header><subsection id="HAF4BD2B06944472D9B3D6927EF32D3B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal responsibility for pallid sturgeon recovery</header><paragraph id="HFF2DD0DF9F14478C802BE4228746F02D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall retain exclusive responsibility for fulfilling obligations relating to the pallid sturgeon (Scaphirhynchus albus) under the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BA7C098C61445F5950B7D9362C0E9CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No obligation on the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District and the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project shall not be required to perform, fund, or participate in any activities mandated under the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) relating to the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel or pallid sturgeon (Scaphirhynchus albus) conservation associated with the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H587719836CBA4C7087763E135BFD14A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with State and Federal Agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate with Montana Fish, Wildlife and Parks, the North Dakota Game and Fish Department, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and other relevant agencies to ensure proper conservation measures for the pallid sturgeon (Scaphirhynchus albus) without burdening private or local irrigation operations.</text></subsection></section><section id="H028DAACA89394B05824091537A21182D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibition of transfer of responsibilities</header><subsection id="HE7F635E9571149EE879E9157B27F8975"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on transfer or delegation</header><paragraph id="H5CD61D6018BA49E99DE89EDF0D1AF67C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not transfer, delegate, or assign any financial, operational, or maintenance responsibilities for the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel to any non-Federal entity, including—</text><subparagraph id="HEFC85E070BCC4B1992E9F9DCF3A96ADF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H388CE3541E98404CB61AC1A956FC23D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE831D9AE4F944A9831F1789D1A7D8CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any State agency, local government, or private entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6455F906C78C4671A37B329EB404989A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No agreement, contract, or memorandum of understanding shall have the effect of transferring to the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, or any other non-Federal entity the ownership of, responsibility for, or cost burden of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9652CBB111A24991A4C88C503B67A60D"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Invalidation of prior attempts To transfer responsibility</header> <paragraph id="H6AC8CD945BDE4D32BB6ADECD06124862"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any prior administrative action, agreement, or cost-sharing arrangement that attempts to impose financial or operational responsibility for the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel on the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project shall be null and void.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFFC25349DA044519833D9104740434D4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Termination of agreements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall terminate any provision of any agreement that is inconsistent with this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section><section id="HBB3ACCC131BD48DD977AD44D13C81DFE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Legal enforcement and judicial review</header><subsection id="HAEB7DDDE978447BCAECA06380EECB803">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Right To petition for Federal compliance</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, and any affected stakeholder may file a complaint in Federal District Court seeking a declaratory judgment or other appropriate relief if the Secretary attempts to transfer to a non-Federal entity operational or financial responsibility for the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H08853EC9A6C84BC88FE89065430FA9F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States District Court for the District of Montana shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute arising under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9988ACC542B459ABC71406F98EB8FD8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No private cause of action against non-Federal entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act creates a private cause of action against the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, or any other non-Federal entity with respect to the operations and maintenance of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDD4AC3E8A6634E2185314BD0446EC7E5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Long-term Federal funding and resource allocation</header><subsection id="HF8E80D7983134273A265F2EA709229FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ongoing Federal responsibility for operations and maintenance</header><paragraph id="H75E2653B3B024785B4979EDC209AFD01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall be the sole entity responsible for operations and maintenance and repairs of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED109762DDA34A1085F010AAB0FF60A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall fund all necessary repairs, modifications, and infrastructure improvements to maintain the effectiveness of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H980A887292B144DB8585D5458AE74B8B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No financial burden</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, and any other non-Federal entity shall not bear any financial burden for maintenance, repairs, or monitoring of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BE983474D65463AAD614DF3D1A46123"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H62C4CE7BC08942839E61E91EBCD56ABF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter—</text><subparagraph id="H8CCE56D3BA1440CB9AD0BE425F8FE207"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure continuous, uninterrupted operation of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA8E2687CBCE4B7286C24B35555D3119"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct necessary engineering evaluations, repairs, and upgrades in the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel as part of an ongoing Federal commitment to the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA455F55C383842BF8DC83854F7CC2D6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement adaptive management strategies in the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel to address environmental, hydrological, and biological changes affecting pallid sturgeon (Scaphirhynchus albus) passage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80EEBCA841004332B0A7FBA95968BC76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C33529CB90848E1BB1A78D12B90A388"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall administer the funds made available under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H623400A6A08D4B429ECE926BA298F4BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not transfer or delegate to any non-Federal entity the funds made available under that paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB59771CBA5A44EC7A0EE39A9AB1BE187"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a biennial report describing—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CDB40752FD04F5D8806939C947D9D6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the operational status of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H707BE010146946DB9D6109862324D0EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any ongoing or anticipated repairs, modifications, or adaptive management actions with respect to the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35FEC25D1891416F843DA1339450D835"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an updated cost analysis of operations and maintenance of the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91DE9010BA6A4B5E84B2D756320C0559"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordination efforts between the Secretary, the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Chief of Engineers, and State agencies with respect to the Lower Yellowstone Fish Bypass Channel.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0ABEE145829F4F47B1FE6169F16F19E3"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text><paragraph id="H8547021A35354B918BD1D50ECD97D15C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifies or diminishes the authorized purposes of the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3C6566A6CB44FF29627605ED0204B9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affects any existing water rights of, or contracts or agreements between, the Secretary and the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District or the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H973723EB3D89471F89E6E6400831778F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imposes any new regulatory obligations, requirements, or liabilities on the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation District, the Lower Yellowstone Irrigation Project, or any other non-Federal entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC656B3AF422D499CA44BD41020A12828"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifies or impairs State water law or any existing agreements relating to water distribution and irrigation operations; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H221ED32C7A0441E6B33858439B5BBD6A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">alters the statutory and regulatory obligations of Federal agencies under the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) or the <act-name parsable-cite="NEPA69">National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

