<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB50002FFCBA945E59A6DF8F8EE8896FC" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1318 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the month of May 2026 as “Progressive Supranuclear Palsy and Corticobasal Degeneration Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1318</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the month of May 2026 as <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy and Corticobasal Degeneration Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas progressive supranuclear palsy, often referred to as <quote>PSP</quote>, and corticobasal degeneration, often referred to as <quote>CBD</quote>, are rare, adult onset, rapidly progressing neurodegenerative disorders that affect multiple areas of the brain and cause complex symptoms and care needs;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas although some symptoms may appear similar to that of other neurological diagnoses like Parkinson’s disease and frontotemporal dementia, progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration are distinct diseases with their own unique trajectories and care needs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas while estimates vary and the conditions are frequently misdiagnosed, approximately 30,000 Americans are living with progressive supranuclear palsy and 2,000 Americans are living with corticobasal degeneration;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas delays to both accurate diagnosis of progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration and access to neurology professionals specialized in these diseases are common, causing confusion, anxiety, and frustration;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration can cause significant difficulty with movement, balance, speech, swallowing, cognition, vision, mood, and a variety of other complex symptoms;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration are aggressive in their progression, with most individuals becoming dependent on care in 3 to 4 years and having an overall life expectancy of 7 to 8 years from symptom onset;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are currently no disease-modifying treatments for progressive supranuclear palsy or corticobasal degeneration;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more research is needed to understand the roles of environmental factors and genetics in why people develop progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are countless family caregivers, friends, and loved ones whose lives are greatly affected by progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas additional research, support services, and education are needed to maintain quality of life for those affected by the disease, lead to better treatments and prevention of complications, and find cures for progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the establishment of the month of May 2026 as <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy and Corticobasal Degeneration Awareness Month</quote> will benefit individuals diagnosed, families, healthcare professionals, and communities across the country and further bolster awareness of the diseases: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFA9BE1F90E924491B36A9274C1986E56"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H04E8774B25294FF48AB59C09CC5B3558"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H899494ED86774A23B0039222C62583BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy and Corticobasal Degeneration Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03A5D1CA93DC4BA2B88724BDAC86D605"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy and Corticobasal Degeneration Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56C9019D1F334CE48F1F3D6AB6CEA5B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports research on diagnosis, prevention, treatments, and cures for progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC51DA15922BD49559FEF1890C53C3A25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the strength and resilience of the progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration community; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AF9B6DC10A74FB9802F072443F556A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>commends the individuals, families, volunteers, healthcare professionals, researchers, and organizations across the country who are working to improve the lives of people living with progressive supranuclear palsy and corticobasal degeneration.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

