<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H51436B30368B4925966C5D267D39275C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 862 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that a commemorative postage stamp should be issued in honor of the Buffalo Soldiers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 862</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that a commemorative postage stamp should be issued in honor of the Buffalo Soldiers.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 28, 1866, Congress established 6 all-Black regiments, later consolidated to 4, to help rebuild the country after the Civil War and to patrol the remote western frontier during the Indian wars;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Colonel Charles Young was a Buffalo Soldier and the highest ranking African-American commanding officer in the United States Army from 1894 until his death in 1922;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas more than 200,000 African Americans served in World War I and more than 1,000,000 served in World War II;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers received their name because of the buffalo’s fierce bravery and fighting spirit;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas African-American troops accepted the name, Buffalo Soldiers, with pride and honor;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers fought alongside White regiments in many conflicts and were instrumental in the exploration and settlement of western lands;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, over the 82 years of the Buffalo Soldiers’ existence, 23 men received the Congressional Medal of Honor, the highest recognition awarded by the United States Government for military service;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers ceased to exist in 1948 when President Harry Truman signed Executive Order 9981 mandating equal treatment and opportunity for African-American servicemen;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Buffalo Soldiers are a significant part of American military history;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a stamp was issued in honor of the Buffalo Soldiers on April 22, 1994, and this stamp was placed on <quote>off sale</quote> in December 1995; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas reissuing a postage stamp to honor the Buffalo Soldiers is fitting and proper: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA79CA1CABAA143C784E8F20FD20A379F"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H80AB43252AD444AC9BCF3A8FDBF9B0CE"><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> <paragraph id="HEFA07394F2C54314B8485F095551FC08"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a commemorative postage stamp should be issued in honor of the Buffalo Soldiers; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1C06EC9C15843659D2B5ACDB071761F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Citizens’ Stamp Advisory Committee should recommend to the Postmaster General that such a stamp be issued.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

