<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6BB1EBD9A51499085A2FD86403E76F4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1422 IH: Congratulating the New York Knicks on winning the 2026 National Basketball Association Finals.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1422</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the New York Knicks on winning the 2026 National Basketball Association Finals.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on Saturday, June 13, 2026, the New York Knickerbockers (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Knicks</quote>) won the 2026 National Basketball Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NBA</quote>) Finals, defeating the San Antonio Spurs in Game 5 by a score of 94–90 to win the series 4–1;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Knicks were established 80 years ago in 1946;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Knicks have called Madison Square Garden (<quote>the Mecca</quote>) their home since 1968;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Knicks last won the NBA Finals 53 years ago in 1973 and last appeared in the NBA Finals 27 years ago in 1999;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no">
 <text>Whereas the Knicks finished the 2025–2026 NBA regular season with 53 wins and 29 losses, a winning percentage of .646;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Knicks defeated the Atlanta Hawks, Philadelphia 76ers, and Cleveland Cavaliers en route to the NBA Finals;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Knicks went 16–3 in their playoff run and had the highest point differential and net rating in NBA playoff history;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the NBA Finals had the highest television ratings of any NBA Finals since 1998, the year of Michael Jordan's last NBA Finals run;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in Game 4 of the NBA Finals, the Knicks had the greatest comeback in NBA Finals history, overcoming a 29-point second half deficit to take a commanding 3–1 series lead;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in Game 4 of the NBA Finals, OG Anunoby won the game with a tip-in with 1.2 seconds left, which many are now calling the greatest play in the history of New York sports and one of the greatest in the history of the NBA;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Knicks came back from double digit deficits in every game they won in the NBA Finals, becoming the first team in history to do that;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Jalen Brunson was named the NBA Finals Most Valuable Player, finishing the series with a 45-point game on the road, tying Michael Jordan for the most points scored in a closeout game on the road;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Jalen Brunson, Josh Hart, and Mikal Bridges became the first trio of teammates to ever win a championship together in college (Villanova) and in the NBA; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas this Knicks team united millions of New Yorkers with their grit, resilience, and unrivaled excellence: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3882AD8F82814D41B8D2C8843903108A"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H35DF88E2004840928C1F4A8635E43CEE"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC8BF89F42A3C4B6CBCAF30D2640272FD">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>congratulates the New York Knicks (referred to in this resolution as the <quote>Knicks</quote>) on winning the 2026 National Basketball Association Finals;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9A58A602CCC476A83C762F023453A72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the Knicks for—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9AF93F15F6BB464AA11F98070849DAF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>their ability to unite New Yorkers of all backgrounds behind a common cause;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B05359312814518907B6E361949DC5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the excitement and spirit they brought to the streets of New York and basketball fans around the world; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA69B45947A02460A80E08E9EC76ED23A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the inspiration they provided to millions of people to believe in themselves and never give up; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5A86DBF69D64EEEA1FB283B524D45CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives of to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H534EF53A91304953ABC35887B1A7BD7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the owner of the Knicks, James L. Dolan;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CE37266E4E846DFA2220DDF671E75AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the president of the Knicks, Leon Rose; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AF533324F0A4899B402D4197442CC49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the coach of the Knicks, Mike Brown.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

