<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL26311-8P3-JK-GPN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4695 IS: Curbing Online Non-consensual Sexually Explicit Nudity Transfers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4695</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a private right of action against a person who transmits unsolicited intimate visual depictions.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Curbing Online Non-consensual Sexually Explicit Nudity Transfers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CONSENT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id59786ee2677c403c9f244989665bba4f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transmission of unsolicited intimate visual depictions</header><subsection id="id48ea4d0d54e742b69ab95b089a507b8f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id8eeb0115d2964260800b3996304ac06c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consent</header><text>The term <term>consent</term> means an affirmative, conscious, and voluntary authorization made by an individual free from force, fraud, duress, misrepresentation, or coercion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16f7c997888746139c93cf002803502d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intimate digital forgery</header><text>The term <term>intimate digital forgery</term> means any intimate visual depiction of an identifiable individual that—</text><subparagraph id="id3cbcf4eeefa7416994f29bead1bc5367"><enum>(A)</enum><text>falsely represents, in whole or in part—</text><clause id="id102de92cdc8147c4af9acea089701f64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the identifiable individual; or</text></clause><clause id="id0b00992675b945c48f70e4e9f0023619"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the conduct or content that makes the intimate visual depiction intimate;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6241ebb78cb2446fa72dcd43e114591c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is created through the use of software, machine learning, artificial intelligence, or any other computer-generated or technological means, including by adapting, modifying, manipulating, or altering an authentic intimate visual depiction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb5fb767127be43658063e1815d6863a4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is indistinguishable from an authentic intimate visual depiction of the identifiable individual when viewed as a whole by a reasonable person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e4cfb5eed114aab8088ab189576ba69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intimate visual depiction</header><text>The term <term>intimate visual depiction</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id27ae32cf1df140669539938b8384065d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 1309 of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6851">15 U.S.C. 6851</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e1e09cb875346fb85771103a3212b3a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an intimate digital forgery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35b70052046b48138d004eafb2c56755"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transmit</header><text>The term <term>transmit</term>, with respect to a depiction—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fb49e7eed5f4a62a07af7d3c8194f07"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means to send the depiction directly to 1 or more individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdef0b2bdc6d442983096299027cb9f6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include publishing the depiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id352f5f84e5314b72b4c418917c7f05f4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil action</header><paragraph id="id486f4c766f624572ae9b332f55ae2d63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Right of action</header><subparagraph id="id534750dfb4294b5096efffc8094a4a5a"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Prohibited transmissions</header> <text>If an individual 18 years of age or older, or any person that is not an individual, (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>sender</quote>) knowingly transmits to an individual (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>recipient</quote>) an intimate visual depiction, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce or using any means or facility of interstate or foreign commerce, without the consent of the recipient, knowing that, or recklessly disregarding whether, the recipient has not provided consent to receive the intimate visual depiction, the recipient may bring a civil action against the sender in an appropriate district court of the United States for relief under paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5829b1967eb445c59d874fc947806f83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rights on behalf of certain individuals</header><text>If an individual who receives an intimate visual depiction as described in subparagraph (A) is under 18 years of age, incompetent, or incapacitated, a legal guardian of the individual may bring a civil action under that subparagraph on behalf of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92b4980f7a0d4a009b7926fa51ab0b0d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Privacy protection for minors</header><clause id="id480ab168de7340d6818d029771c13cf3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a civil action is brought under subparagraph (A) on behalf of an individual who is a minor when the complaint is filed or by an individual who was a minor when the acts giving rise to the civil action took place, the plaintiff may elect to use the plaintiff's initials or a pseudonym in all filings with the court.</text></clause><clause id="ida8490cad96b24fa9a662863c20752867"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>If a plaintiff elects to proceed using the plaintiff's initials or a pseudonym under clause (i), the court and each other party to the action shall use the plaintiff’s initials or a pseudonym in—</text><subclause id="ideadfbe22a5164a65bf5a6092ab47ae4f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any order, filing, or other such document; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idc0ac704a4e7f4d55b21712d7ba8243e5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any proceeding that is transcribed by a court reporter.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ba64c32f195464e80d8aa408baa43b5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>A civil action under subparagraph (A) may not be brought against a person who transmits an intimate visual depiction for a good faith medical, educational, or law enforcement purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id94bf2d02d61540e689cf50f0a89413ed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action brought under paragraph (1), an individual may obtain—</text><subparagraph id="id277818c1ab0f4fd0a47636d203c9cae0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>either—</text><clause id="id45b4a4a845c74a72b71f75152110b840"><enum>(i)</enum><text>statutory damages of not more than $1,000; or</text></clause><clause id="id1902eafbdbe7427294edd127c6b6f2a3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compensatory damages for emotional distress;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5db3034092446e8bbb749660bae5176"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reasonable attorney fees and costs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idadc872c78c1c47dba277480421867e09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a temporary restraining order, a preliminary injunction, or a permanent injunction ordering the defendant to cease transmitting intimate visual depictions to the plaintiff without consent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id977545e8794c4d9db3f6f67ff8b08114"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relation to criminal laws</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to modify, impair, or supersede any provision of criminal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c1f1a340f5d4ef4a631faae357a4231"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed or applied so as to abridge the exercise of rights guaranteed under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id548d91de20ed4b9b99e074cf5036e052"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this section, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this section, and the application of the provision to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

