<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC60EDBBAAF54B97BF8ADE1AF6A6B48E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8832 IH: Supporting Women with Career Opportunities in Policing Services Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8832</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Task Force on Women in Law Enforcement to study and develop national hiring standards for law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDDA10D3E31084D319D79A822420FF39C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H85A679A3C34748F8841FED0CA0664672" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Women with Career Opportunities in Policing Services Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Supporting Women COPS Act of 2026</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HBF351590455B42A8926B7D6C0C6B8C73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Task Force on Women in Law Enforcement</header> <subsection id="HA840A4D89B244BD4BF529E8B137F8EED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a Task Force on Women in Law Enforcement (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>) to study State hiring standards for law enforcement officers, develop national hiring standards for law enforcement officers, and develop recommendations for female officer retention and promotion.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1EAF5D9A613943FDB2A848716E149789"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall be composed of 12 members, appointed by the Attorney General as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HE32F08983486463DB7658D560A06003C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>One representative from the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE5BAA3E8E184D9FB67410E43C6630D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Two mayors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA916EE8B5544EFBB354B67862BB7C63"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three female police executives, one of whom serves as the head of a municipal law enforcement agency, one of whom serves as the head of a State law enforcement agency, and one of whom serves as the head of a sheriff’s department. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H518D9269CF604A7EB7325A109E762C5B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two female law enforcement officers with the rank of lieutenant or below. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C0DAD6561854E659B6410815B6C47A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Two representatives from community-based organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H479E92C5007C423FA52EE82DC783C784"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative from a law enforcement accreditation or standards and training organization. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE66355DE7D94D319FAD6BF621C8C564"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative from a national law enforcement organization representing women. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D2FDCCA3A914020A5C24E52826EA0CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of the task force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Task Force are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H9C71C510F4F84E6BABDD332BEF2212F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop recommendations for national hiring standards for law enforcement officers, including standards for physical fitness, critical thinking, and communication skills, that do not disadvantage applicants based on sex. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6224D5621B0E472A9C757995CCC221FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop recommendations for female officer retention, addressing barriers including physical fitness after childbirth and family responsibilities, such as childcare.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H098488D553464C009E69D9B2D88A9928"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To develop recommendations for female advancement to leadership roles in law enforcement. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E19E463B67A4066A9C23E0DF54011E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Task Force shall submit to Congress a report that details its findings and recommendations.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H03A2F851E8DE489BB0D6627D1AF519CF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Incentivizing States to adopt standards</header> <subsection id="HAEBF6084270C45D3A9761BE675512D91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in the fiscal year that begins after the development of the recommendations under section 2(c), a State that adopts such recommendations shall receive, in addition to the amount that the State otherwise receives under subpart 1 of part E of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program</quote>), an amount that is equal to 5 percent of what such State receives under such subpart, which may be used for the purposes authorized under such subpart.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26E6AD6F89314283A70999BCB9DF60B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out subsection (a) for each fiscal year beginning in the fiscal year that begins after the development of the recommendations under section 2(c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC5FA663661D44382B9EBACF9B1B7FAE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> <paragraph id="H21297D3A0645450992082C2FB54ECBCA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to provide technical assistance to assist States in adopting the recommendations under section 2(c). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD8AC65DE9C940F3A6B02E19BB3B9B04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

