<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7BB9FE2B5B3472685C495EF8AD32D06" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5847 IH: Airline Travelers Right to Know Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5847</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251028">October 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, with respect to requirements for air carriers to disclose certain exposures to toxic fumes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H47E5CDC992CF4AEF9D02CC057020F304" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0BFE933C155D434198218E2ED127D315" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Airline Travelers Right to Know Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H06B06BC4276142CAB7895B8301D3E7DD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Airline toxic fume disclosure</header> <subsection id="HB9C45F72A94E41FD96F5EAF13B0BFB74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart III of part A of subtitle VII of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3F711B26D7FA4A9EB366D50C7ACEFFA9" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<chapter id="H558FBFCE3A3B498B9CB3775A976B25C4"><enum>455</enum><header>Toxic Fume Disclosure</header>
<toc container-level="chapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H558FBFCE3A3B498B9CB3775A976B25C4" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="H79368425A50E4CAEA5894C11D97298CC" level="section">Sec. 45401. Definition of Administrator.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HEAF20FBFE4744410B9BD2E2A787DF6EC" level="section">Sec. 45402. Toxic fume disclosure.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD062669F9713461F9B15D1DD0E9E787E" level="section">Sec. 45403. Passenger notification prior to ticket purchase and check-in.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H2F0B64BA4D344BE18EA95409AA093946" level="section">Sec. 45404. Immediate notification of toxic fume events aboard aircraft.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H4503D429C4E248678B62C19BE646A53C" level="section">Sec. 45405. Crew notification of toxic fume events.</toc-entry></toc>
<section id="H79368425A50E4CAEA5894C11D97298CC"><enum>45401.</enum><header>Definition of Administrator</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter, the term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></section> <section id="HEAF20FBFE4744410B9BD2E2A787DF6EC"><enum>45402.</enum><header>Toxic fume disclosure</header> <subsection id="H69665728778B4926B09812735D6DA33D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall implement and enforce a right to know of potential toxic fume exposure policy to inform air carrier passengers, pilots, and cabin crew employees of the potential exposure to toxic fumes that cause permanent health or brain damage that such passengers, pilots, or employees may encounter onboard passenger-carrying aircraft operating under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3E24E1469410444DB0D6EEAE3CE0F607"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The right to know of potential toxic fume exposure policy under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H625EDEDA492D41C4BDB5F490842993EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be made available in all pilot and crew member contracts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0184FA32FF43481C9BE657B0985376A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be made available to all air carrier passengers immediately after purchasing a ticket for transportation by such air carrier or a third party ticket booking entity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4ABD3BEFFD54CBC8E3D1D7B154EB8D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include details on the potential for acute or chronic impairment relating to such fumes to an individual;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H278401113AFF47B6A840F87D2096AC8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include details on chemicals known to cause cancer, birth defects, and other reproductive harm that may be present in jet engine exhaust, fumes from jet fuel, and exhaust from equipment used to service airplanes, while making clear that sometimes such chemicals enter the jet bridge and are present throughout the duration of the flight;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6C3371086F24EEEA745A9422118424D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide information on safety management systems in place that could protect individuals from such exposure;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADF4BB3053E849759CA97E4C3BB8FBB4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide information on safety management systems to use if exposed to toxic fumes such as oxygen therapy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EE2916147D64B09B95245FAF6BA83B6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide that passengers of air carriers and air carrier crew members have a right to use cabin oxygen masks in response to a toxic fume event.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE737E921FA894F9194CF9325DD3D60F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall impose a civil penalty under section 46301 for each violation of the disclosure required pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD062669F9713461F9B15D1DD0E9E787E"><enum>45403.</enum><header>Passenger notification prior to ticket purchase and check-in</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this section, operators of passenger-carrying aircraft operating under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, shall require passengers to indicate an understanding of potential toxic fume exposure onboard such aircraft in ticket purchase process.</text></section>
<section id="H2F0B64BA4D344BE18EA95409AA093946"><enum>45404.</enum><header>Immediate notification of toxic fume events aboard aircraft</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall notify all affected customers, flight attendants, pilots, and aircraft maintenance technicians of any exposure to toxic fumes aboard aircraft as soon as an air carrier confirms to the Administrator toxic fumes were detected onboard such aircraft.</text></section> <section id="H4503D429C4E248678B62C19BE646A53C"><enum>45405.</enum><header>Crew notification of toxic fume events</header> <subsection id="H0ECD74DC89814F4F808F06F423C62E52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Operators of passenger-carrying aircraft under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, shall inform all crewmembers of such aircraft of the most recent toxic fume exposure on such aircraft, whether the issue that led to the exposure has been resolved, and if any crewmembers have requested treatment for such exposure.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9BBE6F39201545F596B0E738EEA24992"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right To decline assignment</header><text>Operators under subsection (a) shall provide crewmembers with an option to decline an assignment onboard an aircraft covered under subsection (a) if the issue that led to an exposure reported under such subsection has not been resolved, without penalizing such crewmember.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7F386DCE200E40D89BFD9BF84DFD7CED"><enum>45406.</enum><header>Civil penalty for false statement, misrepresentation, imparting, or conveying false information</header> <subsection id="HD68E9EE8E18345DE831937948CB5B4E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall impose a civil penalty under section 46301 for each specified violation.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H32DA95E04B104A9FA8CF975C62511D11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified violation</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>specified violation</quote> means any false statement, misrepresentation, impart, or conveyance of false information by an operator of an aircraft under section 45404 or 45405 demonstrated by a confirmed illness of a customer or employee of a flight provided by such operator.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7B26D18DA2684F0493913A49D81116FC"><enum>45407.</enum><header>Penalty for missing reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If an operator of passenger-carrying aircraft under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, that is required to report information under this chapter is missing any such report on inspection by the Secretary of Transportation, the operator shall be liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of $100,000.</text></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HEBD53FF7210F48499DF79C56C0ECDB62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for subtitle VII of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 453 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H6E2F0039D6A3419583C4B9C63CE465FB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="chapter">455. Toxic Fume Disclosure</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF406CABA1D6647D783350A86A4EDB6D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulation</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation administration shall issue such regulations as are necessary to amend section 13.18 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to include violations under section 45402 of title 49, United States Code, under the procedures for civil penalties under such section 13.18.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF4D4CADD26504D4DB4649AF3265AA971"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Toxic fume sensors</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to—</text> <paragraph id="HE8DD5D016DAE4D298F862BDA3C05E5FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require operators of passenger-carrying aircraft under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to install sensors that detect toxic fumes onboard such aircraft; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC56A88F71A74CB0A30E29BF83EA13EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>amend section 13.18 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to include violations of the regulations issued under paragraph (1) under the procedures for civil penalties under such section 13.18.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6ED67EDAB16A45B88245A465A3CAF05D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Oxygen for crewmembers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to require operators of passenger-carrying aircraft under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to procure and make available to all crewmembers on such aircraft mobile oxygen masks for crewmembers assisting passengers with oxygen masks in the case of a toxic fume event.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

