<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEBA2C05ECA004DB5BB8C5414144CF979" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9511 IH: NFIP Premium Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9511</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to develop a flood insurance information tool, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26124744C5A24029B10DF66529416BD5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE122A7482633445193BFD798B49BDE11" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NFIP Premium Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HBA2CC2B81ADF4228A8BD2345AE79579C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dissemination of flood insurance information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by striking section 1313 and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H2C9D390BADD942228E214B6CF9D41606" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCEFF3C6037FF47CB97DAB57C6394BFA7"><enum>1313.</enum><header>Dissemination of flood insurance information</header> 
<subsection id="H3B15C5DF85F246618B538669BC6E4D93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure that the declaration page for each flood insurance policy issued under the national flood insurance program for a property shall, not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this section, include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFE78FB7445C3403BAA996066276F6887"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The current insurance premium for such property, including a description of any discounts being applied including any discounts associated with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H921C30DB3A1E4F3996297A37EBD8E29C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>building, construction, or substantial improvement which began before the Administrator published an initial rate map for the community;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DD8BAD5064440E1BEE0D908CA4EEF10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligibility for less than actuarial rates under section 1307(a)(2) or section 1307(g);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEFD26E8B3F7041798FA5669C12B3D229"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the newly mapped property discount under section 1308(i);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H682AC2E701834473AD27731706733022"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an estimate of the number years remaining until the premium for such property shall match the full-risk based premium for such property, having accounted for the annual limitation on premium increases under section 1308(e);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77CF3FE05D5A4EB0A2A42D2B52852724"><enum>(E)</enum><text>available mitigation options and associated premium savings;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36B1E37BC55D4634AEA3D512A446B403"><enum>(F)</enum><text>claim history;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1589F8AC7D54B91AFAF859EAA6F5277"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the community rating system under section 1315(b); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F9B7B172C8444749164F70FE7092022"><enum>(H)</enum><text>annual limitations on premium increases under section 1308(e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H541B9EB3B5944D45A7839601255CB297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any annual limitations on premium increases under section 1308(e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6837C2F0A66B4299BBF48D76D2E6BF81"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The replacement cost value.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB1922DDF6A64E0CAFEAB3D770237C9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As determined not to be exempted from release or disclosure under any applicable statute and not in violation of personally identifiable information privacy requirements by the Administrator, all rating factors for the property, and the property’s rate for each factor, under the risk premium rate estimated under section 1307(a)(1) of the National Flood Insurance Act, including the property’s base rate, building value, concentration risk, contents value, deductible insurance-to-value, drainage area, distance to the coast, distance to lake, distance to ocean, distance to river, elevation, elevation relative to lake, elevation relative to river, first floor height, floors of interest, foundation type, levee quality, machinery and equipment above first floor, replacement cost value, structural relative elevation, territory, and type of use.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33E6BEF831494E089F2635E0E412BE9F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any special category that applies to the property, including repetitive loss property or severe repetitive loss property.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2C57C51883340B0A7479C350F8FBFFD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any flood insurance requirement that applies to the property as a result of disaster assistance previously provided by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE217019D3424CD9B2D6554128D4421D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On and after the date that is 36 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the website address where the flood insurance information tool established pursuant to subsection (c) may be located.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA97E3F3087224F36B3DEE16BDC11F4FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Explanation required</header><text>If any item of information required to be included on a declaration page under subsection (a) cannot be provided, an explanation of why such item of information cannot be provided shall be included on the declaration page.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H097F1996E8BB4832B0A98A3104AD9A50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required information sharing</header><text>The Administrator shall, beginning on the date that is 12 months after the date of the enactment of this section, share with each insurer that issues a flood insurance policy for a property under the national flood insurance program, any information the Administrator has that relates to the items listed in subsection (a) for such property.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E4547FBC6B345388989D959BDA1F5EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Flood insurance information tool</header> 
<paragraph id="HF38742BFC4C74979B4D1A45F34C8F836"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall, not later than 36 months after the date of the enactment of this section, develop a flood insurance information tool that is accessible online and contains the following information with respect to each property for which a flood insurance policy is available under the national flood insurance program:</text> <subparagraph id="H83FD2944901F4C438C60483F9FDE181D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The current insurance premium for such property, including a description of any reason why the current premium is less than actuarial rates; including due to grandfathering, pre-FIRM discount status, newly mapped property status, or a Community Rating System status.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H458C42E8099C48E4B28A36235FE98327"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of any limitations on annual premium increases.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF000B31156D4AF4A50447DF5C88AFA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The risk premium rate for such property.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EACC57B909B41B09518BDD46A2840F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The replacement cost value for such property, and the date on which such value was calculated.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4227C5086E9A458CB918F8CA88F053E4"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As determined not to be exempted from release or disclosure under any applicable statute and not in violation of personally identifiable information privacy requirements by the Administrator, all rating factors for the property, and the property’s rate for each factor, under the risk premium rate estimated under section 1307(a)(1) of the National Flood Insurance Act, including the property’s base rate, building value, concentration risk, contents value, deductive insurance-to-value, drainage area, distance to the coast, distance to lake, distance to ocean, distance to river, elevation, elevation relative to lake, elevation relative to river, first floor height, floors of interest, foundation type, levee quality, machinery and equipment above first floor, replacement cost value, structural relative elevation, territory, and type of use.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC137BE4474604EE8A1429EFD3E863F7F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A detailed flood history for such property that includes a list of any prior claims under the national flood insurance program associated with such property and the dates of such claims.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD341F95B2F8C4491B559AB8FC980B7F6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any special category that applies to the property, including repetitive loss property or severe repetitive loss property.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71EF01EB4C7A4F1D8D6362BEC6BB4A96"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The date of the most recent flood hazard determination of such property and the date of any planned future flood hazard determination of such property.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H636AAEA0CAFA4F3FB5CC0D3FA33D1BE2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any flood insurance requirement that applies to the property as a result of disaster assistance previously provided by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5F2CABDC705434F98B850D0D6BDD44B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Any additional information the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA3AFE8359964D73916CDBCAE832B8BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Explanation required</header><text>If any item of information required to be included in the flood insurance information tool under paragraph (1) cannot be provided, an explanation of why such item of information cannot be provided shall be included in the flood insurance information tool.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6457E4BBC22D44C9B73DED5859863A47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Access to the flood insurance information tool</header><text>The Administrator shall, notwithstanding any conflicting provision in the Privacy Act of 1974, provide access to the flood insurance information tool, suite of tools, or discrete parts of such tools, to—</text> <subparagraph id="H010A8A3606C84726BDDDA0270DC08842"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public, for all information where the Administrator has determined that release to the public is in the best interest of the public; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8A65D36B26A4CE1B63FF85B17660ACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>owners of properties for which a flood insurance policy is issued under the national flood insurance program, for information where the Administrator has determined that release to the public is not in the best interest of the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD21708E4D5D146FEB405327C86AB4514"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjustment capability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the degree practicable, the flood insurance information tool, or suite of tools, developed by Administrator shall allow users to, with respect to each item of information listed in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F0A52438D9D4FF6A990EE0C5D557747"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adjust variables that change over time and impact flood risk; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6888A0DFA56D440BBA4113A1AED32B9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate how such adjustments or mitigation activities would—</text> 
<clause id="H9220E6CBFA9D4D35AFD1B55B020EDCAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduce the risk of flooding; and</text></clause> <clause id="H82825575E69E46189F1F01FD33E95C59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>decrease premiums.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C011DA0E24344F3AA567C5897E579C2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of existing tools</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, when developing a flood insurance information tool paragraph (1), improve upon or expand an existing tool or resource used by Federal Emergency Management Agency if improving upon or expanding such tool would reduce the cost of developing a flood insurance information tool paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBA64C2B9332541A9831158E09DA8DF83"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Replacement cost value defined</header><text>The term <term>replacement cost value</term> means the cost to replace that part of a building that is damaged by flood, without depreciation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0B1FE2FDDAA34E1F8A9E410E7B290C08"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional information availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall publish online, for each State, county, and ZIP Code in the United States, a distribution showing the median, mean, lower and upper quartiles, maximum, and minimum—</text> <paragraph id="HD767C224523442B596052294C208673A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the chargeable premium rates prescribed under section 1308 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H187D6323382C47AF90284B015890FBBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>full risk premium rates under section 1307(a)(1) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H4562F34B232C44BE8A1196542B5F82EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall, not later than 2 years after the date on which the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency makes available the flood insurance information tool required to be developed under section 1313(c) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, publish a report that analyzes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B09DEAA53E34B92BEEDF229FA454B1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whether the following information could be added to flood insurance information tool established by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency pursuant to section 1313 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968:</text> <subparagraph id="HD795246652684873959D9E28B916471C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any property acquisition programs for which the property qualifies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13D950F6F1CF4230A9213346EE77E436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any nature based solutions that may be used to reduce the flood risk for the property.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8F0F8D858A94F4FA313077FB33BDC5F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Coastal restoration projects, as implemented by a State or local government or included in a State-approved coastal master plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED0FDD0A5F5F4F46BC999354D8A7A417"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any planned or existing flood defenses in the area in which a property is located, including projects authorized by the Water Resources Development Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79816D3407D24D7E9F8A1A2332E61D90"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any implications that additional development in the area where property is located may have on flood risk.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H540D7AB344A5478E8C1193786712435B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any standards established locally that affect the repair or improvement of the property, including—</text> <clause id="HA1818634B88B40399C98F4C8EFFDBBB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any limitations on repairs or improvements based on the value of the property; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC67C721615FC45BAB89CEBC80434E4F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any local standards that go beyond the standards required under the national flood insurance program.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB35FC16153124118B6EE1F51AD7573C5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A description of any community rating system rating that impacts the property and discounts that may be available based on this rating system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F360381BBD143EA8BCE6161DA279A10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether access to the flood insurance information tool established by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency pursuant to section 1313 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 could be provided to prospective buyers of properties for which a flood insurance policy is issued under the national flood insurance program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92A2D614FBDE4C629676B00B55C6F49B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Whether the flood insurance information tool established by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency pursuant to section 1313 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 could allow users to, with respect to each item of information listed in paragraph in the flood insurance tool, adjust variables that impact flood risk, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3FA633532E1149D1AE201A33C66AC206"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relative sea level rise;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCEBA1BA8926B4797898914430D751C06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>extension or reduction of impervious cover;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C364FA35D144034AB479AEE902A223E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>levee reliability changes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9352D0FF5ED34E6293F16D65EEDD956D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>coastal land loss or coastal restoration, including hydrologic restoration, sediment diversion, marsh creation, shoreline protection, and other project types.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAF75B4CE1C94B989E5BCDB4936E5C2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether the types of information available within the flood insurance information tool established by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency pursuant to section 1313 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 could be expanded further.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H797B171F5AFA49EF9E4DB65D3BF1DD0A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Whether the information provided by the flood insurance tool established by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency pursuant to section 1313 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 could be used by policy holders as part of any appeals procedure implemented by the Administrator on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

