<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E784E005A3F423A98340218C1CE3397" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8371 IH: Reform Immigration Through Biometrics Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8371</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To evaluate U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s implementation of an integrated biometric entry and exit data system in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H625C6A120ED04EA594CBB964C33D672A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2A44A88F93DC4BBDA7096BBB32F8BC01" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reform Immigration Through Biometrics Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7406B6907A9E48A4B9CA3435BFAEC242"><enum>2.</enum><header>Evaluation of CBP’s implementation of an integrated biometric entry and exit data system</header> <subsection id="HCDD10E88422A4B77878A36096F110E73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <paragraph id="H6A7F8FAB18AE452291F0507356C8D007"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on the status of efforts to implement an integrated entry and exit data system in accordance with section 110 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1365a">8 U.S.C. 1365a</external-xref>; in this section referred to as the <quote>System</quote>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A611DBF4F0B47C39F5F7D02B7B57D85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include information relating to the following with respect to the System:</text> <subparagraph id="H19FD27B9175042BE8849222F8D7DB809"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The impact on arrival and departure wait times.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD2D87CEC0B95404CA51B5375EE554E84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An evaluation of audits conducted on devices procured by the private sector.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5EBF2190A50D445FAC6A9FEF0142F8FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An evaluation of prior and ongoing consultation with the private sector.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1238E2BBE58347F3824899911AB51E7B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Milestones and metrics of success that have occurred already, and whether such milestones and metrics should be updated to successfully carry out the congressional directive to establish the System.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE821FB09F07248B28CCD100D2ABCDBF9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Risks and mitigation strategies to address such risks.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4BB1913C1D342DDBE96C0FB15798987"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effects of the System on the following:</text> <clause id="H1C5581C2B649401E80B8ABC1B55DEAC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legitimate travel and trade.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFB0C15DE87074F3E94FD379EAF11805F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Combating terrorism.</text></clause> <clause id="H58089FA580104699B9FEFDE53CCB760C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Identifying visa holders who violate the terms of their visas.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CEEB6C51CCC4B369ADC1B039955F7B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the collection of biometric data under the System shall cause the least possible disruption to the movement of people or cargo in air, sea, or land transportation while fulfilling the goals of improving counterterrorism efforts and identifying visa holders who violate the terms of their visas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H58B4234EC7514567BF264C40E6E5BA72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data matching assessment</header> <paragraph id="HC501ACDD519E40CEB4B9C23E2FB184ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>in general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on how the System is currently matching biometric information for an individual, regardless of nationality, citizenship, or immigration status, who is departing the United States against biometric data previously provided to the United States Government by such individual for the purposes of international travel.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05F8E7F92025448EA96BD9678E2D0DE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall not include any information relating to citizens of the United States, except to describe the privacy protections for such citizens with regard to facial recognition.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H931EAA3A08D445F2A18BA7D82579EE04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Further evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on whether the sharing of biographic data provided to the Department of Homeland Security by the Canadian Border Services Agency pursuant to the 2011 Beyond the Border agreement has occurred, and the impacts of such data sharing agreement.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H42442B9AA02F468781008F63C8D46AC2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other biometric initiatives</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as limiting the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to collect biometric information in circumstances other than as specified in this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H245E70A7F016447D99C6D3FAD98BE980"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section may prohibit the collection of user fees permitted by section 13031 of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

