<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2BB6A8A0FD774A11A7175F09BCA7A572" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8873 IH: Recover COVID Unemployment Fraud in Banks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8873</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To recover unclaimed pandemic-era unemployment compensation funds held by financial institutions or escheated to State unclaimed property administrators, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1FF95F7B34DE49118452769920BAB55D" style="OLC"><section id="H25CB91B4F87A470FA64A3C294C281094" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recover COVID Unemployment Fraud in Banks Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDB78321D252F484DB5EB58B8346144D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>National recovery coordinator and task force</header><subsection id="H68E5391588414ABC8185F75960E0037C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H2BC1A21ED5CE4BFDAF1A9B61F3E4E645"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of national recovery coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Inspector General of the Department of Labor, and the Attorney General, shall designate an official to serve as National Recovery Coordinator to oversee and coordinate the activities and responsibilities of the task force described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A773E13945048778DC9A8699557E58C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Task force establishment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the National Recovery Coordinator shall convene a task force to be named the <quote>Recover Pandemic Unemployment Funds in Banks Task Force</quote> (in this section, the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE7CF8472784021A9DA1BC937786182"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Task Force shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H34B7324EB6974614B494AA370CB4A1DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Attorney General, or their designee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE2FDD490DFC4174BEF095C030A56201"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Labor, or their designee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE4651C94D974AEABF51979312DBCE1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Inspector General of the Department of Labor, or their designee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92814BF6323141CD97A5D81622ED8EFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury, or their designee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA30FF96E6A54261A13305CF164C7484"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Chairman of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or their designee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33C1ADB18B2B4E49AB0C4732DC822C1D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, or their designee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80AB7F5E5F8043ED87E552E9358691C4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Task force responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the responsibility of the Task Force to—</text><paragraph id="HD6089CC5C08643569CF8A620CB6494CB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with applicable State agencies to identify Federal pandemic unemployment compensation payments issued on prepaid debit cards that—</text><subparagraph id="H8375902031924D0EAFD4A4B205575AA2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are held by financial institutions, and other entities identified by the Inspector General of the Department of Labor, contracted by a State agency to transfer such payments to unemployment claimants; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4162055DC2D64B1AB36B18144F2BF0BF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>were transferred by such an entity to, and are currently held by, a State agency responsible for unclaimed property;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81DEABD42D594536ABFB6801F808F7FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate with appropriate Federal agencies to develop model processes which comply with relevant Federal and State laws and result in cost-effective recovery of the payments identified under paragraph (1), including issuing guidance, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, to administrators of State agencies responsible for administering Federal unemployment compensation payments or determining fraud in such programs, including—</text><subparagraph id="H289C4659B89342A487C80ABB6047ADEF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidelines for—</text><clause id="H0FCB2F34E908440E8CA7D80B41C6D7E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reviewing such payments and determining if such a payment was an improper payment;</text></clause><clause id="H3B872BCB692C497485C8FBFCDAACF902"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determining whether cost-effective recovery of an improper payment is possible, including a threshold, or a methodology for calculating a dollar threshold, for cost-effective recovery; and</text></clause><clause id="H2DC0707D8CCF4C9087052F4B7AADC40D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>actions, consistent with State law, to be taken by the State agency if an improper payment is determined to be the result of fraud;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC868E995D72F45758EDF4B8E61C82295" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assurances that, subject to section 303(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/503">42 U.S.C. 503(g)</external-xref>), any action taken in relation to a determination that a payment identified under paragraph (1) is an improper payment shall be taken under State law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF53AF07C6D2249EEB52D8EB87FD9608E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a model notice and information, developed in coordination with the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, about resources available to individuals whose identity information is determined to have been fraudulently used to obtain Federal pandemic unemployment compensation; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF781A1B0851E442398DCA7112BDF44BD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the legal pathways described under paragraphs (3) and (4) for recovery of payments that are improper payments held by institutions and agencies described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05BEE3A848054FF99EE7338D90CA4AC8" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedural requirements for State agencies to follow when funds are returned by such institutions that provides a standardized methodology to return funds to the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EC0411538D44A239465D8778B080909" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue guidance, in coordination with the Comptroller of the Currency and Chairman of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, to financial institutions described in paragraph (1) that are holding payments that are improper payments that provides information on a legal pathway, consistent with banking regulations and applicable contracts with State agencies, for returning such payments to the appropriate State agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73D7DD03B1734966B91C959EEE9DB292" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue guidance, in coordination with the Secretary of Treasury, to administrators of State agencies responsible for unclaimed property on the obligations of such agencies to review and return payments described in paragraph (1)(B) to the appropriate State agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30740B3A645F469FA8DF868AD559272F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the guidance required to be issued under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (b), the Task Force shall consult with State agencies and incorporate best practices from previous attempts by any such States to recover payments determined to be improper payments from institutions described in paragraph (1)(A) of such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D009F1794DC4B718112EDAB39D39082"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State administrative costs</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall reimburse States for all administrative costs incurred as a result of coordination with the Task Force by reason of an agreement under section 2102, 2104, or 2107 of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9201">15 U.S.C. 9201</external-xref>; 9203; 9205).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2144B050E44E497B9B151394C5DE6E52"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Except as otherwise specified, in this section:</text><paragraph id="HBC724873E16E46158FAEFE39C429ACD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal pandemic unemployment compensation</header><text>The term <term>Federal pandemic unemployment compensation</term> means a payment of—</text><subparagraph id="H5B007D57528348B7A0E91D9DE21EA5C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistance under section 2102(b) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9021">15 U.S.C. 9021(b)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB74F32CCA88644A8BFFC78CB751E6F1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal Pandemic Unemployment Compensation and Mixed Earner Unemployment Compensation under section 2104(b)(1) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9023">15 U.S.C. 9023(b)(1)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B8A0C708CCD479BA74961630DD6D423"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pandemic emergency unemployment compensation under section 2107(a)(2) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9025">15 U.S.C. 9025(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34A9FE7F43194BA29D284AC656CC8C06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Improper payment</header><text>The term <term>improper payment</term> means any amount of a pandemic unemployment payment to which the individual is not entitled.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4CEA3C9419E4BA096DBF1877B411EBA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State; state agency; state law</header><text>The terms <term>State</term>, <term>State agency</term>, and <term>State law</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 205 of the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3304">26 U.S.C. 3304</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0752345F5E274D0FB01992760EF518E2" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of the statute of limitations for pandemic unemployment fraud by individuals under certain unemployment programs</header><subsection id="H36D9E4251AB443C2A47D6F3FDE03F84A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pandemic unemployment assistance</header><text>Section 2102 of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9021">15 U.S.C. 9021</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3C4531A5549A49F49321F5AF6729616B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A5B330E9006417D8E9C5E5DC3EDEAAD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1E7D23FBCDD4B99969C52FA1FC8A2CF"><subsection id="HA7473C9A3C2D4A568BC7090D26ADA7B3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statute of Limitations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05D5FD10B4AD470481DC3E3EA17ADF07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to paragraph (2), any criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action for a violation of, or conspiracy to violate, section 371, 641, 1028A, 1029, 1341, 1343, 1344, 1349, 1956, or 1957 of title 18, United States Code, or section 3729 or 3802 of title 31, United States Code, with respect to any unemployment compensation claim funded in whole or in part by pandemic unemployment assistance under this section shall be brought not later than 10 years after the date of the violation or conspiracy.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F265EAF20B24C599BC04CF755CF1A92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action if the statute of limitations applicable to such criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action expired prior to the date of enactment of the Recover COVID Unemployment Fraud in Banks Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9977438BC194F9285D41AA1DC6B1055"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Pandemic Unemployment Compensation and Mixed Earner Unemployment compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2104(f) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9023">15 U.S.C. 9023(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2CEE8253592443CAC3ACFBCDE7662CA"><paragraph id="H244ED3F62E5C4322A6BFCFCB49B58DDD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statute of Limitations</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E4F776E7DAF46D09F76536C362A12C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subparagraph (B), any criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action for a violation of, or conspiracy to violate, section 371, 641, 1028A, 1029, 1341, 1343, 1344, 1349, 1956, or 1957 of title 18, United States Code, or section 3729 or 3802 of title 31, United States Code, with respect to any unemployment compensation claim funded in whole or in part by Federal Pandemic Unemployment Compensation or Mixed Earner Unemployment Compensation under this section shall be brought not later than 10 years after the date of the violation or conspiracy. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3BC78B5F32E4215A204BB596B439165"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action if the statute of limitations applicable to such criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action expired prior to the date of enactment of the Recover COVID Unemployment Fraud in Banks Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1C6055FC76B24DA1A20F7A3088B7C0F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pandemic emergency unemployment compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2107(e) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9025">15 U.S.C. 9025(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9052459D8CBB4346B2E1E51C13A16732"><paragraph id="HF5836EC16C754F9B83E1917A49821146" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statute of Limitations</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A1FD99162EB4220BD442CA22A58983A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subparagraph (B), any criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action for a violation of, or conspiracy to violate, section 371, 641, 1028A, 1029, 1341, 1343, 1344, 1349, 1956, or 1957 of title 18, United States Code, or section 3729 or 3802 of title 31, United States Code, with respect to any unemployment compensation claim funded in whole or in part by Pandemic Emergency Unemployment Compensation under this section shall be brought not later than 10 years after the date of the violation or conspiracy. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D54B08F1F8F4870818A945E48483902"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action if the statute of limitations applicable to such criminal prosecution or civil enforcement action expired prior to the date of enactment of the Recover COVID Unemployment Fraud in Banks Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1B6C8B723D9149DC914603F155C9EC9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by section Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

