<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC93B43D35AB4CFCA86E3D1D41ABF15C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6515 IH: To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to prevent duplicate enrollments in Exchanges.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6515</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to prevent duplicate enrollments in Exchanges.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF5D03B61C085428191ABE5D082B328EE" style="OLC"><section id="HE34713E7FF0646D8A091197CC5882F47" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Preventing duplicate enrollments in Exchanges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1411 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18081">42 U.S.C. 18081</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9FD23B67A29A426B983B9477E688C945" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H0E30923D8987437BBE844EFF398F4E26"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Preventing duplicate enrollments</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HF268189FC70349B1854EDC9277A11E76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, as part of the program established under subsection (a), a process for identifying whether the social security number provided by an individual who is to be covered in the individual market by a qualified health plan offered through an Exchange is identical to the social security number of any enrollee in any Exchange under this title enrolled for the same period in which such coverage is to be effective; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDAB13DE84004459A57C4639F56B97AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case that identical social security numbers are so identified under <internal-xref idref="HF268189FC70349B1854EDC9277A11E76" legis-path="(j)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, take such actions as are necessary to ensure that duplicative advance payments of premium tax credits under section 1412 are not made with respect to an individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

