<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26H01-VGX-GM-XLY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S5023 IS: Ban Birth Tourism Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 5023</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the inadmissibility of certain aliens seeking citizenship for children by giving birth in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ban Birth Tourism Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id7412A6D3D96840158B63DA4AA2A30A4A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inadmissibility of aliens seeking United States citizenship for children through birth tourism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(a)(10) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(10)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id751691273B8F45B8ABB7775190EC8FA6"><subparagraph id="idEE3E13E6E6D345719C32C0D96FFC9531"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Aliens seeking citizenship for children by giving birth in the United States</header><clause id="id90F8A257F0D94219A43357617220E326"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any alien seeking admission to the United States as a nonimmigrant under section 101(a)(15)(B) to engage in birth tourism is inadmissible.</text></clause><clause id="id8B02C20AA5714F7F8993E7DD73A88926"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Birth tourism</header><text>An alien is engaging in birth tourism under clause (i) if, based on the reasonable judgment of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or a consular officer, the alien—</text><subclause id="id4666cdc1c71b4a15a86166d60506df15"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is seeking to enter or reenter the United States for the primary purpose of obtaining United States citizenship for a child by giving birth to such child; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31f22a77a2b545aa967ce7905dd3206a"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is likely to give birth to a child within 10 months of entry if such alien is admitted to, or physically present in, the United States or its territories or outlying possessions and, as a result, is likely to obtain United States citizenship for such child based on the child’s birth on United States territory.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idc6eac7fb8aac46dab59ed7c3de881409"><enum>3.</enum><header>Deportability of aliens seeking United States citizenship for children through birth tourism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 237(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id285c506a7287469a9640d6837a863c7f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (G); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3639eab728514538b2d9d74ed0ed5040"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2f6c055fba64c249577c2c69a741b08"><subparagraph id="idd72651725daa4b14864e2b3bef66ee50"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Birth tourism</header><clause id="id9b5ab8d050094632a248417f0c250563"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien is deportable if such alien has entered the United States to engage in birth tourism.</text></clause><clause id="id00890d654c044f2088b8a453c4ea2aaf"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Birth tourism</header><text>An alien has engaged in birth tourism if, based on the reasonable judgment of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or a consular officer, the alien—</text><subclause id="id136493355b994de495840b09b2ba8b56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>entered or reentered the United States for the primary purpose of obtaining United States citizenship for a child by giving birth to such child; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id8288dc1f8152461392365da321b71b9b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is likely to give birth to a child within 10 months of such entry while in the United States or its territories or outlying possessions and, as a result, is likely to obtain United States citizenship for such child based on the child’s birth on United States territory.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

