<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO26105-HHH-0P-NY0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3785 IS: North Rim and Kaibab National Forest Restoration Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3785</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize direct emergency acquisition flexibilities for the National Park Service and Forest Service for the purpose of retaining, vetting, approving, and expediting contractor approval for the clearing, rebuilding, maintenance, and improvement of areas of the Grand Canyon National Park and Kaibab National Forest damaged by certain wildfires, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4DDCC15E06A6445FABFA558892D1E178"><section section-type="section-one" id="H44D885DE79A64F47B73F8E5318611371"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Rim and Kaibab National Forest Restoration Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id02d37dca81f2452bbd94395b6f632f9c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="ide92441bcf2844f90b09c56a2fe7491b1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Grand Canyon is a national treasure that has exceptional historic, cultural, and geological value;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf28e1707bc88425ab5d8bcc58d71bbc1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Grand Canyon region drives the local economy through tourism and outdoor recreation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23b8f684dd7e4a6db279be17bf487211"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Grand Canyon is the ancestral homeland of 11 Indian Tribes, the members of which now live in the States of Arizona, Utah, New Mexico, and Nevada;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id755afe7d31a64fdfb407fda60af546f1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restoring the landscapes in the Grand Canyon helps uphold the responsibilities of the United States to the Indian Tribes referred to in paragraph (3); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf27bb88c492d48f282dcb6e0206c14df"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Dragon Bravo Fire and White Sage Fire—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee23b06f1fa942bba992f3867ffe5cdd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collectively burned more than 200,000 acres of land in the North Rim and Kaibab National Forest; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d19c56a2cdb46d1a8529d543eb35a36"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">destroyed more than 100 structures, including the Grand Canyon Lodge.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8CCAFE6BC6A74C318A0717CE3EC69A7E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H367560AF7A1440F0B5F0F3180FB04EDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered Area</header><text>The term <term>covered area</term> means any area within the Grand Canyon National Park or Kaibab National Forest impacted by the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6139209793d4e3b9475082ac3ec6861"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dragon Bravo Fire</header><text>The term <quote>Dragon Bravo Fire</quote> means the wildfire in the North Rim of Grand Canyon National Park in the State of Arizona that began on July 4, 2025, and was contained on September 29, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e119f0849994d3caed4fd184f943196"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Forest management or restoration activity</header> <text>The term <quote>forest management or restoration activity</quote> means slash and hazard tree (as defined in section 512(a) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1772">43 U.S.C. 1772(a)</external-xref>)) removal, erosion control, slope stabilization, tree regeneration, wildlife rehabilitation, and reseeding with native seeds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7BFB36E09614AED911BCC11305D8356"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbd4264eebdb49e49169b1165503437f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, with respect to the Grand Canyon National Park; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef354045f51c4ebd834989a15797a6f1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, with respect to the Kaibab National Forest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f8f98dd6d594be8865a8e190aab9c79"><enum>(5)</enum><header>White Sage Fire</header><text>The term <term>White Sage Fire</term> means the wildfire that began near Fredonia, Arizona, on July 9, 2025, and was contained on September 12, 2025.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H75DF373E97F0487D883D41886F03DAA1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Emergency contracting authority</header><subsection id="H86FAD08ACDAC4F87AF6AA77869ED1649"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned may use emergency acquisition flexibilities under part 18 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), including increased micro-purchase thresholds, simplified acquisition thresholds, and other authorities described in subpart 18.2 of that part, in contracting for the following services within the covered area:</text><paragraph id="H58D41E48A4A2448AA2F00FB9027BE70A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forest management or restoration activities carried out in response to the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DF65B1EB22747F5BA9ADAC49E29C5C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rebuilding, planning, development, and design of structures affected by the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40D6BA2FCB734685B9DD3C621DF16B57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improvements to the grounds and structures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF628F8C0955746A280A90EE9ED82F1A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Other recovery efforts necessary for the economic and ecological well-being of the covered area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01AEFA0440F040CEABF9839481F7E7B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process for other services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided by law or regulation, the authority granted under subsection (a) shall not apply to contracts for services other than those described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of that subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2C57E9D5C5AB41C7B20A88C6D73AED40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned begins to use the authority under subsection (a), and every 180 days thereafter until the date that is 180 days after the date described in subsection (e), the Secretary concerned shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Natural Resources and Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided0fbcd460a444c994cfeb4b4fba7532"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all expenditures of the Secretary concerned related to the recovery efforts for the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable, in the covered area, including—</text><subparagraph id="H70C0CDC013EE46B8BBAC9A913E7E176D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the expected cost of recovery efforts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFD14C9CB0704F14AEC2A7A44634B5D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of cost expenditures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB29B1E7999BB4DE68B4A3AF23D3AB350"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of cost overruns;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB0F755A5C3F42D8A3C30394692F8915"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the identification of contractors performing the work associated with the recovery from the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE401E66667674C7D8F1C9D7C594D1A26"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of any affiliations or conflicts of interest between—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55f073203539419d81a9b88fe1e4b9e6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contractor; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8e75e691ef0422eab7bd863e8ae621f"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idf458b31ce0054d95a280a3dc4036957f"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contracting office at the Grand Canyon National Park or the National Park Service; or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9700ff98e504fb9aa0815b87609f4c8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the contracting office at the Kaibab National Forest or the Forest Service;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0815E500B9FA4522BD64CA339D822F13"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of any waste, fraud, or abuse detected during the recovery efforts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C834110F52E418EA0A125ED15334601"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the identification of any contracts that came in under expected expenses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82EA1BCB8A7943AC8AD11CD190AA09E3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an estimated time of completion for all projects and full recovery efforts related to the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E2BAD615B6047F991F313D01C2FEB0B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of whether an extension is needed for the authority to complete projects associated with the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida963e7ef9b5043e997b817c54d8bdba9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any progress with respect to recovery efforts by the Secretary concerned in the covered area relating to the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable, during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H113436B5C7C74697900D9D94B9FAF4C1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If, after the date of enactment of this Act, a new wildfire ignites within the covered area that impacts recovery efforts relating to the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable, the Secretary concerned may request a 1-year extension of the authority granted under subsection (a), subject to congressional approval.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE621F198F4F8471F8AFD5CD3180DA538"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>The authority granted under subsection (a) shall expire on the date that is the earlier of the following:</text><paragraph id="HC7058763009A4323850F69A6AF3143DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99D26F89340F4173B660CD7F2DF9B7B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The date on which recovery efforts within the covered area are determined by the Secretary concerned to be complete.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb452eb9917a049509b7e13909aefda78"><enum>5.</enum><header>Participation of Indian Tribes and local stakeholders</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5ff62c4f827490fb166e668c4352f00"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the conduct of planning, design, and reconstruction activities of the Secretary concerned relating to the recovery of the covered area in response to the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable, the Secretary concerned shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3c5978420344f3fac71a3a414438f93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">invite applicable Indian Tribes to participate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0dd0c03024194b3a97c0ddd0a68d138b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage with other applicable local stakeholders (including units of local government, nonprofit organizations, local businesses (including Tribal businesses), and community groups).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef15b82df4ae4ced94cfe1a3f84c6d36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tribal businesses and local businesses</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary concerned shall prioritize contracting with Tribal businesses and local businesses to carry out reconstruction activities relating to the recovery of the covered area in response to the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3216c6e35a4344d9bfcb7d7fd4739c17"><enum>6.</enum><header>Contracts with concessioners</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date described in section 4(e), to facilitate recovery efforts relating to the Dragon Bravo Fire or White Sage Fire, as applicable, in the covered area, the Secretary concerned may enter into noncompetitive procurement contracts with existing National Park Service or Forest Service authorized concessioners in the covered area to carry out coordinated recovery efforts by the Secretary concerned and the concessioners at facilities in the covered area that are operated by the National Park Service, the Forest Service, or the concessioners, as applicable.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93bdb836ee694597a76588ca7aa9931f"><enum>7.</enum><header>Study and report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly conduct a study of, and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on, the costs of carrying out the recovery efforts authorized under this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

