<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCECB32433392461CAE466F61E2DBBD4B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1101 IH: Censuring Representative Tony Gonzales of Texas.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1101</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Censuring Representative Tony Gonzales of Texas.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Members of the House of Representatives are entrusted with positions of authority and are expected to uphold the highest standards of ethical conduct in both their official and personal interactions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas actions by Representative Tony Gonzalez of the State of Texas failed to meet even the minimum standards of ethical conduct by having an affair with a member of his staff;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas alleged text messages between Representative Tony Gonzales and this staff member have been published by multiple news outlets;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas those published messages include a request by Representative Gonzales where he asks the staff member to <quote>send [him] a sexy pic</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reporting further indicates that the staff member told Representative Gonzales the interaction was <quote>too far</quote>, yet the communications continued anyway;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a Member of Congress who solicits sexually explicit material from an employee under his authority abuses the inherent power imbalance in that relationship and betrays the trust placed in him by his staff, his constituents, and the House;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such communications between a Member of Congress and a subordinate staff member are incompatible with the standards of professionalism required of a Member of Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives (Code of Official Conduct) provides that a Member <quote>shall behave at all times in a manner that shall reflect creditably on the House</quote>; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the publication of these communications has undermined public trust in the integrity and professionalism of the House of Representatives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H74862CE3B3F2499B8B9B39CEA8C497C4"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H01016F4FE43B4040ACD8601701D8D5A2"><enum/><text>That—</text><paragraph id="H01017AF4069E455EB2A29768684A38C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the House of Representatives hereby censures Representative Tony Gonzales of Texas for conduct that has brought discredit upon the House;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H321A89B039BD492BAAB3A861AC5B7C89"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Tony Gonzales shall present himself in the well of the House for the pronouncement of censure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A9EF44F6512493DBAFA16BD658DED44"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">this resolution be entered into the Journal of the House as an expression of the House’s condemnation of the conduct described herein.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

