<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA27FF93A50E4DB0942D1C9A2DC111B4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7389 IH: Motor Vehicle Modernization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7389</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modernize the motor vehicle safety programs of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEF2B6ACBB7BE4677901215CC68212FC4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBA97FE13536B485DA9E8294EA6F6036D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Motor Vehicle Modernization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9859FC5097014E09AA6682EFEF5AF757" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H534EE4657C4E48E6B21C4FF06CE58FDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability of certain definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The definitions in section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code, apply to this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H966F4FCEE708466788E80204B5607AA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act: </text> <paragraph id="H6C4F8D3EAE8F41FDBCB400A8B94B81EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> means the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47D70D855E8B4282BFDE690206EE62D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9CCBD8E735C4B01B649C5729C5BE6DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ADS-equipped vehicle</header><text>The term <term>ADS-equipped vehicle</term> means a motor vehicle equipped with an automated driving system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0821A94C637443BAAA96253AAF14AF66"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Automated driving system</header><text>The term <term>automated driving system</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF86C05B5168414689FECCAF7558AEB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means hardware and software that are collectively capable of performing the entire dynamic driving task on a sustained basis, regardless of whether such system is limited to a specific operational design domain; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15460EEBD5A7474BAA6F4D6411CB97D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes only a system that meets the definition of Level 3, Level 4, or Level 5 automation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF29345381BDC4AF0B023E022D43BB23A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dynamic driving task</header><text>The term <term>dynamic driving task</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA9EDA1F3A5FA4764BC03C85545545B35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means each real-time operational and tactical function required to operate a motor vehicle in on-road traffic;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C3D0BE999FB416FB10780A45703BA14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excludes any strategic function, such as trip scheduling and selection of a destination or waypoint; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9611394F400C426280FBB3767169FD21"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes—</text> <clause id="H323CB22E1D2C417D9A7968507E3BA15C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lateral vehicle motion control through steering;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF56655DBF3084EB59DD0E5CA1A40B12A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>longitudinal motion control through acceleration and deceleration;</text></clause> <clause id="H30A5D409D53B4DF99178589C25D10197"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>monitoring of the driving environment through object and event detection, recognition, classification, and response preparation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8416FB83B79144869FE8EF48AE007C94"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>object and event response execution;</text></clause> <clause id="HB83E3270C42745DAB3E93C9172AE530B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>maneuver planning; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA9B44ADAD27B46FF9DEBAE853FD3EE73"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>enhancement of conspicuity through lighting, sounding the horn, signaling, gesturing, or another indicator.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46FB1D2DD1014528BF703DEF41588582"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Level 1; Level 2; Level 3; Level 4; Level 5</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Level 1</term>, <term>Level 2</term>, <term>Level 3</term>, <term>Level 4</term>, and <term>Level 5</term> have the meaning given those terms in the April 2021 edition of the J3016 recommended practice of SAE International, <quote>Taxonomy and Definitions for Terms Related to Driving Automation Systems for On-Road Motor Vehicles</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE82F7AF8148404281BE78A1A00C1730" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>New Car Assessment Program; NCAP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>New Car Assessment Program</term> and <term>NCAP</term> mean the program established by the Secretary pursuant to section 32302 of title 49, United States Code, to develop comparative information on the safety performance of passenger motor vehicle safety technologies to assist consumers with purchasing decisions and encourage manufacturers to improve the safety of passenger motor vehicles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E5E85EAA185450D8285F0282C131DD9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Passenger motor vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>passenger motor vehicle</term> has the meaning given that term in section 32101 of title 49, United States Code. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6085E836E472435FB840D98D0EC38689"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8437C17E0CD4B5FB9CED659B1B03D01"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE369931937D246759E64FA623FBA1B53" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Motor vehicle safety rulemaking and research priority plan</header> 
<subsection id="H0391BB05A1A34DFBAADA0B86200C8CDD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Priority plan requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall develop, and regularly update, a comprehensive motor vehicle safety rulemaking and research priority plan (in this section referred to as the <quote>priority plan</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1EA5A26DB2F34EA9980DD015BB426813"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority plan contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each priority plan submitted and published under subsection (c) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB01D876BBBAA429BBC6396583076D60E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of each motor vehicle safety rulemaking planned for the 36-month period beginning on the date on which the priority plan is submitted and published under subsection (c), including the following information with respect to each such rulemaking:</text> <subparagraph id="H4DC66BA61FAB4382B62D85AA20BB885A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any statutory authority, mandate, or deadline for such rulemaking.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62253FE79CBF45FFACA535178B78F786"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The status of any research required to support such rulemaking and a link to a publicly accessible website that contains such research.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H960E67C941FE4208A8A072BA41D261F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether any motor vehicle safety technology relevant to such rulemaking has been included in the NCAP.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9743D9A843E43BE80F89DA8C601A2F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether manufacturers or other entities with expertise in the engineering and testing of motor vehicles have developed performance test criteria for evaluating any such motor vehicle safety technology and whether such criteria could be used or modified to meet the objectives of such rulemaking.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H377B785DBE244828B74E7AC2EF22B62D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The timing of expected milestones with respect to such rulemaking, including an advance notice of proposed rulemaking, a notice of proposed rulemaking, and a final rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5B76C81738149A8999268647C86C057"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of the research priorities that the Administration anticipates working on (without regard to whether a rulemaking is planned or any research has been finalized) during the 36-month period beginning on the date on which the priority plan is submitted and published under subsection (c), including information on the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6E13BD33ED174FE180D6CDFCDCA9EC8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The objectives of such research priorities, including an identification of any rulemaking to be supported by a research priority.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94283AFAAE0F47A5B9CEDB873C663580"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any information, data, or evidence gathered in the NCAP with respect to such research priorities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B22A03445764AF78C203056A5B06946"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The timing of expected milestones with respect to such research priorities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84ECA517F990470B9C5161F35C8A904B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except with respect to the initial priority plan submitted and published under subsection (c), a comparison of the contents of the priority plan to the contents of the previous version of the priority plan submitted and published under subsection (c).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF06CB353E5204271B7182C4DF1F36740" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of each motor vehicle safety rulemaking required by an Act of Congress but not included in the priority plan and a timeline of when the Administration intends to complete each such rulemaking.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HED7EDF2BA256476DA431EAA7F18A8EC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission; publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H65B30FB69D1245179DAC91B70631A397"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the priority plan to the relevant congressional committees; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD62CB42BE3546E29B97EFFCD60CE8C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish the priority plan on the website of the Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HACD3C41B2A5D49EEB42AAD593289C73E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator fails to submit or publish the priority plan under subsection (c) by a date required under such subsection, the Administrator, not later than 30 days after such date, shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a written report that describes the reasons for such failure and provides an updated timeline and plan for submitting or publishing the priority plan.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9C859B2BE6D444699994CD1D982AED73" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>New Car Assessment Program reform</header> 
<subsection id="H4624C515EF994E3284D69BFC26B74F5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>New Car Assessment Program Office</header> 
<paragraph id="H779971C8E10D4CA9876EAD48C9E518CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish an office within the Administration to be known as the Office of the New Car Assessment Program (in this section referred to as the <quote>NCAP Office</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD551CB0ABA64333B8A70B27A29B5404"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Associate Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The NCAP Office shall be led by an Associate Administrator who is selected by the Administrator and who has expertise in motor vehicle safety.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB898A469B15A491C981E1A5A1442F4BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Associate Administrator of the NCAP Office shall be the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H89CDC1ED42614A97B82A82D88207A8B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Advise the Administrator on each function of the NCAP.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0112CDD1A68F45BAAE7E72ED477B2B1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Administer the NCAP.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B717F11D55648DD9BD0D57F377CEDEA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Establish roadmaps for the implementation of the NCAP under section 32310 of title 49, United States Code (as amended by paragraph (4) of this subsection).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8E975A0F66243A7BFCBCD0D8C8BB960"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Establish a process for reporting results of the voluntary performance testing program under paragraph (5) of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB14696462D184D91BF04563A0961A3FA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Conduct consumer education activities under paragraph (6) of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FE73F2B26094A92A2D4E2616D60D56B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engage with the NCAP Advisory Committee established under subsection (b)(1) of this section, manufacturers, other relevant stakeholders, and the public as the primary representative of the NCAP.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A938ED7316D4404B471FAD7F4F54ECE"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluate and make determinations on including passenger motor vehicle safety technologies in the NCAP, including by—</text> 
<clause id="H854BC526080B47B1AB436150389D8A94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluating the reported results pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection; and</text></clause> <clause id="H99C13DC27A924B3384AE64435F4C518B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluating recommendations made by the NCAP Advisory Committee pursuant to subsection (b)(6)(D) of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5253C13818E4144B8BCE5BFB4AB2446"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Carry out any other related duties as determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8456157F982341DE8AFAA86E156A705F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>New Car Assessment Program roadmap</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 32310 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07F5A94D29984CA68EF54507263C7F88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H8A3E69A72A9D45558571C76E1545662B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>4</quote> and inserting <quote>3</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD4EA80057CA64E289CB25A8220C23758"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>)</quote> and inserting <quote>the Associate Administrator, in consultation with the NCAP Advisory Committee,</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8272EAC6440242CDA6E4A62FD5D36D1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(3)(C), by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Associate Administrator</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H903C80A8B5354CCAB70BAA4E7187A9D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Associate Administrator</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H694B07B258184FBAAE3AF2FA06980A8D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), by striking <quote>Secretary</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Associate Administrator</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB143A51C2E65413F8947D03542C69D9D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H15EDD283D4284DD9A467969904FBFEA3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HB50D0D2AE2D3426F9C02C8333DDDC61E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEBEA6EC71D2245D7AE52B01D56984F8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Associate Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Associate Administrator</term> means the Associate Administrator selected under section 4(a)(2) of the Motor Vehicle Modernization Act of 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF587B4016E6D422A8436468724B25C31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NCAP Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>NCAP Advisory Committee</term> means the NCAP Advisory Committee established under section 4(b)(1) of the Motor Vehicle Modernization Act of 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3D0EEF6ED184425A118C480FC82DA7A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Voluntary performance testing program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Associate Administrator of the NCAP Office shall establish a voluntary process under which a manufacturer may test the performance of passenger motor vehicles of the manufacturer and report the results to the Associate Administrator.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B4A7BBD76694A5CBD89B30CB651841D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consumer education activities</header> <subparagraph id="H7A3A449676D447698B6677547854411F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Associate Administrator of the NCAP Office, in coordination with the Associate Administrator for Communications and Consumer Information, shall conduct consumer education activities to promote information developed under the NCAP and increase consumer awareness of passenger motor vehicle safety technologies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8ED3D367FA494DE894E9875FAF1D7D61"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consumer education activities carried out under subparagraph (A) may include the following:</text> <clause id="H54E7523AEEE04F6D9F63119919294DB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Development and distribution of written educational materials.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4D7C5A1C201540DC81F0EE480A74186B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Creation, production, and dissemination of public awareness campaigns, including through print, broadcast, digital, and social media platforms.</text></clause> <clause id="HA0B34EB004DC4CB3A13AD206ABF7DAFC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Purchase of advertising time and space in any media, including television, radio, digital, and print.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6679FB5232FE4896843657C5BB25A804"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Establishment and maintenance of websites, mobile applications, and other online content.</text></clause> <clause id="H2D219F72B3C84EF7843CCCD1E68BE3FE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Engagement with community-based and national consumer motor vehicle safety organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F02793709E843698ED10E90BD741231"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Associate Administrator of the NCAP Office shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report that details the consumer education activities conducted under this paragraph, including, with respect to such activities, information on—</text> <clause id="H595863059A3B4604AB526C4AC3F6B84E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expenditures;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H852DD64EFF1044E6AF2F1E558462BB56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>target audiences reached; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE351FDFFB31C467E99603B392F5B18DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any performance metrics used to evaluate the efficacy of such activities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D6B6EFB7FA84527981AAD6E7BCE4247"><enum>(b)</enum><header>New Car Assessment Program Advisory Committee</header> 
<paragraph id="HE6A05BAE652640679397D9F5258DCC1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish the NCAP Advisory Committee (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to provide independent advice and recommendations to the Secretary, the Administrator, and the Associate Administrator of the NCAP Office on matters related to the functions of the NCAP Office.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99071544EF9648C39099043976E0D2B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall be composed of 18 members, appointed by the Administrator, as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H11C90DBD1C1544BE9CA6512740126617"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 representatives of national consumer motor vehicle safety organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E4B40348A2547E5BDDD1BEC70D6084C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 representatives of institutions of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) with expertise in motor vehicle safety.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H798FA8AF2B1043B0AF79DED1D67E3ED3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>4 representatives of manufacturers of passenger motor vehicles.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF18B931B64F641FAA27BFBCBFCC47862"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 representatives of manufacturers of motor vehicle equipment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37CA3BA5D24D4CEEB6EE7A7D36FEB7AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>1 representative of technology providers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF38AA5C38B0248B39168E2ACEF8C2112"><enum>(F)</enum><text>1 representative of the property and casualty insurance industry.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0AB7A656FDE4B29AC8F5ECB74733BDC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>1 representative of State highway safety offices.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADAE817B2CBF4E6B8508E5A35973EB99"><enum>(H)</enum><text>2 members with expertise in public health, data science, or human factors.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9982460CA014FCEBD563E4C85B5B754"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 representative of a disability advocacy organization.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6BE03B004F34830A5F8549009B50404"><enum>(J)</enum><text>2 representatives of families or organizations that advocate on behalf of victims of accidents involving motor vehicles.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1B164B40B244A058168393777E80DE7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header> 
<subparagraph id="H38970948DBE64317A088A4C7E1359FAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member appointed to the Committee—</text> <clause id="H2E1771B2AD244B29BF2EACE00527C809"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall serve an initial term of 4 years (or until the Committee terminates under paragraph (8), if earlier); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H32AE8E3413C94DD79CB31BB2C89E925E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be reappointed for 1 subsequent term of 4 years (or until the Committee terminates under paragraph (8), if earlier).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3391D75B7A6C420FB8A10FA94084C188"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A)(i), with respect to the first 18 members appointed to the Committee, 9 shall be chosen by the Administrator to serve an initial term of 2 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32E285DA55F74BFFBD42DC010034DA01"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rate of pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Committee shall serve without pay.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E51AF0207E345F5904C638CAE0F0B11"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Committee shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13AFAC611A8B48D7B17422AA4711EDE3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Committee shall be the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HE3FA73CD24E147948D7FA327BE176418"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide recommendations to the Secretary, the Administrator, and the Associate Administrator of the NCAP Office to improve the NCAP.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22BC539CBC6549BDB28C5316C65BE08C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Review, assess, and evaluate passenger motor vehicle safety technologies with the potential to reduce traffic injuries and fatalities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCD316B4A6D8406DAF64472882E7A0F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solicit and review information, data, research, and evidence with respect to passenger motor vehicle safety technologies from public and private sources, including industry stakeholders, researchers, national consumer motor vehicle safety organizations, and Federal agencies (as determined appropriate by the Administrator).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0BBCFF06CF4405693FC2BE52A73057C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommend passenger motor vehicle safety technologies to be evaluated by the Associate Administrator of the NCAP Office for inclusion in the NCAP.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF13430D043D4F9CBD8ACB0CF284FFA0" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and in consultation with the Administration, manufacturers, national consumer motor vehicle safety organizations, experts in academia, and other relevant stakeholders, the Committee shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report that assesses the feasibility of establishing a public-private partnership, a nonprofit organization, or any other similar entity to develop, update, and operate the functions of the NCAP, including by assessing the following with respect to such a partnership or entity:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEFB6CDF08B0D4EF890918E611028984C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Governance considerations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H999C5EFA50DA4F72B9FCEDDBC8330F89" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Structure.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC2C3A98B10E4F9F9F5D8234C137895F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Efficacy in educating consumers on and encouraging manufacturers to include new safety features in passenger motor vehicles.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB01C675A6ECD4B879D81ACABE0FF3CDF" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Impact on motor vehicle safety.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F9A57CE25E141E1A7E82B703540AF92" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Passenger motor vehicle safety ratings used internationally that are similar to the NCAP.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3050C20C89045F68B9B454B868B7DC8" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Expected cost of such a partnership or entity as compared to the cost of maintaining the NCAP under the Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F7359608342417784CF31903337158F" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sustainable funding mechanisms. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H136AE80B586E4C5C9692A406CC98C651" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Processes for ensuring the NCAP (or any partnership or entity responsible for developing, updating, and operating the functions of the NCAP) informs the development of motor vehicle safety standards prescribed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9B96FF5A06449999922642AE14FEACE" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monroney label considerations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H846819625E4F4378951887DCCD3919C5" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs associated with participation by manufacturers in the NCAP, including any alternatives for manufacturers to self-report information related to passenger motor vehicle safety ratings from the manufacturers.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA9F71C513F045B78770B26AB1E58750" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Processes for ensuring the independence of the partnership or entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H412E26A1CE214E79A014D5B6C790590D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date on which the Committee is established under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBAAEE7150374470AB8CCDAAFAED9C31"><enum>(9)</enum><header>FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply to the Committee.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H42A5438AE8A24277BD1A124069B6E08C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB73B7333FF3244E8B858D5BBC93EFB93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluates the implementation of this section, including the amendments made by this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87F6ED8C073B416487DE86278C8F4DFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides recommendations for the Administrator and the relevant congressional committees to improve the implementation of this section, including the amendments made by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2EF6F1E76AD47A4ACA3615161939145" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Passenger motor vehicle safety rating defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>passenger motor vehicle safety rating</term> means a system to evaluate and compare in an objective manner passenger motor vehicle safety technologies using stars, medals, points, or other similar indicators. </text></subsection></section> <section id="H8062C186DC1049BA8DC04FCD2279EC30" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Review of motor vehicle safety standards</header> <subsection id="HD6240D745BFD4E498C97366252BE0367"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 4 years thereafter, the Administrator shall conduct a review of the motor vehicle safety standards prescribed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, to determine, in accordance with this section, if any such standards should be revised or eliminated.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCD7E7A1799564EFC9BB20319A5384540"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determinations</header> 
<paragraph id="HB7D47EC2340E449FA426A824878673DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a determination under subsection (a) with respect to whether a motor vehicle safety standard should be revised or eliminated, the Administrator shall consider the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HE041E8EC16304588B9288D7C17FBF8DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The extent to which such standard satisfies the purpose described in section 30101 of title 49, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83CBC4FD36144171A3189A89D768AF57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Safety information, data, and evidence related to such standard.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D11ED1B840647D9A061FEC7736B19A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on advances in motor vehicle technology related to such standard.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62615CCD1C3A48ED8C50FB9E0870E2C4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs for manufacturers related to such standard.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD79304B452F4734910BD6C5ABE747CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Changes in technical standards related to such standard.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A91991955A549E0B314BBA8EE1E51CD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">International policy developments related to such standard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26F08D9FEF3B4906AF90F1C019A84E1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public feedback</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In reviewing motor vehicle safety standards under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8609CC9CD7FC40F5AE12A27E36EEAB91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicit public feedback through a request for information; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A02ADF4AA144F1AAC3CB57D54C79966"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a period for public comment on the responses to such request for information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00C49EEDDB5843DBA139C608EBCB9F81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consistency with motor vehicle safety</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may only make a determination under this section that a motor vehicle safety standard should be revised or eliminated if the Administrator determines that doing so is consistent with motor vehicle safety.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0E69D1AD814940BFA22201385D871587"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the completion of each review conducted under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA5F3081B5C494128B9E324CEC1C84B82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the results of such review; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB84F5475F0914A1DA3B564666435EEAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate, into the first priority plan submitted and published under section 3(c) after the completion of such review, any recommendations of the Administrator with respect to revising or eliminating a motor vehicle safety standard.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9DE00876E47A454CA8BDF26E910ADAB7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking accountability report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 24210 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/308">49 U.S.C. 308</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDF3C1ADC9AEA470D9FC29C96BFC15684"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H88AAA37480274587942E341A013D5545" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H1AC9F7DA168F41F78CC8CBB63BE22E9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is associated with the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration and—</text> <subparagraph id="H8051A66B01A44F5AB2FA878C53677202"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is carried out pursuant to—</text> 
<clause id="HD9B63A92C5784416BE5C203DC5DC3C73"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">MAP–21;</text></clause> <clause id="H829BBE2AA95C4FE19F4CABC820AE3DCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the FAST Act;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7A5E3A5CDD3346D9B3CB38609A2AA0A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>this Act; or</text></clause> <clause id="H236A9D676FAA49669DD01AB64596F829"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Motor Vehicle Modernization Act of 2026; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F2178A3E74B4DD9AA3483608E973358"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is included in the most recent Unified Agenda of Federal Regulatory and Deregulatory Actions and is required by an Act of Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33BC5F9083DD4F139966BF4AB818BCEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H96810D1BA3104C41839306552E9F77AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>an explanation</quote> and inserting <quote>if such deadline has passed, an explanation</quote>; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE0745C8982D43E38DFB87B3699863DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7912EECA507B466983F6BEFBF1D6352A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F1150BA59154F60A4591DC87CE42EA2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9C532D2A7EF64D7C9C9365A7514DABF2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HFF27A2D0261A4200811A7E754167F1A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of substantive activities conducted, including any relevant research conducted, and rulemaking milestones completed with respect to the covered rulemaking.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HA3481ED6ECCC4D6DA2D6CDCFE5C7E1C3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Project schedule management practices</header> <subsection id="HCDA5C541093844AB8CE3338452AF8D29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemakings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall update the procedures associated with rulemakings related to motor vehicle safety to ensure—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBF088F05F543400E911155ED3C521F68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use of recognized project schedule management practices; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DB8040ABE704ADBBA73CB58DCBCCD08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adherence to applicable Federal standards with respect to such practices.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3DB9557721D5422484A50A27400871B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall update the procedures associated with satisfying reporting requirements related to motor vehicle safety to ensure—</text> <paragraph id="H6C6FFEAD14164091912FA9EDD246DB4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use of recognized project schedule management practices; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97C19DC3C946406D9FE30EC4315BB512"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adherence to applicable Federal standards with respect to such practices.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC72186FB8A3B4DE1ADBB3C736D7295B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO study</header> <paragraph id="H973BC2F568A5456AA4B902A2095FE6A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to assess the implementation of this section by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D3DEFB884E04A229F2A08B5B6341D64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5EC128600B894F258C00F14C38D4B997" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>General exemptions</header> <subsection id="HC7937D28B7244999B4F3DB42E7F9B7B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Process guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue guidance to establish and make available processes, including performance-based or risk-based assessments, by which a manufacturer may demonstrate an equivalent safety level for purposes of clause (ii) or (iv) of section 30113(b)(3)(B) of title 49, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8983F54F9BF462495758D3B63109BD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30113(d) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>2,500 vehicles</quote> and inserting <quote>90,000 vehicles</quote>. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H880BAC3BD45E45E79AE3A1E3F8361D90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maximum period</header><text>Section 30113(e) of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDFEAFD48C70D40C58534A838CF6A085A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H44A9D1C941634B0783FD93D35B7A940D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maximum period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An exemption or renewal under subsection (b)(3)(B) of this section may be granted for not more than 5 years.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H0844F932CB8E47C08CD614A299672900"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Section 30113 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1965F16B493244A48EFD437BF26CCF5A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H62E133CA5D6240EDB8C01E11F445D5F0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Deadline</header> 
<paragraph id="HF3610D2DACBC406DB7A688D2157A7219"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall issue a decision with respect to a complete application for an exemption submitted under this section not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary receives such application.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1E7BD64014F49A58DC26C40285D0032"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to meet deadline</header><text>If the Secretary does not issue a decision with respect to a complete application within the period required under paragraph (1), the application shall be deemed approved unless the Secretary provides to the applicant during such period written justification that identifies the manner in which the application is incomplete.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAB6247663D61467F84F51086F7458590" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>9.</enum><header>Testing and evaluation of motor vehicle equipment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 30112(b)(10) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H806DD705680E4C55993746C7A15AB7AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or motor vehicle equipment</quote> after <quote>motor vehicle</quote> each place the term appears; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7D9DCC9E7654A378B0CC2A2C30FCC20"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or motor vehicle equipment</quote> after <quote>motor vehicles</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBE787ECC006F4C06A2C70AD48A01B1B9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>10.</enum><header>Recall rate improvement</header> <subsection id="H4B02A2E528CD4C70B9065EB0D2F752ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct a study to identify factors that result in a motor vehicle involved in a recall not receiving the service necessary to remedy the issue that is the subject of such recall.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC5AF25F04524F9988B9F6C54F4FA144"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, using existing authorities, shall take appropriate actions to—</text> <paragraph id="HC0405A82899A417F8530B30EC3A195DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>address factors identified under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB31440094DFA445685683FC3B9D184B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve the efforts of the Administration, manufacturers, and third parties with respect to increasing the rate at which motor vehicles involved in a recall receive the service necessary to remedy the issue that is the subject of such recall.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5BB8CF86B0FB4CF29A83477108A89F88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H5E7468D2840341D8A7B4F1734E6EE710"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H364901A856B54D18AB605ADCBE9A22C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the actions taken by the Administrator under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3A78D4414C7042B69B6DDCA1BBB03A41" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>11.</enum><header>Modern recall notification procedures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 30119(d) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE7E4A3AFD0954062A01673CC9AA3C248"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by inserting <quote>(or other form of contact information)</quote> after <quote>address</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54F5EBDFB8B544CB939B6C1B45D5ED09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H206400ACF47347B4A5B8D4809B60A1BB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H8DB38FEF96FA418D9F007A4462D69CE5" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification required under section 30118 of this title may be sent by certified mail, electronic mail, or any other manner (including other electronic means) prescribed by the Secretary by regulation, except that, if a registered owner provides a request to a manufacturer through a reasonable means (as determined by the manufacturer) asking that such notification be made by certified mail, such manufacturer shall comply with such request with respect to such registered owner.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H7BB4AB7393A441E793768397C2357AF8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>12.</enum><header>Clarification with respect to defects and noncompliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 30118 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H65F76DF0A2364BBCAE0A26F8E9222887" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H15EF14B09EFF41CD990B637C36652CE3" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="H5C040C56103C44F784E459F88F659E50" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The requirement to notify under subsection (c) does not apply to a manufacturer until such time as the manufacturer makes the relevant decision under paragraph (1) or (2) of such subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFE24EFC580946D386C96FEDF8FB69FE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplier notifications</header><text>A notification of defect with respect to original equipment made by the original equipment supplier is not determinative of whether a defect exists in a motor vehicle in which the original equipment was installed at the time of delivery to the first purchaser. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46F8794F564A43218054066E1A2544ED" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Good faith</header><text>Nothing in this subsection relieves a manufacturer of any obligation under subsection (c) to make a decision in good faith.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H03A4A9D565F545B5AE4133F7F15B92E4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>13.</enum><header>Consumer education on motor vehicle automation</header> <subsection id="H71AE2C15D73C4E7AB453DFF860C9A485"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of working group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish a working group to facilitate consumer education efforts with respect to automation in motor vehicles.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77CFB7476EC441DA9DB04956B0FFF4A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The working group established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H327192605BBA46AB82D0ED5F1C305E99"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations to the Administrator on education and marketing strategies, including strategies that may be voluntarily employed by industry stakeholders, to responsibly inform the public, including vehicle owners and operators, about the differences between motor vehicles equipped with Level 1 or Level 2 systems and ADS-equipped vehicles; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5250AE8218714671B673ED1B96B0DBA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 3 years after the date on which the working group is established, submit to the relevant congressional committees, and make available to the public, a report containing such recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEB86307CE4E640FCA271553D8A550290"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties described in subsection (b), the working group shall consider the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H99FEBD506FC14D58A0124A77BF182F20" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The respective capabilities and limitations of motor vehicles equipped with Level 1 or Level 2 systems and ADS-equipped vehicles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30A5BD7C02844B1CA6CCB1A3BBCC5722"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The engagement methods with respect to motor vehicles equipped with Level 1 or Level 2 systems and ADS-equipped vehicles, including disengagement methods with respect to ADS-equipped vehicles.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBC0C63FF55A4C4F8DF7A4269A01A140"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The human-machine interfaces with respect to motor vehicles equipped with Level 1 or Level 2 systems and ADS-equipped vehicles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96BACB7BE80E450FBC361E2311B0AD7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Responses in the event of a crash or system failure, including emergency fallback scenarios, with respect to motor vehicles equipped with Level 1 or Level 2 systems and ADS-equipped vehicles.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E5B7498E4344969AACA1D720310E892"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The value of consistent nomenclature and taxonomy for technology features and systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BBA450E04844A029C63D0D2CC992CEE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The role of the New Car Assessment Program in facilitating public understanding of the differences between motor vehicles equipped with Level 1 or Level 2 systems and ADS-equipped vehicles.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54831B8EC2CE4EEE89BBAE220DDF0829"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="HD504386EDEC44B729A97E7D015E9595D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall appoint, as members of the working group established under subsection (a), individuals with expertise in motor vehicle automation technology, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H307B3B8D634D4581929A4393BE57A085"><enum>(A)</enum><text>representatives of—</text> 
<clause id="H116C7C8B1B2E4EBABE20D633DF7747A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>manufacturers;</text></clause> <clause id="H442A427391414C2A8E724A2BBC4A1774"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>dealers;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBD89A737FFC24CEC92CFCC0FC401142B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>motor vehicle owners and operators, including fleet managers, rental companies, and transportation network companies;</text></clause> <clause id="HFCA645CA810D47A88CA2FF35C79C3EB2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>consumers or consumer advocacy groups;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE23D47C33624089AD9262C5E964F742"><enum>(v)</enum><text>marketing professionals;</text></clause> <clause id="H2AA90EF70E3A4FCE84A05F954702F7F9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>entities with national experience in consumer education, including drivers’ education;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9930D28458E54AC1B5D04D4C4F23B944"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>safety organizations; and </text></clause> <clause id="H7EE9476E94844119B37856C501886D8D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>national disability organizations and national organizations representing older adults; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFCC26074DB84488AC5C1F4450D30DDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other individuals the Administrator considers appropriate and qualified.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF05D8E022C644D4835D19352DCC5D88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the working group established under subsection (a) shall serve without compensation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B02AC21BC9442879990E1BAEE88A192"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the working group established under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9E425EDE01934C61B874BFFEFBB6EA8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Federal Trade Commission, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE6C16C1D734476FAB3F5D4F018FA882"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure public participation, including by soliciting input through requests for information. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E501EAE01F745D382D7E0A86517026F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The working group established under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date on which the working group submits the report required under subsection (b)(2).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6CD4DFC2FF5C4A559EBD3CCEAE0544C9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply to the working group established under subsection (a).</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H680D7FDA21584A18A9D950C564F84F79" section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no"><enum>14.</enum><header>Study on passenger motor vehicle ownership</header> <subsection id="H688DBAE2628E44A9AC3743803C9F5A80" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine under which the National Academies shall conduct a study on the average age of passenger motor vehicles and passenger motor vehicle ownership costs. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FC7293AF0CF49E39E93CC96FB15DA52" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study conducted under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H02C4B1C9BF1E46CE833BCCBEB5D16514" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Trends with respect to the average age of passenger motor vehicles.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49B0DF32A79B440295996ECA8512BE10" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Trends with respect to passenger motor vehicle ownership costs, including trends with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H51DDA6E35A3A4EFDA11D6BAFE55E5C33" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>total lifecycle costs; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5144D48460614371B9FF909D9C108363" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>related factors, including—</text> <clause id="HC472F94783A24F99B7696CC1E87900B3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>initial purchase price;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDF7FBF9E7685497A81E84DB95148BEF1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>motor vehicle manufacturing and supply chain matters;</text></clause> <clause id="H04F5944AC2FC4DE0A306E907A6EDF56B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>financing;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0ECBACDABA0D4590A25C7D0DD1A5D611" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>insurance;</text></clause> <clause id="HEC3166457CA949A0A03E6374AC94D915" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>subscriptions;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9D5AE70537794443AFC48FC154A5C785" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>power requirements, such as with respect to electricity, gasoline, and other fuels;</text></clause> <clause id="HB2BF5918F7EE4ED7AC3C4F08E9ED3B05" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>repair and maintenance;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4B8B529D929148F7ABDAF3A50E989840" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>depreciation;</text></clause> <clause id="H1F974D376A8741629A21B6AB66654173" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>optional safety features; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H66555423349F42BAA654543449689250" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>optional convenience features.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18F4977E2CA94C7695824530F32B747A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Legal, policy, economic, and regulatory factors that affect the average age of passenger motor vehicles, passenger motor vehicle ownership costs, and consumer understanding of such costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4E0D2BBC27DF438BAE1709E6CA2A13FD" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9B61CBA201C3418BAA189A15B72F3544" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>15.</enum><header>Automated wheelchair securement systems</header> <subsection id="H396686F9281E43448435B412E4804C91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct a study on the feasibility of incorporating, into motor vehicles, automated wheelchair securement systems to increase the safety of wheelchair users in motor vehicles.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7ABFC02D4389483D92CBCD6489E38168"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with university transportation centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with university transportation centers established and operated under section 5505 of title 49, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEC515D5D57D9441C8A24DE6E893DC679"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the relevant congressional committees and make publicly available a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a) that includes an analysis of the feasibility of incorporating, into motor vehicles, automated wheelchair securement systems.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0BA87699B51D41FEB950694EA850E44C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Automated wheelchair securement system defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>automated wheelchair securement system</term> means an automated system that, using a universal docking interface geometry standard, secures a wheelchair within a motor vehicle utilizing a deployable anchor.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA1CA506549754098A16B26597AA1C02A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>16.</enum><header>Study on modernizing vehicle identification numbers</header> <subsection id="HDAC93B4F5B894B0891540E87E5535D75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct a study on modernizing the VIN system.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7999FC129BA4B2EB34290A6270BC076"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study required by subsection (a) shall analyze the following:</text> <paragraph id="H0E770AC3AB6E408FA25D5687BC2E6088"><enum>(1)</enum><text> How the VIN system is used by the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF48FE70AE33E4D949029850F94146875"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3109922478344E13BBA2BAF3A17E4DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Heads of other relevant Federal agencies (as determined by the Administrator).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7CABB85FA3564957ACAE1F637C141790"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State and local governments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H603C5B3BF11545B4A97AADF0B0EA4D31"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Manufacturers.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54162FF9EA7A4C4FAF492AB8B240D988"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Law enforcement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BB6C2A1A93D4C5A81DAA2A02A203E88"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The property and casualty insurance industry.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H725CAAF264BF4D38814A126119D2ECB4"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other user the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13783025266741F4A86823CDF6D5313A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any limitations of the VIN system, including with respect to motor vehicle safety and regulatory compliance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF501AA2AC56C4E8989F763A21E349891"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations for Congress and the Administration to improve the VIN system, including with respect to motor vehicle attributes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE113EE857B1C43578FAAE642BDAEFD81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study required by subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0FDEC7999527484EB311CBBEC50D26E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State motor vehicle agencies that are responsible for the registration and titling of motor vehicles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45014B0BDB20477DBD7855175B8273D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State and local law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3757D8F3E0E7400AB061ABE5D0AB3DD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Emergency responders.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A3E39285A7D4FB49AC82187CF58F296"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Roadway safety organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEDE5A29AFFA41BB9E0865401FC89867"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Consumer motor vehicle safety organizations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H872DD73966EC4F47A968C023BE13B5E1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>International standards organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9621B12736DF498FA386F4503BBB399D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Manufacturers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6CB392DDC4E4176BE92D051FC205145"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Dealers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CE99370A4664ED3A529474788D7AA58"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The property and casualty insurance industry.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B15BA70CE304C608EA5073F72F9C2C5"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other stakeholder the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E29FAD830204E3AB268874A20EF3E8C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the results of the study required by subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAF47B417BED04268B84A139CCEAA9A22"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HED0F6352ECDD4021BE642F1F66E61EAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Motor vehicle attributes</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle attributes</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3D50CA71E4E340AB8CF233BAE69673C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Means of propulsion.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF47DA602D37E4624A62F02571EB233BF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Level 1, Level 2, Level 3, Level 4, and Level 5 automation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29669949FCF14FDEBEB134CB32429BE9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Driver assistance technology.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7EFDC9CBA8F3476EACA3C65AF488CB02"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Electrification specification, including with respect to battery capacity and charging capability.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6BC882C77CAE4E5F8997B09781BFA0FA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Connectivity requirements. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1B0C0525BBD40A492E8B3445BEE1FAD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Over-the-air update capability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C7ACAD86BEB41C5AD8993932BE6955F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>VIN</header><text>The term <term>VIN</term> has the meaning given such term in section 565.12(b) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC42A5FA49CB8422E9ADE23BCDB9BBCEA"><enum>17.</enum><header>Motor Vehicle Fire Rescue Working Group</header> 
<subsection id="HB4AF48A06180421286167944908E90E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish the Motor Vehicle Fire Rescue Working Group (in this section referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>) to provide independent advice and recommendations to the Secretary and the Administrator on matters related to ensuring the safe and efficient extraction of occupants of motor vehicles post-crash.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE3283A6C78844039BAE1407CF6B1FA7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Working Group shall be composed of 15 members, appointed by the Administrator, as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H931DDFF7043A4D95B7CC9F14F3AE3077"><enum>(1)</enum><text>4 representatives of manufacturers of passenger motor vehicles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DAA0BDAE04B4CAD8DE17B5141EA119D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 representatives of national consumer motor vehicle safety organizations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9D64A2908C6402E9F9440DA23059CA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>4 representatives of organizations that represent first responders, including firefighters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9124CB7DC8240299106699DB084D56F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 representatives of institutions of higher education (as defined as section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) with expertise in motor vehicle and motor vehicle battery safety.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81A95B6AE63C4E748BC5D77D38F054E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>2 representatives of manufacturers of motor vehicle batteries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57844946024342F194F7F218F6A5EDBC"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 representative of manufacturers of fire rescue tools.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7C25C4C9A7994EA5ADE7928EB6A6F259"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms</header> 
<paragraph id="H20101D9BF0E04914BE8B16A6D6A0E7F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member appointed to the Working Group—</text> <subparagraph id="H51470824DF814B138C329C7D4353F7FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall serve an initial term of 4 years (or until the Working Group terminates under subsection (h), if earlier); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC79620A37F2D4F2A81D980E1F7ECD381"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be reappointed for 1 subsequent term of 4 years (or until the Working Group terminates under subsection (h), if earlier).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B1B08B51C20413880189C9BD97F15B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), with respect to the first 15 members appointed to the Working Group, 7 shall be chosen by the Administrator to serve an initial term of 2 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5FC411FE77A44A13B32FA58461B553F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rate of pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Working Group shall serve without pay.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H721821363C8E46E4B22BCE2B595CEC07"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member of the Working Group shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H49DBCD8E07F245AFB7E800D63A537031"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Working Group shall be the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4A1E2C9A861B44B1ADAB02EE750029EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Review, assess, and evaluate factors to facilitate the safe and efficient post-crash access of first responders to motor vehicles, including the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB50A19BA898446798CFB1CC3B0EFB024"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Post-crash fire rescue tools.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B20FB5C8A8345A98A096959CD389269"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Modifications to the design, construction, and performance of motor vehicles to improve access points for first responders.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DD0E65F018240DFB609915183C76F9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Standardized motor vehicle fuel type labeling.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD63EEF78323F4E82B150646CBDB6C499"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Fire suppression methods appropriate for motor vehicle batteries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA68F1C16F874B70875441550EEDB36F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any design or engineering of motor vehicle batteries that minimizes thermal runaway incidents.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9B334E6D829465498B72122B887540A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other relevant factor reviewed, assessed, and evaluated by the Working Group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03C1A2A031BD41999E164B2087226197"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Provide recommendations to the Secretary and the Administrator about the factors reviewed, assessed, and evaluated under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5924E58FDE1A4DB8B7B10BBF9938BE00"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Working Group shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report about the work the Working Group has done pursuant to subsection (f), including any recommendations provided pursuant to subsection (f)(2).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD50584F9CD084D4EA5A0E9F0C51DA043"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Working Group shall terminate on the date that is 60 days after the date on which the report is submitted pursuant to subsection (g).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0C8BBA6BCE814FB499BD6EC8813D3901"><enum>(i)</enum><header>FACA</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply to the Working Group.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H00098443E4EF4D2B853A0EDFFAE168E6" commented="no"><enum>18.</enum><header>Paperwork Reduction Act exemption</header> 
<subsection id="HDEFF6FD29FD2416D823AAD4D1B84013A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research efficiency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research performed by the Administrator pursuant to sections 30181, 30182, 30183, and 32502(g) of title 49, United States Code, is exempt from subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA0818DA3D8314626BA76B3DC382002F0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Committee efficiency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9D5A58F17FB94629B6D3262E9F316F40" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Solicitation of information, data, research, and evidence by the Committee pursuant to sections 30181, 30182, 30183, and 32502(g) of title 49, United States Code, is exempt from subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFB84FB8914944E692AA46DA02DB718C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committee defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>Committee</term> means the NCAP Advisory Committee established under section 4(b)(1) of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

