<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC26230-F6J-KF-0X5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4044 IS: Support for Astrophysical Observatories and National High-Energy Astrophysics Hubs Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4044</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260310">March 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to designate national high-energy astrophysics hubs.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id62343c5586bc4735a30910794f7819ad" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support for Astrophysical Observatories and National High-Energy Astrophysics Hubs Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="S1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Support for astrophysical observatories and national high-energy astrophysics hubs</header><subsection id="idef2eb4159d464a2ab5d6cda30ae18783"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id5456d8072d55446b93609225d168b3db"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should maintain its global leadership in high-energy astrophysics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc33a21f71f54dccba07e56aaaf83308"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in order to maintain such leadership, the United States should support X-ray flagship missions based on the recommendations of the most recent and future decadal Surveys in Astronomy and Astrophysics issued by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id682d542d31644315867ecdd8f8cc3c2e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the workforce associated with high-energy astrophysics constitutes a national strategic asset that will be critical to the development and eventual operation of any such flagship mission; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd513f90be81749c59a368ff96548842e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>proactive steps should be taken to ensure that the capabilities of current high-energy astrophysics facilities continue to serve the scientific, educational, and commercial interests of the United States long beyond the duration of the current high-energy astrophysics flagship mission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id622449faa2254d978e2ac4e6727c09f5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><paragraph id="idd2077ff0edf242a1b4bfd0ae29b15c66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall designate as a national high-energy astrophysics hub each eligible facility described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4e9173b446741d89f1a9fe695a53084"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible facility described</header><text>An eligible facility described in this paragraph is an entity that—</text><subparagraph id="id8d076319fd8743298761726820b73532"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7219accc4f914859a9ae34606913152d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is party to a contract with NASA; and</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id340a1f32acc44dc584bd44f40b6ff3d2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>plans and operates missions that conduct activities for purposes of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19f8a4f3c0ad454fa2fd360754d4e693"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensuring continued United States leadership in high-energy astrophysics and related space sciences;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6986b47a4a444ea5acd7fd7cde7d9797"><enum>(II)</enum><text>supporting training and workforce development in data-intensive high-energy astrophysics, aerospace engineering, and spacecraft operations;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2edfb6a39ee4abc9a4734a1d751f572"><enum>(III)</enum><text>advancing United States capabilities in high-performance scientific software, spaceflight operations, and technology transfer;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8d7731140ae46d8a826c14386e45b3d"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>enabling future high-energy astrophysics missions through mission design, planning, and scientific coordination; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfaa13e619e6b4012b185af156472b486"><enum>(V)</enum><text>serving as a collaborative national resource for academic, governmental, and commercial partners; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff46bb93acc14942820c5d0d2b7dd3e4"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9eed441146644cb49cf5665a3b2dd8ca"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an institution of higher education;</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4639924bafc40a287df1d0c023b09c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is an appropriate State or Federal entity, including a federally funded research and development center; or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b86c411ae0148ada00063d589811884"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a nongovernmental organization with expertise in advanced energy technology research, development, demonstration, or commercial application.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

