<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H51BE57A6F16646ECA6871DE98C6CE5F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8304 IH: Credential Repository and Transparency in States Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8304</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Labor to establish a grant program for States to improve or establish a credential repository, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2C6E9B04DA18422DBD08E69B2B942591" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC58E8B5865BC4B29BAF47885B976E934" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Credential Repository and Transparency in States Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CREATES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H14C6595D70FD4410BD886FBE98CB0DEE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to provide assistance to States for the collection, development, analysis, and sharing of information on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H239C48E46A1D4704AB571CCC087763D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all of the credentials offered in each State;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00525946C337498DB6E13440D4BD2323"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the quality of such credentials, including their use by employers for making employment-related decisions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC376FF1F38314B458C99A3E10F782383"><enum>(3)</enum><text>education and career pathways that lead to such credentials and occupations in a State; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DE45C36268B42649BACE8390F222B19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the sharing of such information with individuals in each State, enabling them to make informed education and career choices.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC44E660FEB024A028F32CA6CD745A76C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program Authorized</header> 
<subsection id="HCC9B2143A74146BFA6837FAB1B38B6ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization and limitations</header> 
<paragraph id="H26F6DB5EBA6D422C80F4FF9A33DE4386"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts made available under section 4, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to States to establish, expand, or improve a State credential repository that contains information on each covered program, credential, and training provider in the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1D7A8C1BE9C402D9343841E86052D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this Act shall be awarded for a period of 3 years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC822D10CFF54D2A90524790AF336B9A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>In awarding a grant under this Act, the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H4922A48D908446468EFFBE91581C9578"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not award a grant in excess of $10,000,000; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H507B96521F2A4D4EACC20E038BD5FEA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in deciding the amount of a grant, shall take into consideration—</text> <clause id="HBEE697C0FC9B4AADB49DE5C968B8B679"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of credentials offered in the State; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC2E2136F60C941A3A55A55EB532939B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of training providers in the State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73EB2DB2609E44309BD21FFC29912CC8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the Secretary receives an application submitted under subsection (b), the Secretary shall make a determination as to whether the State that submitted such application will receive a grant under this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9586EF8F25AA40E4B3B928390AA942FA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limit</header><text>The Secretary may only award one grant to a State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H05A7E0D41E96416EACB940C009400352"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary shall require, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC26521B6C3BD48C4AE280785EA01B7EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on how the State will establish, expand, or improve a credential repository that satisfies requirements under subsection (d);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1173768BA3842BCAE752F4C35F5CFA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on the data policy a State will establish under subsection (c)(1)(B);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF92404B08CC04CFB9559C4110386D315"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any products, tools, services, or resources that a State develops pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(E);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88FC6A227D554FABA601D9B86D87ECA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assurance that the credential repository will be interoperable with other State credential repositories; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6B0D1BD89424F05841539A5F6A418C1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assurance that the State will establish and maintain the credential repository in accordance with the requirements under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDA235582202F4052943E8C4581749B07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header> <paragraph id="HD260B050B8A948239EBDE761E294C1A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State awarded a grant under this Act shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB0102B3A5BD14F1190D7A5422AF18E3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a credential repository, as described in subsection (d), through a process that includes input from the public;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FF5C45DFE564F21A56B32BDF4C987AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a data policy for such repository that addresses how the State will ensure that the repository meets the requirements described in subsection (d);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF82F6D08587A4616ADFF698328DAA730"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assist training providers in the State in the collection of information on the primary indicators of performance described in section 116(b)(2)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>) for each covered program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC993881EFB5F4D778A6E07AEAE168AF2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide guidance to education, job, and career counselors in the State on how to use the credential repository; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B5F540085B747FFB747AEE3B6495055" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop or facilitate access to products, tools, services, and other resources, using the information and linked, open, and interoperable data contained in the credential repository, that benefit workers, employers, educators, counselors, policymakers, and others.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D2FE80B4F3D4682959DCC4DBDD86B3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized use</header><text>If a State carries out all of the activities under paragraph (1), the State may use any excess grant funds to publicize the repository of the State to individuals in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H991EA20EE22948DD886EB57F17C5A446"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credential repository</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives a grant under this Act shall establish a publicly accessible credential repository that—</text> <paragraph id="HF97127D789CF40C0A7E52E9005C4981E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEA003BE711C3432E9E5CF887ED46BAFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each credential offered in the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD22807442BBE41B08E76B72375906821"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each training provider in the State;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H646516BB0B8641AA9A2FA83E06E5CB91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes information on—</text> <subparagraph id="H9C44B0FE8D274673BB2876630BAB3C8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each training provider in the State—</text> 
<clause id="H0BBC0B4978444D3AAA34EA122A45EA3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>process and outcome quality indicators of such training provider for each covered program offered by such training provider; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0D4A10905966455D8D50857E843F8F60"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each credential for which such training provider offers a covered program;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A6CA457A6064399A4AB90250BB85624"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to each covered program offered in the State—</text> <clause id="H75C5AF77A8E54C989E140D0E90A92A4C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the competencies and skills an individual develops by completing such covered program; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H06E37CAE324145D885B487D7240960CA">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the cost of enrollment for an individual to enroll in such program; and</text>
                        </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF1DD341580254CBEBB94F9BDCE10CF85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to each credential offered in the State—</text> <clause id="H74DFD4F47B9B4F7599A3AF0B1F7375A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the training providers that offer such credential;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H032BAE55487C4FC3896A1AF076527A0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any assessment that an individual is required to take to earn such credential;</text></clause> <clause id="H350BA9DCB1A54AC8A15E98E537C14BA9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the cost to an individual of each such assessment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H313B9E4E77024D78A8538ADA9870ADA5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any postsecondary credit or equivalent transfer value recommendations of such credential, such as the recommendations provided by the American Council on Education’s National Guide, guidance from a statewide education coordinating entity, or recommendations or guidance from a comparably similar entity, as available and appropriate;</text></clause> <clause id="HD04254407FA64BCA87214BE2D0A1A3C1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the career pathway or program of study that such credential is a part, as applicable;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7534CCBF25F64DB7921F0715B047974D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the outcomes associated with such credential, including—</text> <subclause id="H83D38CEC26024DDE98AA394B09D9CAE7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the earning and employment status of individuals after earning such credential;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFFBEFA25E82A4E4181406087EE4D5D9D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the completion and pass rates of individuals in each career pathway or program of study for which the individual earned such credential; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1ACD63267E894AF79BC6676DD16F8F7F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>other calculations, including the return on investment, as determined by the State, for an individual after earning such credential;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H8E1ED6106F444DB38940AF0331DB33E6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the job skills an individual develops in earning such credential; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA7DE0A5B879E42FB80E70B2FB9E23D26"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the industries and occupations for which such credential prepares an individual;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E64FAAC2A604FF980B4B6E0B325F553">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>aligns with, complements, and enhances eligibility lists or criteria for training providers, such as the eligibility criteria established under section 122(a) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3152">29 U.S.C. 3152(b)</external-xref>), or a program or pathway approval process required by the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (U.S.C.) or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code (otherwise known as the Post 9/11 Education Assistance Program);</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C9C7E7BA78B4FE383A8D3A37E95C27C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is updated on a continuous basis to ensure the accuracy and recency of the information and data in the repository;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE576B528B63D424BAB6DB8531E65607D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>uses data formats that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7B666A41252C4E3CA001052EBD0543EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are transparent, linked, open, and interoperable with other State credential repositories;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44EB971029D0484D97E484943E532AE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are aligned with widely recognized and adopted standards, which may include the use of credential transparency description language specifications; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H01D8942BC7AA4F2BA96C78BFDFF3B561"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for open access to the data in the repository across State and national borders and industry sectors for guidance counseling, career navigation, and other comparably similar activities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72471D9612DE4C3E864E3A1588EB4927"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has functions to search, discover, compare, and analyze each credential, covered program, and training provider in the State; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD999BBAFD1C449BCBCC53853DEAD2CA1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>includes any other information as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H44C172395AFF4630A042FD907EF5A5FC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Privacy protections</header><text>In carrying out the activities under this Act, a State shall not collect or include in the repository any personally identifiable information.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H46B6A397D3EE4A5BB82628851816999C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HE7E2BC48DFE94068A0BE5126D8BAE5BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and on an annual basis thereafter, a State that receives a grant under this Act shall submit to the Secretary a report at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including information on the improvement or development and implementation of the credential repository in such State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60325318450943E1923D20792DBE3C5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduced burden</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, and in consultation with the States receiving a grant under this Act, shall implement processes to reduce the burden of reporting information required to be reported under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC90E111E9D245C58F4E4F4511A7E1A1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HA8ECF6E91F5446008F1C621F254B07F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered program</header><text>The term <term>covered program</term> means a program that is offered to individuals to earn a credential.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69CD74BE586F4CB0A2A9F538071C35BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credential</header><text>The term <term>credential</term> means an education or occupational qualification or achievement used to indicate suitability for a future educational opportunity or career opportunity, including diplomas, digital badges, certificates, certifications, a recognized postsecondary credential, occupational or professional licenses, microcredentials, and degrees of all types and levels.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DD326DE98D64769ADC37CEA39266338"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term>, unless otherwise specified in this Act, means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0222B6018B241A38EE72DD629D18F18"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training provider</header><text>The term <term>training provider</term> means an entity that offers a covered program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E43164444FE4373B3B1AD71EA6C72E7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>WIOA terms</header><text>The terms <term>career pathway</term>, <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3113">29 U.S.C. 3113</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD6B3E582FFCC45F6A0C11C029801D8E3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HDE1ECDB9F70848FCBA8029E50ABA9C31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act for fiscal year 2028.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFF8E31285D9D4956B18A9CEAB38E2003"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Remain available</header><text>The funds appropriated under this section shall remain available until September 30, 2029.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

