<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO26057-SHC-7T-0FT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3720 IS: Bay Area Ridge National Scenic Trail Feasibility Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3720</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260128">January 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study on the feasibility of designating the Bay Area Ridge as a national scenic trail, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H88B6B17617FE40B9A3EECA13443B003A"><section id="id8e009e060ad843408906dfb08846cfd4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bay Area Ridge National Scenic Trail Feasibility Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9412fa04899b417482b1fcd1dfc4260a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that the Bay Area Ridge Trail—</text><paragraph id="H5601A46DB9B7463397CEFCA657C9D647"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a scenic nonmotorized multi-use trail that extends approximately 550 miles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A9437565042446BBE91A39474623156"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consists of approximately 415 completed miles and another approximately 140 miles of the route that are not yet completed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC84213C4E00D4E30A31BA4BDCE3CE9A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is located near urban areas of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b80bc89fb6e4e8aa1fbe83faff18b26"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allows people to access the scenic ridgelines of the San Francisco Bay Area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H320CCFB68C2A4B72B51D68B644D40682"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provides maximum outdoor recreation potential to a large, diverse population and many year-round visitors to the San Francisco Bay Area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD35E41ECF34C9D85580436512644F3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provides for the enjoyment of nationally significant scenic, historic, and cultural qualities, including the Pacific Ocean, the Golden Gate National Recreation Area, and State and local parks, among others;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72117B6C50C14049B9408706BC6AD3E9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>passes through diverse environments, including marsh, grassland, mountain, canyon, rivers, and forests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEECC10D91D44446A02C176868D17AF3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>includes landforms that exhibit significant characteristics, including the Golden Gate Bridge, the San Andreas fault, volcanic areas, geologic formations, and wetlands; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C33502628E401CA8609F8132369104"><enum>(9)</enum><text>connects with side trails and regional connector trails, such as the Bay Trail, Vine Trail, and Coyote Creek Trail, which provide additional public access and connect to major population centers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBD6E4D334E1B4C7B8A6AA350118B76C1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Bay Area Ridge National Scenic Trail feasibility study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(c) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7DF3E2C5BEBD4C6BA0C55731468EC125"><paragraph id="H4F53A348F5CB448D9CB065A23817FB01"><enum>(50)</enum><header>Bay area ridge national scenic trail</header><subparagraph id="H7C1E8FAA4B204F17B006BEA62A2794E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Bay Area Ridge National Scenic Trail, a multi-use trail extending approximately 550 miles along the ridgelines of the hills and mountains surrounding the San Francisco Bay Area in northern California and connecting over 75 parks and open spaces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A4FF549A8F6480AB081EB130BD58ED7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b), not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with interested organizations (including the Bay Area Ridge Trail Council), shall complete and submit to Congress the feasibility study for designating the Bay Area Ridge Trail as a national scenic trail.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9954C5C5C0B84DFA8722EC5E986F2856"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The study under this paragraph shall be conducted in consultation with each Federal agency and State agency that administers land through which the trail described in subparagraph (A) passes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

