<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA516682BC764D0185688B1B536CE99B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7936 IH: Bioindustrial Scale-Up for Supply Chains and Energy Resiliency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7936</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to support the development, demonstration, and commercial application of biotechnology products to increase energy resiliency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6FAF3C1F40BF412A8EEB96A90A2ED111" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5762420DFB3B48338AAF54E0DF0E32D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bioindustrial Scale-Up for Supply Chains and Energy Resiliency Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H505F4DFE458C42F7A7999D64D0DAA8F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="HFE8F015078A840138425A4B770D543C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the biggest roadblock for United States biotechnology innovators to commercialization is proving that their products and processes can scale, thus showing investors a path to financial return;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9638DDF143E4A4D90551D70836B1C2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States faces several main challenges to securing the broad range of infrastructure needed for the breadth of products that biotechnology can make, which are that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDF92B2605E9147E6AD17273692596AD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States lacks sufficient biomanufacturing capacity, including because researchers are generating new products faster than manufacturing capacity is increasing and building new facilities is expensive and time-consuming; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6685C0F51F7F4E7AB04DE4CC76FC1686"><enum>(B)</enum><text>biomanufacturing technologies of the future have yet to mature into routine commercial applications, as current biomanufacturing facilities are generally optimized for 1 type of product and are usually not compatible with other products; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E493C892821482EAB515D9EDAA1C00F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to position the United States as a leader in bioindustrial innovation and enable participation in groundbreaking projects through state-of-the-art infrastructure, it is critical to establish technology maturation facilities to provide world-class capabilities.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H18F52DA3A4A141BC9F0CA323BBAAF668"><enum>3.</enum><header>Bioindustrial scale-up for supply chains and energy resiliency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 932 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16232">42 U.S.C. 16232</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HB57629987C8A47069BBBD08869CEA80C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H949A3728494D43D18204BC4A84508686"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as paragraphs (5) and (7), respectively;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78D8AE513D364B71AADBC303452B84B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (5) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2BE888ECC4A4994A53A8DD792ED7E38"> <paragraph id="H0A2A365B4C3A42BBA56F3D296F4C80C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biobased product</header><text>The term <term>biobased product</term> has the meaning given the term in section 9001 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8101">7 U.S.C. 8101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB5745A744B904BD6BFC8F3F3559DD6F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bioindustrial manufacturing</header><text>The term <term>bioindustrial manufacturing</term> means the use of living organisms, cells, tissues, enzymes, or cell-free systems to produce materials and products for nonpharmaceutical applications.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D225D8924DE4E6890A0FF74C2A97146"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Biointermediate</header><text>The term <term>biointermediate</term> means an intermediate product that is derived from biomass or waste streams, including carbon oxides.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFF48447E62684F249CEB32C5FDD51471"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Biomanufacturing</header><text>The term <term>biomanufacturing</term> means the use of biological systems to produce goods and services at commercial scale.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4739A1F6456247CA97E1376F919F68AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5) (as so redesignated) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9137457E8611477A89211CC7BEA96E30">
<paragraph id="HB249DE9E4E1847E88869BBC82294C0E1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Biotechnology</header><text>The term <term>biotechnology</term> means technology that applies to or is enabled by life sciences innovation or product development.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AE8572CC9DC484F853AAD71C78FA897"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7) (as so redesignated) the following:</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D9E09178E57403ABC0803C866713F33">
                        <paragraph id="H94E3BE29EBFC4292B370A8368CC9750A">
                            <enum>(8)</enum>
                            <header>Open access</header>
 <text>The term <term>open access</term>, with respect to infrastructure, data, or research resources, means that those resources are—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="H01906BDB2A604039883B171B4D23DFD7">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>available without licensing or intellectual property barriers; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="H098D271CC7B34890881F0D00321D6ED6">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>accessible to public and private entities on an equitable basis.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H7ECFD073FCBC4F04B53539241B4A9B88">
                            <enum>(9)</enum>
                            <header>Phytobiome</header>
 <text>The term <term>phytobiome</term> means a network of interactions of plants, their associated communities of organisms, and their environmental context.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HB957717D678243BDB7B4CD0B23813E06">
                            <enum>(10)</enum>
                            <header>Technology maturation</header>
 <text>The term <term>technology maturation</term> means the development, testing, and scaling of technologies to a level of readiness suitable for commercialization or integration into industrial processes, including activities such as prototyping, pilot-scale testing and demonstration, and early-stage manufacturing and market entry.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H6A3D1323D22B47B7B6ED32C9FEC6DA31">
                            <enum>(11)</enum>
                            <header>Waste stream</header>
 <text>The term <term>waste stream</term> includes municipal solid waste, food waste, urban wood waste, food processing and fermentation waste, sewage, biogas, industrial waste gases, carbon oxides, atmospheric oxides, and waste gases that are effluents or byproduct streams from various societal pursuits that are targeted toward disposal, discharge, or burning.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE172C13352B84AA19231674B492C8F83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E9CA61DE7804F6BA4E01F5D7B32CC21"> <subsection id="HD362B196DD03406BB46E57E49FB0E7E1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Bioindustrial technology maturation facilities</header> <paragraph id="H22C8BEB068C64D7D8F52927CBF11E1BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2030, the Secretary shall establish not fewer than 2 bioindustrial technology maturation facilities (referred to in this subsection as ‘covered facilities’)—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9944D1395E894595A6B3B42325A1FC71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to derisk product and process technologies for biotechnology-based products relevant to the mission of the Department;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2900E2551B8A49E8A72EC9DB92ACF5A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that are precommercial; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42F606414DAB40E7B2D49460F1727B08"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that shall operate as user facilities available to governmental and nongovernmental users.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1C3EAE4C3124C4EA0D91DF6A21FF3B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the number, type, and location of covered facilities to establish, the Secretary shall—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8694CFDAF9742F59DED59D9BED68A0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider—</text> <clause id="H2B04376EF7034164B4950D2A2C5D73A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the greatest needs of industry and the gaps in current types of infrastructure;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC515656C63824EC2AA06ED01A0282444"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>unique capabilities that are currently not available anywhere in the world;</text></clause> <clause id="H2BE64148647640B085B057E7CCA811DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how the covered facilities may—</text>
<subclause id="H133D414D9E444BBF9659B01E17756D79"><enum>(I)</enum><text>complement current infrastructure and capabilities, including infrastructure and capabilities of—</text> <item id="H76AD21C030ED44158CE2785ABFFA6C52"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Department, including National Laboratories;</text></item>
<item id="H5481F529C27744DC8197028C10B1A67E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></item> <item id="HA6F4D3BE577C4AFBA02E24817FDD8B97"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce; and</text></item>
<item id="HD31B1623A0644F7D9F326CCA6A00DD4A"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>other covered facilities; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HFB7D8DCBDFC24407B06DEA8808C0B801"><enum>(II)</enum><text>increase production levels by functioning as a connected network, including by ensuring that available fermentation capacity, including of covered facilities and facilities of the Department, covers the full range needed for precommercial scale-up; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H1C2589B2F9764E4182C9B2FA64DCE782"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how each covered facility aligns with regional and local workforce needs, pre-existing capabilities, the skills required for the proposed biomanufacturing operations, and the potential for regional and local workforce development and job creation; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61274D6636554F9AB96ACDF822082989"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that—</text>
<clause id="H81C01BF17FA044C3A7F44455B56EDC9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>covered facilities are in geographically diverse locations—</text> <subclause id="HA996A593F9144FEF89183B149EB53BBF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to maximize access to biological material needed as an input to bioindustrial manufacturing processes;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB8588868DAD842D59D84F4A2AFA2343E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to leverage available industrial and academic expertise, including workforce and human capital; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC8AA1BE3127641A6A094F74000A2E3C8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to leverage relevant domestic infrastructure required to secure supply chains for chemicals and other materials;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E2D5E2589734FFDA7F2069F21744D84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered facilities are complementary to each other and any other existing related facilities; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7707E821F134D02A488C6302E3707EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the first covered facility is planned and built within a 2-year time period, and the plan for the second and each subsequent facility is developed while construction occurs on the earlier planned covered facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE93069DB9CE24CF58782188FCD2056BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Activities carried out by a covered facility may include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H921181E60A1A479ABFF7DC8A3F76B409"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conducting pilot and demonstration projects to evaluate bioindustrial manufacturing processes and technologies for customers.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H19E08818268542D9A60C5CF28131D4A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Conducting activities to scale bioindustrial manufacturing processes and products for scale-up and deployment efforts, and larger, higher, or different levels of production for customers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C6FDD5C4FF94B3FAA8ADD9597FE5C08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Developing, testing, and implementing applications and tools, including equipment, hardware, software, and algorithms, with industry and academic partners.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD80D8A669A984167AB6B3B4E9C1A324A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Addressing technical challenges around bioindustrial manufacturing inputs and the technologies and processes that break down or convert biomass, waste streams, and other inputs that are useful to the bioindustrial manufacturing process, biointermediates, or other products.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1C1EC4CACD441319D4BC68B293D229F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Supporting training and workforce development needs in bioindustrial manufacturing.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEB43E088D3B044069405C8924E59E6BD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Establishing an interoperable, secure, digital infrastructure for collaborative data exchange across entities in the bioindustrial manufacturing community, including government agencies, industry, and academia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D18AD280F7E4F9C8FC74ACDC2243813"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Developing and implementing digital tools, process security and assurance capabilities, cybersecurity protocols, and best practices for data storage, sharing, and analysis.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD73672F1272C426291FA25A4BBAB7BAC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Leveraging data, modeling, and expertise to assist stakeholders in quantifying economic effects of, and future investment strategies relating to, emerging processes and technologies, and incorporating those findings into techno-economic analysis.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2259FCD883114749B190FB47A671F414"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any other activity that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H655094BB139F4F53B7D0C98D89FEBF0B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out the activities described in paragraph (3), a covered facility may—</text> <subparagraph id="H51E9F41335CC439C95305CBE94F5681E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and implement policies to ensure open access to the covered facility for public and private sector entities, with a focus on inclusion of rural communities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H58B91762AA9047009A07C644C172B5FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pursue cost-sharing and cofunding arrangements or opportunities with private sector stakeholders to supplement Federal funding and promote financial sustainability; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04D371F524A942F6A3F3496D4B358A94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to maximize the impact of the covered facility, coordinate and collaborate with—</text>
<clause id="H56A81A34A767460C9E1CA88A85DADFE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>industry partners, including to identify priority research, development, and demonstration needs;</text></clause> <clause id="H8DFC4B7DC4A143779DD8A576C102659E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other Department facilities, including National Laboratories;</text></clause>
<clause id="H648193DBB80A429FBECB44C30BD3AD94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the defense community, including the Department of Defense and BioMADE;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1BD542F28F94F688F01EC599D5E35F6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agricultural community and relevant Federal agencies, including the Department of Agriculture;</text></clause>
<clause id="H495C29C66D77404F95DD6495A6C63BB0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the transportation sector and relevant Federal agencies, including the Department of Transportation;</text></clause> <clause id="HB5B07E5269424D488C327DBF63BF0EFE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other Federal agencies, including the Department of Commerce, as determined necessary by the covered facility;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA5C00AF620A844F0A746874DA19AEE06" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Federal education and workforce development programs, including the National Science Foundation;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE9FB8FB176F4C30A8AE04626600D8EC"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">institutions of higher education;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H532FBD3003AA4FB3A8532A91C63DA3E7"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rural community stakeholders;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53750E1387454E908589F3DABA84A8BF"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nonprofit organizations;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BDCE1E71E8440CAB0EFFEC86CB59181"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State and local governments; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4547AEEDD59A48EA98FE4BF9799B8820"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>international bodies with relevant scientific expertise.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAAB9C269E7604F48A100DD5A8CC9DFC5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Request for information</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bioindustrial Scale-Up for Supply Chains and Energy Resiliency Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall publish a request for information that shall be used by the Secretary to evaluate—</text> <subparagraph id="HE875CC8FCF904A0E8623FF21E366DFD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing and planned bioindustrial technology maturation facilities in the United States, including facilities with gas fermentation technologies and large-scale fermentation tanks with robust sensor suites;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6A5BD7777A5C4DC9B58CD8EC1A6595D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>best practices for collaboration at those facilities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A3CEF1AD3EA40E7A6554EA98D081EC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other information determined necessary for the development of the strategic plan under paragraph (6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB67845178E8B4E1FA4E8B510733DEA91"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bioindustrial Scale-Up for Supply Chains and Energy Resiliency Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a strategic plan for the implementation of this subsection that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H069CADD9DFE248CC889CDA6ABDA0D2EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of capacity scaling needs to determine what type of additional technology maturation facilities are needed;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9049ED036D994C018A040B13BB2C5B4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the type, size, and location of each covered facility that the Secretary intends to establish;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DCEF79F887F46EBA91BA1BB51D49009"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of covered facilities that the Secretary intends to establish;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAD97C869DD504213B7010F6E1E1EEF5E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the timelines associated with planning and execution of each covered facility, phased over time; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF003EB0F50244F3D92F9F36CE8B9BCE8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a general description of—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5350ED5687624C23B434207F37761A9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the focus of each covered facility, including the types of manufacturing equipment, if any, that are expected to be procured for each covered facility;</text></clause> <clause id="H0FC2B0B8B9494A758886C09F5FDCE897"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how covered facilities will work as a network to maximize the variety of bioindustrial products available to be produced by the network, including how the capabilities of covered facilities will complement the capabilities of existing and planned technology maturation facilities, including those of other Federal agencies, including the Department of Commerce and the Department of Defense;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC0D2B0F6BF6B414C810089C161B3D929"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how that network will support the establishment and maintenance of the bioindustrial manufacturing industrial base;</text></clause> <clause id="HED4536AF46004FF284C894C9E187EFDA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how the Secretary intends to ensure that data is collected and shared with the rest of that network, as applicable; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C65C3AB2517489C9797A7AAFB45EF97"><enum>(v)</enum><text>how the Secretary intends to coordinate with other Federal agencies, including the Department of Commerce and the Department of Defense, to ensure the effective use of funds, development of capabilities, and prioritization of biotechnologies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF7DED33AFF843418FE4AACD525DF555"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Intellectual property protections</header> <subparagraph id="H06CDBC6D68EB46EDB1BA46D9491FAAA5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal employee contributions</header><text>Any intellectual property created by a Federal employee at a covered facility in the performance of the duties of that Federal employee shall be considered to be part of the public domain.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1313BDEC84EE4764A1FAFAB56A3B04EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other entities</header><text>Any intellectual property created by an individual at a covered facility who is not a Federal employee shall be protected under applicable intellectual property laws, subject to the terms of the contractual agreement that the individual has entered into with the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H190DA441F3C14B54B0739B32C758E1E5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Data sharing</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, a covered facility shall establish a secure, interoperable digital system to facilitate data exchange across government, academia, and industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H19EC46D4221743EC95B42356E82D0139"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bioindustrial Scale-Up for Supply Chains and Energy Resiliency Act of 2026</short-title>, and at least once every year thereafter for the following 7 years, the Secretary shall submit to the relevant congressional committees, and make publicly available, a report on the activities carried out under this subsection during the year covered by the report, including the progress made in implementing the strategic plan under paragraph (6), including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93C10DD1B1C6468688F6372DFDBD1287"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of existing covered facilities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30AD6C87BF5D41D392EFE6BBDFF3E5FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of additional covered facilities being planned, if any;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7C7BC5F031047B8869823FD186B6001"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the activities carried out by covered facilities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBC27F5AD21AF4245B9AEE7FDB95C782E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any collaborations under paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62EE18D1D3C243E2931EB123B6B87E68"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $225,500,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4BE4AFC9F81421C8D5FE5D663DF7CA5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/58">Public Law 109–58</external-xref>; 119 Stat. 594) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59991E6356014DC1969058B04932D4B1"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

