<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H332A661780F9463DB39B68F472416D46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6788 IH: Montana Sportsmen Conservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6788</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To release from wilderness study area designation certain land in the State of Montana, to improve the management of that land, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H316858AF73274370A2DFFC1CD83D0B26" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H153D50A0009244D494DE292E95188C78"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Montana Sportsmen Conservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE0547D3BF6EA477284238394F43E01A2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="H4E200370BA8D40D2AA911E038872FB7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under the Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/150">Public Law 95–150</external-xref>; 91 Stat. 1243), 9 wilderness study areas comprising a total of 973,000 acres of land in the State of Montana were set aside for the Secretary of Agriculture to evaluate the suitability of the wilderness study areas for designation as wilderness, in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>), with the evaluation to be completed not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of the Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/150">Public Law 95–150</external-xref>; 91 Stat. 1243);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H948583D463D743B1A05A428078853177"><enum>(2)</enum><text>between 1979 and 1986, the Chief of the Forest Service—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2B32054C975143B2BC7E5F6867E8A446"><enum>(A)</enum><text>completed the studies of the 9 wilderness study areas referred to in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20C03D87DDC84101B0E252961A83A322"><enum>(B)</enum><text>based on those studies, determined that 608,700 acres of the original 973,000 acres designated as wilderness study areas by the Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/150">Public Law 95–150</external-xref>; 91 Stat. 1243) were unsuitable for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System, including the 81,000 acres within the Middle Fork Judith Wilderness Study Area;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC2F2F9258A1E47A8AF3C06F9F3BE78E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in 2021, following a 6-year collaborative process, the Forest Service again determined, in the revision of the Helena Lewis and Clark National Forest plan, that the Middle Fork Judith Wilderness Study Area is unsuitable for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8784BBFF04FA45CA9531B04B2F6AD261"><enum>(4)</enum><text>under the <act-name parsable-cite="FLPMA">Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), 38 wilderness study areas comprising a total of 447,327 acres of land in the State of Montana were set aside by the Bureau of Land Management to evaluate the suitability of the wilderness study areas for designation as wilderness, with the evaluation to be completed not later than 15 years after the date of enactment of that Act;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H482582149E94472FB047D10E7FD4D3D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in 1991, the Director of the Bureau of Land Management submitted to the President a recommendation on the suitability for designation of the areas described in paragraph (4), which was subsequently submitted to Congress, under which the Director of the Bureau of Land Management determined that 273,828 acres in the State of Montana designated as wilderness study areas by the <act-name parsable-cite="FLPMA">Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) were unsuitable for wilderness designation, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H425F696A43DF4F07BF441E625CEA50D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the 11,380 acres of land within the Hoodoo Mountain Wilderness Study Area; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD85689BCC8C04F50A4CFACD8FCB5E4EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 11,580 acres of land within the Wales Creek Wilderness Study Area;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H022BAD3221E042DF87017A3DD12DDE7C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in 2020, following a 5-year collaborative process, the Bureau of Land Management, in the revision of the Missoula Resource Management Plan—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBEC257B9AAB9415695B1D4985A0C2546"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reaffirmed that the Hoodoo Mountain Wilderness Study Area and the Wales Creek Wilderness Study Area were unsuitable for wilderness designation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE335F2E5F1484EE1BF2133F9D9FCDED6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommended alternative management parameters for the Hoodoo Mountain Wilderness Study Area and the Wales Creek Wilderness Study Area;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEF270DCAEB9547AFB81D93FB014C4AEC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>despite the recommendations of the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management, after the completion of the studies for suitability of the land in the State of Montana designated as wilderness study areas under the Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/150">Public Law 95–150</external-xref>; 91 Stat. 1243) and the <act-name parsable-cite="FLPMA">Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2BF511970662467AAB39D0610957C072"><enum>(A)</enum><text>over 1,100,000 acres of public land in the State of Montana remain as wilderness study areas until Congress acts; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFC21054ED4F5431DBD44B2979603F757"><enum>(B)</enum><text>over 700,000 acres of public land in the State of Montana currently designated as wilderness study areas have been determined unsuitable for wilderness management;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7616E2545616499C9412FD831D1E1147"><enum>(8)</enum><text>if the wilderness study area designation was removed from each of the Middle Fork Judith Wilderness Study Area, the Hoodoo Mountain Wilderness Study Area, and the Wales Creek Wilderness Study Area, land managers would be able to better conserve and manage the areas in accordance with applicable land and resource management plans that retain certain protections for the areas, while providing for—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCCD7F60924A74EEFBE67D3CF196BC543"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhanced sportsmen opportunities in the backcountry of Montana;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED29D3DFF009427CB4D74BAD6EFADB5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improved public access; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB9AD2D7AE6DB4488AC4A8E82A2DF69AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the conduct of wildlife habitat and wildfire mitigation projects;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6677F70E89634907A2A1B0309D706B1C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the applicable land and resource management plans referred to in paragraph (8) were developed through a multi-year, collaborative process supported by—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7336987979964D7498166DD8E0E02FE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resource needs and conditions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21AE4EB222174974BD9B8A2622D5F03C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the best available science; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19E78513550C4011BA4D767B55BFA6A2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>following release, the respective land management agencies shall continue managing the areas described in paragraph (8)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D0D33EF5E8F449DA4BC055A7258B603"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with applicable environmental and administrative laws; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H755936B9DDA24078A4A4E466A1C10A5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>based on local input, multiple-use and sustained yield principles, and land management objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HBAC88F4501D4430D87513964B2B75AC4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Release and improved management of land comprising certain wilderness study areas</header> <subsection id="HA86DBA18CB024A9BB9CF0032C1CE043C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Middle Fork Judith Wilderness Study Area</header><text>The approximately 81,000 acres of land comprising the Middle Fork Judith Wilderness Study Area—</text>
<paragraph id="HC6D0636AE2384ECCA15EF1DBB403F7D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall no longer be subject to section 3(a) of the Montana Wilderness Study Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/150">Public Law 95–150</external-xref>; 91 Stat. 1244); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F882079E7D84162B0DF37E7A61BD3BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be managed in accordance with the applicable land and resource management plan most recently adopted under section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1604">16 U.S.C. 1604</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7B8077BC7DBF4439A860B4D03D5F2A96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hoodoo Mountain Wilderness Study Area and Wales Creek Wilderness Study Area</header><text>The approximately 11,380 acres of land comprising the Hoodoo Mountain Wilderness Study Area and the approximately 11,580 acres of land comprising the Wales Creek Wilderness Study Area—</text> <paragraph id="H3BBEC4FC460141039FABED8E46EBAA80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall no longer be subject to section 603(c) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1782">43 U.S.C. 1782(c)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H50CE397D23BF42B88B2897A84A62260F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be managed in accordance with the applicable land management plans adopted under section 202 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

