<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC3B5A2FDA3BF4EC0995E0E365482B403" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6668 IH: Clean Water Standards for PFAS Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6668</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish effluent limitations guidelines and standards and water quality criteria for perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC4DD538A0D6B449EB9F7CF8BC9F425EC" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H9890C4B1E38445A0A1810E388161E61B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Water Standards for PFAS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0956C4028F1E47B59E02260D70135393"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clean Water Act effluent limitations guidelines and standards and water quality criteria for PFAS</header> <subsection id="H7580758D5C264F7B89A31BF5E3780A86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H3EB9C7566EA14DAA8BC477855613FDAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H118DE549843A4D49A98FB5B048C2912C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effluent limitation</header><text>The term <term>effluent limitation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 502 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEFE85492350C4168B6983EC14DD53338"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Measurable</header><text>The term <term>measurable</term>, with respect to a perfluoroalkyl substance, a polyfluoroalkyl substance, or a class of those substances, means that the substance or class of substances is capable of being measured using any test method promulgated under part 136 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9ACD436327F447E910CC0A1A82886CE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Perfluoroalkyl substance</header><text>The term <term>perfluoroalkyl substance</term> means a chemical of which all of the carbon atoms are fully fluorinated carbon atoms.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE909AF89C89B47FAB0E2442CA4E0FA76"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Polyfluoroalkyl substance</header><text>The term <term>polyfluoroalkyl substance</term> means a chemical containing at least 1 fully fluorinated carbon atom and at least 1 carbon atom that is not a fully fluorinated carbon atom.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0334252A77C4AE0A817C57E98E1BCF2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment works</header><text>The term <term>treatment works</term> has the meaning given the term in section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H67622748E0B5492780CA9949705B1DAA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadlines</header>
<paragraph id="HE0D5751EB0C34B158FEA0F5DF4626D8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Water quality criteria</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register human health water quality criteria under section 304(a)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1314">33 U.S.C. 1314(a)(1)</external-xref>) to address each measurable perfluoroalkyl substance, polyfluoroalkyl substance, and class of those substances.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H358765A182754CDE9C36A9EF99F98D31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effluent limitations guidelines and standards for priority industry categories</header><text>Not later than the following dates, the Administrator shall take final action on a rule establishing effluent limitations guidelines and standards, in accordance with the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>), for each of the following industry categories for the discharge (including a discharge into a publicly owned treatment works) of each measurable perfluoroalkyl substance, polyfluoroalkyl substance, or class of those substances:</text>
<subparagraph id="HAE72B6ADF19F419095D90E73BAB27E09"><enum>(A)</enum><header>During calendar year 2026</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2026, for the following point source categories:</text> <clause id="H84AE1C2A3265426DBA6123845E1710A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Organic chemicals, plastics, and synthetic fibers, as identified in part 414 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause>
<clause id="H1BF8382EE0D640FF9ED254FB56042611"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Electroplating, as identified in part 413 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause> <clause id="H79688254970E4A0EB9338DE7065F9AD4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Metal finishing, as identified in part 433 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7C2A482DBC454F3086B6CA19CC519D11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>During calendar year 2027</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2027, for the following point source categories:</text> <clause id="HAE61FADEA2EB4730BCDAA74987FD5941"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Textile mills, as identified in part 410 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause>
<clause id="HEAA7A55E2BD6467298649F128CAFA1AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Landfills, as identified in part 445 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA8741357C4447AEB69E52CC3B2E855B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>During calendar year 2028</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2028, for the following point source categories:</text>
<clause id="H3BFB7B48CC094991A589BE575055F503"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Leather tanning and finishing, as identified in part 425 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause> <clause id="H58475E0AFB3543638D5155B5D9B8FAF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Paint formulating, as identified in part 446 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause>
<clause id="HEB865CB3D34E468BB46C46862FB2E229"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Plastics molding and forming, as identified in part 463 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5B68F5C21A6147D5ABA49DFDD033FC12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Monitoring</header> <paragraph id="H0718F336EA6C4EB5B9F1808DDE492509"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Monitoring requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H9005081919FC41508E4A7F6C66BFF9D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall require monitoring of the discharges (including discharges into a publicly owned treatment works) of each measurable perfluoroalkyl substance, polyfluoroalkyl substance, and class of those substances for the point source categories and entities described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FEFA168738141ABBF4B041D210C60EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain monitoring required</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall require monitoring of the discharges (including discharges into a publicly owned treatment works) of each measurable perfluoroalkyl substance, polyfluoroalkyl substance, and class of those substances for the following point source categories and entities:</text> <clause id="HB13FC932D2044C43BCBAADBE16BC7A3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Pulp, paper, and paperboard, as identified in part 430 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause>
<clause id="HAFA68A40D6FB41E5B5596465568E018F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Airports (as defined in section 47102 of title 49, United States Code).</text></clause> <clause id="H60D5752B881D4427933317087785664B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Electrical and electronic components, as identified in part 469 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33FEA3FE8E8546B6887DC5C6C66444BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header>
<subparagraph id="H25CFB6A55B084AE5A1BFAFE8A53B12B7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2026, the Administrator shall make a determination—</text> <clause id="HB276F94308DE4AD5B5E81D04C03503FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to commence developing effluent limitations guidelines and standards for the point source categories and entities listed in paragraph (1)(B); or</text></clause>
<clause id="H7D060FA492E6482595DEEC295798B2C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to not commence developing effluent limitations guidelines and standards for those point source categories and entities, including an explanation of the reasoning for this determination.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H932CE43816D741D498FCB62D4BF63D12"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any effluent limitations guidelines and standards for the point source categories and entities listed in paragraph (1)(B) shall be published in the Federal Register by not later than December 31, 2028.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB4C8F8A7D75149768B9E4DF6DEEFB5C9">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Method promulgation</header>
 <text>Subject to the requirements of subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>), not later than January 31, 2026, the Administrator shall promulgate Method 1633A, as described in the document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Method 1633, Revision A Analysis of Per- and Polyfluoroalkyl Substances (PFAS) in Aqueous, Solid, Biosolids, and Tissue Samples by LC–MS/MS</quote> and dated December 2024 (or a successor method of equal or greater validity and standard), under part 136 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H640763BE81E441C89FAE80846C3571CB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Administrator shall notify the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate of each publication made under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H034975630C80451FBBCAF7676841109D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Pretreatment program</header> <paragraph id="HBC510A6D807148A88E3E2576EF66CDEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall award grants to owners and operators of publicly owned treatment works—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA8FFABEE50FB48EFAC1DE6EEDF585CA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out pretreatment program activities conducted in accordance with part 403 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), that address contamination by perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54468865E13244FC9FC2AA3CBEF5B513"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to further monitor, assess, or analyze local sources of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances that enter into the treatment works.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E4CEACD44EE423BA37A324A3F683C2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this subsection $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAF5DC34B3FFF460CA8674231ECBB9D28"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section (except subsection (f)) $12,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 to 2030, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

