<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F04D9985D664755A4174829FC10D095" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6253 IH: Algorithmic Transparency and Choice Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6253</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require online platforms to disclose policies and provide options relating to personalized recommendations systems to minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCF2C491E77E4456D97BDE4937C0D9E91" style="OLC"><section id="H214A2E7B4CD04D728E2124E86472515E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Algorithmic Transparency and Choice Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H160A51CE8EBE4E1096ACC3520A1B2E89"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notice and algorithm preference requirements for covered online platforms to provide to minors</header><subsection id="H9FF908588D2E485CB4D6901A094E555C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the provider of a covered online platform shall do the following:</text><paragraph id="HEB292A89A67648CE87B7F709F0E40C04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Provide covered users of the platform with the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9C190FBCE8D94FDAB400C91C80853CAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notice that the platform uses a personalized recommendation system to select the content the covered user sees, presented in a clear and conspicuous manner on the platform whenever the covered user interacts with a personalized recommendation system for the first time.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6641E00928AD4EFF9B2F7A171BD4FE65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A notice, included in the terms and conditions of the platform, in a clear, accessible, and easily comprehensible manner that is updated whenever the platform makes a material change, that includes the following:</text><clause id="HB36B8FEAFDFB43CCBCD305CD3BECBC56"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any feature, input, and parameter essential to the operation of the personalized recommendation system.</text></clause><clause id="H9599F604D5F3461097AEE8DDD690F0A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How any user-specific data used by the personalized recommendation system is collected or inferred about a covered user of the platform and each category of such data.</text></clause><clause id="H3D6658D2FEC24286A55765437644A811"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any option that the platform makes available for a covered user of the platform to opt out or exercise an option under subparagraph (C) or (D), modify the profile of the covered user, or to influence any feature, input, or parameter used by the personalized recommendation system.</text></clause><clause id="H4A75B292DD8E4C4CA5F798E41BD46283"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any quantity (such as time spent using a product or specific measure of engagement or social interaction) that the personalized recommendation system is designed to optimize, as well as a general description of the relative importance of each quantity for such ranking.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AAA772ECB254CDE9F405974000577D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An option to easily switch between the personalized recommendation system and an input-transparent algorithm in their use of the platform.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76CE520218DF46CF8F791944B247F604"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An option to limit the type or category of recommendations from a personalized recommendation system.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A16036A333E4E3BA70E62B9DD8A69C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Provide an input-transparent algorithm as the default setting for a covered user of the platform.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEEF0116FBF474D238F20FDCAAADFD7A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph id="HE054858C2A6E4D65B8F345544F87E400"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05C998DAA3DC4EEDBA0FF4772C778AB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><subparagraph id="H07023970AE98443297F2E6B8B45CFABE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDA0F1697068430E811B81ED6C23D299"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DA728863A8C475B9322BFBB959B48C1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2A5D534F09449C6A505B278E6BFD093"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="HC57816ADC1D34ACF9880970B30254330"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure of proprietary and privileged information prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to require a covered online platform to disclose any information, including data or any personalized recommendation system—</text><subparagraph id="H8FEDC91888A044998BDF7D5F6C667E4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relating to a trade secret or other protected intellectual property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF66C577F628947299FDBF12988A7467A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is confidential business information; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6F030C0B18D4945BC658C693AB674AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that is privileged.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89FE9E23537C4CB7A28AF454AFD168AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to limit or prohibit the ability of a covered online platform to, at the direction of a covered user or group of covered users, restrict another covered user from searching for, finding, accessing, or interacting with the account, content, data, or online community of such covered user or group.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AE99DAC233448CCB443A57F7AB7B749"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC34E046CE6BC495D8DEC8CEE00A47E5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approximate geolocation information</header><text>The term <term>approximate geolocation information</term> means information that identifies the location of an individual, but with a precision of less than 5 miles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B31D55AD9DC4C22BB855F60289ACF24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H348D86FDF07F41E6978AF443504619C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Connected device</header><text>The term <term>connected device</term> means an electronic device that—</text><subparagraph id="HD3F4343EEE864F76B91A5C0ADB6C9DA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is capable of connecting to the internet, either directly or indirectly through a network, to communicate information at the direction of an individual;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H006E62A641264B468A1ED95349705847"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has computer processing capabilities for collecting, sending, receiving, or analyzing data; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF942E7FD3204412AF123028AD54B7FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is primarily designed for or marketed to consumers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H269B9BC5DCA84EF69F3D87FF53CAA43B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered online platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered online platform</term> means an online platform that uses a personalized recommendation system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDC76448717841EF8943C4A7F06E0A08" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered user</header><text>The term <term>covered user</term> means, with respect to an online platform, a minor who registers an account or creates a profile on the covered platform.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84FE21623A5F48F5B7DF49EBB6F5A0DF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fully automated system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fully automated system</term> means an operation or set of operations performed on data with minimal or no direction, instruction, prompting, oversight, involvement, or intervention by a natural person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F4735EBED864E13A206C52C0C5992D4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Input-transparent algorithm</header><subparagraph id="HAADE09F2432141EB9FF6E5C43E81F84A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>input-transparent algorithm</term> means a fully automated system that does not use the user-specific data of a covered user to determine the selection, order, relative prioritization, or relative prominence of information that is furnished to such covered user on an online platform, unless the user-specific data is expressly provided to the platform by the covered user for such purpose.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE38C441F3844DBBF333C719E6A08B5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data expressly provided to the platform</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), user-specific data that is provided by a covered user for the express purpose of determining the selection, order, relative prioritization, or relative prominence of information that is furnished to such user on an online platform—</text><clause id="H972AEA09459747C893C2EF299F182453"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any search term, filter, and speech pattern supplied by the covered user (if provided for the purpose of enabling the platform to accept spoken input or selecting the language in which the covered user interacts with the platform), saved preference, the resumption of a previous search, and the current precise geolocation information that is supplied by the covered user;</text></clause><clause id="H7CC9131669BA4CF2A44CAC6489D9F331"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes the current approximate geolocation information of the covered user;</text></clause><clause id="H6303A26675B441B7ACB73A006C9A1229"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes data affirmatively submitted to the platform by the covered user that expresses the clear desire of the covered user to receive particular information;</text></clause><clause id="H4A5B6392BD9F4EFD9B07EB81DD9EB487"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>does not include the history of the connected device of the covered user, including the history of web searches and browsing, previous geographical locations, physical activity, device interaction, and financial transactions of the covered user; and</text></clause><clause id="H1DD2C7A9947F412DBF0C913B5A95D9F3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>does not include inferences about the covered user or the connected device of the covered user, without regard to whether such inferences are based on data described in clauses (i) or (iii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69B07CE6422B4ED58366D02F76C759EF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual under the age of 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB694840AC6E04EA2A46985D8650ACE96" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Online platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>online platform</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H635F4C5D0D174E14A85E9A32EF9A434F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a public-facing website, internet application, or mobile internet application, including a social network, or video sharing service—</text><clause id="HBA47619DF95A4E708894402BC73A1ED2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that serves the public; and</text></clause><clause id="HFE5C84A995894622A8B23789AA18AC91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that primarily provides a forum for user-generated content, including messages, videos, images, games, and audio files; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1006C07552EC458399C4FC96F450FB21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="H1581CE4E50F540D384C0376AB4C32C3F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a provider of broadband internet access service (as described in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulation); or</text></clause><clause id="HFE24EE238BFE427D9831ADB476FCDC68" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>electronic mail.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EDECBB2968C48D38DB08511414AF5C2"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Personalized recommendation system</header><text>The term <term>personalized recommendation system</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HB2910734823E4BB897A9670DFB9DBD25"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a fully automated system that determines the selection, order, relative prioritization, or relative prominence of information that is furnished to a covered user on an online platform based, in whole or part, on user-specific data that was not expressly provided by the covered user to the platform for such purpose; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23853254CA13483FB2E1B3F7CD39677C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a fully automated system used by an online platform if—</text><clause id="HFB0EACA12A3845F68617F201EE93DE4C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the only user-specific data, including any inference about the covered user, that the system uses is—</text><subclause id="HFBAD70DEBF684230A719DC5F62E65474" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>information relating to the age of the covered user; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H84B3E546FD9D4C438EBD74900E497E8C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such information is only used to fulfill a request to restrict the access of a covered user to content on the basis that the content is not age-appropriate for the covered user; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDBB0B2DA2CF34B5E84B28F905F7BCDF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such system is designed to block or filter spam, prevent or detect fraud or other illegal activity, or preserve the security of any system, product, or service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F02F25DEF63400FA7FF830F53E9FAAB"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Precise geolocation information</header><text>The term <term>precise geolocation information</term> means geolocation information that identifies the location of an individual to within a range of 5 miles or less.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD524BDBC1C242009FEDC69DB5A3EC6C"><enum>(12)</enum><header>User-specific data</header><text>The term <term>user-specific data</term> means information relating to a covered user or a specific connected device that would not necessarily be true of every individual or device.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EE0C1AD8AE34F3D8FE6094F13F63A53"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relationship to State laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State or political subdivision of a State may prescribe, maintain, or enforce any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law, if such law rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision covers the requirements of subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

