<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26980-CL8-78-34J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4537 IS: To repeal the Military Selective Service Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4537</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To repeal the Military Selective Service Act.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id62152732E63A43B9BEDD5FE04FB77AA6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Repeal of Military Selective Service Act</header><subsection id="H80CAC2DA3AF4448A8AF7AA81BFA0E266"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>The Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3801">50 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA411F77B36924327B28150391022C1B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers in connection with repeal</header><text>Notwithstanding the proviso in section 10(a)(4) of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3809">50 U.S.C. 3809(a)(4)</external-xref>), the Office of Selective Service Records shall not be reestablished upon the repeal of the Act. Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the assets, contracts, property, and records held by the Selective Service System, and the unexpended balances of any appropriations available to the Selective Service System, shall be transferred to the Administrator of General Services upon the repeal of the Act. The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall assist officers and employees of the Selective Service System to transfer to other positions in the executive branch.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCBBD39AF71DB46E8ACCA47B889B59E8F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on existing sanctions</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HF3FBB07815AF4686978A20E64D16F2E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person may not be denied a right, privilege, benefit, or employment position under Federal law on the grounds that the person failed to present himself for and submit to registration under section 3 of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3802">50 U.S.C. 3802</external-xref>), before the repeal of that Act by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBEC28E4064FD4DC692C58E79085AE381"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A State, political subdivision of a State, or political authority of two or more States may not enact or enforce a law, regulation, or other provision having the force and effect of law to penalize or deny any privilege or benefit to a person who failed to present himself for and submit to registration under section 3 of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3802">50 U.S.C. 3802</external-xref>), before the repeal of that Act by subsection (a). In this section, <quote>State</quote> means a State, the District of Columbia, and a territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3FA34F1CEEF64E7EB69E7778289C63C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Failing to present oneself for and submit to registration under section 3 of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3802">50 U.S.C. 3802</external-xref>), before the repeal of that Act by subsection (a), shall not be reason for any entity of the U.S. Government to determine that a person lacks good moral character or is unsuited for any privilege or benefit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF0333433D4141988EDB5009961E5BA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conscientious objectors</header><text>Nothing contained in this Act shall be construed to undermine or diminish the rights of conscientious objectors under laws and regulations of the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

