<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE6B47B34FDE45E3B6B16A56DB7D3AF9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7066 IH: Stopping Hikes In Electricity from Large Load Demands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7066</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to add a standard relating to the consideration of large load facilities as a class of electric consumers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFBD5251A50924ADB8DC2A8F7AED24BE5" style="OLC"><section id="HB6588E707D4640FD99D83B4C7379DD15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Hikes In Electricity from Large Load Demands Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHIELD Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFE3EA9BE06D640F49CAC83ACD9D26592"><enum>2.</enum><header>PURPA standards for large load facilities</header><subsection id="H27C1231ADC674CFC85BDC579CA2988AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 111(d) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2621">16 U.S.C. 2621(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H36409DADEC554F459FE1ACA5C2005C88" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HCE53289993234816887486B152840402"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Large load facility class</header><subparagraph id="HA4DC4EF8D33B40DF89E6E8ADB3E89E46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Classification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Large load facilities shall be considered a class of electric consumers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8D39F3F48044A3089536A24A07903AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cost recovery relating to large load facility class</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each electric utility that provides electric service to a class of electric consumers described in subparagraph (A) shall fully recover from such class all costs associated with any upgrade made to the generation, transmission, or distribution facilities of the electric grid, including local facilities, in order to meet the demand for electric energy from such class, including in the event that a large load facility ceases operations or uses less electric energy than projected at the time of such upgrade.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2E88AB1DA234DECAE13511A42EE7848"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Grid reliability for large load facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each electric utility shall prioritize, among requests from owners or operators of large load facilities for electric service, such a request under which the owner or operator agrees to employ—</text><subparagraph id="HC55FDD041A6F4298A7FA23E9C56FCD19"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">features that reduce the demand for electric energy from the electric grid during times of peak demand, including—</text><clause id="H4A07727565E64375807055D8FCC32A95"><enum>(i)</enum><text>energy efficiency or energy conservation measures;</text></clause><clause id="H1A06A77EB760495DB4C61C8342630AC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>onsite energy storage; or</text></clause><clause id="H82F08A0BD3A44283B72D60B97153CEF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>demand response or load flexibility technologies; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9829BB9F13FD4A15984C7AA955E370EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>zero-emission electric energy generated onsite or procured within the same balancing authority through a power purchase agreement to meet all of the demand of the large load facility for electric energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3EB0529A064A4B84A9A0EB647E42636E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 111 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2621">16 U.S.C. 2621</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFF1D96615CD24BC19C3B35D43A9E4324" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H6EE73A49131F492DB7C20E448CD7F6AF" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of subsection (d):</text><paragraph id="HE0861639D61348FDB201B892049D4C9F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Large load facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>large load facility</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HC75EC1CFE77E4735A7DA92E0C4A33413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a facility, or an aggregation of facilities at a single site, with respect to which the peak demand of such facility or such aggregation of facilities exceeds 75 megawatts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EA390FC54484C188BFAA09FC089794D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include an existing facility with respect to which any increased demand is predominantly caused by electrification or measures to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7EA4193A1DA426B8C732BF051640017"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Zero-emission electric energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>zero-emission electric energy</term> means electric energy generated without emitting greenhouse gases, including from solar, wind, geothermal, hydroelectric, tidal, fission, or fusion.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF70B2CCD9AA546C9BD74960A47A6DC74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H0E8C65CD0E594193AB3CDE940CC7855A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Obligations to consider and determine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 112 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2622">16 U.S.C. 2622</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H398ABA3EDFF14185AB67D4D24AB22832"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H86473F603FDF44CC872C3EC92E8DFA3C"><paragraph id="H48374AF79FA54AFD9048B7A6A43F43FE"><enum>(9)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8263ED5BD92D4A1983977B73537C1AEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, each State regulatory authority (with respect to each electric utility for which the State has ratemaking authority) and each nonregulated utility shall commence consideration under section 111, or set a hearing date for consideration, with respect to each standard established by paragraphs (22) and (23) of section 111(d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE731E5284264A39B40BCBC046CAE348" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, each State regulatory authority (with respect to each electric utility for which the State has ratemaking authority), and each nonregulated electric utility shall complete the consideration and make the determination under section 111 with respect to each standard established by paragraphs (22) and (23) of section 111(d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60AC2DBEBAE341508184EB1C0A273C4B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after completing the consideration and making a determination under section 111 with respect to each standard established by paragraphs (22) and (23) of section 111(d), each State regulatory authority (with respect to each electric utility for which the State has ratemaking authority), and each nonregulated electric utility shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report detailing the process used for consideration and an explanation for the determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H089244C45CBC4F51BFD3BCF24D8A40EE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="HF2509A65739B4700BC5CC2AE6C1DDE08" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HFDFE9D09FE804E32AD019B9F3B5EAF38" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>In the case of the standard established by paragraphs (22) and (23) of section 111(d), the reference contained in this subsection to the date of enactment of this Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of enactment of such paragraphs (22) and (23).</quote> after <quote>paragraph (21).</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C1AF9B50F1041409580E4A03AFEC0F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6ED1B26F555A4FB1BDADDC1B0BD8799B"><subsection id="H1573F47111B94132BA71EAA64BCB2A99"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Other prior State actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (b) and (c) shall not apply to the standards established by paragraphs (22) and (23) of section 111(d) in the case of any electric utility in a State if, before the date of enactment of this subsection—</text><paragraph id="H1E491E8305B24994B6AFBBEA2277C204"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State has implemented for the electric utility the standard concerned (or a comparable standard);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF624F961279F4A10A9E6A53824B0585C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State regulatory authority for the State or the relevant nonregulated electric utility has conducted a proceeding to consider implementation of the standard concerned (or a comparable standard) for the electric utility; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC0F3BB518D14E08B06A9DFE92DE4E2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the State legislature has voted on the implementation of the standard concerned (or a comparable standard) for the electric utility during the 3-year period ending on that date of enactment.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37C7C271576E4DB290AFC77CBA1B128A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prior and pending proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 124 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2634">16 U.S.C. 2634</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>In the case of each standard established by paragraphs (22) and (23) of section 111(d), the reference contained in this section to the date of enactment of this Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of enactment of such paragraphs (22) and (23).</quote> after <quote>paragraph (21).</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

