<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26047-T1F-9D-2LS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3634 IS: Accountability for Withholding Aid and Relief Essentials Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3634</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To express the sense of Congress regarding the conduct by the Netanyahu administration in Gaza and to impose sanctions to discourage governments from obstructing humanitarian assistance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="idb2f4d926c01247349ae0ee1d94b4a515"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accountability for Withholding Aid and Relief Essentials Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AWARE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id226a5300071c4ae6813223acb217daef"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idfd67e98aaeff474f88374050b8eae2d2">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id14e295fa5e6449f88eb599eef3a17e5d">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="iddc1adeef97d440a8bb3e371b4e33bdae">Sec. 4. Statement of policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7a5b6c4e92334f1787fb0f19f8819fd8">Sec. 5. Identification of covered persons obstructing humanitarian assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb5d2823aa43f44a2bfb1257123eccad4">Sec. 6. Imposition of sanctions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7fdc665bfe06412b8c429be5e12a1ff6">Sec. 7. Waiver for national security interests.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4c094acaf9db49ff89f306a193e10cee">Sec. 8. Termination of sanctions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id643a60a5b76a4b0cb935133e818ffcc8">Sec. 9. Congressional oversight.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6c120d33d5494044871ad42e25f73717">Sec. 10. Sunset.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id97eaad1adb8d4685ba62461b3d9be7d5">Sec. 11. Severability.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idae887417b98a4dac97eec3c67fa24e7e">Sec. 12. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="idfd67e98aaeff474f88374050b8eae2d2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id3539ef6d7793416a82346ec7e82d7c26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to many credible nongovernmental organizations, such as Doctors Without Borders, the Government of Israel under the leadership of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has heavily restricted the distribution of food, fuel, medicine, and other humanitarian assistance to civilians in Gaza.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde8d8473a998452881a11ecb28252b64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States has at times had to take extraordinary measures to work around the Netanyahu administration’s restrictions in order to provide aid to the people of Gaza.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e5fbfed212a4ec8a9d171d6752b01d6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In a longitudinal, cross-sectional study published in <quote>The Lancet</quote> in October 2025, medical scholars from the Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health and the United Nations Relief and Works Agency found that, between January 2024 and August 2025, during the Netanyahu administration, tens of thousands of preschool-aged children in Gaza were suffering from preventable acute malnutrition and faced an increased risk of mortality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb37fea6273e46d4b3284302ff7c066e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The entire population of the Gaza Strip, an estimated 2,200,000 people, is facing acute levels of hunger and, according to the United Nations, since January 2025, more than 20,000 children have been identified as suffering from acute malnutrition, a telltale sign of imminent famine. To a great extent, this is a result of the policies of Prime Minister Netanyahu.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f194a922e054a88b6843f76a13cd58e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United Nations Relief and Works Agency states that the amount of aid allowed into Gaza must reach a minimum of 500 to 600 truckloads of meaningful aid per day to meet the necessary minimum to prevent starvation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf36ea2797824905aecd3edf3b89b2bb"><enum>(6)</enum><text>During the Netanyahu administration, from May 19, 2025, through January 7, 2026, according to the Monitoring and Tracking Dashboard of the United Nations Office for Project Services, fewer than 17,000 trucks of humanitarian aid had made it to any of the crossings along Gaza’s perimeter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf563c33cf7f943dc9f9c45ae36b155cd"><enum>(7)</enum><text>According to the Netanyahu administration’s Ministry of Diaspora Affairs and Combating Antisemitism, nongovernmental organizations wishing to supply humanitarian assistance in Gaza must be registered with and approved by an inter-ministerial team led by the Director General of Ministry of Diaspora Affairs and Combating Antisemitism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idedea774462f040b3bd93a3982e49f5fc"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to the Netanyahu administration’s Ministry of Defense of the State of Israel, Israel’s Coordinator of Government Activities in the Territories office, which assists in determining the eligibility of a nongovernmental organization in the registration approval process, requires additional clearance for and coordination with nongovernmental organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac9a07519394491baf12c3b9e993833f"><enum>(9)</enum><text>There already exist established, universal standards, such as the Sphere standards and the United Nations coordinated response guidance, that an organization must meet in order to function as a credible, legitimate humanitarian organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf8e0c13822234213b264bc73e7fc99e9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Prime Minister Netanyahu has repeatedly denied the existence of mass hunger and starvation in Gaza.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida92c19bde5d2441798b8b680aeadea59"><enum>(11)</enum><text>According to Doctors Without Borders and Human Rights Watch, Palestinians in Gaza in need of aid receive contradictory and counterproductive information regarding aid availability, often with very little notice from the Netanyahu administration, which leads to confusion, puts them in dangerous situations, and diminishes their ability to actually secure aid.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3cdc3a97f454316a8f387cdc5138cf4"><enum>(12)</enum><text>According to a July 23, 2025, statement from more than 100 nongovernmental organizations, the Netanyahu administration’s Coordinator of Government Activities in the Territories office heavily restricted the humanitarian assistance distributed outside of the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation network.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c48d5b59e694883801e526a1b03fa95"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On July 1, 2025, more than 170 nongovernmental organizations, such as Doctors Without Borders, called for the dismantling of the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation as a result of its violations of international norms associated with humanitarian work and concerns of harm to civilians at distribution centers of the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc16691d84b964f7cb5af4fd55c8a7533"><enum>(14)</enum><text>During the Netanyahu administration, the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights has reported that more than 1,000 Palestinians in Gaza have been killed seeking food, more than 800 of whom were killed at or around distribution sites of the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8921eea57dc48339a75175629157fd5"><enum>(15)</enum><text>During the Netanyahu administration, Human Rights Watch has reported that multiple sources, including former staff of the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation, have witnessed instances of the Israel Defense Forces opening fire on aid-seeking Palestinians with live ammunition near distribution sites of the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id296901daef0842e08c6e449a9cb329f3"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Gaza Humanitarian Foundation received on-ground logistical and security support from Safe Reach Solutions and UG Solutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc558e5c6c1da4804a0ff75344df7b787"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Government of Israel and Hamas entered into a ceasefire on October 10, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id99009529677547b9ad8f610ce49a7c7a"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Gaza Humanitarian Foundation suspended its operations on October 10, 2025, following the start of the ceasefire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2440bc75fe454103813e7b4a7646e483"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Despite the suspension of operations by the Gaza Humanitarian Foundation, numerous nongovernmental organizations have reported that Safe Reach Solutions and UG Solutions plan to continue operations in Gaza.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d5d19828a3147bfbc844bfbbc171756"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Despite the ceasefire and the proposed increase in humanitarian assistance, restrictions on delivery and distribution persist under the Netanyahu administration and actual levels of humanitarian assistance remain well below what is needed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad58533308de4c41b987cddf13bfa1c3"><enum>(21)</enum><text>More than 40 nongovernmental organizations operating on the ground in Gaza issued a statement on October 23, 2025, stating that, despite the ceasefire, Israeli authorities under the Netanyahu administration have continued to arbitrarily reject shipments of humanitarian assistance into Gaza, including items such as blankets, mattresses, food and nutrition supplies, hygiene kits, sanitation materials, assistive devices, and children’s clothing, and have caused almost $50,000,000 of essential goods to sit stockpiled at the crossings, unable to be distributed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9516f22930ad4fc6b46357db956a283a"><enum>(22)</enum><text>The Director General of the Ministry of Diaspora Affairs and Combating Antisemitism, the Minister of Diaspora Affairs and Combating Antisemitism, the Coordinator of Government Activities in the Territories, the General Staff of the Israel Defense Forces, the Chief of the General Staff of Israel Defense Forces, the Defense Minister of Israel, and the Prime Minister of Israel all have authorities to help ensure the delivery of humanitarian assistance to Palestinian civilians in Gaza.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a09c159c3c9437c876fa8389a0eb7d9"><enum>(23)</enum><text>The Minister of Diaspora Affairs and Combating Antisemitism, the Defense Minister of Israel, and the Prime Minister of Israel all have authority to change policy to ensure the distribution of humanitarian aid in Gaza.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a41c078bafd4368814cabf610c5a543"><enum>(24)</enum><text>International humanitarian law, including customary norms and treaty law, prohibits the use of starvation as a method of warfare and requires the protection of civilians’ access to humanitarian assistance.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id14e295fa5e6449f88eb599eef3a17e5d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="idb12f874f12454839bdfbe3fd5ea92e3a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Israel has the right to self-defense and the United States is committed to helping Israel safeguard its people from future aggression;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2f0058158b5451490c7ca8cfbb059bd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hamas should be condemned in the harshest terms for its premeditated, coordinated, and brutal terrorist attacks on Israel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d6dcf3e8124424db27720adf067b55b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hamas’s abductions and threats made against hostages, including threats to use hostages as human shields, are abhorrent;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida41243f6fc9943d0a95c1ef756ddde78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hamas should immediately cease its attacks against Israel and return the body of the deceased hostage;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd7d41fec192437f8f52abe6b72a3ed6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the people killed by Hamas’s terrorist attacks deserve to be commemorated, and the hostages, people wounded, and their families deserve the support of the people of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ffe3499d0c64e4081246d536dc5aac2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>all countries should unequivocally condemn Hamas’s war on Israel, including Hamas’s intentional targeting of, and attacks against, civilians;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbdd140dab22e46a689df0bfecf6d901a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the United States appreciates the global advocacy efforts calling for the release of all hostages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ef509cb03544f96ac4216424ded8fb1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Iran’s support for global terrorism, including its support for terrorist groups, such as Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad, should be condemned and opposed by all available means;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda663854dc8847d18bc5b5a4a1ef4b85"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the blocking of the borders of Gaza by the administration of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu in 2025, which prohibited entry of food, medicine, infant formula, fuel, and other humanitarian assistance and essential services, should be condemned;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05b11436db4f476589696805790693e0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the vast majority of men, women, and especially children in Gaza, are civilians and not agents of Hamas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ccbb96c8cf1449382f9e266e2e9b989"><enum>(11)</enum><text>actions by the Netanyahu administration that have contributed to the humanitarian crisis and acute suffering of Palestinians are horrifying;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ae2be3973c94dcdbf3d3c110c9bac69"><enum>(12)</enum><text>occupying powers have a responsibility to ensure the safety and well-being of the civilians in the occupied territory;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a247162fd9d4c9abab0b064d98a693b"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the Netanyahu administration has implemented policies that have regularly and deliberately undermined the delivery and distribution of humanitarian assistance to Palestinians in Gaza, exacerbating the humanitarian crisis in Gaza;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2c9fc79a9df47059bd3ae6fff183edf"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the restrictions on aid are being carried out by the political appointees and senior military leadership of the Netanyahu administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id61199849381445f29e2905f740c0cc1a"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the restriction of aid by the Netanyahu administration is not consistent with the State of Israel’s core values and commitment to human rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcf9751941584610926f6992bdc40390"><enum>(16)</enum><text>the Netanyahu administration’s conduct has eroded the State of Israel’s standing in the world by undermining the rule of law and violating fundamental human rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida04fbb32c09544d7b7bf8b0eec58262a"><enum>(17)</enum><text>the United States can support the State of Israel’s right to exist while opposing the policies and conduct of the Netanyahu administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc9c7bc271744cbdb6d0c072f5ed6412"><enum>(18)</enum><text>the United States condemns the Netanyahu administration for restricting aid, but it continues to greatly value its relationship with the State of Israel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id849d6e5712f94f65bf2fcfcaf7fecaa9"><enum>(19)</enum><text>the Netanyahu administration’s restrictions on aid create dire conditions for the civilians of Gaza, including death from starvation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b23f087b30f478fa11bdbc622d9b8f3"><enum>(20)</enum><text>children dying of starvation serves no military aims for Israel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8938e3cc2780428393d8f75f04071980"><enum>(21)</enum><text>such dire conditions undermine Israel’s future security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide617c67195a94280ab6e2b65c2d53cac"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Prime Minister Netanyahu or his successor should immediately facilitate the delivery of neutral, independent, impartial, and safe distribution of humanitarian assistance by all legitimate local and international actors to end the humanitarian crisis in Gaza as soon as possible;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32ac00b1d8bd462cbebb01392407f6bf"><enum>(23)</enum><text>legitimate local and international actors delivering and distributing humanitarian assistance should at all times be safe from deliberate, incidental, and collateral harm from operations by Israel and its surrogates, including under the Netanyahu administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97054959b9a3408fa7e263fd0abc1d44"><enum>(24)</enum><text>the President, the Secretary of State, and the heads of other relevant United States Government agencies should urgently use all available diplomatic tools—</text><subparagraph id="idc0860083f9d54550bc5cc0c3a8f687b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to maintain the ceasefire and hostage release agreement agreed to by Israel and Hamas on October 10, 2025;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id298fc9036c3f4553b5166827d1752cad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to bring about an immediate and sustained surge in humanitarian assistance to Palestinian civilians in Gaza; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4cffdca14c8a47bbabe1effb40426c77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to lay the groundwork for a broader regional peace through implementation of the 20-point plan included in the agreement described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="iddc1adeef97d440a8bb3e371b4e33bdae"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that—</text><paragraph id="idf78ffc006ae848b9b58df1faf20faee1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protected persons are entitled at all times to sufficient humanitarian assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaede87e05ff24803a47c7c7f85fc3c5c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a government is unable or unwilling to ensure delivery and distribution of sufficient humanitarian assistance to a territory under its control, that government must allow any and all United States and internationally recognized humanitarian organizations to deliver and distribute sufficient humanitarian assistance to the protected persons in that territory; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1365d7854a0a48b6a72abc5c2fe183d6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any covered persons acting on behalf of a government found to be restricting, diminishing, undermining, or preventing the delivery and distribution of sufficient humanitarian assistance to protected persons, including protected persons residing in a territory under the government’s control, are in violation of the policy described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7a5b6c4e92334f1787fb0f19f8819fd8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Identification of covered persons obstructing humanitarian assistance</header><subsection id="id18abbae8b860409cb37f25dde95bbad2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="id37126ec223394174b564df467c44b7ec"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all covered persons the President determines are in violation of the policy described in section 4;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7300020e7fe7430bb2191ea6c62bec79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each such person—</text><subparagraph id="id07eb14a22e5b4af7b0c2e7ba2ec1f36d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a justification for inclusion of the person on the list, including a description of the information supporting the inclusion of the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80b4f1d98e0a4b18829f95b064f4cc51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement of which, if any, of the sanctions described in section 6 have been imposed, or will be imposed, with respect to the person within 30 days of the submission of the report; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bc5a4ddc9c04479a50e4c65047f92d0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if sanctions under section 6 have not been imposed and will not be imposed within 30 days of the submission of the report with respect to the person—</text><clause id="id005bfb495fae4393ba4669d40533085d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of the specific authority under which otherwise applicable sanctions are being waived, have otherwise been determined not to apply, or are not being imposed; and</text></clause><clause id="idedc94884abe24d5e97bd246b911bb631"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a complete justification of the decision to waive or otherwise not apply the sanctions;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2008226f0e99470b8a0e24ebca72aa20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if few or no such persons have been added to that list during the year preceding submission of the report, a description, prepared jointly by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State, of the reasons for not adding more such persons to the list; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d1f21b9218f4477a941beb1199ffa86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description, prepared jointly by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State, of efforts by the executive branch to encourage the governments of other countries to impose sanctions that are similar to the sanctions imposed under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc4e0eb68b1e14446aff12740f9b882a5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of report</header><paragraph id="idf5dd29334c3543718cd2c0ad7feceb9a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2), each report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in an unclassified form.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ec90ca9c1b044e5b78c7a57ad12b36d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The name of a person to be included in the list required by subsection (a)(1) may be submitted in a classified annex to the report required by subsection (a) only if the President—</text><subparagraph id="iddf7b6f019046456bb59f2c1339e23480"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that it is vital for the national security interests of the United States to do so;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc023804dcbff448686d2e5a7a6ec0901"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses the annex in a manner consistent with the intent of Congress and the purposes of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf028e180e6d04d6589c101ce0f1caa5d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less than 15 days before submitting the name in a classified annex, provides to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership—</text><clause id="id78460091cf0b46119e794276bd4b67a2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notice of, and a justification for, including or continuing to include the person in the classified annex despite any publicly available credible information indicating that the person engaged in an activity in violation of the policy described in section 4; and</text></clause><clause id="id8ed6efea1fc74b11ae88c6ef8f96b578"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notice of, and a justification for the issuance of any waiver issued with respect to the person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe4681c20e0b468f938b8fb256c5d708"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of the report required by subsection (a) shall be made available on a publicly available internet website of the Federal Government not later than 30 days after the report is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb5d2823aa43f44a2bfb1257123eccad4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><subsection id="id4904b40af3ea4a5cafe3229b60507150"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose sanctions under subsections (b) and (c) with respect to each covered person included in the list required by section 5(a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="idb6dbe6b579c745c9b5cb7166b2ac4845"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diplomatic sanctions</header><paragraph id="ida17277723c9f42d19157a512a90f6e52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered person included in the list required by section 5(a)(1) is—</text><subparagraph id="id84b0104e5aa743708461c221233bb20c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4124cf65d63748858db0a9a40fd3f048"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd07b29383de3486c80bbc22bc30fec43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d9210e1dcfc483b96ab4b24e89c9cef"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visa and other entry documentation revocation</header><subparagraph id="id2b6bda1418734965b951e15d7665d697"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to any covered person included in the list required by section 5(a)(1), regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7716a3bb787f4a7a8d3a650fb35816d7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>The revocation of a visa or other entry documentation under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="id9c63e296b335494491c985405fd24040"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></clause><clause id="id24fd0727617946ed87f8d1dbe1543d37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the covered person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4208ef141a974c00abf853668ca29f36"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><subparagraph id="id3abad67ac7bb4cea95490b15710e569b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State may issue a visa otherwise prohibited under paragraph (1) or not revoke a visa otherwise required to be revoked under paragraph (2) if the Secretary determines that doing so is necessary—</text><clause id="idd1a9dae1783249fa9debe6e335e27a1d"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>to enable the President to receive an ambassador or other public minister under section 3 of article II of the Constitution of the United States in a manner consistent with the Vienna Conventions; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id350d5887f5764607b172d3cae9f0e1e1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or with any other applicable international obligations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f64959b89dd4821b43063eacf9d6461"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limits on exceptional visas</header><text>A visa issued pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be strictly limited in scope and duration to the minimum required for the purpose for which the visa is issued.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1677ad1902e04c16bf3dae1c7930292c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial sanctions</header><paragraph id="id94023501600a475790d35b60b1afe3f2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a covered person included in the list required by section 5(a)(1) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide01a4af2e12649d3bc3c749b1adef14e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="id4ce5f3a54bde4935acd65f196ac0f431"><enum>(A)</enum><header>National security</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (1) shall not apply to a covered person if the President determines that not applying the sanctions with respect to the person is vital for the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ade5422eb3342628610caf7856cbea1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (1) may not be imposed with respect to a transaction or the facilitation of a transaction for the provision of humanitarian assistance to protected persons, including a transaction relating to—</text><clause id="id05d544d4d7c547c68163ae5fa2a1d0e7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the delivery and distribution of humanitarian assistance to protected persons; or</text></clause><clause id="idbc4cb73e48b14dafb69dbce5eef52e22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out the delivery and distribution of humanitarian assistance to protected persons.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided3235e406ac42e09a2f6db60e4569d6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relating to importation of goods</header><clause id="id0e63793da7774795bf8b3d72c62a4f93"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions under this Act shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></clause><clause id="idc1b49c879cfe49c7b4b532a554776f13"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this clause, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id32b0882edad5401ca10c6a8a82a03f87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph id="idc6e9d7ef7c87482eab9792f3f0e36d57"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of paragraph (1) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that paragraph shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac7763bd2f17400bb8004f7b9b0b2186"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for financial institutions</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe or amend regulations to require each financial institution that is a United States person and has within its possession or control property or interests in property of a covered person included in the list required by section 5(a)(1) to certify to the Secretary that, to the best of the knowledge of the financial institution, the financial institution has blocked all such property and interests in property.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id557608d769f4443cbf744caf416ed704"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7fdc665bfe06412b8c429be5e12a1ff6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Waiver for national security interests</header><subsection id="id6776288bf96b44a797976a9bd94211c9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not withstanding any other provision of law, the President may, for renewable periods not to exceed 180 days each, waive, in part or in whole, the application of sanctions under this Act with respect to a covered person if the President—</text><paragraph id="idf1da1313d6fb4836a1ab67017284d730"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb46ad757d56c44c8ac5d103d414f6a2a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report that describes the waiver or renewal and the reasons for that waiver or renewal; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id99b1f22ea976463a850ec5453c5bf534"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a joint resolution of disapproval relating to the report submitted under subsection (b) is not enacted into law pursuant to section 9.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9e2f13b381354dd0b16d2a6ab52f03ef"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>For each waiver granted under subsection (a), the President shall—</text><paragraph id="id0a4e72971e474e139a85446b787f15d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>limit the duration and scope of the waiver to the minimum required to serve the national security interests for which the waiver is issued; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1cca6de320034a6da9b2e7f7c1b8daab"><enum>(2)</enum><text>upon expiration of the waiver, immediately determine whether the covered person covered by the waiver still meets the criteria for inclusion in the list required by section 5(a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1c193736d23e44c3a33de6d1b5446cd8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Persons meeting criteria for sanctions</header><text>If the President determines under subsection (b)(2) that a covered person still meets the criteria for inclusion in the list required by section 5(a)(1) after the expiration of a waiver applicable to the person, the President shall apply sanctions under section 6 with respect to the person.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id68eab6c107de470b8ba4899a68d39c0a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Persons not meeting criteria for sanctions</header><text>If the President determines under subsection (b)(2) that a covered person no longer meets the criteria for inclusion in the list required by section 5(a)(1) after the expiration of a waiver applicable to the person, the President shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id96305e3cefdd4294814f050878d401e1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pursuant to sections 8 and 9, notify Congress of the intent of the President to terminate the application of sanctions under this Act with respect to the person; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4f7ea2c5ff4f45f0a920e5c2bce5609a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>resume making annual determinations with respect to whether the person meets the criteria for inclusion in the list required by section 5(a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4c094acaf9db49ff89f306a193e10cee"><enum>8.</enum><header>Termination of sanctions</header><subsection id="id7a7b5afc2e024022aff340f891791cbd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination of sanctions on individual persons</header><paragraph id="id76a2c304bb314c61ba3c2152600546cf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this Act with respect to a covered person if—</text><subparagraph id="ida284cd93994040c4a11f5d9afb7eec77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President determines that—</text><clause id="id2b6b7c1c24cc4646b0ad8264fc5a30e5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>credible and verifiable information exists that the person never met the criteria for inclusion in the list required by section 5(a)(1);</text></clause><clause id="id8910b08371fa4cd19875ded2893b3f2e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>credible and verifiable information exists that the person—</text><subclause id="idb23799f3f4614245aa37bf10f3d6813c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no longer meets such criteria; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id93e8487a79b4409fa476f36ef46427ea"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has credibly committed to not engage in any activity that would meet such criteria in the future; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id9757bc44ffce47f98d1036b7dc42dbc2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the termination of the sanctions is in the national security interests of the United States;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38087289dd93456da08a99f654f2bc12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report that includes—</text><clause id="id9ca07a22588340f4a2768db9b44d6694"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a request to terminate the application of sanctions under this Act with respect to the person; and</text></clause><clause id="idcedee84fd5e64d2884beb7790a724e03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the reasons for that request; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17397a026e79438985788659279533bc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a joint resolution of disapproval relating to the report submitted under subparagraph (B) is not enacted into law pursuant to section 9.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idac2ba3bcb0fd46049a68d6ba87f21a30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidentiality of proprietary information</header><text>Proprietary information that can be associated with a request to terminate sanctions with respect to a specific covered person may be included in a report submitted under paragraph (1)(B) only if—</text><subparagraph id="id39c242a20ef7486c96ecb203de677373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appropriate congressional committees and leadership provide assurances of confidentiality; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc641b75e446e4a2cad0a4a4423d1bdd9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered person consents in writing to the inclusion of the information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id958327c8cbbb4cc992c8179334d8919f" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of sanctions program</header><text>The President may terminate the application of all sanctions under this Act with respect to a country if—</text><paragraph id="ida8ea6039643e4a6b90911c0ca02be7c2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President determines that there no longer exists any covered person in that country that meets the criteria for inclusion in the list required by section 5(a)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc29e8320908641c3917474239826d89e" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="idbaf6e8286e3748fc8e07b469ea7e8b2c" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a request to terminate the application of sanctions under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id363dc090673b4d5aa2415573957aad8d" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the reasons for that request; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id94e1912f6d7e468ab202fc0ebe9e090c" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a joint resolution of disapproval relating to the report submitted under paragraph (2) is not enacted into law pursuant to section 9.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id643a60a5b76a4b0cb935133e818ffcc8"><enum>9.</enum><header>Congressional oversight</header><subsection id="id78e785b174374d759eb8fd4e25e5a2af"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Congressional requests for determinations of specific covered persons</header><paragraph id="id5078a9755e4146f498867e7a1ccd7ac5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after receiving a request from the chairman and ranking member of one of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a covered person meets the criteria for inclusion in the list required by section 5(a)(1), the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="ide5350d65d67c435d87b1600924a666d3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine if the person meets those criteria; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9bcd8c2091b444d875a3ab5b93ca585"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the chairman and ranking member a report with respect to that determination that includes a statement of whether or not the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions under this Act with respect to the person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id69c036ec5898432b9fee908bc8fae53f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1)(B) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf56a8a8ac691479fb213de4acbe4c973"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to congress of proposed action</header><paragraph id="idf43d7d1bc3d54841baccf443ffa5e87d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, before taking any action described in paragraph (2), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and leadership a report that describes the proposed action and the reasons for that action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id834be8f51abb43038e13e53856d3fe3e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text>An action described in this paragraph is—</text><subparagraph id="idfc3a66e96f324c039ac589eca2cc6b18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an action to waive the application of any sanctions pursuant to section 7; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c5c0093aaf543cc9ec7c348f6291e98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an action to terminate the application of any sanctions pursuant to section 8.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8fb70e61bf044c2480dc351e51793853"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional review of requests for proposed action</header><paragraph id="id04c61d09e02a45c7a0c559ce213d5ab5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period of 30 calendar days beginning on the date on which the President submits a report under section 7 or 8, the appropriate congressional committees should, as appropriate, hold hearings and briefings and otherwise obtain information in order to fully review the report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida22955fc3c8549d29bffd71377521b87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The period for congressional review under paragraph (1) of a report submitted under section 7 or 8 shall be 60 calendar days if the report is submitted on or after July 10 and on or before September 7 in any calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94bacc8d1e534023b7d98881ad1f98c1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on actions during initial congressional review period</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during the period for congressional review provided for under paragraph (1) of a report submitted under section 7 or 8, including any additional period for such review as applicable under the exception provided in paragraph (2), the President may not take the requested action unless a joint resolution of approval with respect to that action is enacted in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd430df8c44c140baa9acaa3758003f65"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on actions during presidential consideration of a joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a joint resolution of disapproval relating to a report submitted under section 7 or 8 passes both Houses of Congress in accordance with subsection (d), the President may not take that action for a period of 12 calendar days after the date of passage of the joint resolution of disapproval.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaccddcdfd4f54652811f7f6c34e96b97"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on actions during congressional reconsideration of a joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a joint resolution of disapproval relating to a report submitted under section 7 or 8 passes both Houses of Congress in accordance with subsection (d), and the President vetoes the joint resolution, the President may not take that action for a period of 10 calendar days after the date of the President’s veto.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2386581e4f24c9c82f260a3aa5b3bb9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effect of enactment of a joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a joint resolution of disapproval relating to a report submitted under section 7 or 8 is enacted in accordance with subsection (d), the President may not take that action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc3b102c0bff8468ca5689e862cf722dc"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint resolutions of approval or disapproval defined</header><paragraph id="id2feaba7ce1e14c90b1ff8072179541d5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress—</text><subparagraph id="id028b64defc784ca6bd52dae196957d3e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>A joint resolution approving the President’s proposal to waive or terminate the application of certain sanctions with respect to the obstruction of humanitarian assistance.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7f607a39f9d46e6bf4ab8b2cfbe4a2c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>Congress approves of the action relating to the application of sanctions imposed with respect to the obstruction of humanitarian assistance set forth in the report submitted to Congress under _______ of the <short-title>Accountability for Withholding Aid and Relief Essentials Act of 2026</short-title> on _______ relating to _______.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with either section 7 or 8, as applicable, the second blank space being filled with the appropriate date, and the third blank space being filled with a short description of the proposed action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a5de198cae14686afbaf6e05fa28208"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>The term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress—</text><subparagraph id="id13cff2da69e04d15ad32cd015eb0d203"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>A joint resolution disapproving the President's proposal to waive or terminate the application of certain sanctions with respect to the obstruction of humanitarian assistance.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id042d108ff8d5427cb657c4d0f4659355"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>Congress disapproves of the action relating to the application of sanctions imposed with respect to the obstruction of humanitarian assistance set forth in the report submitted to Congress under _______ of the <short-title>Accountability for Withholding Aid and Relief Essentials Act of 2026</short-title> on _______ relating to _______.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with either section 7 or 8, as applicable, the second blank space being filled with the appropriate date, and the third blank space being filled with a short description of the proposed action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id420c4f17f6184a7ea8108f905dff5d73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period of 30 calendar days provided for under subsection (c), including any additional period as applicable under the exception provided in paragraph (2) of that subsection, a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced—</text><subparagraph id="idee477c843b2d4f01a78941e88520a87e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the Senate, by the majority leader (or the majority leader’s designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader’s designee); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b49dd50c64d47b9b454ab51868a6b53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives, by the majority leader or the minority leader.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6437e5e6632a475a97181a2499de1660"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Floor consideration in house of representatives</header><text>If a committee of the House of Representatives to which a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 10 calendar days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0f68e689d2a46abb1da8799dfb1f7fa"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration in the senate</header><subparagraph id="id6c0bfdaa4ab542caac760e217d779fdd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id031707ef584b42319cf6ec61e3c0c33a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the Committee on Foreign Relations has not reported the joint resolution within 10 calendar days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id267f56c08a2f427da7d864c3a1bdb113"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Foreign Relations reports a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval to the Senate or has been discharged from consideration of such a joint resolution (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5aea11be73b44fa7b07647b0928a2ab8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate to the procedure relating to a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id795c84a1670b44d3b18d21780ce8c5d3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to a joint resolution of approval or joint resolution of disapproval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with the joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e1bb6dcfd4040de9c0f1578cc260665"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rules relating to senate and house of representatives</header><subparagraph id="id744210e5a05f4e9aad70dd7ddef38e88"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Treatment of senate joint resolution in house of representatives</header><text>In the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply to a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval received from the Senate (unless the House of Representatives has already adopted a joint resolution relating to the same proposed action):</text><clause id="ida6f54da3c70d44dca02ca47512d9439e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></clause><clause id="id019d42d372cd48dfbb9c5fe679c7636e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the Committee on Foreign Affairs has not reported the joint resolution within 2 calendar days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text></clause><clause id="idece3dc90d80f4e70bf4ed4d3bac0ce2b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after the Committee on Foreign Affairs reports the joint resolution to the House of Representatives or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House of Representatives. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House of Representatives has disposed of a motion to proceed on the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></clause><clause id="id23770c80644e49168983c41f9fa87fa2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final adoption without intervening motion except 2 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on adoption of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6ad5550ae774ebcb6cab55a9ce6aae9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of house of representatives joint resolution in senate</header><clause id="id427b9f6c9f3f41e2af2cfe4fd2fc19b8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Receipt of house resolution before adoption of senate resolution</header><text>If, before the adoption by the Senate of a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply:</text><subclause id="id6061ee8e51f048ba9c1a5e2525d39820"><enum>(I)</enum><text>That joint resolution shall not be referred to a committee.</text></subclause><subclause id="id2b7162093b104923903446d7cf9bfa06"><enum>(II)</enum><text>With respect to that joint resolution—</text><item id="id8aefb0cd01b14a5c9041940ee44dd2a1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the procedure in the Senate shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the House of Representatives; but</text></item><item id="id385666a911464728a9d268429e53d3be"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the vote on adoption shall be on the joint resolution from the House of Representatives.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="ida3994b395fcf4adab76e637bc1a9d704"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Receipt of house resolution after adoption of senate resolution</header><text>If, following adoption of a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval in the Senate, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, that joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate Senate calendar.</text></clause><clause id="idab3d5311e2434167a0dfbcdddf3a682b"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>No senate companion</header><text>If a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval is received from the House of Representatives, and no companion joint resolution has been introduced in the Senate, the Senate procedures under this subsection shall apply to the joint resolution from the House.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58b0d8761961442abc528014bda2ac63"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to revenue measures</header><text>The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply in the House of Representatives to a joint resolution of approval or a joint resolution of disapproval that is a revenue measure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6d5e70033674f5f9b779821ced79bd1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rules of senate and house of representatives</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph id="id9f19de053b80455aa01e00c97c11f335"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House of Congress, respectively, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id553e2cc0d4e74477add3e288ccc44784"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6c120d33d5494044871ad42e25f73717"><enum>10.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="id97eaad1adb8d4685ba62461b3d9be7d5"><enum>11.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of any such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of the provisions of this Act, and the application of those provisions to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></section><section id="idae887417b98a4dac97eec3c67fa24e7e"><enum>12.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ide5f3cbb926204b80a40430e0f8b23de1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ide771a5b31453422b860a640e78a913e0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f0de2daa9a044ecaeb447fd08594baf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc280c50630f04fd9b1bd345a414a464f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees and leadership</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees and leadership</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ide874257de78f4450b476e7af67ad5aeb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appropriate congressional committees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26d87960303b44ad8ce2fa2a5b1e99e7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddbfb1403b86d4583a3b196854a84cd7a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Speaker, the majority leader, and the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1fe69224a97340369193d8647bffb5ec"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <term>covered person</term> means a foreign person who is any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id6ee44ad2478b4f778a64d48e7d0ed465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The prime minister or head of state of a foreign government or any official in the office of the prime minister or head of state in a foreign government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bee19f401a84c859ce154d06f6ef8ac"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A cabinet member or any official serving in the office of a cabinet member of a foreign government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6d23bb6fd744bc5833bf65852be2939"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any official of a foreign government who reports to a cabinet official.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf49f8db83f64423820e5f488dac65fb"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any official of a foreign government overseeing civilian coordination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7ab0c1167c4450692d7c420ea070c46"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any official of a foreign government facilitating humanitarian projects.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd9f6b7ab3d9410a91518d2e9bdf7fe3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any official of a foreign government facilitating infrastructure projects.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae31cd2dc63442e1b0ccb6823e1e2fef"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any commissioned officer serving in the military of a foreign country with a rank equivalent to the rank of lieutenant colonel or higher in the United States Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id508a4c24b2b7424cabfaa35ea1a662e4"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other individual of equivalent rank serving in a security agency affiliated with, associated with, or working on behalf of a foreign government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0735ba186b554ff8be2179569d380148"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any entity, including a foundation or economic conglomerate, overseen by an individual described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (H), or owned or controlled by such an individual, that is complicit in financing or resourcing the restriction of humanitarian assistance to protected persons.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9358b6bcdb8a42f28b934d9321669c04"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Any person determined by the President—</text><clause id="idbc0c9362a9694abdae5e9c5444ab9a26"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4956839c20dd4c3baec58d6a604f2181"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to be complicit in financing or resourcing the restriction of humanitarian assistance to protected persons; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id56b0d1e8b1784c5db7e9af3001957045"><enum>(II)</enum><text>appointed by an individual described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (H) to a position—</text><item id="id41c1d5a692924e658ae5b488eea78234"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>as an official of a foreign government; or</text></item><item id="id259e789919e1452b9997be69c4993dfa"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the head of a nongovernmental entity;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idab176d188f694c9bb94f8abfa346ee92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of any person the property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to section 6(c);</text></clause><clause id="id1c36801fb8ea4283b8066d934db54b51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to be owned or controlled by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly any person the property and interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to section 6(c); or</text></clause><clause id="idc6d42a4ac3694244b07d4c2e16aae0ed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to be a member of the board of directors or a senior executive officer of any person the property and interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to section 6(c).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1932c80be6d43c4b5a06791f2cc799d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d2b15777e6f4496bf6de24da4c47e71"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Humanitarian assistance</header><text>The term <term>humanitarian assistance</term> includes the provision of food, water, shelter, health services and medicines, hygiene products, clothing, essential services, and basic service delivery items, such as fuel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68182cbcbd2a4505965a23ee3c364223"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Protected person</header><text>The term <term>protected person</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="idf6a4914beb44494f95922f496095b97a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a civilian, noncombatant, and takes no part in hostilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd69536a38cd4033a790fed1e32e11b1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>performs no work for, and provides no material support to, any United States recognized terrorist or insurgent organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc19864d6c319431db0caf640b71b3dce"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United States and internationally recognized humanitarian organization</header><text>The term <term>United States and internationally recognized humanitarian organization</term> means any international organization or nongovernmental organization that—</text><subparagraph id="id5a59c92f4e3e4c64b3c8c5275f38c23c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides humanitarian assistance that is recognized by and in good standing with the United Nations and the United States Government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e20d7c266de405890ed6153ed07b230"><enum>(B)</enum><text>complies with established professional standards, such as the Sphere humanitarian standards or the United Nations coordinated response guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa6d8ccbfab54cfabeaf01fd4b524b73"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idce35443d70ff4a279a3b707d2acb815d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c7e9ac15e5d4e649916aa4a8d327eaa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idedec727c87354484acb28c520999de97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id26c21202a3ba457e8eefab596d0bdd0b"><enum>(9)</enum><header>United States recognized terrorist or insurgent organization</header><text>The term <term>United States recognized terrorist or insurgent organization</term> means an organization that is designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf51de5deab34724a7d3726d6729521c"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Vienna Conventions</header><text>The term <term>Vienna Conventions</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ida96fa41ef89447a09ae27c34ace43ec4"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations, done at Vienna April 18, 1961 (23 UST 3227); and</text>
        </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58f115c38dc44177a2fb7a92002e2396">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963 (21 UST 77).</text>
        </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

