<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF38C2AC0D6354820B308EC5C62CCB2A3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6245 IH: Prioritizing Lifestyle and Activity for Youth Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6245</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an interagency task force on youth health and wellness to encourage community-supported physical activity spaces.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E12472B9B7A4CC18928089C71DFBEB9" style="OLC"><section id="HFA44C62FB13A405781D96E69C2297C63" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prioritizing Lifestyle and Activity for Youth Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PLAY Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1DC046447E614DE4B7A424E8B873CBFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H253BBE008A174375997D92155E429788"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Playgrounds help enhance children’s cognitive functions and build important creative thinking and problem-solving skills that contributes to their emotional and physical well-being.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA32C2E86A4E4591BD3461E3B0E61835"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Playgrounds are critical to children’s physical and mental health, and every child in America deserves access to a safe and quality place to play.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF84CB0CA3D114DFEB5D7BDD8DF4B07B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Local green spaces can reduce surface heat temperatures by 10 to 20 degrees, which has become the number one weather-related killer in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4B30FE15FE47648C5962EC6F2495DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Safe and accessible playgrounds are proven public health infrastructure that promote physical activity, reduce chronic disease risk, support social-emotional development, and strengthen community cohesion.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9813A7A2A1874609BECB16D752958EBB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interagency Task Force on Child Wellness and Physical Activity Infrastructure</header><subsection id="H071D1CA0EF494DFFA81ADE2AC8427A09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a task force to be known as the <quote>Task Force on Child Wellness and Physical Activity Infrastructure</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1DD7C7E4A36949CD887FFFC1AEC5F5EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of the following members or their designees:</text><paragraph id="HCDAFB14445BF46539ED6DEB1E4AAADAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9340AB1E4D494A7482BBEFFFFED99577"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A8BC83BC09E4A5CB7FEF91A69946B1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7695C8981034771B378CD3C0E1475A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBA97F186E324089874717DCD5CAFBFE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H482E69EEEBD84B6EB57103C47EADD2FE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B8A6B8AFA6A4E9D8902A2EC42618790"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF294A7AE4FF948A7AAF9A641F867C591"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97B643BB92064F5AA51F4A47B964DCD3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Chief of the Army Corps of Engineers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1DDD253593C4CF79BF26C9D0735CA01"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2C0ACABAA1446D98BF7DE21ABDCC119"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H024BF40DFF444DD6B8C7C0FE4601552B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Any other member that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H443B533268644B4487563A6EF5BBFBC2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairpersons</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of the Interior shall serve as co-chairpersons of the Task Force (in this section referred to as the <quote>Chairpersons</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA87563C834047E0868D2F40DC01D951"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="HD46083EAA41F4549B02E09C974C97985"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>The duties of the Task Force shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H1B9078FFDD254E8AAF21A5DF93AA0E4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify opportunities to formalize coordination between the Department of Health and Human Services, public health and public lands agencies, and partner organizations regarding the use of outdoor spaces for creating outdoor environments that encourage physical activity and well-being among youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H063B507759244F5EAD654DEABB05CDBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to identify existing barriers to providing children with opportunities for accessing close-to-home, community-driven, and outdoor spaces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H230320DE77DF41A8B415BC59B7BD7DD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to develop recommendations to better facilitate active play for the promotion of health and well-being, academic learning, and safe community centers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1A2668D6BFB48C9B664836C4CBBDCAA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to develop recommendations for how agencies may work together to ensure the ability of child wellness infrastructure to meet the diverse health, environmental, and resiliency needs of the surrounding community; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3A42600BFE2484EB682771C2AE85C55"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to identify and promote scalable models, such as public-private partnerships between public, private, and nonprofit sector organizations, that build evidence-based play environments proven to improve children’s physical and emotional health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE09A9CE17441B6BE3E9EDB4CA8D69C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Task Force shall carry out the duties under paragraph (1) in consultation with appropriate health and wellness and outdoor recreation groups, including organizations with experience in community-led playground development, child health, and physical activity promotion.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C57FFD225E045B4B9C1F27F989FE383"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H609E682FB709493181AE9F73AA8DEFD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preliminary report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Task Force is established, the Chairpersons shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the preliminary findings of the Task Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29501DDA829F494781D1A20B492B511C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the submittal of the preliminary report under paragraph (1), the Chairpersons shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the findings of the Task Force, which shall include the recommendations developed under subparagraphs (C) and (D) of subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2850EECB22A14338A1EA137D8B23A9F5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Task Force shall terminate on the date that is one year after the date of the submittal of the final report under subsection (e)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0DC9B9BF7E7749C89DC7DC82A394130C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC8F75C15BB494194A9CF0A6CEE869E94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H798E3871EB034182BAEC6FDDA0A92930"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3078CD01E1134E5DAD19F9F6C0FC18AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA1A7426BEEA4A6D8BA561524501BF4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child wellness infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>child wellness infrastructure</term> means community-based environments intentionally designed to support children’s physical activity, play, and health. Such infrastructure may include playgrounds, outdoor learning spaces, nature play areas, and safe places for movement and social interaction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65235219D3BA4064AD64C01F16CD2C47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text>The term <term>public lands</term> means any lands under the jurisdiction of the Federal Government or a State or local government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1306ABAD38B44B1FA786BBC7F351B84D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Youth</header><text>The term <term>youth</term> means any individual under the age of 18.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

