<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3792D76E5B14AE785A0B01E62A5D7FE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9046 IH: COVID-19 Military Mandate Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study on members of
      the Armed Forces who separated from the Armed Forces due to the mandate to receive the
      COVID-19 vaccine and the transfer of education benefits by such members, and for other
      purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H15EAC50407974DE8A6BB5E6BACF08F9E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA58CE1A09EBF4228AE94113912B36D2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>COVID-19 Military Mandate Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3525FF1C452B42D0ACF6B0DFF7B6357A">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Study on separation of members of the Armed Forces due to the mandate to receive the
        COVID-19 vaccine and the transfer of education benefits by such members</header>
      <subsection id="H53247D74D8EE4BBB8E8F8529A2B0F847">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Study</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall conduct a study on covered individuals and the transfer of education benefits by covered individuals to covered dependents.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2A81F713C88B4908AB392DD5D2A80D1D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Report</header>
        <paragraph id="HC955F08B198A42F7B6933A4DA88309FD">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Requirement</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report containing the results of the study required by subsection (a). Such report shall include—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H0E0E0293305B48029348743A2212D008">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the number of covered individuals;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0003945C65924B12B3D6C99946B02083"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the number of covered individuals who initiated a transfer of education benefits to a dependent in accordance with section 3319 of title 38, United States Code, before separation;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H663218DFB98B45A39345B6DB405D6BAC">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the number of covered individuals who initiated such a transfer and did not complete the years of service in the Armed Forces necessary for such dependent to commence use of such education benefits in accordance with such section before separation;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H2D3EB78E2AFF478DAF9EF4DE173CE1E7">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>the number of members of the Armed Forces who were denied a religious exemption from the mandate to receive the COVID-19 vaccine during the period beginning on August 24, 2021, and ending on January 10, 2023;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4E68389CA95746A08EDC843EB175DA73">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the number of covered individuals who were denied such a religious exemption;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF7D8623C2D34483388FAC5FE6EAF01BB">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered individuals who returned to service in accordance with the terms of Executive Order 14184 (relating to reinstating service members discharged under the military's COVID-19 vaccination mandate);</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4800D07A07CB4A16915775ADD95F2377">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>the number of covered individuals who returned to service in accordance with the terms of Executive Order 14184 (relating to reinstating service members discharged under the military's COVID-19 vaccination mandate) who initiated a transfer of education benefits to a dependent in accordance with section 3319 of title 38, United States Code, before separation and return to service;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H9B2CC5A4CF184060B904F9CE5763FFAA" display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>the number of covered individuals who returned to service in accordance with the terms of Executive Order 14184 (relating to reinstating service members discharged under the military's COVID-19 vaccination mandate) who initiated a transfer of education benefits to a dependent in accordance with section 3319 of title 38, United States Code, before separation and return to service and completed the years of service in the Armed Forces necessary for such dependent to commence use of such education benefits;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8E0EADB61FBC4E379AAA5D1DE16A129A">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the number of covered dependents;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC88831E735F46B8B8335EFD94380BCA"> <enum>(J)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the budgetary impact of allowing each covered dependent to commence use of education benefits that were transferred to such covered dependent in accordance with section 3319 of title 38, United States Code, without regard to whether the covered individual who transferred such education benefits to such covered dependent completed the years of service in the Armed Forces necessary for such covered dependent to commence such use; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7A3E970958F845E08095B7053474FBFA">
            <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>any recommendations of the Secretary to address the separation of covered individuals and to ensure covered individuals receive appropriate benefits as veterans of the Armed Forces.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD61F038AEEF041BA9DB4FC75D35C0D47">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Disaggregation</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Defense shall disaggregate the elements of the report required by paragraph (1) that are described in subparagraphs (A) through (J) of such paragraph by—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H535448A42A134AAD8269B7C8F2866A13">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Armed Force in which the covered individual served;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC6F186450D44807BDF10FF52E796DCD"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>whether the covered individual served in an active component or a reserve component;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8987DCC0A73C4FDC9BE2923490F527F9">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the grade of the covered individual;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD63EC0610DFB463EBED7C4E3405E1560"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>the years of service in the Armed Forces of the covered individual at the time of separation; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H6A2DF1703A434D5696BD4A67D740C96C">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the characterization of the discharge of the covered individual.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HFBCF07B120CD41B0BB5F0C8042B26B76"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Public availability</header> <text>Not later than 60 days after the Secretary of Defense submits the report required by subsection (b), the Secretary shall make such report publicly available on the internet website of the Department of Defense.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC2CFA18B174D4219AC343D267A49F700">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HCB1FD9CE625340AFB721FE33438914C7"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Covered dependent</header> <text>The term <quote>covered dependent</quote> means a dependent of an individual who—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HD1968362BDEB44699C1D0916B18BC3F0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is a covered individual;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H857C763CBFE94E0099DACC86978A9805"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>initiated a transfer of education benefits to such dependent in accordance with section 3319 of title 38, United States Code; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H49225F340161442BA08C0833C6040A1D">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>did not complete the years of service in the Armed Forces necessary for such dependent to commence use of such benefits in accordance with such section.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4CBAAEB762264CE6A7945AB2A9F73C95">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Covered individual</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means an individual who, during the period beginning on August 24, 2021, and ending on January 10, 2023, was involuntarily or voluntarily separated from an Armed Force solely on the basis of the refusal of such individual to receive a vaccination against COVID-19.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

