<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H52CBE57F616B4B2F984D8FBE2AE3D60B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8903 IH: Renter Resource Center Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8903</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a renter outreach resource, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2055E1D9B1FC4DBABF77825B06F0B5A7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC7BB396F49ED4A579D922784CAEDCD08" commented="no" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Renter Resource Center Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H820270D08BDC463286D86F402E6A04E7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Renter outreach resource established</header> 
<subsection id="HFB690C2CFBE1439D84ADC03B571806EC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish a renter outreach resource that consists of a toll-free telephone number and a public website designed to assist renters of residential properties owned by a covered large institutional investor in—</text> <paragraph id="H03F77539C3E7404DA7B55D69D87CE539"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notifying Federal agencies about disputes relating to the rental of such properties, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF5F407B498944DEB975FD87DB33FBD76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disputes about potential violations of Federal law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A4503BD74884E26A8EBE3BB9A8BA626"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disputes about potential violations of State law; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1EA98B6D0FC742AB9B6FE9C1743FE9CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other disputed renter matters;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H408CBFA32D1145FDAB5F51DC2E22B498"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sharing information about such disputes with other Federal agencies, including other Federal agencies that manage similar disputes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E5F0637B8CC4605BEAA61383E413C1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>monitoring such disputes; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2D0C01A54734F4FADF31CAD96FB72E4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>resolving such disputes, to the extent practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8A7DDAA32994DAE8DB01F44A18B20B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Response to outreach</header> 
<paragraph id="H7B45428BEC984A10910EBDEB83B65B5A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish reasonable procedures to—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDC7A6A021244EDB9EF4E4BA3267DEB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promptly respond, in writing where appropriate, to a renter who provides information to the Secretary about a dispute using the renter outreach resource established under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6594363906B4D51BE78B0E7CDDF800B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>document such responses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF575D1E28AD94DBDBA6DC49D483B90E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Responses provided under paragraph (1) shall include, where appropriate, information about—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H997989A7818A46BBB75B6B1DD16A13CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>steps that have been taken by the Secretary or another Federal agency in response to the information about the dispute provided by the renter, including determining the appropriate covered large institutional investor involved as described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H253E6FF6C8F9432EB5370D1DDFD8BC82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any responses received by the Secretary or another Federal agency from the covered large institutional investor related to such dispute; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E81CF64AF1A475F84920FFFFC93A34F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any outcome of the dispute, to the extent practicable.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE48CF92E9AE45149680F58DFDA7FA7B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investigation of potential violations of Federal law</header> <paragraph id="H5C7A914DD3C34DDE899C21DD176D2730"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promptly process and investigate any information relating to a dispute received through the renter outreach resource established under subsection (a) about a potential violation of Federal law that is received from a renter of a residential property owned by a covered large institutional investor through the renter outreach resource established under subsection (a), including by sharing information about such potential violation of Federal law with any relevant Federal agencies, as the Secretary may determine appropriate, and by determining the appropriate covered large institutional investor involved as needed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H237FB04A8CD544E49F5691A72B642758"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responses to requests for information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered large institutional investor may respond to any request for information made pursuant to paragraph (1) and may include in such response whether such covered large institutional investor owns the property described in such request for information.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56F18E323CD04FC3A58F8DFB83228569" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information for appropriate State authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the Secretary receives information about a potential violation of State law or about a dispute received through the renter outreach resource, from a renter of a residential property owned by a covered large institutional investor through the renter outreach resource established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall, at a minimum, provide the renter with contact information for the appropriate, State-specific, State authority authorized to process and investigate such information.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H74641CB8065C4CDC9FC4E322634414B6" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice about renter outreach resource</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered large institutional investor shall—</text> <paragraph id="H121CAFD6218B4817BC398B0BEF84C530" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to each renter of a residential property owned by such investor at the time such renter first occupies such home and annually thereafter—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H17CD92385CBF4B95B686DA7C1B12CAD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">written notice about the renter outreach resource established under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAAD9DCDDF7644A1865E06F357691E1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, phone number, and email address of the person or entity responsible for receiving and addressing renter disputes for the covered large institutional investor, and update the name, phone number, and email address within 30 days if such information changes prior to the subsequent time at which such notice is required to be provided; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6682B437E50E409F86559AF61B07AED1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prominently feature information about the renter outreach resource established under subsection (a) on a public website of such investor that is accessible by such renter.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H52CC6E73F2E4472287C85CD52B78FE55" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report to the Congress</header> <paragraph id="H1D346877495B4FCE89E7835A5C9DE48B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than March 31 of each year, submit to the Congress a public report which analyzes and aggregates the information received or obtained pursuant to this Act during the prior year that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3A4648C4FBA14AB6BEE36C16D17273C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the types and the number of disputes received about potential violations of Federal law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9906F15B809E4E5E854C3158268427F5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the types and the number of disputes received about potential violations of State law;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE7F6CE4B7DD4D019A2790232C8F8A43" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the types and the number of disputes received about other disputed renter matters;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CD46C88BAD84BE29C7ED3265084614F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>where practicable, information about the resolution of such disputes; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBCA62A76C2B4D33BD0140ED38471F2A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information provided to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under subsection (h).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC4B1670F6464D0D86C767BE3F231667" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Anonymization of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any data included in a report that is submitted under this paragraph shall be aggregated or anonymized so as to protect any individual dispute or personally identifiable information received through the renter outreach resource.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5A2675466274F8BBCD5B4CFB3CE4E71" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Protection of personal information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In complying with the requirements of this Act, the Secretary shall take such measures as the Secretary determines are necessary to provide for the protection of personally identifiable information received through the renter outreach resource in a manner that conforms with existing standards for protection of the confidentiality of personally identifiable information.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H57AEBD35B6D4475CB9E23F65A9AE5405"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An owner of a residential property owned by a covered large institutional investor, as such term is defined in subsection (i) shall, beginning in calendar year 2026—</text> 
<paragraph id="H99F7E22B92C04E6AA7C26230E9047BDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify the Secretary each year, before December 31st whether such owner remains a covered large institutional investor as defined in subsection (i); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38E9A493E60244478411E303D0E25DE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in such notification, identify how many covered single-family homes such covered large institutional investor has direct or indirect investment control of as of the date of the submission of such notice, and the city and State where each such covered single-family home is located, unless such covered large institutional investor owns 10 or fewer covered single-family homes in such city.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6B1A3FF240634DF1AE5B22DD472B635E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HCEEB440F31AF4FF79813685D575B3ABD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered large institutional investor</header> <subparagraph id="H12ACCEBFDC8649E985CBC31DD78E8E90"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered large institutional investor</term>—</text> 
<clause id="H2B56E186FC894C658349CFB5E5BF2F27">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>means an investment fund, corporation, general or limited partnership, limited liability company, joint venture, association, or other for-profit entity that is a legal entity structured in a manner that is not aforementioned that—</text>
                            <subclause id="HC6091F426846464FA880E24001D59DAC">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>is engaged, in whole or in part, in the business of investing in, owning, renting, or holding covered single-family homes; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="H9838AC80367B47F295528CBC07DF197E">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>alone or in concert with 1 or more other entities, beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, has direct or indirect investment control of not less than 350 covered single-family homes in the aggregate, not including any covered single-family home purchased in an excepted purchase made after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="HE3D0B9C9C13B44C7A6E2C81DB3C1D809"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <subclause id="HBF2B5D13A23642408A28A938941D243E"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>any local, State, Tribal, or Federal Government entity or instrumentality thereof;</text>
                            </subclause> 
<subclause id="HF73CDD5E49234F41ADBC6267FD405977"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 that is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD53B82B302D64BD0B93F51D4E25FD41A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community land trust as such term is defined in section 104 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12704">42 U.S.C. 12704</external-xref>), as amended by this Act.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2401702B2E44439A3EEF02180408B52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investment control</header> 
<clause id="H820AD623B7794BD29CC833E3C392C790"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, an entity has direct or indirect investment control over a covered single-family home if the entity—</text> <subclause id="H0357DCDEB0B9457D942064534E6A2C34"><enum>(I)</enum><text>owns, or has primary authority or fiduciary responsibility to make material investment or management decisions relating to the covered single-family home;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD81CF9E1529A4913BCD0ED68D3CF59B1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is or directly or indirectly controls, the general partner or managing member of the entity that owns the covered single-family home;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H76D795E930774D5784729BDC5C1309CF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is or controls the investment manager, management company, or investment advisor of the entity that owns the covered single-family home;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H215E357B7154497392F639C54691E64B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>owns or controls more than 25 percent of any class of equity interests of the entity that owns the covered single-family home, unless such entity is a passive investor; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0432E9708DA945C4B2F8250375CEB974"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise controls the entity that owns the covered single-family home.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFBDF2CDFDEEB44B68B6EF59BB29E4C9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Passive investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, an entity shall be considered a passive investor if such entity does not satisfy subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAE85EDB880640629A63DD85E20A1106"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header> <clause id="H56818162B23F40C380C7F595D5220BB8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to establish that an entity has direct or indirect investment control over a covered single-family home solely by virtue of—</text> 
<subclause id="H0F24AAE406894859BA0D8AAA928EC1CC">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>such entity’s entry into, or performance under, a third-party contract for the property management of a covered single-family home, including tasks related to maintenance of the home and the selection of tenants, provided that such entity does not have direct or indirect investment control over such a covered single-family home; or</text>
                            </subclause> 
<subclause id="HE641EA28894F496D8C6701BA8440AE1B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owning a fractional interest of a covered large institutional investor.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE4A96F4CBF64CF0B04855BFFB58B604"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered single-family home</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered single-family home</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF5A1F959C3614E9DB362F610DD1102D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a property that contains 2 or fewer dwelling units that are each intended for residential occupancy by a single household; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5260522FB4B34D7D993899DD9F9106F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> 
<clause id="H3A7328A298F94269B05D9A8FA7F2C49E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a manufactured home, as defined in section 603 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H1C3C80CF3F9B4901BF9C95164E35F0E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a property that, when occupied, has always been occupied by a renter;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEED2C1DC87EA48C6AAFE63269EC4D3F3" commented="no">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a property that, when occupied, is rented to a member of a regular component of the Armed Forces or a member of the National Guard on full-time National Guard duty, active Guard and Reserve duty, or inactive-duty training (as those terms are defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code) who has received—</text>
                            <subclause id="HCD1D2BA28EB643DFBC87290E7D3865D5" commented="no">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>temporary duty orders to deploy with a military unit or military orders to deploy as an individual acting in support of a military operation for a period of not less than 90 days; or</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HAE4503F5B0564DC0B7487CE8F04D38A0" commented="no">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>orders for a permanent change of station;</text> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="H27F3D6073EC74A738C1D311B225E1BFF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a property owned by its owner for less than 365 days, other than a covered single-family home purchased pursuant to paragraph (4)(F);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6B69B143AB5A4C25BBD979449B1D262D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a property that is made up of multiple rental homes or units constructed on a single parcel of property that cannot legally be sold as individual homes or units without further subdividing the property;</text></clause> <clause id="HA5ACD776556E4A81926AD75EB9762FBA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a property that is actively under a first-look period for owner-occupants or HUD-approved affordable housing nonprofits for a period of not less than 30 days; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H98D94B41DBBF41E0A47F55A89FCBFD1E"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a property that is designed and intended to be occupied or leased by the bedroom or in which individual bedrooms are intended for occupancy by separate, unrelated persons under separate lease or occupancy agreements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1018294A35B7467C90DA67C4B52B9D4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Excepted purchase</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>excepted purchase</term> means any purchase of a covered single-family home that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA56DB5AC3B0A48C79AF92955C3DFF09A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">or will be newly constructed, renovated for sale, or a rental conversion for sale by an owner and not as a residence rented pending sale;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A1CAB37979D48E78DD06E2A6321419E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pursuant to a build-to-rent program where an owner purchases, constructs, or constructs and retains a newly constructed covered single-family home to be managed as a rental property, whether as part of a community made up exclusively of renter-occupied single-family homes or as part of a community made up of single-family homes that are both owner- and renter-occupied;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC6179C0186AC47059C62E3AF7D7DAFE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursuant to a renovate-to-rent program that substantially rehabilitates a covered single-family home that does not meet—</text> <clause id="HCC32FF92D88243F7B6C3F667CE9A66BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">structural or core system elements of local building codes; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H15C98F1A66A44EFFA54436FFFB5BF54B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minimum property standards required for conventional mortgage financing;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA47672F6BCF04069A7E40DE86C20D85C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>pursuant to a home-ownership program that—</text> 
<clause id="HEB190B316A4E4A8BB2386ABD7A55AE47"><enum>(i)</enum><text>requires rental payments and any other fees that are not greater than those collected by the covered large institutional investor on other similarly situated covered single-family homes not covered by the eligible home-ownership program;</text></clause> <clause id="H8BA6F6FD82274469817DBF484F20B76C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides for positive reporting of rental payments to consumer reporting agencies for any renter, who shall be informed of and opts into such reporting;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0B4E358B3FBA497BA020FB9EB6D14B73"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for a right of first refusal and a 60-day first-look period for the current renter in instances where the covered single-family home is offered for sale to another owner; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA2DE76335B37435482181BFBA324EBCD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires contribution of meaningful financial support from the covered large institutional investor, including price concessions, for the purchase of a covered single-family home by the renter, whether for the home the renter is occupying or another home;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00A6AF52A10D42219CC996DF6A6475ED"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in connection with the satisfaction of debts previously contracted in good faith and where the owner has the right to repossess the covered single-family home under such contract;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51D228CCF04F4194B6B230F244C80710"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>undertaken by a mortgage servicer, lender, or other entity that has a legal right to purchase or otherwise acquire a covered single-family home, for the purpose of loss mitigation or compliance with servicing or investor obligations, and not as a long-term investment strategy, and is solely as a result of—</text>
                        <clause id="H4D65ADA38B27496A8538BCA418B0E77F">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a foreclosure;</text> </clause> <clause id="HA6B6776158F7401EAC104A20A8E2CD7C"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a deed in lieu of foreclosure;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H032CB94E8A6A4AC89556EEE1ED1CC1F2">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>enforcement of a mortgage, deed of trust, or other security interest; or</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H388960C3279B4340953C85B96B6C45E7">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>operation of law following borrower default,</text> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">provided that for federally backed mortgage loans as defined in section 4022(a) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9056">15 U.S.C. 9056(a)</external-xref>), including such loans that are sold to a third party, when the foreclosed property purchased under this provision is offered for sale, the mortgage servicer, lender, or other entity provides a 30-day first-look period to an owner-occupant or to an affordable housing nonprofit approved by the relevant Federal agency;</continuation-text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H254F57CF675442A2854277C09805CAD9"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchased from a covered large institutional investor that either owned the covered single-family home on the date of enactment of this Act or purchased the covered single-family home through an exempted purchase;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H556DE6521D3748AFABEFFD9BEFE6A09D"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intended and operated for occupancy as part of a community for households with 1 or more members aged 55 years or older, and to the extent required by law, satisfies visitability standards established by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H482E46FC435C4CE4B46874BD87383243"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intended to and will be after the purchase operated as a facility—</text> 
<clause id="H98B2A962F27E4E9AB9AE012131B59C43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>used to provide residential care to individuals with disabilities (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)) or developmental disabilities (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15002">42 U.S.C. 15002</external-xref>)); and</text></clause> <clause id="H177C33D65ABA4F5CA3D5C98B113F8A23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that connects such individuals with community-based services that are approved by Medicaid or Medicare;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92F777F7FD8E4131AF231C759C4815E7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>acquired as a part of a community of 5 or more contiguous rental units;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H227CEF23640642C89F64BF85F716C465"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">planned, permitted, financed, and constructed as a part of a single unified rental community on a single platted parcel, where a owner or an affiliate thereof owns or controls the land and manages the community as a single rental facility, and the individual structures within the community are not offered or intended for individual sale to separate purchasers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02EFB4C9F973460184E919EFF867F273"><enum>(L)</enum><text>purchased with support from any program described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or any other affordable housing program in which the rent of supported units is restricted; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CC13C558A444062B829637D41B2388E"><enum>(M)</enum><text>executed through a combination or series of purchases described in subparagraphs (A) through (L).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H899DF81355DE4B58B22087FC9A17EBB2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>First-look period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>first-look period</term> means the specified period of time commencing on the first day on which a property is made available for sale during which it is exclusively made available for purchase only to the entities specified.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H763D26F8F39C401488D2D32124FF4184"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Purchase</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>purchase</term> includes any purchase, transfer, or other acquisition of a covered single-family home, including through mergers, acquisitions, foreclosures, or bulk purchases, whether or not for cash consideration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCD13D3BAD0E4000B9E5CEC799269B00"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E7B203317444132B8C5D6EF4097DC91"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

