<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1106D376B5084D79A47C64FD51916D7E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6000 IH: Veterans’ Sentinel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6000</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the collection and analysis of data regarding certain suicides by veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H245C7DF32AE841E3B95317FC5019E7DC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A5C24CFD4F4417491F5315D6E4A15FA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans’ Sentinel Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H05AD60B310D84DE5BFD7F48B956F8C16" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Suicides by veterans on property of the Department of Veterans Affairs: collection and analysis of data; working group</header> <subsection id="H603C607996A6465C9F5D2B143B594421"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Section 1709B of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H937BFF6D29174B409764C4A256D9DA64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H453CA06DAF994DC2933B676AC55C7207"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (2) as subparagraph (3); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H889CBE1469394AFBA9DC1E674C731B50"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph (2):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HC9F33E88E569412090C1166C1C48D0F5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H738CC77F9BA54FAFA5476EF3B03EDBA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The statistical trends and recommendations described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39066D17232C4F509E626B8B13527F32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b), as amended, as subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H468F133024794AE08A370201C5662777"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection (b):</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H1A7D012C1B004224BA743EB41507E9CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HD5FCC0E925CD454FA223821233D19DE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>On-Campus suicides</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H33B7FE27AD5F4FF9AEE482D360432675"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the statistical trends of suicides and attempted suicides by veterans that occur on the property of the Department; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4D260AE511B4EDDA524FA8D270E601F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine recommendations for preventing such suicides and attempted suicides.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HD9873D6B6A5247C3B71F7EE50194507B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Working group</header> <paragraph id="HAB86DC98A8CB43A5AB152A5254534A18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a working group to collect and analyze data regarding on-campus suicides and attempted on-campus suicides.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF358AA5F0944B09AD2971A3D30C5CE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>In collecting and analyzing the information under paragraph (1), the working group shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B69640F878E49A691FA3FD8CB10428C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review root cause analysis data available to the Secretary regarding all on-campus suicides and attempted on-campus suicides;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3E023FAAF1F45C2860BE0A8920745DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to on-campus suicides—</text> <clause id="H7FEEAE4C0D9E4A3EB24032DB70821EF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze data available to the Secretary under the Behavioral Health Autopsy Program of the Department, including family interviews; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2355989677F843318299C54DD3464572"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>document reasons for any deficiencies in the data collected; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD6248BADCFB40908C111C0C30EE7636" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less frequently than every 90 days, communicate with the medical centers and field offices of the Department in order to coordinate the collection and review actions of the working group with such actions carried out by the medical centers and field offices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H690022763B2B4DF3B21151B76914DB2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data collection improvements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The working group shall consider, and may implement for purposes described in paragraph (1), improvements to the processes by which the Secretary collects data regarding on-campus suicides and attempted on-campus suicides in order to unify the disparate sources of such data, including with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H05FB925F872248B3ACF22D3A0F7230B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modifying incident reports and other methods to collect data, including both suicide and attempted suicide report fields;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H30C2F55DADD24D4CBF67DCB124258ABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing and ensuring that each source of data relating to on-campus suicides and attempted on-campus suicides includes a specified section for such on-campus incidents; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B31E64D2F364E5291B1F6591F4C37BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing an associated management system to consolidate all relevant data for on-campus suicides and attempted on-campus suicides, including such data from Behavioral Health Autopsy Program assessments, health records of the Department, root cause analyses, incident reports, and other sources of data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC601E2AB19F4CDCBDB024CEE5435FF7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter during the period of operation under paragraph (6), the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and Senate a briefing on the progress and findings of the working group established under such paragraph.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E55EBB5B47940F3BBB6620E0F440809"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the end of the period of operation under paragraph (6), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report detailing—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBFB760020BEF49E1A74806ACC65BA32A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the working group established under such paragraph; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H817B09A9244E4F8E9101F962E71C2FDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations to enhance the data collection and management by the Secretary with respect to on-campus suicides and attempted on-campus suicides, including improvements identified under paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49B2F70C6BBC4462ADEF03950B0C33B3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The working group shall operate for a period determined by the Secretary that is not less than two years and not longer than five years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H653EF2AC83014767912E5BFB768B45E5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>On-campus suicide defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>on-campus suicide</quote> means a suicide described in section 1709B(b) of title 38, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a).</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

