<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9FF32F1F5F634E7D913309BACEA4500E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6591 IH: Computer Science for All Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Education to carry out a program to increase access to prekindergarten through grade 12 computer science education.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEC7B0CC782E64D3DAA09B4FA211B7BE6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H37E46D755CBB4296A61C716781673D7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Computer Science for All Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6E019C3AAE2143719931D59FD8A42747"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2B1BB2B3AC614C8C9A75F2F79A51E8E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Computer science is transforming industry, creating new fields of commerce, driving innovation, and bolstering productivity. By 2034, computer science and information jobs are expected to grow by 20 percent, faster than the average of any other occupation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1912BD4CB0C547839741831CB1B97D92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Knowledge of computer science and use of technology is increasingly essential for all individuals, not just those working or planning to work in the technology sector.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B139E204D544E8A962D4C284C949A79"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing students with computer science education in elementary school and secondary school is critical for student success, and strengthening the workforce of a 21st century economy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A4AE16ADCAB4D73A9F41E58C1FA5B57"><enum>(4)</enum><text>While an estimated 90 percent of parents want computer science taught in their children’s schools, just 60 percent of public high schools offer a foundational computer science course.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC48D5EFCC70B414DA0DF09924A87541D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Black and Hispanic workers in the science and engineering workforce continue to be underrepresented. Black employees represent 11 percent of the United States workforce, but only 9 percent of the STEAM workforce. Hispanic employees represent 17 percent of the United States workforce, but only 8 percent of the STEAM workforce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EDCD46BD8B74357A1221346FCAC4DA1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>While underrepresented minority students overall face an opportunity gap in STEAM education, women of color particularly face an achievement gap in science and engineering education. In 2022, while women were conferred nearly a third of all science and engineering degrees, women of color received only 15 percent (Black: 3 percent; Hispanic: 4.5 percent; Native American or Alaskan Native: 1 percent; Asian or Pacific Islander: 5 percent; and multiracial: 1 percent).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FF10AC567F94C8CA580853CD4690CF7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2022, of all engineering technologies and engineering-related bachelor level-related studies, only 4 percent of nationwide enrollment was represented by Black students, while just 13 percent were represented by Hispanic students.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E94CA590DF54FEB98C517720B2FCEE8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Women overall face challenges in accessing computer science education. Only 18 percent of all bachelor’s degrees conferred in computer science went to women in 2015, and women of color received only 9 percent of degrees (Black: 3 percent; Hispanic: 2 percent; Native American or Alaska Native: 0.8 percent; and Asian or Pacific islander: 3 percent).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H164D1C334C614AE4B9675D1CFF93B6B0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Lack of universal computer science education is evident in the lack of a widespread tech industry, which is overwhelmingly concentrated in a few cities nationwide. Tech industry entrepreneurship is concentrated in just a few States and computer science education is limited to affluent schools and students, placing low-income, minority, and rural communities at risk of being left behind.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA5C00CDE901443BEB32AD42B8392D0EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC72A3D0825DB4B7E951E4657475B3DCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Computational thinking</header><text>The term <term>computational thinking</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2C600F93AC7474DB963E7D1940D876D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the wide range of creative processes that go into formulating problems and their solutions in such a way that the solutions can be carried out by a computer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F6D59D46D034107B6A6DA871FB35F5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may involve some understanding of software and hardware design, logic and the use of abstraction and representation, algorithm design, algorithm expression, problem decomposition, modularity, programming paradigms and languages, issues of information security and privacy, the application of computation across a wide range of disciplines, and the societal impact of computing. Programming is a hands-on, inquiry-based way in which computational thinking may be learned.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA46270B9A6B4B62BC8B894E3DCF1F10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Computer science education</header><text>The term <term>computer science education</term> includes any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBFB4B908A5E74B79BA117A5B5A9DC349"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Computational thinking.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE55104DC73F34EF292ED015C459DAFD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Software design.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8BE1C96D4E6449284EFAC404316EF4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Hardware architecture and organization.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE566CC3DD9D6467CBB00B4AFC816F35C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Theoretical foundations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97EBCD1053024057846132B67C82D74A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Use of abstraction and representation in problem solving.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E38256E8D4A41A0B6D20ABCFD4827AA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Logic.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5ABC7596C33E42BD876238671011E4B0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Algorithm design and implementation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18D9DCEBB84C41F891AB62B9D749EAE7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The limits of computation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE22A9E8E88364615BCD85A601BA9DFA5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Programming paradigms and languages.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36B9B2DD9CB948DDB7C5B29696D42991"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Parallel and distributed computing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2DDD472E894B4DE59CFC75986AC1D19E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Information security and privacy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB081B7E4D2D7469BB95592B1EB40A7AD"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Computing systems and networks.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A42CB2BBE2F4AB4B8C3C3F060BAB711"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Graphics and visualization.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H986BD4B23D854EDC9A844D6DE10ADBDD"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Databases and information retrieval.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB6250754AA940B89F760F7C81A64E87"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The relationship between computing and mathematics.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE20C092C32044518856255F50E8C27EE"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5586F9584A94959B0B7908F05F214E0"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Applications of computing across a broad range of disciplines and problems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9EC473D05A84CAB8BC333A241D47492"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Cloud computing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H579CAA6F44F84F0484AE2DC45AC378C1"><enum>(S)</enum><text>The social impacts and professional practices of computing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H987A8E49339C4ED695E6F2C99F92028B" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State, local educational agency, or eligible Tribal school that demonstrates an ability to carry out an ambitious computer science education expansion effort for all students served by the State, agency, or school, respectively, including traditionally underrepresented students. </text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7BE01DFAE7E4C21B357F078A582D7F0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible tribal school</header><text>The term <term>eligible Tribal school</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E5A929496A3427CA2F295AEEF8CE7BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Education;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H21C8D7887918414884ACE8718A946278"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a school operated pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450">25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9633DA5496144F919C3B94F7A55EAEF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a tribally controlled school (as defined in section 5212 of the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2511">25 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66289686F5444553805936C5C4B2C4CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H455E1693D5EA4101ABF69A299748CE7E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency that meets the requirements of section 1003(f) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6303">20 U.S.C. 6303(f)</external-xref>). </text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0DA684619D54FD2A63468757310CC89"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Poverty line</header><text>The term <term>poverty line</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/8101">20 U.S.C. 8101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4B83BB977374D80A92969CACCDA5EB7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1937A777DDA94266AC53EE87BF2A739F" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>), in which at least one local educational agency is located.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FE36EA76E7D460DA042F01ED22BAC7A"><enum>(10)</enum><header>STEAM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>STEAM</term> means the subjects of science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics, including computer science.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBA7FCDC6D8A443B496E3CA679CDC1A84"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants to states, local educational agencies, and eligible tribal schools</header> 
<subsection id="H19CF18DF0606475983A9ACA44451AC9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants to states, local educational agencies, and eligible tribal schools</header> 
<paragraph id="H1BD35EDF156044A2BE3046C732B43CD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to serve as models for national replication of computer science education expansion efforts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF054112F10D24B72A82F5DB60CDE7CF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consortia and partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may apply for a grant under this section as part of a consortium or in partnership with a State educational agency or other partner.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD824CF6E6D94378B16606F6DCBB2017"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H822A686260C64203AA6BEF1FE6A5D0A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application requirements</header><text>An eligible entity that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including, at a minimum, plans for the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7B3D9A30B0C04C659C64128919BD9183"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Every high school student served by eligible entity to have access to computer science education not later than 5 years after receipt of grant funds.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD77ABBF5171444328650422AA2884CBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All students served by the eligible entity to have access to a progression of computer science education from prekindergarten through middle school that prepares students for high school computer science education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6931A513771461B84915C76BED5F5EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Expansion of overall access to rigorous STEAM classes, utilizing computer science as a catalyst for increased interest in STEAM more broadly, and reducing the enrollment and academic achievement gap for underrepresented groups such as minorities, girls, and youth from families living at, or below, the poverty line.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BF5998305F647B981D9AD124BA09724"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Continuous monitoring and evaluation of project activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9C6BFD20F5B49AA96337AFA961FD412"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effectively sustaining project activities after the grant period ends, and the length of time which the applicant plans to sustain the project activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6CB79129C18458D917A2BA4092CE6F0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preparing the students for application of computer science knowledge in rapidly evolving technologies, such as artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAEE09830BEB64A1BB21CCC790046EF4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H14802347315242689B3E6DD275E62180"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required activities</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds for each of the following activities:</text> <subparagraph id="H94B6DCE3E01A46F2873389C2DC852B18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training teachers of elementary school and secondary school to teach computer science.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFECAFEAD7CE84DE5B410AC8303B51ADE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Expanding access to high-quality learning materials and online learning options.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC885662A9D5A4CA0884C8DC9DBB85340"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Creating plans for expanding overall access to rigorous STEAM classes, utilizing computer science as a catalyst for increased interest in STEAM more broadly, and reducing course equity gaps for all students, including underrepresented groups such as minorities, girls, and youth from low-income families.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H10D0CE02ED5E413082952C432920B406"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ensuring additional support and resources, which may include mentoring for students traditionally underrepresented in STEAM fields.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0BCEC8BE86C47D986F1BD18CC27E7A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible activities</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may use the grant funds for the following activities:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCCEE4A5C3F4C46B8928A3D6222075D0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Building effective regional collaborations with industry, nonprofit organizations, 2-year and 4-year degree granting institutions of higher education (including community colleges, Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions, American Indian Tribally controlled colleges and universities, Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian-serving institutions, Predominantly Black Institutions, Native American-serving, Nontribal institutions, and other minority-serving institutions), and out-of-school providers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83325A235B6D4554B29312F1C3FD1EF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recruiting and hiring instructional personnel as needed, including curriculum specialists.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H184005BE09B746FEA5BF36A9CBFE0487"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Preparations for effectively sustaining project activities after the grant period ends.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0ADEC851185E4D31B49E86E1C5108C93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Disseminating information about effective practices.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48EBE10F143D4CE5BFF5726A6FB6908E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Including the use of artificial intelligence in the classroom to expand students’ access to a rapidly evolving technology. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H084E559527BE4358842C7603EC0C5A5D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 15 percent of a grant awarded under this Act may be used to purchase equipment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7AAEC75EB6DE4B3292B3DFAC0FD6B89D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National activities</header><text>Of the amount appropriated under subsection (e) for a fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve not more than 2.5 percent of funds available for grants under this section for national activities, including technical assistance, evaluation, and dissemination.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H598D605D659942908B6FDFB4045A52B0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section a total of $250,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and the succeeding 4 fiscal years.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD3383EF3A04E4CCDA38F7EEC3FD8676B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H2B33B4E7A79744FAB6CB5C8FCCA1D604"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grantee reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall submit to the Secretary a report, not less than twice a year during the grant period, on the use of grant funds that shall include data on the numbers of students served through activities funded under this Act, disaggregated by race (for Asian and Native Hawaiian or Pacific Islander students using the same race response categories as the decennial census of the population), ethnicity, gender, and eligibility to receive a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2AE021F7F3314E25BC172E72548862C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report by the secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the first grant is awarded under this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report based on the analysis of reports received under subsection (a) with a recommendation on how to expand the program under this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H598E30E67CF64FE3AFCB5F0D5F7CDA7D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Amendments to other laws</header> 
<subsection id="H2177DFAFED4C4B1BB9A3591426376918" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Education Organization Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203(c)(1) of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3413">20 U.S.C. 3413(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, which shall include information with respect to the existence of computer science education (as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Computer Science for All Act of 2025</short-title>), disaggregated by the type of computer science education and by State, local educational agency, and eligible tribal school (as such terms are defined in such section 3)</quote>. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HC41E8972D54F48629FDE463B8A3D12CB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>The Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 153(a)(1) of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9543">20 U.S.C. 9543(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0FD528ED71D545FDA5124F235DA255A8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (N), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB689A273F4E84D0C93B61627678950CD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H643A5603BC504E08B2EEBD41EEA4A587" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H93EC2292B58146AD8F6774723493C3E1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H5D734ADC17F747E9A3077E3147B9F2E2" commented="no"><enum>(P)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the existence of computer science education (as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Computer Science for All Act of 2025</short-title>) in elementary schools and secondary schools, and the degree of competency in computer science fields among such students.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


