<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H514B21C806C249DE80A79E99818D3234" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5943 IH: Transforming Healing, Resilience, and Integrative Veteran Engagement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5943</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a Task Force on Complementary and Integrative Health/Whole Health, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB16529652DF64F7D94CB6C97A9E218BF" style="OLC"><section id="HA0E8AFF178FF4D77841B8402019ACB64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transforming Healing, Resilience, and Integrative Veteran Engagement Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>THRIVE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HCD806DA5F3CB46BEA4E42FE488FEEF7C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency Task Force on Complementary and Integrative Health</header><subsection id="HF6CAB43C7AAB43DB916B816C87E419CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a task force, to be known as the <quote>Task Force on Complementary and Integrative Health/Whole Health</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE27711DA898402CAAF063E61BAB5F3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The task force shall be composed of the following individuals or their designees:</text><paragraph id="HB31814A7400F4400B690DE2E7D2AE7EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, who shall serve as the Chair.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF759B4E986604BEFB54E9FC141B77649"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Director of the Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41694C55194F4FBCAD91320F115552B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Director of the Research and Development Office of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40216E1BA66545079A5F6B8DE792D597"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Director of the Office of Patient-Centered Care and Cultural Transformation of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC716E6E6277C44D6A1164CD84616069D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>At least one representative from an academic institution who specializes in complementary and integrative health research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B2300F48C0F45B48C74F211D75D8E6F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>At least one clinician of the Department who has experience treating veterans with one or more of the following conditions:</text><subparagraph id="H747FD4E224714CBDAE58CEB0B06B13C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Post-traumatic stress disorder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4454C9261F6147ABB247FF58B1CF1FF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Traumatic brain injury.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C643EFEE17F41B1A99D1E31927CF041"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Depression.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CB05054BBF84AE3ADBC4903C67CF529"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Anxiety.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA84373FE922F456888A393803AE719F6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>At least one representative from a veterans service organization focused on—</text><subparagraph id="H8A5ABD03F0AF416EA12F4D2C8DDE8580"><enum>(A)</enum><text>treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder, depression, and anxiety; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AC20EE364D545FF9D57336FAF3BF6D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suicide prevention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73F9A636F017448C9865972E85C30345"><enum>(8)</enum><text>At least one representative from another relevant organization involved in researching, diagnosing, or treating post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, depression, anxiety, or suicide prevention that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines is necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38AD1A0EB96E4783ADF2316641C75A64"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least one representative from a community-based program with demonstrated success in improving veterans’ mental health and well-being through complementary, integrative, or peer-led approaches. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4EAC8B52807408CB55AF7B63C09312A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The task force shall carry out the following responsibilities:</text><paragraph id="HA27C74036CD64439B5DB876DFFD2F00D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assessing the current access of veterans who receive medical care at Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities to complementary and integrative health/whole health therapies and program for veterans and how to make such therapies and programs more accessible to such veterans at such facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H583E96D6DFC94BCB8AE4CDDF3430E0A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Developing a framework to determine—</text><subparagraph id="H20C5E114F43944E7BEB0F5D8A226A982"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of complementary and integrative health therapies, including acupuncture, biofeedback, clinical hypnosis, guided imagery, massage therapy, meditation, tai chi, qigong, and yoga, peer-supported programs, and health and wellness coaching programs as treatments for post-traumatic stress disorder, traumatic brain injury, depression, and anxiety, and for suicide prevention; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54BA33A558E94C80B77D25D90DB6DA35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether and how the Department of Veterans Affairs should expand or modify access to such therapies and programs. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79D4715C8BFE4F6B89EE94B20E567947"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying gaps in research and implementation of complementary and integrative health/whole health therapies at Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities, including gaps in knowledge of effectiveness or safety, provider training, and availability of services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D4626F71FBB4FAB9BC8EDBC81322AAC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Determining how to integrate emerging complementary and integrative health/whole health therapies, including peer-led models and health and wellness coaching models, into the continuum of care of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CDAB52A126344EC869BE96405AFD30A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analyzing any factors contributing to treatment dropout, low retention, or relapse among veterans and how the Department can improve outcomes for such veterans. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0D4E1A1C89E41DFA6DCBDF317D697BF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Identifying any additional resources or authorities the Department needs from Congress to improve accessibility of complementary and integrative health/whole health therapies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC580F0B17734F24BA84A46C76F9D5A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the establishment of the task force, the task force shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs the recommendations of the task force with respect to the responsibilities under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H5548DB9C71BF4BC29F5FA30224ADE9BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H4B7C7644D8084DDCA90CE8F673B88E82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs receives the recommendations of the task force under subsection (d), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on such recommendations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6774618A673E4D818A7DE8D0D8431E49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of submission of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing a plan to address such recommendations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D46EC00D4EF44AF9900DE5E68814092"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The task force shall terminate on the date on which the task force submits the recommendations to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H46A8C33582164B289A307A933E193872"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB65110A661A745689CF7245530483C52"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>peer-led model</quote> and <quote>peer-supported program</quote> mean a program or approach in which veterans with lived experience are trained and engaged to provide counseling, mentoring, training, or support services to other veterans, as a complement or alternative to services provided by clinical professionals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8CAF93ECC0C4C02ACBA2847E6C7D0C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>community-based program</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H3490D44F27084489B79505C316D6D82D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a program providing health or wellness services that is operated by a non-governmental or nonprofit entity in a local community setting, rather than directly by a Federal agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFA7F2FE5581400CA622917AC97596F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes programs that receive funding from the Department of Veterans Affairs through grant programs or partnerships to enhance veterans’ mental health, suicide prevention, or overall well-being.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

