<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB26792C976B846A49FE2427053EE92D8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8908 IH: Stop The Overuse of Petitions and Get Affordable Medicines to Enter Soon Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8908</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend subsection (q) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to clarify the process for denying certain petitions whose primary purpose is to delay the approval of an application submitted under subsection (b)(2) or (j) of such section 505, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA527473FF95D45EE9029528758F273E6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6BD6748294F24EA7B18482F866A89C48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop The Overuse of Petitions and Get Affordable Medicines to Enter Soon Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP GAMES Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7251786642FF4FF1AAC485B6D43FD1E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Denial of petitions whose primary purpose is to delay approval of certain applications</header> <subsection id="H29DA875A106C47E88EFAFEA5423DA45A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505(q)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(q)(1)</external-xref>)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0274DCE22D9B48F39B4794A8229E595B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by amending clause (i) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD15BA0E51AB64286BD00647F1DABBE27" style="OLC"> <clause id="HA94B2442B6B14C689CF6C9C831020A72" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the request is in writing, is a petition submitted to the Secretary pursuant to section 10.30, 10.31, or 10.35 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), and is submitted not later than the date that is 60 days after the information upon which the petition is based first became known to the party on whose behalf the petition is submitted; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A39679273BA448BB9B687F72C6F6D0A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subparagraph (E) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B0E2148645B4EBD996BA6CC379C94D2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H8925400E917143528970FAB46A1196B6" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Denial based on intent to delay</header> <clause id="HB2920751AB844F32BCB41F3278E6AB59" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a petition or a supplement to the petition was submitted with the primary purpose of delaying the approval of an application or the petition does not on its face raise valid scientific or regulatory issues, the Secretary may deny the petition at any point based on such determination.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA37940F8FBDF4723BFD7078D5EC95DEB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may issue guidance to describe the factors that will be used to determine under this subparagraph whether a petition is submitted with the primary purpose of delaying the approval of an application. Such factors shall include the following:</text> <subclause id="HC91B52EC5E39419C83512DB21186A38D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Submission of a petition where it appears, based on the date that relevant information relied upon in the petition became known to the petitioner (or reasonably should have been known to the petitioner), that the petitioner has taken an unreasonable length of time to submit the petition.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2CD795ABD44C4E89AC72E871FB4D23C0" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Submission of multiple or serial petitions raising issues that reasonably could have been known to the petitioner at the time of submission of the earlier petition or petitions.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H84CA39E152704CD3B51B38F2ABE62C6D" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Submission of a petition close in time to a known, first date upon which an application under subsection (b)(2) or (j) of this section or under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act could be approved (such as submission close in time to the expiration of a blocking patent or exclusivity).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6F26DE245BC644C0B627B601CA152D34" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Submission of a petition without any data or information in support of the scientific positions set forth in the petition.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC086ECC0836740B191C55936915A7E32" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Submission of a petition raising the same or substantially similar issues as a prior petition to which the Food and Drug Administration has already substantively responded, particularly where the subsequent submission closely follows in time the earlier response.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC9BB1752350F4FD599E4D3735684E6E9" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Submission of a petition concerning standards for approval of a drug product for which—</text> <item id="HE934F57896514D52AFAC146735DF62C0" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Food and Drug Administration has provided an opportunity for public input (such as when the Food and Drug Administration has issued draft or final product-specific guidance applicable to the drug product); and</text></item> 
<item id="H5D4A1C99898949AF896C1DD0ED9C044C" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the petitioner has not provided comment other than through the petition.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H74D751AB3A99473E98B6BB530761C09C" commented="no"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Submission of a petition requesting that other applicants must meet standards for testing, data, or labeling for their products that are more onerous or rigorous than the standards applicable to the applicable listed drug or the petitioner’s version of the same product.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC680A32559DE45F49A1ED848BE9D555C" commented="no"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Other relevant considerations, including the history of the petitioner with the Food and Drug Administration (such as whether the petitioner has a history of submitting petitions which the Food and Drug Administration has determined were submitted with the primary purpose of delay).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA0CAB4900C4E4010AAC8F8FA274F3007" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Referral to FTC</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a petition has been submitted with the primary purpose of delaying the approval of an application, as described in clause (i), the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Federal Trade Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4CC4F13F9004D83AEC50316700F89CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD835BCBAF4EE437F9C24E596D975DDDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (G) through (I) as subparagraphs (F) through (H), respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC213C3463BDD45CD9E6CC4355B690D0F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (G), as so redesignated, by striking <quote><quote>I further certify that the information upon which I have based the action requested herein first became known to the party on whose behalf this petition is submitted on or about the following date: __________.</quote></quote> and inserting <quote><quote>I further certify that the information upon which I have based the action requested herein first became known to the party on whose behalf this petition is submitted on or about __________, which date was not more than 60 days before the date of submitting this petition.</quote></quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H292532AE5B124A50B828009CF9834F55"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), as so redesignated, by striking <quote><quote>submission of this petition</quote></quote> and inserting <quote><quote>submission of this document</quote></quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H662966E2420C47FE915911919736EBA1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exhaustion of administrative remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505(q)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(q)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8E0221E15B9445B19E7E8575C37FD489"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9A7D000F297C4DD0857E4EA78237E35B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">within 150 days</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB35467AFC3F1402AB33225D2475004A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>during the 150-day period referred to in paragraph (1)(F),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3CA5A309B4C64DF08E542229A7E52780"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending clause (ii) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H953D1F02296D4456A8234A1C5E90B433" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="H2E7F546EC52A4BA3B1DAA3388B86BB10"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on or after the date that is 151 days after the date of submission of the petition, the Secretary approves or has approved the application that is the subject of the petition without having made such a final decision.</text>
                            </clause>
                            <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F0B96A2945B4DE0848BBE8C33D69BE7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD83C8623967C4B5CBAFFE3A0DF11B6D9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H8AC107C73B8B4A9E9F54BF2C3C10DAD2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Dismissal of certain civil actions</header> <clause id="H8B7542C7D643410881D87AF11D06116A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person files a civil action against the Secretary in which a person seeks to set aside, delay, rescind, withdraw, or prevent submission, review, or approval of an application submitted under subsection (b)(2) or (j) of this section or section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act without first submitting a petition to the Secretary under paragraph (1) that describes all information and arguments that form the basis of the relief requested in such civil action, the court shall dismiss without prejudice the action for failure to exhaust administrative remedies.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB434AABE0154264A4776301840B5C19" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Timeliness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person files a civil action against the Secretary in which a person seeks to set aside, delay, rescind, withdraw, or prevent submission, review, or approval of an application submitted under subsection (b)(2) or (j) of this section or section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act after the date described in paragraph (1)(A)(i), the court shall dismiss with prejudice the action for failure to timely file a petition.</text></clause> <clause id="HA992661A89CA41F7847D4ECC164E9FA3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Final response</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a civil action is filed against the Secretary with respect to any issue raised in a petition timely filed under paragraph (1) in which the petitioner requests that the Secretary take any form of action that could, if taken, set aside, delay, rescind, withdraw, or prevent submission, review, or approval of an application submitted under subsection (b)(2) or (j) of this section or section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act before the Secretary has taken final agency action on the petition within the meaning of subparagraph (A), the court shall dismiss without prejudice the action for failure to exhaust administrative remedies.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1FBA73F814F9460EAA1194F441921AB0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting to Congress</header> <text>Section 505(q)(3) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(q)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD69EEEE1FC9A45AD8A1C19154F55BCDE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>specifies</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0AE91D02E5C4D29B07E476F67D517DE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D), by striking <quote>the number</quote> and inserting <quote>specifies the number</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF12020A00E54D35A7643D0B2A0ECD5B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4FBF79C2F03403ABB38933ABDC63FEE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F7D835F5E48440BBADA54301DB69E8C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60FA242180E44DCE9B7151EC2C80C27B" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HA0E0954DC89440F2AE199EE1B6B71D21" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H55D6FA60E17D4A7791E6909EF82A9967"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lists each petition submitted during such period and, for each, identifies the petitioner;</text></clause> <clause id="H9C5C8CB0E03B4423864A9C0BD3333723" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>quantifies the time and resources expended on each such petition;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H77A6C01D51B2438BAC0B0CC7C2C825EC" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>states the timing of the petition relative to the expiration date of the patents specified in the pending application in the certification under subsection (b)(2)(A) or (j)(2)(A)(vii), as applicable;</text></clause> <clause id="H3758D9D72DC04CE1BA0B0FE48BCDC0A4" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>quantifies the delay, if any, caused by any such petition on the approval of any application submitted under subsection (b)(2) or (j), including a description of how any such delay is calculated and an estimate of when any delayed approval would have been granted absent the petition; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB832AD8CD0E84181B588D35CFAA8A792" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in cases in which a pending application and a petition with respect to such pending application are disposed of on the same or nearly the same date, states when the Food and Drug Administration would have disposed of the pending application absent the petition.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

