<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC3DF7A1CE61749CD8C28A9DDF5F49FE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6734 IH: Auto Data Privacy and Autonomy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent manufacturers of covered vehicles from accessing, selling, or otherwise sharing covered data without consent of covered vehicle owners, to require manufacturers of covered vehicles to provide covered vehicle owners with access to, and control of, covered data, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2B48DD88B8B941DB96C2545C37A57803" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3F0A1A3C645C4E4EAA06579AB508A8AA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Auto Data Privacy and Autonomy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3A2BCEF713F74AC3B210C80498A6C4B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC571544C65AE46108CC301BA974744A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H598C55ADB48B4E12B207300596B3BBE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered data</header><text>The term <term>covered data</term> means user data and vehicle-generated data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D111A0C0EE54EC5908F5F7037142D78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered vehicle</header><text>The term <term>covered vehicle</term> means a motor vehicle or a vehicle primarily used for farming or construction.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99BD128EC6444C95B245A610E0651878"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Geolocation data</header><text>The term <term>geolocation data</term> means information that reveals the past or present physical location of an individual, a covered vehicle, or device.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1E627EA837545FCB8091DD1F4638CE8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle</term> has the same meaning given such term in section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code, and includes a motor vehicle trailer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC61A75D1D254C8FB73994AC51C9C158"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>The term <term>personally identifiable information</term> means information that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5239994E5AB042E4B5AE38DDCC9A9F74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>directly identifies an individual such as the name, address, social security number or other identifying number or code, telephone number, or email address of an individual;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1AE9D88E509454FB6DB817E7FEEABCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>indirectly identifies an individual such as the gender, race, or date of birth of an individual; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7278D177D2849FC940ED2A76F23F7A1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reveals the geolocation data or internet activity of an individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE101C8E8F29341E588DFC131EDD3D00F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>User data</header><text>The term <term>user data</term> means data transferred to a covered vehicle by the owner or user of such vehicle.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B54EF0077B74E0FAA154E88B131432C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>User preference</header><text>The term <term>user preference</term> means any choice with respect to a configurable setting of a covered vehicle made by or for the benefit of the owner or user of such covered vehicle.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD2327D1F946417C8D26B037E0D93FDC"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Vehicle-generated data</header><text>The term <term>vehicle-generated data</term> means all electronic data generated or processed onboard a covered vehicle, such as data generated by sensors, receivers, computer processing units, or other vehicle components and includes the geolocation data of such covered vehicle.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H83EC58608ED54922A61F2C3260369E1F"><enum>3.</enum><header>User data and vehicle-generated data privacy and security</header> 
<subsection id="H1F1CF7FC7F0D41CE89CE49EEEC829863"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on manufacturers</header><text>With respect to a covered vehicle, a manufacturer of such vehicle may not—</text> <paragraph id="H7959A1CAFFD34893AE8A3FCC17ACA11D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access covered data, unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9976A2E1CC46475A88307B1E9BC274B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the owner of such covered vehicle or, in the event of the death or incapacity of such owner, the next of kin of such owner affirmatively consents to such manufacturer accessing such data and such consent—</text> <clause id="H6FE0A61605B142A3A4F964622E981767"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is freely given;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEE8F9A05115E4EA0A4457E8B3B97B6EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is informed, specific, and unambiguous;</text></clause> <clause id="H09BD03D9ACD7473BB0370AB071DF3EF6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is in writing; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H680A47DD738742969D8DFF91A0A75B7D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may be easily withdrawn; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDFB1E0177C154A91BA606A3FC3CF5D07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such data is accessed solely to improve covered vehicle performance or safety;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBC8E6BB8A2D4C06AC370EF669CC67B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sell, lease, or otherwise share covered data, unless—</text> <subparagraph id="H213F8AA96E5C4DF4B8E0CB1B6A7637F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>required to do so—</text> 
<clause id="H152F4CFC87FD40EB979B852141C38FED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pursuant to a lawfully executed warrant;</text></clause> <clause id="HACF8B590A71643E1B12367A2603243EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pursuant to a court order that provides the covered vehicle owner notice of the order and at least 48 hours to object and request a hearing; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H271BC197450E499E8615BBD49C22B036"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to facilitate an emergency response; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F1BA350E90B49BDB8025ED9F07764C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the owner of such covered vehicle, or, in the event of the death or incapacity of such owner, the next of kin of such owner, affirmatively consents to such manufacturer to do so and such consent—</text> 
<clause id="HAD5B1C0FCB5B429A80620A6DF6C3F47B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is freely given;</text></clause> <clause id="H34A5D488BA034C75ACF5FA0618A2FA1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is informed, specific, and unambiguous;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBCA8FA3D0C624464A00C47F7E6FAA203"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is in writing; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF7EC89AAD32B4C1CA0F673C48F810782" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may be easily withdrawn; or</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5D3E1E768FC479F9E26B52DEBE0ACEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sell, license, rent, trade, transfer, release, disclose, provide access to, or otherwise make available personally identifiable information of a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3DBE78C4A4CB46CCBC84F6FCCA482429"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H817D9F1A6B9A49E584AB16586039D5D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF70F941DA934362A78E464545D11F00"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Russian Federation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H456C6AD43A4D421882B3F659D29CFF43"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3332EB2640884FD4AE0995E1E97B9671"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC1866D2DF15F4CA99153413FC489C557"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Federal Communications Commission, submit to Congress a report that describes with respect to covered data—</text> <paragraph id="H5880E5493A494AC4BD12A2E7F2E47356"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the types of such data that a manufacturer of a covered vehicle accesses;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A9926F6C1FD4B55A2FD20AD185B0AF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the individuals and entities, other than a manufacturer of a covered vehicle, that access such data;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A6BA94720044033B1A17AB7F2DFCC60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal or State Government entities that access such data and how such entities use such data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H528D125C7A86419FBA8DB1DFBD171AB1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the individuals and entities to whom such data may be sold or otherwise shared;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H538B21BF41E24896A3936D1FEEF1A201"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the foreign governments to whom such data may be sold or otherwise shared and how such data is used by such foreign governments;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD26FDD95AFDF43379949CE84B6F80DFE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the cybersecurity capabilities and risks associated with covered vehicles;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A459DC8430C4D209E0E9DE2D38B065A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>occurrences of such data being compromised, including the prevalence of such occurrences and any entities with ties to foreign governments associated with such occurrences; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFE2741A1C534FBEAB49567C9023BFA5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of the feasibility of a technology-neutral, standards-based, secure interface to allow an owner of a covered vehicle access to such data designed without preference or prejudice towards any technology or service used to access and control such data by such owner, and not contingent on ownership or licensing of proprietary technologies by such owner or a manufacturer of a covered vehicle.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9542B7628CAD412B97DC553F2F98AEF8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Vehicle owner’s data access and control</header> <subsection id="H11C41F95C2374881AD7FA2A5B1F2FBC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The manufacturer of a covered vehicle shall provide to an owner of such vehicle access to, and control of, all covered data generated or processed onboard, or transferred to, such vehicle—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2AC80A043E6440E9918ABDEA1CD4F9A3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at no cost beyond the purchase price of such vehicle;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1FFE828C42242E48EAF0A8EBEE4E49C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in real time;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB971DC52DD354B7D9F97D3A3D092D945" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>without any restriction or limitation on use or authorizing access to third parties;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEE586B925F0485AA4C2F63C9F63633A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>without a requirement that the covered vehicle owner pay a fee or purchase a license to decrypt such data or use a device provided by such manufacturer to access and use such data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3EA5C5A2F00470AB02E7317DBA9E8BD" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>through the vehicle’s interface port and through wireless transmission of such data to the extent such vehicle is equipped with technology to wirelessly transmit such data; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3EC6012BFDF47FEB7FAC72C6D807A7D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in a manner that enables the operation of an open application programming interface that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF333FFEA8B874E98B736D67585A98254" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitates deletion of all user data stored in a covered vehicle; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA1CA3878FEE24BD9AF742FAF7AD4031D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enables the setting of any user preference by the covered vehicle owner or another user of the covered vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E346FF9DA7A4A3C9ED176C25D482826"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header><text>This section supersedes any statute, rule, requirement or other legal obligation of a State of political subdivision thereof that relates to the requirements of this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9C2A1A2F574C45DA9AB0602E6B4D3EA3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="HF4D117535BEA4BF1B3117C3D3B729248"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive act or practice</header><text>A violation of this Act shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0F681FD32C74D7C9677C25BE722A30E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H46DB5F61442A4C978735EDBFBC79395E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56B3812702394614971B716946A4B759"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96C89D7846BB44E192EF18A5A0D8F2C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2859B91049D748438D118C575F2114F2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Disclosure of confidential business information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 4, nothing in this Act shall require a manufacturer of a covered vehicle to divulge confidential business information (as that term is defined in section 512.3(c) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></section> 
<section id="HDB320EA9C95249469F0ED0BE7F654CB1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date that is 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> <section id="H0FFD393D72A94019B7841DEE8B28B119"><enum>8.</enum><header>No new appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act. The Commission shall carry out this Act using amounts otherwise appropriated.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

