<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B0D132B81CD4D1E83213E0BCB722ADB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7357 IH: TSP Fiduciary Security Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7357</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to address the responsibilities of fiduciaries with respect to the Thrift Savings Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26B15B2521FA4BC8B105EF4B43B0C46E" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H455632D9D6D3418892F97A4C51973BBF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TSP Fiduciary Security Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB989DE18D2714DEF8A030684CB3620E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H2706E8DE475E46ED916D5DD478F64648"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board has a fiduciary duty to manage the Thrift Savings Fund in the best interest of the beneficiaries of the Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C1B48F44B2F493683F38E356EAA2475"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The principal beneficiaries of the Thrift Savings Fund are the civil servants of the United States, and members of the uniformed services, who are tasked with defending the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E67FC1A2043409AA99D9E6A8978E5E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The duty of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to manage the Thrift Savings Fund in the best interests of the beneficiaries of the Fund includes a duty not to harm the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4E5F6053A4A84E72AA402775CA88222B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fiduciary responsibilities with respect to Thrift Savings Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8477 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8E2A94356C454183BA98231AC6796239"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HC7F5FF4B6E5C4153817E9566CEEA7F52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5C4EBC5473841978F5AB7A890F1F631"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC3327A04FA44831938C4202950BC52A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H773913FF8BB3421B80B4C985273F36C7" act-name=""><subparagraph id="H66168B6ED7D6419D8B68DB08F94F7C1F" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, by preventing the investments of the Thrift Savings Fund (or portions thereof), and the exercise of voting rights associated with any such investments, from harming the national security of the United States.</text></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F5E7AA9BB24B839BC08384F30D110B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H25B7EF888B384628AC37B69595AC3B9D" act-name=""><paragraph id="HBBD8CEF5600B4D7C96E49BCECB374C45" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8BA43E34618A4AED9CFB0D3E3AC39BB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, no fiduciary shall be personally liable for any monetary damages, or be assessed any civil penalty, under this subsection with respect to a breach of the requirement under subsection (b)(1)(D).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="HBD3DBA5C82AA4552B69EB875B55CC26B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subparagraph (A) shall cease to have effect beginning on January 1, 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H153EFBCB312E43AEB7E8716090BEA0E8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review of Thrift Savings Fund for compliance with fiduciary duties</header><subsection id="HC79153EB913D4F5E8E1778ADBE68CD2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8477(f) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3E1C548A783F4C4EBEFE3DE8C67D77D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(f)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF31D38E1627475BAF3181F1AF0FAD92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5AE80F2679ED4B4FB977DE6A620B6D5B" act-name=""><paragraph id="H8CA760AD06C940D08A3C2553E212FD7A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDDFA2BE863ED47BC978CFDEB265DE403"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall prescribe regulations to carry out subsection (b)(1)(D) with respect to each of the following:</text><clause indent="up1" id="HADB270793550469A9C7A37C10ED154FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The investments of the Thrift Savings Fund, which shall include the establishment of standards by which compliance with subsection (b)(1)(D) with respect to the investments of the Thrift Savings Fund (or portions thereof) shall be determined.</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="H50890A7B77224E009A371095F622BD30"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The exercise of voting rights associated with the investments of the Thrift Savings Fund (or portions thereof).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H44B826AF393C4B9BBCEA03C97004D250"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The regulations prescribed under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall include—</text><clause id="HB9068E768A654F20B2C5BA8FE2AB2DF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the establishment of a process by which the exercise of voting rights described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be reviewed by the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of the Treasury, for compliance with subsection (b)(1)(D) with respect to the exercise of those rights; and</text></clause><clause id="H8BFF5A175E1F4A9784EA52A622DD2494"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the establishment of standards by which compliance with subsection (b)(1)(D) with respect to the exercise of voting rights described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be determined, including the factors contributing to a determination that a covered vote would not comply with subsection (b)(1)(D).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H6E5E0F44658E4B9DACCCF98B590D6ADB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For the purposes of any regulation prescribed under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Labor shall presume that—</text><clause id="H9DDA1E2A4F8B41D2A8B6E2FA93F4A8AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an investment of the Thrift Savings Fund (or portions thereof) does not comply with subsection (b)(1)(D) if the investment invests in—</text><subclause id="H563DA66C4B084B698B32711D6A457DEC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an entity included on—</text><item id="H478D3A7B6E3E41A49FE4969D595B8C8B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the list of Communist Chinese military companies maintained under section 1237(b) of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note); or</text></item><item id="HAA0FD0C387EF4B0BAF57AE104AA538AF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the entity list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations; or </text></item></subclause><subclause id="H84C479D53CD24A16811D5977B8CDEB10"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a parent, subsidiary, or affiliate of, or an entity controlled by, an entity described in subclause (I); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H19BCF4075BB2498DA12F15A18EBB6DEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an exercise of voting rights associated with any investments of the Thrift Savings Fund (or portions thereof) does not comply with subsection (b)(1)(D) if that exercise of voting rights is a covered vote with respect to a proposal that would— </text><subclause id="H5E5508A3ADA44AA1A02D25CD2F807931"><enum>(I)</enum><text>approve or ratify a transaction, including a transaction described in subparagraph (D)(ii)(I), that would cause, or would reasonably be expected to cause, an entity to which the covered vote applies to—</text><item id="H47411E5ABE7A4E97B7C6BCB8C7D045BA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>breach any contract with the Federal Government to which the entity is a party, and under which the consideration provided to the entity over the course of the entire contract is more than $10,000,000, if the entity has otherwise complied with all applicable laws and regulations in fulfilling the responsibilities of the entity with respect to the contract;</text></item><item id="HD58D2F47A8FB4B608F4E8E40BA71D985"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>significantly reduce the production of, or the capital expenditure or research and development expenditure with respect to, any— </text><subitem id="H2A83755BC7EF42DAB19F9658D9AFF635"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>industrial resources, critical technology items, or materials that are essential to the national defense (as those terms are defined in section 702 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4552">50 U.S.C. 4552</external-xref>)); or </text></subitem><subitem id="H036249B1164F4A47B383181BDB296566"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>emerging and foundational technology identified by the President under section 1758 of the Export Controls Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4817">50 U.S.C. 4817</external-xref>); or</text></subitem></item><item id="HC6F9FF0F2D824992B4648F41D5895142"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>outsource or substantially sell, whether to any affiliated entity or joint venture, or by contract, to any entity located in a covered country, any—</text><subitem id="HB2042F23FE04463590FC624490B1D18D"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>industrial resources, critical technology items, or materials that are essential to the national defense (as those terms are defined in section 702 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4552">50 U.S.C. 4552</external-xref>)); or</text></subitem><subitem id="H9B18D6A69FD746F194514BACB781E498"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>emerging and foundational technology identified by the President under section 1758 of the Export Controls Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4817">50 U.S.C. 4817</external-xref>); or</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H3395E60BD4464939B562CAFDD02FC9DB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>elect to the board of directors of any entity an individual who—</text><item id="H1987A048A8874081BECF9231CAFDC5DE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is a director, officer, employee, or affiliate of any entity described in clause (i)(I);</text></item><item id="HE2300730F2344BFA8C123BDAEA31AC16"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>at any time during the 5-year period preceding the date on which that election occurs, was as described in item (aa); or</text></item><item id="H0226C0DC6EA54FEFBBD4EB533B2F0F1B"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a reasonable investor would believe supports any proposal described in subclause (I).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H69D99502FF134A48AFB63F45860FD8CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In this paragraph— </text><clause id="H0C99D572F505416397AF279ED6FB6A1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>covered country</term> means—</text><subclause id="H078074E4B6AF4374B559B9520A182DFA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, North Korea, Iran, Syria, Sudan, Venezuela, or Cuba;</text></subclause><subclause id="H70B52B1AD7BB43AA868361C8EB6911C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any country, the government of which the Secretary of State determines has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to—</text><item id="H7BBA589B222B4A52B7692D7DDAF1E8B5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>);</text></item><item id="HB0C804549A7D4263985F785321DD3E51"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>); </text></item><item id="HF19F20B2132E4DB3AC5EBE9EB3EF5A36"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text></item><item id="HC123AD4E43454284A2FC4E297724CD0B"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>any other provision of law; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H229D5F522A7C4F37AE904C5B806B5018"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other country that the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of the Treasury, designates as posing an undue or unnecessary risk to the national security of the United States; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7A20F437B6AB47F88282D32C77595E42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>covered vote</term> means a vote in favor of (or an abstention with respect to) a proposal to—</text><subclause id="H3BE89031BB9E4EB9A73C49064C92D2C7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>approve or ratify a transaction involving an entity, including—</text><item id="H06D76F1D04324477BABB73BF32C1458C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any sale of, or other disposition of (whether in a single or a series of transactions) assets or capital stock; and</text></item><item id="H2A86C0CA3B764E48AEA03C1DD9FDB37E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any merger, consolidation, joint venture, partnership, spin-off, reverse spin-off, dissolution, restructuring, recapitalization, liquidation, or any other business combination or strategic transaction; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H346FDE94B57B4124AF387644B3C7997F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>elect an individual to the board of directors of the entity that is the subject of the proposal.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79BD760D8588459784576D4566F8D2DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of exercise of voting rights; report to Congress</header><text>Section 8438 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB2AB25F208BC4DACB64E010F9383661D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph id="H885BBF97663841DF82826A287E8AAA4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(f)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0FE4798B23C4F1081AFD6B579680CAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HACA1948404704D358D2A1D774EEB2CC0" act-name=""><paragraph id="H05AE6758288744D2929F45A9D1FFC058" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the purposes of paragraph (1), a review of the exercise of voting rights for compliance with section 8477(b)(1)(D), including under the regulations prescribed under section 8477(f)(2), shall not be considered to be the exercise of voting rights associated with the ownership of securities by the Thrift Savings Fund.</text></paragraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E2805A4533347D1B41BD77C5F6F6079"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDAE1D0B86C5E47BFBB79A4DB113C31FF" act-name=""><subsection id="HCE149657B41A46C8A30A4E046383C48C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Labor shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report regarding— </text><paragraph id="H0F745CF1088D4BAFB5229491CD60D898"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the year covered by the report, the investments of the Thrift Savings Fund (or portions thereof), and the exercise of voting rights associated with any such investments, that have been reviewed for compliance with section 8477(b)(1)(D); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H278E05C01E5744E48F08A0D63E6B340B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the outcome with respect to enforcement of each review conducted under paragraph (1) and a justification for that outcome.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA86CAB7065124E2BAE77D2601A299915"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on investment of Thrift Savings Fund sums in entities based in the People’s Republic of China through the TSP mutual fund window</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8438(b)(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H2F200F1B1A7840C1886D091754E232BD" style="OLC" act-name=""><subparagraph id="H91E78280D4524F9090CD335EDF19A4EA" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A mutual fund accessible through a mutual fund window authorized under this paragraph may not include an investment in any security of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H867357C749004523BEC468C03A122295"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity based in the People’s Republic of China; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEEFA02241104120A9D3DB2B1ACBA8E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any subsidiary that is owned or operated by an entity described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

