<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B4A6218477346EB9CDB5F9DAE658443" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9001 IH: Veterans Hearing Aid Improvement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9001</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a demonstration project on coverage by the Department of Veterans Affairs of over-the-counter hearing aids, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H28A8EAB7B4FA40BCACE9D7295A75CA1C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HADC3A6129D934D41868DBFF9A310D707" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Hearing Aid Improvement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBA175EE61988426FB1DEB1D3D98B9C20"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration project on coverage by Department of Veterans Affairs of over-the-counter hearing aids</header> <subsection id="HDED13CEC881949A39610F7F10A39620B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of demonstration project</header><text>Beginning not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall commence a project (in this section referred to as the <quote>demonstration project</quote>) to demonstrate and evaluate the fiscal impact of covering FDA-cleared, over-the-counter hearing aids under section 1707(b) of title 38, United States Code, in the same or similar manner as coverage is provided for prescription hearing aids under such section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H000687F80D734034A9E9E4F61ED2F931"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the demonstration project for a period of two years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H38263C5935344CDEBA4A2354878E4A55"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible participants</header><text>A veteran is eligible to participate in the demonstration project if—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3394BB472FB4F5F99E62B3A65B1A0AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the veteran is enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE038D430595F4EC98277ECE23DA60A3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an audiologist determines, through a clinical evaluation of the veteran, that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19B7DEBF85D54D59B9A89AEA69380C52">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">furnishing an over-the-counter hearing aid to the veteran for mild-to-moderate hearing loss is medically necessary; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BF32AFE53AB4204A31BC539C669A0C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the veteran has no red flag conditions or contraindications for over-the-counter hearing aid use, as specified by the Food and Drug Administration; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26CF6B998A85446AA6513C1CDEB4A466"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the veteran has access to a mobile phone device and mobile data or Wi-Fi, or any successor technology, to operate over-the-counter hearing aid functionality.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HECDBBD25E1D5425F814C2EE41079EDBE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the demonstration project at not fewer than two medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs selected by the Secretary across different Veterans Integrated Services Networks and that have a demonstrated ability to reduce access barriers and provide services to a diverse veteran population in both rural and urban settings and surrounding areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H68BB8833F19141DC80AE3AC37820F33B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Project design</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AEA98CDDA5C4CC4BA9A1572E22F9A4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall design the demonstration project to demonstrate the effectiveness of FDA-cleared, over-the-counter hearing aids compared to professionally fitted prescription hearing aids by an audiologist according to the audiological best practices of the Department of Veterans of Affairs, including the fiscal impact on the Department of providing permanent coverage of over-the-counter hearing aids under section 1707(b) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H920B2D64660643BEA74845D045FE02C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Design elements</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9CDD65BD2864775A535BC45195CF51E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure the demonstration project includes the following study groups:</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BC460CDB5F04A31BC96F59C10734B7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An FDA-cleared, over the counter hearing aid group.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65D93C1B59264EAFB64CAE5BDADCF7B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An audiologist-fitted prescription hearing aid group.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62F338E6D05B4140AFBB3CA753FE2C62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall allocate an approximately equal number of participants in the demonstration project to each group specified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H995640FAF4B64BF98CF3EA882C022F17"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Measurement of benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent possible, in carrying out the demonstration project, the Secretary shall measure both self-reported benefits and speech recognition in noise among a diverse veteran population and evaluate the fiscal impact over a two-year follow-up period of permanent coverage of over-the-counter hearing aids under section 1707(b) of title 38, United States Code, for the FDA-cleared, over-the-counter hearing aids found under the demonstration project to be most beneficial.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HADB6DB2C7679482C9789C6D100E49527"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the demonstration project, the Secretary shall consult with organizations that represent consumers with mild-to-moderate hearing loss and other stakeholder organizations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB87605454154F188604D95E72B01C12"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H0EEEF148C8BF4D2C92A15DA9AB65B39C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than one year after the commencement of the demonstration project, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that describes the progress and preliminary findings from the demonstration project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4949A9D4E9D24237A00978ABEB496038"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FAE023A94544D08B9E2CEB0C365BA5F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the last day of the demonstration project and after solicitation and consideration of formal written input on the project from organizations specified under subsection (g), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a final report on the project.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F3CC801BEB64A089084CE836D72EC83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include an evaluation of the fiscal impact on the Department of Veterans Affairs of providing permanent coverage of over-the-counter hearing aids under section 1707(b) of title 38, United States Code, and such other findings and recommendations as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE718893FF7CB458F9D0B2DA171F3B06E"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>FDA-Cleared, over-the-Counter hearing aid defined</header> <text>In this section, the term <term>FDA-cleared, over-the-counter hearing aid</term> means a device—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="H00C51CFA4F0149B4BB94B5A43FA3C719">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cleared by the Food and Drug Administration;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="H00C7F44F06C94B98BFB180DB0FCA010E">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fully regulated by the Food and Drug Administration under section 520(q) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360j">21 U.S.C. 360j(q)</external-xref>); and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="HB397E6575F594520AED7A57E7D07BE27">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that contains features that allow personalization through technology, such as hearing tests, software, and smart phone applications.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="HA066ED56602942849E694A44EA73B796"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comptroller General study and report on veterans hearing aid benefits</header> 
<subsection id="H532B68385B6849B8BE71F7518A0576A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the furnishing to veterans with mild-to-moderate hearing loss under section 1707(b) of title 38, United States Code, of assistance for hearing aids and related examinations.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8A8DBEB03E74D2E931C9946241E97BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study required under subsection (a)—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0579941D51344A4C9C36292E74976C20"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include an examination of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71E63A4CC85346F5975E082D73EA30A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals in the United States with mild-to-moderate hearing loss who need hearing aids;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1231353410DE417F8C5AF29D981C43B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the medical coverage of such individuals relating to obtaining hearing aids; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD580D23EBC1A43FBBDD72DB064B0A481"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of such medical coverage in meeting such need; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F44EE37358C44CAA7A7C91416849B64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may include an examination of contract design for purchasing hearing aid devices.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8106F8845161467C92669B09BA6B55B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E06CB6925174160B73D1C2800A7DF32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26ADC95EE6BD400290DC65C815B9DA54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include such recommendations on changes to programs and benefits of the Department of Veterans Affairs, including the establishment of new programs and benefits, as would meet the needs of veterans with mild-to-moderate hearing loss.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

