<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF06A10D324054C5491B3209F999D11BD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1387 IH: Congratulating the Carolina Hurricanes for winning the 2026 Stanley Cup Final.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1387</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000405">Mr. Knott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Carolina Hurricanes for winning the 2026 Stanley Cup Final.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Carolina Hurricanes dominated their rivals throughout the 2026 Stanley Cup playoffs, finishing the tournament with a postseason record of 16–3;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 14, 2026, the Carolina Hurricanes defeated the Vegas Golden Knights in their own stadium in game 6 of the Stanley Cup Final, winning the series 4–2;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas, with this victory, the Carolina Hurricanes won their second ever Stanley Cup, coming exactly 20 years after their first Stanley Cup;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the team was led by legendary Head Coach Rod Brind’Amour, who 20 years ago was captain of the team during their first Stanley Cup victory;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Captain Jordan Staal scored 6 goals in the Final, including at least 1 goal in each of the first 5 games of the series, and was awarded the Conn Smythe Trophy as the most valuable player of the Stanley Cup Playoffs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every Carolina Hurricanes player contributed to this winning season, including Sebastian Aho, Frederik Andersen, Jackson Blake, Brandon Bussi, William Carrier, Charlie Cerrato, Jalen Chatfield, Nicolas Deslauriers, Nikolaj Ehlers, Shayne Gostisbehere, Taylor Hall, Mark Jankowski, Seth Jarvis, Pyotr Kochetkov, Jesperi Kotkaniemi, Jordan Martinook, Amir Miftakhov, K’Andre Miller, Alexander Nikishin, Noah Philp, Mike Reilly, Eric Robinson, Jaccob Slavin, Logan Stankoven, Andrei Svechnikov, and Sean Walker;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this winning season was also made possible by General Manager Eric Tulsky and every member of the Carolina Hurricanes organization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there have been reports of <quote>Storm Surge</quote> across the Carolinas since game 6 as the <quote>Caniacs</quote> celebrate their hard-earned victory; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Carolina Hurricanes are active in their community through programs supporting children and families, military servicemembers, and public safety personnel across North Carolina: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9505E3ACA7304489A027AB17C89AF89D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H93DB97E9E142494A917C284B241FFE52"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives congratulates the 2026 Stanley Cup champions, the Carolina Hurricanes. </text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

