<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE3F1E28A669A45CFA337BF64936D050C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6933 IH: Bolstering the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6933</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251226">December 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to complete a long-range strategic review of the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB036130541F4499183C0517BBA396154" style="OLC"><section id="H4587D1BDEBF64BAF84AEED4B12DF0CDB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bolstering the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD0BCD9AC1D024DC3BAE742BAD94B6868"><enum>2.</enum><header>Northeast home heating oil reserve mission readiness optimization</header><subsection id="H4366BD933DBF4D05ADC91720D8613AB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall—</text><paragraph id="H5188EB19D77F4D7C9045E356CA3D2DD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complete a long-range strategic review of the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H234A73D9E2D448CE893E58655DC3BAD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and submit to Congress a report that—</text><subparagraph id="HFCC406302FBB487FB9D76587E568D444"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifies near- and long-term roles of the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve relative to the energy and economic security goals and objectives of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DC055866EB84361BF14FF4C315D4365"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes whether existing legal authorities that govern the policies, configuration, and capabilities of the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve are adequate to ensure that the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve can meet the current and future energy and economic security goals and objectives of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BFA79EBCD1C468B83AFB6D405ACA73A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies the configuration and performance capabilities of the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve and recommends an action plan, including a proposed implementation schedule, to achieve the optimal—</text><clause id="HE4CC84BA89C8468D8A25F7E8F74CF66D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">capacity, location, and composition of home heating oil products in the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve; and</text></clause><clause id="HA64424FE93BD409A8D3D8A5BAE6D56DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>storage and distributional capabilities of the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CB1CCDB7F994703B3401C2B11DB707D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">estimates the resources required to attain and maintain the long-term sustainability and operational effectiveness of the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC55016C322540EBA3EC511BEC95FE0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve</term> means the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve established under part D of title I of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6250">42 U.S.C. 6250 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

