<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E6E1001EE114E47BDB51D90DFE41989" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6831 IH: Stop Padding Presidential Pockets Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6831</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require reimbursement for costs associated with Presidential travel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDDF08F00FF4E4815BF85B3D02A37A258" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA14E2CA4308741DA9E5BA9D44C80C52D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Padding Presidential Pockets Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1108697B46F44E5198A4F8360FF90E63"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reimbursement required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of a person whom the United States Secret Service is authorized to protect under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 3056(a) of title 18, United States Code, if that person travels domestically or internationally in furtherance of the business interests of an entity owned by or controlled by the President of the United States, or from which the President of the United States receives any financial benefit, that person shall reimburse to the Treasury—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8AF2CEFD480344A39FE81D18D2C6B594"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amount expended by the United States Secret Service for the provision of such protection; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CB1F4310A0E4BCC87E9091CF445C968"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amount expended for other costs incurred by the Government pertaining to that travel.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H706B9C72A9324F869C0FEE0EEFF86311"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exceptions to Federal Tort Claims Act</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H868CF68D91144B3BAD98AF02FD64ACC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2680 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7DBDF6BE46A4FCEB34D8FBA09492DFE"> <subsection id="H0BB4D10604A64364AC3D223974D99058"><enum>(o)</enum><text>Any claim, without regard to when the act or omission giving rise to the claim occurred, brought by—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A976BC6E54D47D9A7648176168A65F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H899BD0F6FB19405C97E21F3818992799"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Vice President; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H108DE1BF57A34AD4876E8E07DF51910C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who subsequently becomes President or Vice President while the claim is pending.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BC14FFA467B40A2B5543F7DFF9D70A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to any claim pending on, or brought on or after, the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEBA6F14D26214F429D7A2E1915AF2DD2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on solicitation of donations</header> 
<subsection id="H9C1965799F204BC3B248CC8C12DB2C8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person whom the United States Secret Service is authorized to protect under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 3056(a) of title 18, United States Code, may not solicit any donation for a presidential library or museum while that president is in office. Each such person shall submit an annual report to the Archivist of the United States on each interaction with another party that pertains to a presidential library and museum.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H7825110203B54D3EB8EBC669546F187D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each private entity that administers or lobbies for a presidential library or museum shall submit an annual report to the Archivist of the United States on the financial activities of that private entity that pertain to the presidential library or museum.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4AD0CED798404A9D8C08EEF86D79D123"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Whoever fails to submit a report required to be submitted under this section shall be fined $1,000 each day that the report is not submitted.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA268DC7D6B2E4886BAE8DA359D6423BB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on Presidential activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President may not create a business, operate a business, serve on a board of directors of any business, or be part of any day-to-day operations of a business while in office. If an immediate family member of the President engages in any conduct prohibited on the part of the President in this section, that immediate family member shall submit quarterly reports to Congress and publish a certification that their conduct is not enriching or benefitting the sitting President of the United States. If the President creates, operates, or serves on a board of directors of any business, any income the President earns from such creation, operation, or service shall be subject to a tax of 100 percent.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

