<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD4725FA9F5A47129EF7CFEF8F3BC5F4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6820 IH: Airline Passenger Compensation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Transportation to issue certain regulations relating to airline passenger flight compensation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA6B2084E519D4271AF8E83BB201E407E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8FF77E673E49464983F3C6AE50C40141" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Airline Passenger Compensation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H82BF34F49B0A4A30AC07CD0AD3EF590A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulations relating to airline passenger disrupted flight compensation</header> <subsection id="H0B30D5682E1F47F8AE28B650EF75387C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue regulations to require an air carrier to provide to a passenger on a domestic or international flight who experiences a significant delay or cancellation due to circumstances that are within the control of the air carrier in which such passenger will arrive at a destination airport—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7CD9576A54EE4AB6B572517369A62C72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>more than 3 hours but less than 9 hours after the original scheduled arrival time, compensation of not more than $300, and if any connecting flight is missed due to such delay or cancellation a booking on the next available flight at no additional cost; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAFAC680AF9C4B018B127F73754A9F76"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">9 or more hours after the original scheduled arrival time, compensation of not more than $775, and if any connecting flight is missed due to such delay or cancellation a booking on the next available flight at no additional cost.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17097314307C44E6B9D313EAF715C851"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>The requirements of this section shall be considered separate and distinct from the refund requirements described in section 42305 of title 49, United States Code.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

