<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA26271-650-V8-2T0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4274 IS: Wildfire Investment and Next Generation Stewardship Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4274</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer title to certain aircraft and related parts loaned under the Federal Excess Personal Property program to authorized users after a qualifying period of use, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Investment and Next Generation Stewardship Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WINGS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idcbfae079f29c4449afd76c29897b0b13"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header><subsection id="id540080bfff8f4c698e520f6d8219211c" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id4e31244523fe4c0d931d2a0a5c7ec0ef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since 1956, the Department of Agriculture has operated a Federal Excess Personal Property program through which the Forest Service acquires excess property, primarily from the Department of Defense, and loans such property to State foresters for wildland and rural firefighting purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8ecad41cfc0450c8180983e5d814fe2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State and local firefighting agencies have successfully used aircraft and related parts obtained through the Federal Excess Personal Property program to protect lives, property, and natural resources for extended periods, often exceeding 10 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96939cedf3674008a5b2904a8054ebcb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>After lengthy periods of use, maintenance, and investment by authorized users, uncertainty regarding ownership and disposal authority can create operational and planning difficulties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f6b9857f469408ab1368ca9f56b49a2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Authorizing transfer of title to aircraft and serviceable aircraft parts after a qualifying period of responsible use will improve asset management, reduce administrative burden, and recognize the substantial investment made by State and local agencies in maintaining and operating such property.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc1e7820104014557b5a3fff60a211d01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer title to certain aircraft and related parts loaned under the Federal Excess Personal Property program to authorized users that have demonstrated responsible stewardship over a sustained period.</text></subsection></section><section id="iddb96fa04e1d4495d88bfc42b4f5dfe77"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of title to certain aircraft and related parts loaned under Federal Excess Personal Property program</header><subsection id="id1bb60709efd049e1a4353d71d3f5e7bd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id49c35da59be4404d97f48840e1d5ec60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aircraft</header><text>The term <term>aircraft</term> means any fixed wing or rotary wing aircraft, including installed equipment and associated components, that is made available to an authorized user under a Federal Excess Personal Property program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id619eab9a8e394d638bdbdd5a6b864b58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized user</header><text>The term <term>authorized user</term> means a State, political subdivision of a State, or other entity that is eligible to receive, and has received, aircraft or serviceable aircraft parts under the Federal Excess Personal Property program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id196d344c80be4db3909499da18f78473"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal Excess Personal Property program</header><text>The term <term>Federal Excess Personal Property program</term> means the program (or a successor program) administered by the Secretary under which aircraft and serviceable aircraft parts are provided to authorized users for the purpose of wildland or rural firefighting.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8db50966011d4292b9ef72e9b072db15"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Good standing</header><text>The term <term>good standing</term> means, with respect to an authorized user and an aircraft or serviceable aircraft part, that, as determined by the Secretary, the authorized user—</text><subparagraph id="id8ca29c4f237c4029825ced063ab9eabe"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is, as of the date of the determination, in compliance with—</text><clause id="id521307c591b2426b93b078938c96d14c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all applicable statutes, regulations, and written program requirements of the Department of Agriculture relating to property provided under the Federal Excess Personal Property program; and</text></clause><clause id="id1f6016e005b0445686e4eb6ac2a86e35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the terms and conditions of any agreement or instrument under which the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part was made available to the authorized user;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1e71055bfe14e9ea9d240a8a48a88d3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has timely submitted all required inventories, reports, certifications, and other documentation relating to the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id900c266ac9364df1915132be1dd809e4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not misused, sold, leased, encumbered, transferred, or otherwise disposed of the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part in violation of any applicable requirement or agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5579f8846b354e56a8ff85a778980e8a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has maintained accurate and current inventory records of all serviceable aircraft parts in the possession of the authorized user, whether installed or uninstalled, in accordance with requirements under the Federal Excess Personal Property program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31fd5b20a3c34eec8b6b46d98612a278" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is not, as of the date of the determination, subject to any suspension, debarment, or other formal enforcement action by the Department of Agriculture that relates to the aircraft, the serviceable aircraft parts, or the Federal Excess Personal Property program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id48b88d17b8b148bc9eab747fbbda8da8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d42bb511c274e7889a23f0c02762e98"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Serviceable aircraft part</header><text>The term <term>serviceable aircraft part</term> means any component, assembly, subassembly, spare part, accessory, support equipment, or other item of equipment, regardless of whether it is currently installed on an aircraft, that is—</text><subparagraph id="id20afe6bdf22b40eba5395e94210ed746"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designed for use on, or in support of the maintenance or operation of, an aircraft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14725e5d70374743aabb6bfaa8805d82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made available to an authorized user under a Federal Excess Personal Property program administered by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd0d93886e8748c1955cd110a77bc29e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determined by the authorized user, in accordance with applicable maintenance standards and Federal Excess Personal Property program requirements, to be—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d15b19f4c6f43618e74a51ec55ebddd"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in serviceable condition; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f29b6317b814ef5aa2ec42192651a64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">capable of being restored to serviceable condition through overhaul or maintenance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f0814858c454d60b15d65739a5beecf"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Authority To transfer title</header> <paragraph id="idae489b16b56649c4b0745bd1228f4e2f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law governing the retention of title to property made available under the Federal Excess Personal Property program, the Secretary may transfer all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to an aircraft or serviceable aircraft part to the authorized user that has received the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part if the requirements of subsection (c) or (d), as applicable, are satisfied.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id1ead7bec4d3141fd9fb71ae7b42f588d">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Effect of transfer</header>
 <text>Upon a transfer under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="id8d7530c833174c7cbe1f16abe138f8ee"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the United States shall have no further ownership interest in the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idab2e76f7337b45b7a77841ecf6b39c30">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the authorized user shall assume full ownership of the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part, subject to—</text>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="ide291c7b5abaf455ca3a7deedcca8e12e">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any conditions imposed under subsection (e); and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="ida7d46683e30041218f40dfaffe896f1d">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any applicable Federal law, including laws relating to export controls and national security.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="ide43c93f5964349e4845dccf6f259302d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility for transfer of aircraft</header><text>The Secretary may approve the transfer of right, title, and interest in and to an aircraft to an authorized user under subsection (b) only if the Secretary determines that—</text><paragraph id="id31763a5b3c474f9494bd351a7455e8cf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the authorized user has had continuous possession of the aircraft for not fewer than 10 years beginning on the date the aircraft was first received by the authorized user under the Federal Excess Personal Property program, whether used for operational purposes or as a source of serviceable parts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e30af068c0746b8b5dae1aec0010c93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as of the date of the determination, the authorized user is in good standing with respect to the aircraft; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89f5134ce8d44054b8d9f598193650e1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the transfer would not be inconsistent with—</text><subparagraph id="id585dda76bbc24f588cb05cebb6e74686"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any statutory limitation or condition governing the original furnishing of the aircraft to the Department of Agriculture by another Federal department or agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4da167d8f464b6c8a89e7be361db8be"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any applicable national security, export control, or similar restriction, as determined by the Secretary in consultation, as appropriate, with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of any other relevant Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id668e399287fb40e096089cdab89b7488"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility for transfer of serviceable aircraft parts</header><text>The Secretary may approve the transfer of right, title, and interest in and to a serviceable aircraft part to an authorized user under subsection (b) only if the Secretary determines that—</text><paragraph id="idb2f9be7ef9c5470cbc385bfe9b61b4dc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the authorized user—</text><subparagraph id="id5be442d2c05d421d9e21d48460f28ee0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has had continuous possession of the serviceable aircraft part for not fewer than 5 years beginning on the date the serviceable aircraft part was first received by the authorized user under the Federal Excess Personal Property program; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb697b1f4cd24124a4182b2308c3fcf4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has had continuous possession of an aircraft under the Federal Excess Personal Property program for not fewer than 10 years and the serviceable aircraft part was received in support of that aircraft, regardless of when the serviceable aircraft part was received;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id909bb6960bc843a6a84f67bee41f3641"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as of the date of the determination, the authorized user is in good standing with respect to the serviceable aircraft part;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b80c394a9254d9ca6d589d206a48801"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the authorized user has maintained accurate and current inventory records of the serviceable aircraft part in accordance with standards established by the Secretary, including documentation of the condition, location, and intended use of the serviceable aircraft part; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2f4e6cbad47405a8887142a7c62a8d6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the transfer would not be inconsistent with—</text><subparagraph id="id73d7f0705661442aa4b295256aa3c901"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any statutory limitation or condition governing the original furnishing of the serviceable aircraft part to the Department of Agriculture by another Federal department or agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc0138530d6a649199a8cfe812c55bfab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any applicable national security, export control, or similar restriction, as determined by the Secretary in consultation, as appropriate, with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of any other relevant Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id66d31258672441a0aa2d04797597aa3e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conditions on transfers</header><paragraph id="id3614c5753ff54ee9bd4fcb4a9c1eb3e2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of approving a transfer under this section, the Secretary may require the authorized user to agree, in such form as the Secretary may prescribe, to 1 or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id3d4b076c5a3e4df7a35d84f245642db3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>That, for a period not to exceed 5 years beginning on the date of transfer, the authorized user will continue to use any aircraft transferred under this section primarily—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef2aa9d23261462aae0d6b80d6f81f95"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for public purposes consistent with the purposes of the Federal Excess Personal Property program, which may include wildland fire suppression, other emergency response, public safety missions, and training in support of those missions; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacf34dc593a74935bbcd60aae7022ef8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a source of serviceable aircraft parts to support other aircraft used for the public purposes described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59fa14f68dbb4c5fa8f85db4c65baa23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>That, for a period not to exceed 3 years beginning on the date of transfer, the authorized user—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3422fa0a7be4c948c3affd88c918dc3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will use any serviceable aircraft parts transferred under this section for purposes consistent with the maintenance, repair, overhaul, or operational support of aircraft used for the public purposes described in subparagraph (A)(i); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e4f0581725a4bdcb751210f778fe5b3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will not use any serviceable aircraft parts transferred under this section for commercial resale or distribution except with the prior written consent of the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d8ce589e1f04fc9a1d4039fb8e09df8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That, for a period not to exceed 5 years beginning on the date of transfer, the authorized user will not sell, lease, encumber, export, or otherwise dispose of the aircraft or serviceable aircraft parts transferred under this section except—</text><clause id="id77339871f59049cc9f80ea9a15a94daa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with the prior written consent of the Secretary; or</text></clause><clause id="id2926b989ebd0450e8038e7d64865dfe7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in accordance with such conditions as the Secretary may establish by regulation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide62f2ee61f3b4876a0a8b0356980d3e1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>That, for a period not to exceed 5 years beginning on the date of transfer, the authorized user will maintain such records relating to the use and disposition of the aircraft or serviceable aircraft parts, and will make such records available to the Secretary upon reasonable request, as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b655b0675544ac2ab78135825de5f62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification or waiver</header><text>The Secretary may, on a case-by-case basis, modify or waive the application, in whole or in part, of one or more conditions imposed under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that such modification or waiver is necessary—</text><subparagraph id="id3f2d8a13ed1c405dbd1dbf012fb6b7db"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to protect public safety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id423d37f8f9324283be38691979e2dc9f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to comply with other applicable Federal law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92f40e38f8a54660a52eef7e7d00ae09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>because continued use of the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part by the authorized user is no longer practicable; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id665f26f1b70f43fd941f1e6a41daa3ec"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to facilitate appropriate maintenance, overhaul, or repair activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id65aa5910f55045c9b054d107489dea40"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application and determination</header><paragraph id="id32c10378f0f246a2979a4feba5f950d2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An authorized user seeking a transfer of an aircraft or serviceable aircraft part under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="idec5325bb6ea74f9090381fc89aa3fc37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>documentation of the date on which the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part was first received or placed into service by the authorized user;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id245d42df8c484af9a8c53e410c2866e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the application relates to one or more serviceable aircraft parts, a complete and current inventory of all such serviceable aircraft parts for which transfer is requested, including information on the condition, location, and intended or actual use of each serviceable aircraft part;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd3bc00f582e498cab67a823fa396c32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information sufficient for the Secretary to determine whether the authorized user is in good standing with respect to the aircraft or serviceable aircraft part; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c63199eabc14e6780fef145e0645f4b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any certifications or other assurances required by the Secretary regarding intended future use and compliance with conditions imposed under subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9bcdd903c2684019b1afadf8989a9d68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeline for decision</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a complete application under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall approve or deny the application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca71fada2809404fbef9ff8792fc4b93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denial</header><text>If the Secretary denies an application submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide to the authorized user a written notification of the denial that—</text><subparagraph id="id7d30d6d876c74876868248d502757e43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>states the reasons for the denial; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b875b15462045cfb45ab63d469ca99a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies, to the extent practicable, any actions the authorized user may take to cure the deficiencies and become eligible for a future transfer with respect to that aircraft, that serviceable aircraft part, or other aircraft or serviceable aircraft parts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7f92621c439946dd929b38dba2a2d1d6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate such regulations, or issue such revisions to regulations or written guidance, as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this section, including—</text><paragraph id="id0d4889a2fec443beb9b1a94241cd623b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>objective criteria and procedures for determining whether an authorized user is in good standing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ec32e4d5c3e4079928b470a683949b3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>standards for inventory management, tracking, and reporting of serviceable aircraft parts, including serviceable aircraft parts not installed on an aircraft and serviceable aircraft parts that require overhaul or maintenance before installation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef4e3972d8cb40209d80d1200555aa35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>standards and procedures for evaluating applications and making determinations under subsection (f), including verification of parts inventories and condition assessments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3ddcc90dc024010bcc9f17d761bcd3f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>model terms and conditions for agreements entered into under subsection (e), with separate or tailored conditions for aircraft and for serviceable aircraft parts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide584b6f68f9e4d4d83ffec7b8da87645"><enum>(5)</enum><text>safeguards, including any necessary coordination with other Federal departments or agencies, to ensure compliance with statutory limitations and with national security, export control, and similar requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id46d745c1c9e64ac6a08ebf968c165126"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="idd8f553a986284f5b9c4841d1a224291a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit any other authority of the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="id402f1e277d0244779050ffc444030d74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to transfer title to property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide61b8b6312344dad99341c116c58ef65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to reclaim property; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff8d648e59884bac8350dd050a73c97e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to impose conditions on the participation of an authorized user in the Federal Excess Personal Property program; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7975cb9281f84175b80e65c11b07e2c3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to affect any law applicable to the original transfer of an aircraft or serviceable aircraft part to the Department of Agriculture by another Federal department or agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

