<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H517382E7A8D646668ADFDA534A2225F2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1163 IH: Supporting the recognition of a “Day of Remembrance and Commitment to Maternal Health Equity”, honoring the life of Kira Johnson, and commending 4Kira4Moms for its unwavering dedication to improving maternal health in Atlanta, throughout Georgia, and across the United States, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the recognition of a <quote>Day of Remembrance and Commitment to Maternal Health Equity</quote>, honoring the life of Kira Johnson, and commending 4Kira4Moms for its unwavering dedication to improving maternal health in Atlanta, throughout Georgia, and across the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on April 13, 2016, Kira Johnson tragically passed away following the birth of her second son due to preventable medical complications, a loss that devastated her family and exposed urgent gaps in accountability and quality within the Nation’s maternal health system;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Kira Johnson’s passing became the catalyst for the founding of 4Kira4Moms by her husband, Charles Johnson, who transformed profound grief into a national movement demanding transparency, equity, and systemic reform;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since its founding, 4Kira4Moms has worked tirelessly to improve maternal health outcomes, elevate the voices of Black mothers, educate families, engage fathers, and advocate for Federal and State policies that advance maternal health equity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 4Kira4Moms has supported and advanced landmark Federal maternal health legislation, including the Preventing Maternal Deaths Act, which strengthened maternal mortality review committees nationwide to better understand and prevent pregnancy-related deaths;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 4Kira4Moms has championed the Black Maternal Health Momnibus Act, a comprehensive legislative package addressing social determinants of health, workforce diversification, data collection, climate impacts, and community-based investments in maternal care;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in honor of Kira Johnson’s legacy, the proposed Kira Johnson Act advances critical accountability measures by—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7C2AC2F973DD478582C594E4ED58D41D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing grants to community-based organizations to improve maternal health outcomes, particularly for Black women and underserved communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D549996C8EF4EA284F30703B61446E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>funding training programs to identify and reduce bias, racism, and discrimination for all employees in maternity care settings;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FD98106ECE94044B7044AA25ECF7EFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing respectful maternity care compliance programs within hospitals to handle, report, and address instances of patient mistreatment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF81A9689E8440B4AC1695122B934122"><enum>(4)</enum><text>directing research and oversight, including instructing the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to study training program effectiveness and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to evaluate the impact of hospital compliance offices;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 4Kira4Moms is an official endorser of the Dads Matter Act, recognizing that engaged fathers and supportive partners are essential contributors to improved maternal and infant health outcomes and that Federal policy must strengthen paternal engagement as a protective factor for families;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the organization also supports legislation such as the PREEMIE Reauthorization Act and related perinatal quality improvement initiatives to strengthen care systems and reduce preventable complications;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, under the leadership of founder Charles Johnson and Executive Director Gabrielle Albert, 4Kira4Moms has strengthened its commitment to Atlanta, Georgia, and communities nationwide through advocacy campaigns, public awareness initiatives, fatherhood engagement programs, and partnerships designed to eliminate racial disparities in maternal health outcomes;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Black women in the United States continue to experience disproportionately high rates of pregnancy-related deaths and severe maternal morbidity, underscoring the urgent need for sustained Federal leadership, accountability, and community-driven solutions; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas April 11, 2026, marks the 10-year commemoration of Kira Johnson’s life and legacy, a solemn milestone that calls the Nation to reflection, remembrance, and renewed commitment to ensuring that no maternal death is preventable: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H11E38AFB52304A6C8A53F809F6457E7F"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF1501386586741159781D3669A503BF3"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB0B540158553449DAF62C49CA434348D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the recognition of a <quote>Day of Remembrance and Commitment to Maternal Health Equity</quote>, honoring the life of Kira Johnson and commending 4Kira4Moms for its unwavering dedication to improving maternal health in Atlanta, throughout Georgia, and across the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DFE2D48249E416094DE6AC2F978EDAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applauds founder Charles Johnson and Executive Director Gabrielle Albert for their steadfast leadership in advancing legislative solutions, promoting respectful maternity care, strengthening paternal engagement, and working to eradicate preventable maternal mortality nationwide.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

