<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL26367-YRP-1T-62S"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4333 IS: Victims of Immigration Conduct Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4333</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260416" legis-day="20260414">April 16 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide a civil remedy for any individual whose rights have been violated by a Federal law enforcement officer carrying out an immigration-related enforcement action.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id8e83fe537067466984ca3b6dc4c55378" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Victims of Immigration Conduct Enforcement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VOICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id771ad07e4f554dad8a9518d0070d0560"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Civil remedy for victims of unlawful immigration-related enforcement actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2674 of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id4FA6F2C5299848C78C11FFCF76BE8764"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a)</quote> before <quote>The United States shall be liable, respecting</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63C5EA24029C4D56AD8C38104BC68C24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(b)</quote> before <quote>If, however,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5FAF22D5D63C4C8DB4726453443262BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(c)</quote> before <quote>With respect to any claim under this chapter,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB61F90132E90411F98BCA7E4E190630A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(d)</quote> before <quote>With respect to any claim to which this section applies,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB655D29911C440178746C8A438971509"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3b5cb40e7144f698dc8c25f0b92dcd4"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id591e9d6021ee4097a943de2ce95364c4"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4c0986b9815541cf884c15ba6c08b480"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>Federal law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given the term <term>law enforcement officer</term> in section 1515 of title 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0adcecc51b84425f8dbb5b21486f9546" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, while acting under color of law to carry out an immigration-related enforcement action, a Federal law enforcement officer, or any other person acting under the direction of a Federal law enforcement officer, subjects, or causes to be subjected, any individual within the jurisdiction of the United States to the deprivation of any rights, privileges, or immunities secured by the Constitution or laws of the United States, the United States shall be liable to the aggrieved party in an action at law, a suit in equity, or any other proper proceeding for redress, regardless of whether the officer or other person was acting consistent with an official policy, practice, or custom.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38f4cd1bbe7d45918aa06359dd12bc60" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monetary damages awarded in a case authorized under paragraph (2) shall be paid by the Federal agency that employed the Federal law enforcement officer who subjected or caused to be subjected, or under whose direction another person subjected or caused to be subjected, an individual to the deprivation of rights, privileges, or immunities secured by the Constitution or laws of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id9e819fa025fb404882d71f6a053fb8b1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2675(a) shall not apply to a civil action authorized under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idf46f4b33b9e64f3b99a499d3b4cc4507"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a) or any other provision of law, if the United States is found liable in a case authorized under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the claimant shall be awarded $2,000,000 in punitive damages.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id2629ddce156f4f8db67fe0a9908dc144"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit or preclude any legal, equitable, or other remedy that is otherwise available against an individual Federal law enforcement officer or other person.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

