<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H246BDEFE45424D918B161E91A2D4D8C3">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7648 IH: Local Taxpayer Protection Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7648</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260223">February 23, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to mitigate expenses for municipalities where ICE processing or detention facilities are maintained or under development.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HD669B6F588A5404EB136C074CA62E75B">
<section id="H801BC0F8ED3547919496DAFDCBD66E20" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Taxpayer Protection Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4E47C2E4E6FA4E0DA6E76927EEB4B2AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>In general</header> <subsection id="H46408E7157D7420F9DC4DCEF0B7848D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a program to provide a grant to a municipality wherein a facility for processing or detention of individuals arrested or detained by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement is maintained or under development.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8AC1592531724EB086D3FE68A76959CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of a grant to a municipality may not exceed the combined cost of unrealized property tax revenue and such public utilities in use by that municipality for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H21A1CF196D0845A39E015877ABF9AFC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The grant term shall be 5 years, but a grantee may apply for renewal for the duration of a facility operation in the municipality.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H65A4337BD5444675A43AC3D013342390"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible grantee</header><text>A municipality is eligible for a grant under this section if it is a municipality wherein a facility is maintained or under development for the processing or detention of individuals arrested or detained by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H32141809824443A4B49023506A5EEDAA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header> <paragraph id="HA7D8B5ECE3AB4253953C077A73EDB4FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A municipality seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security an application therefor in such form and in such manner as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines appropriate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A2ECEF6BDB640F584FD8DF23C1162FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC02C93C0AE394264AA8983F507EB7D88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the financial need of the applicant for the grant.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF56B7086E00A4539956A6DA115796A0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the costs and benefits of the use for which a grant is requested.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAC8E82492B543928624598138BC07C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A list of other sources of funding received by the applicant—</text>
<clause id="H88FE0F7C51454473866E42585F4C38AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the same purpose for which the application for a grant under this section was submitted; or</text></clause> <clause id="H467787C52E7644F6B64A6678EBD2649F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>from the Federal Government for similar purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5BB31AF0A17D4A9F897D814F2FC61E89"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such other information as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB32FCAE8B84D46E7BC0DC2EB519C93BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Joint or regional applications</header> <subparagraph id="H2F2E4D976B3442238777B63146F80D8F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Two or more entities may submit an application under paragraph (1) for a joint grant under this section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H232E64BB9FF14F5EB71E044146C4F390"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nonexclusivity</header><text>Applications under this paragraph may be submitted instead of or in addition to any other application submitted under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD24AA6060AB44C1BD3C2C47A69C3D12"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text>
<clause id="HB542C068BE4948468F2FBEE2C85BA730"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publish guidance on applying for and administering joint grants; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD4B0CE2788A047778A4A317BC4F83E31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage applicants to apply for joint grants as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines appropriate to achieve greater cost effectiveness and regional efficiency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4F053E2EB0784E24855F904EA9EF7814"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant under this Act shall be used to defray unrealized property tax revenue, to defray the expense of operating public utilities systems within the municipality, or for both purposes. The grantee shall, to the extent practicable, make a facility described in subsection (a) in the municipality self-sufficient with regard to use of public utilities, or extend the capacity of the public utilities systems to accommodate the use of such systems by such facility.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD3EE78276A854169912574C809CEF19F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public utilities systems</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>public utilities systems</quote> includes water, gas, natural gas, electricity, internet connectivity, garbage collection, recycling, and sewer systems.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


