<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H75E80FDD88434FA69A9A9B0B22D2BC5E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 75 IH: Directing the President, pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution, to remove the United States Armed Forces from hostilities against the Islamic Republic of Iran.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 75</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Directing the President, pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution, to remove the United States Armed Forces from hostilities against the Islamic Republic of Iran.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H9B6DCD4BB7CB4C0E9BC1575821E20C8D"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H9EC4D27359C74155B36B70D17F5CF6DC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H2575BCDAE2CA46A688BBC0476ED7D472"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Islamic Republic of Iran is the leading state sponsor of terrorism and an adversary of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD52F4F31A9746CDAC81131127D14439"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The Islamic Republic of Iran seeks to pose a threat to the United States, its Armed Forces, and allies through its ballistic missile program, its sponsorship of terrorist proxy forces, and pursuit of a nuclear weapon.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H520E158F8BF14B93824C092661B6D268"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Islamic Republic of Iran engages in a range of destabilizing activities across the Middle East and the world which have resulted in scores of American deaths since 1979.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE868FBA2B0BE4A04BDA55FC90E219A4E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8 of the Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7C1F1C5C97D49C79EFAAF6C02A0DDFA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war with respect to, or provided any specific statutory authorization for, hostilities involving United States Armed Forces against the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H068ED7E395FD434BB752FA1E432FD7EB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States Armed Forces were introduced into hostilities against the Islamic Republic of Iran on February 28, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C5D3F73114F4A3D90BC4872AB1FB8F5"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is mandated to brief Congress on the deployment of United States forces, included their estimated scope and duration of their continued use, under the War Powers Resolution.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HDEDDD260A661463D832C208ECAB0345D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of use of force</header><subsection id="H3D4EA65480DA4CC7928309A4E38D7666"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1544">50 U.S.C. 1544(c)</external-xref>), Congress hereby directs the President to remove the use of United States Armed Forces from hostilities against the Islamic Republic of Iran or any part of its government or military, including potential ground forces in a combat role or used for occupation, by not later than the date that is 30 days after the date described in section 1(6), unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or specific authorization for use of military force against Iran.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA6CB999B046F4B849911A41DF1D423E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H6301C77CF6724B03BCAE12B356ED1BD9"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>prevent the United States from defending itself, its Armed Forces, its diplomatic facilities, or allied states from imminent attack;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB3447BB32024EE3B54C5D434DFAA0F4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent the United States Armed Forces from maintaining a troop presence in the region for defensive purposes; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53FCEE76E75249D5BAD32A42FB4809B2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>force the removal of United States Armed Forces in the region who are not engaged in hostilities against Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H27756BE3DA6649129FCDFC7A42D92AA2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule of construction relating to intelligence sharing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this resolution may be construed to influence or disrupt any intelligence, counterintelligence, or investigative activities relating to threats in or emanating from Iran or surrounding countries conducted by, or in conjunction with, the United States Government involving— </text><paragraph id="H3BD42C2360D9430C9697FFB3BC9515F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the collection of intelligence; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H280AF857E1CC461BBA47438A02930EE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the analysis of intelligence; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A4E1D5D9A7D4D7CB78B9DF1FDCDE7D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the sharing of intelligence between the United States and any coalition partner, if the President determines such sharing is appropriate and in the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF17CBA9765DB438EAA5788807A957535"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction relating to nonauthorization of the use of military force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Consistent with section 8(a)(1) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1547">50 U.S.C. 1547(a)(1)</external-xref>), nothing in this concurrent resolution may be construed as authorizing the use of military force.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

