<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06E8C28CCB5F41809E2CF5A9DBFC8FF1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8584 IH: Indo-Pacific Space Partnership Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8584</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Commander of the United States Space Command to submit a feasibility report on expanding the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB8349617A2A3495294DD02E395674306" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H953A58AD51904553B86A906EB4FB6C07" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Indo-Pacific Space Partnership Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E2BA35D61074EEAB0BEA9AE0DD9E19E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Feasibility report on expanding Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender</header> <subsection id="H6112F3483DD24B2C8FCD53C366E5451D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commander of the United States Space Command shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the feasibility and advisability of expanding the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender to include additional allies in the Indo-Pacific region, including Japan and the Republic of Korea.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF233E574E60E431C8D98D4F1D089CCED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H06D27B4FA0004EC59EBB9A0455346AB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of current activities and initiatives to facilitate the expansion of the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender to allied countries in the Indo-Pacific region, including Japan and the Republic of Korea.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E3266D068B142D9B6D42DFC191268D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identification of any policy change the Government of Japan, the Government of the Republic of Korea, and the government of any other allied country in the Indo-Pacific region identified by the Commander of the United States Space Command would need to make in order for the United States to extend a formal invitation for such countries to join the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBBFC61633154E0D9A3993E27DB5472D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of any funding or policy change necessary to facilitate the accession to the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender of Japan, the Republic of Korea, and any other allied country in the Indo-Pacific region identified by the Commander of the United States Space Command.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE0B5039944F4F0C9D1AD6D032AD9615"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of each of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H199BC9056BE6403593674ED87D1B4D30"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The manner in which the accession to the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender of Japan, the Republic of Korea, and any other allied country in the Indo-Pacific region identified by the Commander of the United States Space Command would affect United States national security interests.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF16974B7B784630B6CCB25BD45EF8CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether the accession to the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender of Japan and the Republic of Korea—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA36A01D6B27C4A4DB30EDBBDF880AA92"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is feasible; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE323C23E936476F8B16748EDAF9DAAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would be in the national interest of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H498931F5CD0A41EAAB3604242372DA27"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The additional resources or authorities needed from the executive and legislative branches to carry out the accession to the Multinational Force Operation Olympic Defender of Japan and the Republic of Korea.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF3EE89F1A2E9498ABB5A3398DD924BAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HCD33AE12641D461AA159654F7C2E7AEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DB4633D0C3448A5A8C0048F6C34B9E9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

