<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H2ABA8232040B401C926814605477BB78" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7677 RH: Closing the Provider Fraud Gap Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 513</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7677</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–593]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260406">April 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260406">April 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 25, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study regarding fraud prevention measures in certain Federal early childhood education, child care, and child nutrition programs, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HBC41E2B17C82461282A65CCA0E9AAC86"><section id="H8964F8335A8C4245920F44AEB7D0A8DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Closing the Provider Fraud Gap Act</short-title> of 2026</quote>.</text></section><section id="H0BFF9725C701431CA1CA78954AD87A37"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study and report on provider-related fraud</header><subsection id="H80EF2369F5AF4737B9B649469BBD96C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study regarding fraud prevention measures in Federal early childhood education, child care, and child nutrition programs that shall include an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="H8866C5D5CC844B16AAB9D2FB4DD17A2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the effectiveness of procedures and measures to prevent fraud carried out by providers of services under such programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3359302484E34A25B2BA9D1B4F0CBB88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the data the Federal Government receives in connection with such programs (including through audits and reporting requirements) is—</text><subparagraph id="H2677F288731E45DD877FFE12026884E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sufficient to successfully identify fraud carried out under such programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0E7BF69E56A4E61A3640A0E32869F0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used effectively by the Federal Government to identify potential fraud carried out under such programs; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AC406A45D9F4DAABA9CBE35898D500B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the Child Care and Development Block Grant program established under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HE5DE34E40E754C829235A675BBA14275"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the program integrity results for States that have delegated responsibilities related to program management and administration to counties, local municipalities, or other entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H358E62D73C914A619AE9922086028FD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether any corrective action plans have been implemented by States to improve program integrity results, including any measurable outcomes from implementing such a corrective action plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7498E577ACFA465FB150FCCD71FBCE21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report containing—</text><paragraph id="H05ECC7266938492681B61716A1C19813"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study conducted under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A8214A18B0E4A9F89209CCB52A67C34"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any regulatory or legislative recommendations to improve fraud prevention measures in Federal early childhood education, child care, and child nutrition programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H578AF34A93614F63AA007B2E14D70992"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal early childhood education, child care, and child nutrition programs defined</header><text>For the purposes of this section, the term <term>Federal early childhood education, child care, and child nutrition programs</term> includes—</text><paragraph id="HFE52A45C6FDA418F8CCD8DFD48ED8EEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Head Start programs (including Early Head Start programs) carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0ACF8A8D33C54A59AF03149F3FF806CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Child and Adult Care Food Program under section 17 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1766">42 U.S.C. 1766</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD39BDAAD35E4F23AD6D41903A60C403"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Child Care and Development Block Grant program established under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9857">42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>April 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

