<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C58EF0A4AE546AFB2122FA7A8D04652" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1262 IH: Recognizing and congratulating the Martinsville Missile’s land speed record for a stock car.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and congratulating the Martinsville Missile’s land speed record for a stock car.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 23, 2026, the land speed record for a stock car was set by the Martinsville Missile at the Shuttle Landing Facility in Cape Canaveral, Florida, with a top speed of 253 miles per hour;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Martinsville Missile is a 1969 Dodge Daytona Charger with a 258 cubic inch 1,000 horsepower engine capable of 9,500 revolutions per minute, designed by Joey Arrington of Franklin Country, Virginia;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Tommy Hurley of Ridgeway, Virginia, expertly drove the Martinsville Missile during its record-setting run;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Southside Virginia, including the city of Martinsville and the counties of Henry, Patrick, and Franklin, was historically known for the manufacture and transport of untaxed whiskey and had long been a center of stock car racing;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Virginia American Revolution 250th Commission has been formed to celebrate Virginian’s contributions to the Nation upon the 250th anniversary of the Nation’s independence from the United Kingdom of Great Britain;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Virginia American Revolution 250th Commission is chaired by Virginia Delegate Terry Austin of Botetourt County, Virginia;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the VA250 Car Project is an undertaking of the Virginia Commission and is part of a national motorsports celebration in honor of the United States of America’s 250th year; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Danny Turner, former mayor of Martinsville, Virginia, Joey Arrington of Franklin County, Virginia, and former Congressman Virgil Goode of Rocky Mount, Virginia, devised the VA250 Car Project: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6FA69C983047412CA5154ED0F76DCA3F"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD9CBE2A6E58B4B0491AB88BAED1AE73F"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives extends its congratulations to the VA250 Car Project’s record-setting land speed record for a stock car of 253 miles per hour.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

