<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A7D31D7CB914B2F869DD861220961E7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1030 IH: To end ICE abuse.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1030</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260202">February 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To end ICE abuse.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 7, 2026, a United States citizen, Renée Nicole Good, was shot and killed by an agent of the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (hereinafter referred to as <quote>ICE</quote>) in Minneapolis during an immigration enforcement operation, sparking widespread public concern and protest;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 24, 2026, Alex Jeffrey Pretti, a 37-year-old United States citizen and nurse, was fatally shot by Federal immigration agents in Minneapolis amid enforcement activity, prompting nationwide demands for accountability and independent review;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas multiple news investigations have documented that official narratives surrounding these incidents have frequently conflicted with video and eyewitness accounts, raising serious questions about use of force, transparency, and adherence to constitutional protections;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 3, 2026, the death of ICE detainee Geraldo Lunas Campos at Camp East Montana in Texas was officially classified as a homicide by medical examiners, contradicting prior claims from Federal authorities that the cause was suicide or medical distress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2025 was the deadliest year for individuals in ICE custody in more than 2 decades, with at least 32 reported deaths in detention facilities, according to data compiled by advocacy organizations and confirmed by Federal oversight entities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal law requires all law enforcement agencies to operate in compliance with the Constitution, including the Fourth, Fifth, and Fourteenth Amendments, and to respect due process, equal protection, and the right to life and liberty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sentiments from civic leaders, community members, and legislators reflect distrust in current immigration enforcement practices and emphasize the urgent need for structural accountability and oversight; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has the constitutional authority and responsibility to appropriate funds, conduct oversight, and enact reforms to ensure that Federal agencies act in accordance with the law and the public interest: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H563A5BD5686C4CCD91159DD41F5C59BE"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1E06DDF6E8C0401BB84C5DFEE12C95EE"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives will—</text><paragraph id="HFB48C6B8B9844D15ACB74859E50AB3B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">vote against any new funding for the Department of Homeland Security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H477369BD9B9244A2B7EE52C78881FB5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">repeal the multi-year $75,000,000,000 funding allocation for U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF40C8602A599476DB6FB7A0E454C11CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">initiate impeachment proceedings against Secretary of Homeland Security Kristi Noem, United States Attorney General Pam Bondi, and other responsible officials, for failing to uphold constitutional standards and repeatedly mischaracterizing Federal actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB64B04A3EADF427FA04606C9664E58AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">end qualified immunity for agents of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to ensure meaningful civil accountability for misconduct and unlawful use of force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H149442F9084547E9B5F7A0A5BB61D3CF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct independent Federal and State authorities to investigate and prosecute every agent of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement who has violated the law, with full transparency and public reporting of findings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD51927320AF40848E908396FA622E8B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit all practices tantamount to <quote>Kavanaugh stops</quote>, racial profiling, and the militarization of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement operations through statute and regulation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF87D088CDDC546C8A45A7FCF96356D65"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">codify a clear, uniform, and enforceable national use-of-force standard applicable to immigration enforcement agents, enabling courts to hold rogue actors accountable under existing civil rights laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFE8D3B813E48A596203833D168D4F6"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">replace U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement with a new agency within the Department of Justice that operates with robust civilian oversight, institutional integrity, and full respect for constitutional law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90527D89B4234845B31F4318288DCA7F"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit the use of masks by immigration enforcement officers and require active body cameras and clearly visible identification; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EAD233C9D944263BCD57DB7D97DAA2E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uphold human rights standards for all immigration detention facilities, including independent inspections, guaranteed medical care, mandatory reporting requirements, and enforceable protections against abuse.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

