<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85413A38F26749B0921AFE88687E833C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8877 IH: Improving Self-Sufficiency of Families in HUD-Subsidized Housing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to conduct a study on the implementation of work requirements by public housing agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H82DABFDB817348DDA3ABE80AB7CBED81" style="OLC">
<section id="H383A96CBCCB54C678B3B66B76F121902" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Self-Sufficiency of Families in HUD-Subsidized Housing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H345569777EE5493DB15EE6ABAA4A7014"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving self-sufficiency of families in HUD-subsidized housing</header> <subsection id="H6FDBC7D7E62A476D8A73F92D565A416C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HA2E3AE935E724EF79CAC098ACA85497F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall conduct a study on the implementation of work requirements implemented prior to the date of enactment of this Act by public housing agencies described in paragraph (4) participating in the Moving to Work demonstration authorized under section 204 of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CFA844399B0429997D73EB8017D64BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The study required under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H4AC2FCE48FE04C0C82A5D00EB510DE1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the short-, medium-, and long-term benefits and challenges of work requirements on public housing agencies described in paragraph (4) and on program participants who are subject to such requirements, including the effects work requirements have on homelessness rates, poverty rates, asset building, earnings growth, job attainment and retention, and public housing agencies’ administrative capacity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B4D08E185214FB086CBAE204643E696"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include quantitative and qualitative evidence, including interviews with program participants described in subparagraph (A) and their respective resident councils.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB1AFF8667F945A2A4071FB464AB9D04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the initial findings of the study required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E3A986AB15040D29946578CA93E2B4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public housing agencies described</header><text>The public housing agencies described in this paragraph are public housing agencies that, as part of an application to participate in the demonstration authorized under section 204 of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref> note), submit a proposal identifying work requirements as an innovative proposal.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD5DC6548FD074B14A7E6431DE44FF62A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The requirement under subsection (a) shall apply if the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development determines that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA1A73CFEE0B4CA08CE6E1F8D0BB4699"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there are a sufficient number of public housing agencies described in subsection (a)(4) such that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development can rigorously evaluate the impact of the implementation of work requirements described in that subsection; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA532D027AAA24289B21E3978645413DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the study would not negatively impact low-income families receiving assistance through a public housing agency described in subsection (a)(4).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

