<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT26057-4NH-XN-C11">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3775 IS: Stop Underrides Act 2.0</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 3775</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To reduce the incidence of death by underride by enhancing underride protection on trailers, semitrailers, and single unit trucks, which will result in more survivable truck crashes, to improve motor carrier, passenger motor vehicle, and Vulnerable Road User safety, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H167783F5AF944749A61A40E6B08A007B">
<section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Underrides Act 2.0</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="idf9c19cdaeb974b0e8b8bb81fb188d2c7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header> <subsection id="id42169c8f808b4df3963b4238734b16fd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="ide9cd0ffe9f0d404c88bdcbb3e9ebcd34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>underride crashes involving passenger motor vehicles or Vulnerable Road Users, including motorcyclists, striking and traveling underneath a truck or trailer are a significant public health and safety threat;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idec02d75b82e241fbb217cdaaf2b924e7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Advisory Committee on Underride Protection established under section 23011(d)(1) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30111">49 U.S.C. 30111</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) has reported that, since the formation of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration over 50 years ago, <quote>25,100 underrides and 31,500 corresponding fatalities from side underride, rear underride, and front underride crashes</quote> have occurred and concluded that <quote>no substantial progress has been made by DOT to prevent these horrific crash fatalities and injuries</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idcc8b471fa2574dbbb9b209bb7f35c6f5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the National Transportation Safety Board has recommended the installation of rear underride guards, side underride guards, and front underride guards on tractor-trailers and rear underride guards and side underride guards on single unit trucks to improve Vulnerable Road User and passenger motor vehicle safety; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id40f34c376be3424bbf24270bd18f8bb1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>this Act is introduced in memory of the thousands of victims of underride crashes, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="id8223157da3b44761abb17dce6f0df0ac"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Roya Christine Sadigh, AnnaLeah Karth, Mary Lydia Karth, Sylvia Bingham, Roderick Cota, Moonjohn Kim, Corey Moore, Gregg Williams, Guy Champ Crawford, Carl Hall, Michael Higginbotham, Sandra Maddamma, David Mathis, Mary Katherine Mathis, James Mooney, Christopher Weigl, Bill Zink, David Magnan, Jasen Swift, Samuel Sierra, Brittany McHargue, Christopher Samuel Padilla, Riley Hein, Erin Alexander, Jordan Hensley, Edward Hall, Leslie Rosenberg, Sophie Rosenberg, Ally Davis, Robin Hightman, Alex Wolf, Devyn Killion, Dustin Bosch, Ronald Alleman, Ashley Marie (Walker) Ramirez, Minh-Thi Nguyen, Melissa <quote>Missy</quote> De Leon, Mark Roderick, Karen Bucklew, and Tommy Yaqub;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idda24811c091849089403601e1156f832"><enum>(B)</enum><text>those whose catastrophic injuries dramatically changed their lives, including Julie Magnan, Nancy Meuleners, Joshua Rojas, Maiv Yang, Anita Plantage Bomgaars, Michael B. Hawkins, Roosevelt Smith, and Robert Eshbaugh; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id0360e0b19ee2412d810cceb79c26060d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>those whose precious lives were cut far too short as a result of preventable underride crashes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id2777bbe6e36c4c82aa8e6b0cd678be95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text>
<paragraph id="id6ea506f715b2424d88abaa1df6f5ea65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce the number of preventable deaths and injuries caused by underride crashes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9f93037e34e4e08996966baa2b201f1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure the efficacy of comprehensive underride protection systems on roads in the United States; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id820b9e7719284296814520e0247b0b57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to improve Vulnerable Road User, motor carrier, and passenger motor vehicle safety.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="id284edba506524ec9bd332378bfb940b9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb75202109a04b9991632b476e5eaaa1"><enum/><text>In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id743a7e40919b46f9b5c757e42521c5f0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial motor vehicle</header><text>The term <term>commercial motor vehicle</term> has the meaning given the term in section 31132 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefd86604937b49e786ba2502f598f182"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comprehensive underride protection system</header><text>The term <term>comprehensive underride protection system</term> means all of the front underride guards, rear underride guards, or side underride guards, as applicable, installed on a commercial motor vehicle.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id8ca837cb890e42c799e6d658b57c102f" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Front underride guard</header><text>The term <term>front underride guard</term> means a device installed on or near the front of a commercial motor vehicle that prevents or limits the distance that a vehicle struck by the commercial motor vehicle with the device will slide under the front of the striking commercial motor vehicle.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4cb148e850849b8aacd6939d9c721f4"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rear underride guard</header><text>The term <term>rear underride guard</term> has the meaning given the term <term>rear impact guard</term> in section 571.223 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a6b73c1f38947c0a1d1bfa61ef03efc"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Title 49 terms</header><text>The terms <term>passenger motor vehicle</term>, <term>semitrailer</term>, <term>side underride guard</term>, <term>single unit truck</term>, <term>trailer</term>, and <term>Vulnerable Road User</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="id93f362df7176497ba4ec5fa12f483445"><enum>4.</enum><header>Amendments to title 49 definitions</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc74dad002e54ea988ef110defa695ab"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="id31f0f021334449108734623ca4e44d0d"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>by redesignating paragraphs (11), (12), and (13) as paragraphs (12), (17), and (19), respectively;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id1a616968ce0e4a7ea6862f8c4a7473d4"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by inserting after paragraph (10) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde8cf3bb6202464f89f379ba7a45eaea"> 
<paragraph id="id66b8578a01504532b70f2fabaae5fca2"> <enum>(11)</enum> <text><term>passenger motor vehicle</term> has the meaning given the term in section 32101.</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id1218da8fbae343298fc13d30e7e08a1c"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>by inserting after paragraph (12) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd328b0a7a84342478fec093a40aa77f7"> 
<paragraph id="idca5f5659c2b44a61a8fea164e08a920c"> <enum>(13)</enum> <text><term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id504f10de5b4b4d32955ad46e82a5681b"> <enum>(14)</enum> <text><term>semitrailer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 571.3(b) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idb04e545250294807aaa09a7c1bb821e4"> <enum>(15)</enum> <text><term>side underride guard</term> means a device installed on or near the side of a trailer, semitrailer, or single unit truck that prevents or limits—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b23924f8d33464a8a8a27ebb828722e"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the distance that the front end of a vehicle striking the side of the trailer, semitrailer, or single unit truck with the device will slide under the side of the impacted trailer, semitrailer, or single unit truck; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61d83fc627bd4e09a1458ed319ed6ffc"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevents Vulnerable Road Users from sliding under the trailer, semitrailer, or single unit truck with the device.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id06e495914bb54593a3a79803f4c30b83"> <enum>(16)</enum> <text><term>single unit truck</term> means a large commercial truck (excluding any attached trailer).</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idc536d6ca98d7427991e6b3f607cf2c84"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>by inserting after paragraph (17) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3abcb4d48cac4e9598a3577f7960a349"> <paragraph id="id55b57014cd764deb87e7fcefd950c7e8"> <enum>(18)</enum> <text><term>trailer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 571.3(b) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c77074f029d476a9627a2893e785a72"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>by inserting after paragraph (19) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0bd8c28640c446a99c59357b74f38a36"> <paragraph id="id92057478a6b94eaa88a8791ffec6d9be"> <enum>(20)</enum> <text><term>Vulnerable Road User</term> has the meaning given the term <term>vulnerable road user</term> in section 148(a) of title 23.</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32f4833ed44e4e3cb91594b70e8c1369"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Technical amendments</header> <text>Section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code (as amended by subsection (a)), is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e3902420ac84b4b90189942082721aa"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in each of paragraphs (1) through (18), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id272fa92e380d4c918abdcb5c23555e7d"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in paragraph (19), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>.</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d2e4cc3bc274fcaa03098dcf4b395a8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Underride guard rulemaking</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0feb9d1b7aa54c3eab71a79e64ca870b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE77C944C7A3D4385B5D8866403822DAF">
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcceb556703043be98629c43f5b5e991"><enum>30130.</enum><header>Side underride guards for trailers, semitrailers, and single unit trucks</header>
<subsection id="ida2d8c3fc3c2b40a39efb3d8f32fa43c3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id539c27493e094dd5934ed24bbc061a2e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall finalize regulations that prescribe new or updated motor vehicle safety standards that meet the performance standard described in paragraph (2), including by requiring the installation of side underride guards that meet that performance standard on new trailers, semitrailers, and single unit trucks.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16eefe1143b24c89ab4e7e869e25aab3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Performance standard described</header><text>The performance standard referred to in paragraphs (1) and (3)(B)(i) is that side underride guards shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="id90be7535d90c45839abf70b5601cd600"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent intrusion into the occupant survival space of a passenger motor vehicle when the passenger motor vehicle is struck, or strikes, perpendicular to a trailer, semitrailer, or single unit truck at any closing speed up to and including 40 miles per hour;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idfeb4431a815a455685ea2716c74462ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impede a Vulnerable Road User from passing underneath a trailer, semitrailer, or single unit truck in an interaction along the side of the trailer, semitrailer, or single unit truck; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id988f89e659de433f81eed1ae7352e1ff"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contribute to fuel efficiency through the integration of aerodynamic design or components furthering fuel efficiency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaad610191ab94376855b328a1b3c2a6f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost-benefit analyses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In finalizing regulations under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider and calculate in any cost-benefit analysis—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d14f1370c3a4426a2d8810da54a03e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of deaths and injuries among passenger motor vehicle occupants and Vulnerable Road Users prevented as a result of those regulations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49c2bd2500b2465a8d9a9f9cc4fafac0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>net fuel savings, which shall be equal to the difference between—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fea464a0e954beca37c2c2b2bc84706"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of fuel expected to be consumed by applicable motor vehicles as a result of the adoption of the performance standard described in paragraph (2); and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida76c90455ed94b338d246f296fb52af3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of fuel estimated to be consumed by applicable motor vehicles at the existing rate of voluntary adoption of aerodynamic side skirts without side underride guards as of the date on which those regulations are finalized.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="ide254cf26c80048dc95a999b5a899c6ac"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>The regulations finalized under subsection (a) shall require full compliance with the new or updated motor vehicle safety standards prescribed under that subsection not later than 2 years after the date on which those regulations are finalized.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id27e13ca64eaa427ea22d0ffefb488f42"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of regulations</header><text>Beginning not later than 5 years after the date on which regulations are finalized under subsection (a), and not less frequently than once every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall determine whether any update to the motor vehicle safety standards prescribed under that subsection is necessary to better prevent fatalities caused by underride crashes and improve roadway safety.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="id7e48e4ac4a5c4ebf97253ae3bc75be15" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>If the Secretary of Transportation withdraws the advanced notice of proposed rulemaking of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration entitled <quote>Side Underride Guards</quote> (88 Fed. Reg. 24535 (April 21, 2023)) before the Secretary of Transportation finalizes regulations in accordance with section 30130(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), that withdrawal shall not affect the requirement to finalize regulations in accordance with that section.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42cd101a45be4336946a7727bd2c15b6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide085b7d02b3a4d3bbd3165f2742e81f9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the item relating to section 30128 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8BE54CE2921F4A0AA2D1E5D550F794C0"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">30128. Vehicle rollover prevention and crash mitigation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idece2c576afc44252b24ad960308bebe8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 30129 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE1FB3E51A03144B182360A2965C3530B">
<toc>
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">30130. Side underride guards for trailers, semitrailers, and single unit trucks.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e06b04b250942f1bf5b08d18bc51a8b"><enum>6.</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Underride Protection</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id591d5e775be84106ba9355dd7435c2d7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reconvening of advisory committee</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall reconvene the Advisory Committee on Underride Protection established under subsection (d)(1) of section 23011 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30111">49 U.S.C. 30111</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) in accordance with the requirements of that section.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf444874835b492caca0c342ac95ec30"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23011(d) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30111">49 U.S.C. 30111</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66cee1b4ee9a4ecfbb71beceb9bafa7f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id041c758127084c7894c552781deb202a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>20</quote> and inserting <quote>22</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1c7f1f334cc415fb1be622395b07205"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59694f95cab74251b2760076cef2813c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking clause (ix);</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe14f451494740aab8d3a60a32fa3229"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (x) as clause (ix); and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb489381e5325412391fc79ffd8998eb4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB9B2BFCCB91D4FC59796A2A00D8DA65F">
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60b701d7ded241289a67d26ce06ebc29"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Families of underride crash victims who were occupants of a passenger motor vehicle.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idabd45fc977254a30a39d309b70be364b"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Families of underride crash victims who were Vulnerable Road Users (as defined in section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6fb7b1953bc42d9a4960998481ff2fa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>meet not less frequently than annually</quote> and inserting the following: “meet—</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0938a5d07e0f4f69abc3e107f9e0fcef"> <subparagraph id="id2518cc7ecdb64fcba70ae365fd3e221f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>until final regulations have been promulgated under section 30130(a) of title 49, United States Code—</text>
<clause id="idc8b6bfcb4736458b96132fc121d549d2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>monthly, via conference call or a virtual meeting platform; and</text></clause> <clause id="id13c5cd21e3304fc08b21a66a8c77b0ae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>annually, in person, at the Department of Transportation headquarters; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id3b6a8543204d4c9ba2418fa9e8fa1ce1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsequent to the issuance of the final regulations described in subparagraph (A), not less frequently than annually, in person, at the Department of Transportation headquarters, to assess the status of underride crash protection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id589cef74a9844770a6e6faf2e77be57d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>including deliberative materials,</quote> after <quote>information,</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e01ecd553e94b5ba6b63df20c9a8b33"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>a biennial</quote> and inserting <quote>an annual</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1439c025222d4e95a5c16cd36b07ce1e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53D01F001F3649C1B87DA77A814C6E84">
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4c08a36ecf1425caa3893b292403491"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, the Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2031.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="ide173356c9a8b4d4c8fe0ba9d61063067"><enum>7.</enum><header>Publication of underride research, reports, and recommendations</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56d9a48b4e8c41509485872f4f3a17a7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall publish a publicly accessible website to provide the industry, researchers, advocates, and the public with a repository of underride resources, including—</text>
<paragraph id="id3485d69bf7654f0db9d458a8799348c6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>research conducted or contracted by the Department of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <term>Department</term>) on rear underride guards or other rear impact guards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id7a390dabe2fe45bcb22575c1d67597e2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>research conducted or contracted by the Department on side underride guards or other side impact guards;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id029ee5ca23894171998a0ff5ccccc468"><enum>(3)</enum><text>research conducted or contracted by the Department on front underride guards or other front impact guards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id8e079d1b7a814190ab8ead0e818642c4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a link to the database for the Advisory Committee on Underride Protection established under section 23011(d)(1) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30111">49 U.S.C. 30111</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), which shall be updated in a timely manner;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id981f3c932d744243afcb383d6c9d0e28"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information and links relating to all underride rulemakings of the Department;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id734daa05e71947a58bf29cc745406250"><enum>(6)</enum><text>stories of victims of underride crashes; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idc10a4fe0db754d66a246d83b18a3b444"><enum>(7)</enum><text>documentation of past and ongoing data collection relating to underride crashes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idd2038fbb293049b782e287bae451bb10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary shall update the resources described in subsection (a) not less frequently than quarterly.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="idf66371ac59c34cb880f9eea1975041b0"><enum>8.</enum><header>NASEM and GAO studies</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida83b623c5a264398970286188df7f11b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>NASEM study</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6d03fcbf39f497aa6524e315c6f732b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (referred to in this subsection as the <term>National Academies</term>) under which the National Academies shall conduct a study on the prevalence of crashes involving the front of large trucks, including the threat of those crashes on Vulnerable Road Users.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide26373f9d3ae48e6b31ba6bf74c7258d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the National Academies completes the study required under paragraph (1), the National Academies shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study, which shall include—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ba0d08f90fb42328e5794101e57f83a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations on—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c0d0d306a764d039a435a8b8e62e412"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to better prevent crashes where the front of large trucks contacts a passenger motor vehicle in a manner that causes the passenger motor vehicle to slide under the large truck; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1bb22e80932e4e7cbb74cb4da5c36455"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to prevent deaths resulting from those crashes;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c05a16a7aa7437e8355705b25622bcf"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the efficacy of preventative or protective devices on commercial motor vehicles, such as front override guards, in preventing deaths resulting from those crashes; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id334ac9b543ab4599854250553f281249"><enum>(C)</enum><text>statistics, since 2010, describing the prevalence of fatal and non-fatal crashes described in subparagraph (A)(i), including rear underride and side underride crashes, which shall include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2039a32b268c425892cb739078f896b4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type, make, and model of vehicles involved in those crashes;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6a2f7c1d80e4b39a1382ae55ac6dd59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the types of roads on which those crashes have occurred; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92f4bf240031464d8302b01980e911d3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of fatalities that occurred as a result of those crashes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84f8f7f3b23c4988be049b3ac9924428"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a8d4731e5bf405189150197aeb3298e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Comptroller General</term>) shall conduct a study on the implementation of the final rule of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration entitled <quote>Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards; Rear Impact Guards, Rear Impact Protection</quote> (87 Fed. Reg. 42339 (July 15, 2022)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4af5b5ab525e4cd6baf21b7d1ca0010a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Comptroller General completes the study required under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall submit to the Secretary of Transportation and Congress a report on the results of the study, which shall include—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0e3eeb8ef614465b1073683666f6f66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the implementation of the final rule described in that paragraph;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id0759a4ea6a4c427f9e64140ed7feb0cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if applicable, recommendations to the Department of Transportation describing improvements to that final rule or its implementation; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3e760feb977416ea68d8d96693ae008"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations to Congress and the Department of Transportation on how to better prevent underrides in crashes occurring at the rear of trailers, semitrailers, and single unit trucks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="ide3b3d99d1f4d4cbab693276e119881ad"><enum>9.</enum><header>FARS review; web-based training for State and local law enforcement</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11eed8c18f86433a8e1f02b15c3b550b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">FARS review</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (referred to in this section as the <term>Administrator</term>) shall conduct a review of the Fatality Analysis Reporting System of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to determine—</text>
<paragraph id="iddc826b0ee2874edd82394f3ec8c227e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of fatalities in crashes reported as an underride crash by State or local law enforcement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ide6bcbb37dcb6440e8166ae1c2681e917"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of fatalities in crashes that were not reported as an underride crash by State or local law enforcement but should have been reported as an underride crash, as determined by the Administrator after reviewing, with respect to each such crash—</text>
<subparagraph id="id1df47893ac454909a5bf8aebba904fda"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the initial point of impact of the crash, if the crash is a fatal crash involving a large truck;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id55d0b121cdfc47128636b98e37c42fc5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Crash Investigation Sampling System of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id0b4b59f3dec448a7a936ac7eca9cfc18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>open-source media reports with documented photo evidence of an underride occurrence; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id04bc117a18134fc9b2280a83370e1cd5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other data and documentation, as determined appropriate by the Administrator; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idb0dfadd144c44aa588c1b185d4ae6a2d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations that would improve incident reporting by State and local law enforcement.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce57708174bf4f60b325b3d371cced0a"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Web-Based training</header> <text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop free on-demand, web-based training for State and local law enforcement on how to properly identify and document underride crashes.</text> </subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


