<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT26410-KF1-V8-78R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4936 IS: Standards To Prevent Frontovers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4936</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate a Federal motor vehicle safety standard to reduce the incidence of injury and death occurring to children and others, including vulnerable road users and pets, during low-speed incidents involving motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Standards To Prevent Frontovers Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP Frontovers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idAC7E9B1654A741718030FD00B369EF9D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id248BD6C3EB894731964D840A69992B19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Backover</header><text>The term <term>backover</term> means a low-speed incident where a non-occupant of a motor vehicle is struck by the motor vehicle moving in reverse.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14b8779a141146abbe1ff35d917ea115"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frontover</header><text>The term <term>frontover</term> means a low-speed incident where a non-occupant of a motor vehicle is struck by the motor vehicle moving forward in an area that the driver of the motor vehicle cannot see.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c28b4e139b84ea5bc305c823a073aff"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motor vehicle</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle</term> has the meaning given the term in section 30102(a) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11A2A2FC214346C092B57D32517A487D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id12F3119A439443988FB71EAEF764BA29"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rulemaking to minimize safety risks</header><subsection id="id9b604ee0f4cc4fc4b1a95e05055607fa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall initiate a rulemaking to promulgate a Federal motor vehicle safety standard under section 30111 of title 49, United States Code, establishing performance requirements that reduce death and injury resulting from frontovers and other low-speed incidents.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5112e56494c744fc809d95de48f95dbe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements and considerations</header><text>The performance requirements of the motor vehicle safety standard described in subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd15fa3f6c37483091b2a9df65f1a20b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minimize safety risks of frontovers and other low-speed incidents;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id499361a95e5148e0b94af691cff6b31d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a direct visibility standard; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5295b9e8f024fbb9b22f920dcd81f30"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f0deb8b0cae41779af22a54863541cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at a minimum, the detection of, in the field of direct vision of the driver and blind zones of the motor vehicle and any crash avoidance system—</text><clause id="id974704b11cd54397b1af5c7330ae1328"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a motor vehicle;</text></clause><clause id="id0f5c811a7b7a4298b64e79ca063d52d3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a pedestrian, including toddlers and small children;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida13aff5a4c2f4982b3363aa280679821"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a bicyclist;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e422eae614a4ce1bdd2b9a5ad24ed91"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a vulnerable road user (as defined in section 148(a) of title 23, United States Code);</text></clause><clause id="id8cd43c1aa1d54521ad2b54dc9f9b5e68"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a wheelchair or assistive device user;</text></clause><clause id="id61b832a9bd9c48c09a48567d5d7425e3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a micromobility or motorcycle rider; and</text></clause><clause id="idca499014368f47aeadd922d4bc4b11ca"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other individual, equipment, vehicle, or animal, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2ae5f1a083242d5bb76f42972a60101"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a driver notification system that enables the driver of the motor vehicle to effectively respond to objects described in clauses (i) through (vii) of subparagraph (A) to prevent and reduce the severity of frontovers and other low-speed incidents;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc165e31dd8434007be032e6567dfae0a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an active intervention system that enables the motor vehicle to effectively respond to objects described in clauses (i) through (vii) of subparagraph (A) to prevent and reduce the severity of frontovers and other low-speed incidents; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida24107df0edc45f6a2added320f5df05"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a distinct auditory and visual alert, which may be combined with a haptic alert, any time the driver notification system described in subparagraph (B) or the active intervention system described in subparagraph (C) engages in a way that warrants a driver or motor vehicle response.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf2df35c747044a6a85122ed636ffa697"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timeline</header><paragraph id="id4f58f26e5ed540589fe0b804f5b88235"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the rulemaking is initiated under subsection (a), the Secretary shall promulgate the final motor vehicle safety standard described in that subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb12047d63b04fd985ae5f704c66f8c4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Full compliance</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the final motor vehicle safety standard is promulgated under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall require full compliance with that final motor vehicle safety standard.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13092612a5624a8dbcf50434de77908e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Phase-in period</header><subparagraph id="id2012A8D294E846E09E3C903B7E9746D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may establish a phase-in period for compliance with the motor vehicle safety standard promulgated under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd74c363973794c8e955af83b4ca452f1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A phase-in period established under subparagraph (A) shall only be for a period of time that allows for full compliance with the motor vehicle safety standard in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ABC8D9BA4754081AA6324115CB7968A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Phase-in priorities</header><clause id="id85A3A2C61D964E00AD7D57BCF2632993"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In establishing a phase-in period under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider whether to require the phase-in according to different types of motor vehicles based on data demonstrating the frequency by which various types of motor vehicles have been involved in frontovers and other low-speed incidents resulting in injury or death.</text></clause><clause id="id8DF62314A0AE425DBA791EDE01757CC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>If the Secretary determines under clause (i) that any type of motor vehicle should be given priority for the phase-in period established under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall promulgate regulations that specify—</text><subclause id="id81cfe8a3bce94d87ad0eb33511417cb1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the 1 or more types of motor vehicles that shall be phased-in first; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id755f54f8fc4141179ca2bd02540c6e48"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentages by which those motor vehicles shall be phased-in.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8EA22085056C4187A364A51E135954DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, if the final motor vehicle safety standard described in subsection (a) has not been promulgated in accordance with the requirements of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report, which shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9dc878ade89e4ce0a57a9ed8a1e23a6e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a timeline on promulgating that motor vehicle safety standard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAD03288C85BD49FCAB4400A4DB2565B0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reasons for the delay in promulgating that motor vehicle safety standard; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA7944F98DFA544B9BF1DFE47F494EA82" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the steps being taken by the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="idEDCC848DA9F0473E920A9E5405E863DD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address those reasons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1DCB1DFDE2B94F62BBC77241E59AAD09" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to meet the timeline described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c4afd01a0ba4402af3e391bf00af729"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 30129 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idaed498b0db534d67b7288e825818480d" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="USC"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8555ceb425ae4de8b496095fffebb764"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue a final rule—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ec1fffcdbf648ff989ae84902bc5af8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a compliance date under subsection (b) that is not later than the date that is 2 years after that date of enactment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id584e2461ce904fe2b30957cb6ed8254a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requiring all passenger motor vehicles manufactured for sale in the United States on or after that compliance date to be equipped with the crash avoidance technologies described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="idf4031c30b44146ad90cb6a9b2e039272"><enum>4.</enum><header>Updates to the Non-Traffic Surveillance system</header><subsection commented="no" id="id69657CD55BCF4F019F42EF47FE258E29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall include an element for a frontover and an element for a backover in the data maintained, and the summary reports published from that data, under the Non-Traffic Surveillance (NTS) System of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="idF5CF39800EF84E36850AAB6C5FEFD1F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other reporting considerations</header><text>In addition to the requirement under subsection (a), the Secretary may consider other mechanisms to help inform reporting relating to frontovers and backovers, including changes to State crash report data requirements or other reporting systems.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id863f77d1c0e6475a8a955532e2e3092a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall notify Congress on completion of the requirement under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

