<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HB07DA264233D4B25857A39531697B8FC" resolution-type="house-resolution" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1226 IH: Original Resolution Condemning President Donald J. Trump for his disgraceful, despicable, and disrespectful social media post depicting himself as Jesus Christ, diminishing the dignity of the Presidency and bringing disrepute to the office</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1226</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Condemning President Donald J. Trump for his disgraceful, despicable, and disrespectful social media post depicting himself as Jesus Christ, diminishing the dignity of the Presidency and bringing disrepute to the office.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="H8F5FC3E0683647F0B8F0CADFEFE198AA" display-resolving-clause="no-display-resolving-clause"> 
<section id="HFF6105CE47CB4ED3B19F95835AC658C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Original Resolution Condemning President Donald J. Trump for his disgraceful, despicable, and disrespectful social media post depicting himself as Jesus Christ, diminishing the dignity of the Presidency and bringing disrepute to the office</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4BF972369C86462797130BEE5E4907A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The House of Representatives finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA472106DA41419C9DA1C8ADA5F58A06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On Sunday, April 12, 2026, Donald J. Trump, President of the United States of America, posted an image generated by artificial intelligence (AI) portraying himself as Jesus Christ.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H139299A6AC914F9B951D6B3432C56948"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The image depicts Donald J. Trump, President of the United States of America, in a white robe, placing his hand, with light radiating from it, upon an individual in a manner consistent with traditional artistic portrayals of Jesus Christ performing acts of healing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30E549BAA52D4F229B2D4B8175EC9768"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The image further incorporates lighting effects, including a luminous glow surrounding the figure, along with figures floating in the background and a woman appearing to pray before him, all of which are elements historically used in religious art to signify divinity, holiness, and sacred authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H988157EC13AB467B97FC14C3D2F484FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Public commentary from religious leaders, political figures, and members of the public overwhelmingly described the image as portraying President Trump as Jesus Christ or as a <quote>Christ-like figure</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4672F4E9E8C440D5A857B03BC432EC5D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Jesus Christ is the central and sacred figure in Christianity, revered by billions of people around the world as the foundational figure of Christianity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A455E5104AC49F69DF16FA41404E275"><enum>(6)</enum><text>All who hold public trust, especially those who hold the Nation’s highest office, bear a heightened responsibility to uphold respect for the diverse religious beliefs of the American people.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EFC3D58F5F7463DAD559AA7AC471FDC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that acts by the President of the United States of America that trivialize or exploit any religious symbolism for personal or political purposes are inconsistent with the spirit of mutual respect and dignity that underpins a pluralistic society.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4373968BB954D9FBFB7C1470A1DADB9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that respect for religions by the President is essential to maintaining unity and mutual understanding among people of all faiths and backgrounds in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F751835DC2845AF8D0B168A68E05AD5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that the use of religious imagery by the President for self-promotion or personal glorification undermines the sacred nature of such symbols and can be deeply offensive to people of faith.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE7C5E9DDA9343E693A2A753031B2367"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that the abuse of religious imagery by the President in a manner that may be perceived as irreverent or blasphemous risks fostering division and disrespect among communities of faith.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD77E2E52D722471F862B376C337BC71A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that this conduct by the President of the United States diminishes the dignity of the office, brings disrepute to the Presidency, and undermines the respect the Presidential office is intended to command both domestically and internationally.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD97B54DFC06449938518552A57798C0A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that such conduct by the President of the United States sends the wrong message about the values the United States stands for.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD53B8842456D4FE0B2BE7B4BDE0CFFEF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that the use of religious imagery in what is widely perceived as a self-aggrandizing context by the President risks damaging the image and integrity of the Presidency, which should reflect seriousness and respect for the diverse beliefs of the American people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A7115FD58D74D31B2564E8E9C13D990"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that, by portraying himself as Jesus Christ, he would be perceived as not only trivializing the most sacred figure in Christianity but also making a mockery of the faith, thereby inviting ridicule that diminishes the standing of the United States and its people on the world stage.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA026914F1CA4379B8D08F03AE4E01D5"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The President of the United States of America knew or should have known that the Presidency is an office intended to embody the highest standards of respect, integrity, and seriousness, and conduct such as this undermines those essential qualities and erodes the respect the office is meant to command.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="a1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Condemnation</header></section> </resolution-body> <resolution-body> <section section-type="undesignated-section" id="a2"><text>That the House of Representatives condemns President Donald J. Trump for his disgraceful, despicable, and disrespectful “Truth Social” post depicting himself as Jesus Christ on April 12, 2026, diminishing the dignity of the Presidency and bringing disrepute to the office.</text></section> 
<section section-type="undesignated-section" id="a3"><text>That Donald J. Trump, President of the United States of America, should state publicly that his depicting himself as Jesus Christ was disrespectful and offensive.</text></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

