<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H27C4F8E6B34742A1ABE0A70E50F28883" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 138 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the second Saturday of January as “National Desert Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 138</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108">January 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the second Saturday of January as <quote>National Desert Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas a desert is defined as an arid land with usually sparse vegetation, especially such land having a very warm climate and receiving less than 25 centimeters (10 inches) of sporadic rainfall annually;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas there are 4 major deserts in the United States, which are the Mojave Desert, the Sonoran Desert, the Chihuahuan Desert, and the Great Basin Desert;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is growing concern in the United States and globally for environmental protection and the threats to desert habitats and conservation initiatives;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all living things are intertwined by sharing ecosystems, and desert ecosystems contain biodiversity that only exist in deserts and rely on sustainable practices; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas deserts are among of the most significant ecosystems in the country due to their unique biodiversity, ecological functions, and cultural importance: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCCC3BE1E1DC0406CBBC57EA22A37EB01"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H326003F7059541FBBE9DA373A6FA2576"><enum/><text>That Congress—</text><paragraph id="H93083628B99E490CA0D942A0BA75B3EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Desert Day</quote> and requests the President to issue a proclamation calling upon the people of the United States to observe such day with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17405854005241F7A750064EF899035D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges that deserts are a crucial stop for migrating birds to spend the winter and are part of supporting global biodiversity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF1FDAB53594F6C8C69F4254B919522"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms its advocacy for native landscapes by committing to reduce invasive plant species and continue to maintain a pollinator garden;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B9C4046601D4B7ABB829B2B9297277C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the ongoing efforts by the United States to educate citizens on their role in conserving desert biodiversity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA50E9BDF017B4D24A3A5318987B7A3AE" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the pursuit of policies that ensure the protection and preservation of the world’s deserts.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

