<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0BC8CFD0AB98427FB6EDB633F0D153BD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9589 IH: Declaration of Independence Reaffirmation Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9589</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260702">July 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000139">Mr. Van Epps</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001099">Mr. Haridopolos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reaffirm the Declaration of Independence as an Organic Law of the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26810DA5DE824991B4C5F0B11E4DE94E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9015FF53431F432685E542B85F3E02A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Declaration of Independence Reaffirmation Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCB51B538CABB47E3BBE978B966AAABF7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HF93FBA69292E41C28A806DBCCE883F47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On July 4, 1776, the Continental Congress adopted the Declaration of Independence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF988653939EA40D8B057EE3AE1FFECDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Declaration of Independence announced that the United States of America were free and independent States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE7A04626276B4FDFB9F0654C79C1C9CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Declaration of Independence declares that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights, and that governments derive their just powers from the consent of the governed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F3B0FD9EE1D42ABBED3D8AF91FD55B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Declaration of Independence is recognized among the Organic Laws of the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C68BF2739D64969B9B0D376E301981A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Northwest Ordinance was adopted by the Congress of the Confederation in 1787, and was thereafter reenacted by the First Congress in 1789, so that it could continue to have full effect under the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE5DCA5D8C6F44C8832B1A2F1463B15E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Congress has authority to recognize, reaffirm, and carry forward the foundational laws and principles of the American political order.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0173EDF411FC4A0290BC273D6E578B9D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The 250th anniversary of American independence calls upon Congress to reaffirm the Declaration of Independence as the charter of American sovereignty, natural rights, equal citizenship, and government by consent.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CE159ABC2A74C90A1EC93060155E95E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Constitution of the United States gives lawful form and enduring structure to the principles of republican self-government announced in the Declaration of Independence.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H78936CBA2BB348108D35B57BFF7D0C4D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Declaration of Independence and the Constitution of the United States together establish a political order in which the people are sovereign and public officers are their servants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FA75FB1FE5D4333ADCE0BD910F5A7AF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Declaration of Independence presupposes that Americans are <quote>one people</quote> with the right to govern themselves as a distinct political community, to preserve their national independence, and to secure the rights and liberties of their own citizens.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H1814E940884541ACAEDAE5E9E5F6DA1E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reaffirmation of the Declaration of Independence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress reaffirms and re-adopts the Declaration of Independence as an Organic Law of the United States and as the enduring charter of American independence, national sovereignty, natural rights, equal citizenship, and government by consent.</text></section> <section id="H2ACC504118134EAA9EE256B935431639"><enum>4.</enum><header>Text of the Declaration of Independence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In commemoration of the 250th anniversary of American independence, Congress sets forth the text of the Declaration of Independence as follows:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02E4D35FAF544AC0832FAE1267D899E8">
<subsection id="HB741438123C943259C59CC2F6A1A18E3"><enum/><text>The unanimous Declaration of the thirteen united States of America,</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4DBBAD7CB674E30A4E72858A5F541A2"><enum/><text>When in the Course of human events, it becomes necessary for one people to dissolve the political bands which have connected them with another, and to assume among the Powers of the earth, the separate and equal station to which the Laws of Nature and of Nature’s God entitle them, a decent respect to the opinions of mankind requires that they should declare the causes which impel them to the separation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD2D736E98D08448386027B49BAF4A568"><enum/><text>We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed, by their Creator, with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty, and the pursuit of Happiness.—That to secure these rights, Governments are instituted among Men, deriving their just powers from the consent of the governed,—That whenever any Form of Government becomes destructive of these ends, it is the Right of the People to alter or abolish it, and to institute new Government, laying its foundation on such principles, and organizing its powers in such form, as to them shall seem most likely to effect their Safety and Happiness. Prudence, indeed, will dictate that Governments long established should not be changed for light and transient causes; and, accordingly, all experience hath shewn, that mankind are more disposed to suffer, while evils are sufferable, than to right themselves, by abolishing the forms to which they are accustomed. But when a long train of abuses and usurpations, pursuing invariably the same Object, evinces a design to reduce them under absolute Despotism, it is their right, it is their duty, to throw off such Government, and to provide new Guards for their future security.—Such has been the patient sufferance of these Colonies; and such is now the necessity which constrains them to alter their former Systems of Government. The history of the present King of Great Britain is a history of repeated injuries and usurpations, all having, in direct object, the establishment of an absolute Tyranny over these States. To prove this, let Facts be submitted to a candid world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED0BAD4AB5324B5797F0504D12E07E85"><enum/><text>He has refused his Assent to Laws, the most wholesome and necessary for the public good.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24F7107F77BC4A25A2A9678F8F247804"><enum/><text>He has forbidden his Governors to pass Laws of immediate and pressing importance, unless suspended in their operation till his Assent should be obtained; and, when so suspended, he has utterly neglected to attend to them.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6FD572C2C69489CAD9646925FDDFB17"><enum/><text>He has refused to pass other Laws for the accommodation of large districts of people, unless those people would relinquish the Right of Representation in the Legislature; a right inestimable to them, and formidable to tyrants only.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H13AD2B57B8B047EA89815C668CF70CBE"><enum/><text>He has called together legislative bodies at places unusual, uncomfortable, and distant from the depository of their Public Records, for the sole purpose of fatiguing them into compliance with his measures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BC5DECE2E3E441C8A81390FF32166AF"><enum/><text>He has dissolved Representative Houses repeatedly, for opposing with manly firmness his invasions on the rights of the people.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0914AC2DB3C4436282B4F777210881B9"><enum/><text>He has refused for a long time, after such dissolutions, to cause others to be elected; whereby the Legislative Powers, incapable of Annihilation, have returned to the People at large for their exercise; the State remaining, in the meantime, exposed to all the dangers of invasion from without, and convulsions within.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96C1D0FF15A34B8CA89936025F359447"><enum/><text>He has endeavoured to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose, obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither, and raising the conditions of new Appropriations of Lands.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC78DD89135FE4B6BAAA868AF17ABD01E"><enum/><text>He has obstructed the Administration of Justice, by refusing his Assent to Laws for establishing Judiciary Powers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC39E8B9C88C04942A405ADAF5BA4FAA5"><enum/><text>He has made Judges dependent on his Will alone, for the tenure of their offices, and the amount and payment of their salaries.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F872DB92AF34B30B576E7DED79E0515"><enum/><text>He has erected a multitude of New Offices, and sent hither swarms of Officers to harass our People, and eat out their substance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37B39A78084F48A6B54BE14E08F3B817"><enum/><text>He has kept among us, in times of peace, Standing Armies, without the Consent of our legislatures.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1F61D7129DBE487FBC4477F81EC06FDD"><enum/><text>He has affected to render the Military independent of and superior to the Civil Power.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA629464C8F594CCBBB15B8B045E7142E"><enum/><text>He has combined with others to subject us to a jurisdiction foreign to our Constitution and unacknowledged by our Laws; giving his Assent to their Acts of pretended Legislation:</text>
<subparagraph id="H48CEA9317C5F42989FF1AEEFF84046DE"><enum/><text>For quartering large bodies of armed troops among us:</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8E6465C52EB42D683E1F5693ECCFFCA"><enum/><text>For protecting them, by a mock Trial, from punishment for any Murders which they should commit on the Inhabitants of these States:</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB46BF94806EF49D0B880521C6899C5DE"><enum/><text>For cutting off our Trade with all parts of the world:</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FB64B27B9A944E481D106B3C09D6583"><enum/><text>For imposing Taxes on us without our Consent:</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC67B0C340489476694ECB2692CC0650B"><enum/><text>For depriving us, in many cases, of the benefits of Trial by Jury:</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8C886176D0A497F86DB1E68E304320F"><enum/><text>For transporting us beyond Seas to be tried for pretended offences:</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9F92035B08E443E595F32D6A580B2EE9"><enum/><text>For abolishing the free System of English Laws in a neighbouring Province, establishing therein an Arbitrary government, and enlarging its Boundaries, so as to render it at once an example and fit instrument for introducing the same absolute rule into these Colonies:</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H999E98E6AD8A4A1E84FDC2EED27FE8E2"><enum/><text>For taking away our Charters, abolishing our most valuable Laws, and altering fundamentally the Forms of our Governments:</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC8ACE338E97340BAB3CA1C2B9DF45B98"><enum/><text>For suspending our own Legislatures, and declaring themselves invested with power to legislate for us in all cases whatsoever.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51B9789040F840068773EA3E6461AD12"><enum/><text>He has abdicated Government here, by declaring us out of his Protection and waging War against us.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3889140D12A4AB9AB1AD0DDF9E130B5"><enum/><text>He has plundered our seas, ravaged our Coasts, burnt our towns, and destroyed the lives of our people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7120711ED6344372A2FA6284DD243D96"> <enum/> <text>He is, at this time, transporting large Armies of foreign Mercenaries to complete the works of death, desolation, and tyranny, already begun, with circumstances of Cruelty and perfidy scarcely paralleled in the most barbarous ages, and totally unworthy the Head of a civilized nation.</text>
                    </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD29930B60675428DAD390A41F4CE0AB7"><enum/><text>He has constrained our fellow Citizens, taken Captive on the high Seas, to bear Arms against their Country, to become the executioners of their friends and Brethren, or to fall themselves by their Hands.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE56F4C9190244FAD995B6A775A477C75"><enum/><text>He has excited domestic insurrections amongst us, and has endeavoured to bring on the inhabitants of our frontiers the merciless Indian Savages, whose known rule of warfare is an undistinguished destruction of all ages, sexes, and conditions.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4368A39387B846C9907A965963E7CF78"><enum/><text>In every stage of these Oppressions, We have Petitioned for Redress in the most humble terms: Our repeated Petitions have been answered only by repeated injury. A Prince, whose character is thus marked by every act which may define a Tyrant, is unfit to be the ruler of a free people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H054C74C667884354A337A5DC7F1E16B2"> <enum/> <text>Nor have We been wanting in attentions to our British brethren. We have warned them, from time to time, of attempts by their legislature to extend an unwarrantable jurisdiction over us. We have reminded them of the circumstances of our emigration and settlement here. We have appealed to their native justice and magnanimity, and We have conjured them, by the ties of our common kindred, to disavow these usurpations, which would inevitably interrupt our connections and correspondence. They, too, have been deaf to the voice of justice and of consanguinity. We must, therefore, acquiesce in the necessity which denounces our Separation, and hold them, as We hold the rest of mankind, Enemies in War, in Peace Friends.</text>
                    </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB2168D3A25C5488FAC1A679E4F39055D"><enum/><text>We, therefore, the Representatives of the united States of America, in General Congress assembled, appealing to the Supreme Judge of the world for the rectitude of our intentions, do, in the Name and by the Authority of the good People of these Colonies, solemnly publish and declare, That these United Colonies are, and of Right ought to be, Free and Independent States; that they are Absolved from all Allegiance to the British Crown; and that all political connection between them and the State of Great Britain is, and ought to be, totally dissolved; and that, as Free and Independent States, they have full Power to levy War, conclude Peace, contract Alliances, establish Commerce, and do all other Acts and Things which Independent States may of right do.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C8CFFD01AB64873BE134E114AEE4A64"><enum/><text>And for the support of this Declaration, with a firm reliance on the protection of divine Providence, We mutually pledge to each other our Lives, our Fortunes, and our sacred Honor.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

