<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H374C815268664F3899C735E93672A9F3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6782 IH: Public Health Air Quality Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6782</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect clean air and public health by expanding fenceline and ambient air monitoring and access to air quality information for communities affected by air pollution, to require hazardous air pollutant monitoring at the fenceline of facilities whose emissions are linked to local health threats, to ensure the Environmental Protection Agency promulgates rules that require hazardous air pollutant data measurement and electronic submission at fencelines and stacks of industrial source categories, to expand and strengthen the national ambient air quality monitoring network, to deploy air quality systems in communities affected by air pollution, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H46E7E3B9BC4C4258B8C6BA03B463446E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HA31083D8B4444C5096E771C92D90F982"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Health Air Quality Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" id="HD00C61C8F92D4820929B7C0FF605E2A7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86464426BDBF489CB7405E49F41CDB3F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accidental release</header><text>The term <term>accidental release</term> has the meaning given the term in section 112(r)(2) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(r)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H72F2F379C82C4B1FA209CDBA55424F55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H26623FBB80894236960644506CEE1D87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Air quality system</header><text>The term <term>air quality system</term> means an air quality sensor or set of sensors installed together with instruments to measure meteorology and store and transmit data.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8F593711E754409ABAC688AB6FFA6180"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Area source; hazardous air pollutant; major source; new source; stationary source</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, the terms <term>area source</term>, <term>hazardous air pollutant</term>, <term>major source</term>, <term>new source</term>, and <term>stationary source</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 112(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CA7D58B3B5D44719E2BE8CAD8681AAA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cumulative impact</header><text>The term <term>cumulative impact</term> means the totality of exposures to combinations of chemical and nonchemical stressors, and the effects of those exposures on health, well-being, and quality of life outcomes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9AC7E81473F41469928C99B58E8559B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cumulative risk</header><text>The term <term>cumulative risk</term> means the combined risks to health or the environment from multiple agents or stressors.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC365D49DBA5C4234BD2F468ADA9D8956"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Emissions measurement system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>emissions measurement system</term> means a set of monitors, testing equipment, tools, and processes employed at a facility to measure emissions from direct and fugitive points at a source or facility or at the fenceline of the source or facility that employs Environmental Protection Agency-approved or promulgated test methods for all measured pollutants for which a method is available.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06D5D0EDB67640A4B699619DED36986C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Federal equivalent method; Federal reference method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Federal equivalent method</term> and <term>Federal reference method</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 53.1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or to the same or substantially similar terms in successor regulations).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H52EBF33D061A460F83F0EEE27481EC56"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Method 325A</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Method 325A</term> means the most current version of the test method 325A published by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD27C5909669644928055AA91E9408F5E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Method 325B</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Method 325B</term> means the most current version of the test method 325B published by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7222078F460C406A8A384EC508C01DCA"><enum>(11)</enum><header>METHOD 327</header><text>The term <term>Method 327</term> means the most current version of the test method 327 published by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD1759527ED54D6CB0BF473C105B663B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Method TO–15A</header><text>The term <term>Method TO–15A</term> means the most current version of the test method TO–15 (including TO–15A) published by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H79446EE19B864A9EB7194331F1D09829"><enum>(13)</enum><header>National Air Toxics Trends Network</header><text>The term <term>National Air Toxics Trends Network</term> means the long-term hazardous air pollutants monitoring data network established by the Environmental Protection Agency to assess trends and emissions reduction program effectiveness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9444E726D9A549C694E110DACD352222"><enum>(14)</enum><header>National ambient air quality standard</header><text>The term <term>national ambient air quality standard</term> means a national ambient air quality standard established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H36D533AFAB09443BA7382AF591715345"><enum>(15)</enum><header><enum-in-header>NCore</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>NCore</term> has the meaning given the term in section 58.1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8909975A32334240AE1CD1BA28222532"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Office of Research and Development</header><text>The term <term>Office of Research and Development</term> means the Office of Research and Development of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36C55DEC3E674C0AB5FEFA3B52E1D603"><enum>(17)</enum><header>PFAS terms</header><text>The terms <term>perfluoroalkyl substance</term> and <term>polyfluoroalkyl substance</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 7331(2)(B) of the PFAS Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8931">15 U.S.C. 8931(2)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D687982E6084535B29CDF5D04E610E9"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Real-time</header><text>The term <term>real-time</term> means the actual or near actual time during which pollutant levels occur at or near the property boundary of a facility or in a nearby community.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H172F66D97ACE427688363F32C1C87F04" commented="no"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Source</header><text>The term <term>source</term> is within the meaning of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5161B7570EC4B9C9683AC92E2B7247D"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Test method</header><text>The term <term>test method</term> means a method described in the most recent document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Compendium of Methods for the Determination of Toxic Organic Compounds in Ambient Air</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" id="HF985CA6A353641AE83E1272DE8B7DBC4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Health emergency air toxics monitoring network</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="H1F476D2F5EAD4797AF282D0564334A93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Monitoring</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBC83AE7B7F1245C1B029360C3D1DC55E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall publish notice in the Federal Register of, take public comment for a period of not less than 60 days regarding, and take final action to design and launch a plan and implement a program to administer or conduct, pursuant to authority provided under the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>), including sections 103, 112, 113, 114, and 303 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7403">42 U.S.C. 7403</external-xref>, 7412, 7413, 7414, 7603), emissions measurement and quantification, including the best available form of fenceline monitoring of stationary sources of hazardous air pollutants that are on the list developed under subsection (c), including through expansion of the National Air Toxics Trends Network or through creating a new network, as appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA966789E6DE44463BB379E42E87D7229"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monitoring period</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H55D7AA6320CA46D5B5AC870073869B1B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure monitoring begins pursuant to this section not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act and shall maintain the monitoring required under paragraph (1) for a period of not less than 6 years after the date on which the monitoring required under that paragraph begins.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H50014A2FF88F4CC68021BC8B5EE8E073"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the 6-year period described in subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall maintain the emissions measurement and quantification program under paragraph (1), consistent with this section, through—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H307645C8EA174C69B5904763EBE80D3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintaining monitors at all or some sources under the program under paragraph (1); and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H3D72BC25C92F46DC91D10E42E2F36266"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adding or moving monitors under the program under paragraph (1) to additional sources, following the process for substitution of sources in subsection (g).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D4E1E7358C3447A990DB125F277D740"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Shortened period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator determines, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, that 6 years of monitoring, as required under subparagraph (A), is not necessary to protect public health or ensure compliance at the source or the facility involved, the Administrator may reduce or end the monitoring after at least 3 years of monitoring has occurred.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H85F27E2CF4024F1896240D3852B5E104"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional inspections and testing</header><text>In addition to fenceline monitoring under the program under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall use the authority of the Administrator to inspect and require emission testing at sources on the list published pursuant to subsection (c) to the extent necessary to identify and address the emissions crossing the fenceline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H5E3560DB16F74C09A8E7245AA50405C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of results</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H26C352D288E54B3DA75F568E8F2F7CF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall publish and maintain the plans for and the results of all measurements, including fenceline monitoring, conducted under the program under subsection (a)(1) on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H541AFAC1B6A14DE0A3254B3A7DBFEBCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a highly accessible format;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FE166C5860C4931AEEC88C09F292D1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a centralized database maintained in multiple languages; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H74FEC7561CF44EE5834E8C1834132531"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a period of at least 10 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H512F33D305544973BCF0E8583C85A3E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediate availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that the monitoring data collected under the program under subsection (a)(1) are—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB58289BAFE054A56A17A1229A28B7075"><enum>(A)</enum><text>electronically submitted to the Administrator not later than 1 month after the date of collection of the data; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H71CB0505029D493BBC64B3B43787CD9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made publicly available as expeditiously as practicable, but in any case not later than 7 days after the electronic submission of the data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H164725BF298D48008F9B5D4E659420B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>List of sources</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HAE4C147EC2E647E2BDFC14FF7732F05E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF0EBE5149BE244C4975EE4716D9E066B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall publish, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, a list of stationary sources of hazardous air pollutants that, subject to subparagraph (B) do not already have fenceline monitoring in operation that is producing publicly available data and includes—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H00BE85BC9BCF44D5B93B5615D285DFAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 45 of the sources listed—</text>
<subclause id="H4586D8396D8B463381645C0880B033DF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>as high-priority facilities in Appendix A of the report of the Office of Inspector General of the Environmental Protection Agency numbered 20–N–0128 and dated March 31, 2020; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H110D81F52A7B4A01A0FEA44F4F8889C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as contributing to high cancer risk at the census block level in Appendix C of the report of the Office of Inspector General of the Environmental Protection Agency numbered 21–P–0129 and dated May 6, 2021; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H71463F3ED882481D9A13351F91C56CD5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 55 other major sources or area sources that meet the criteria described in paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D082C97B74E47ADBA9C18F9B977962C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Substitution</header> <clause commented="no" id="HC8481583AFDC4B28B91ABDF027C3580F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Administrator determines, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, that a source described in subparagraph (A)(i) no longer contributes to high health risks or impacts that warrant continued monitoring to advance public health protection, inform improved compliance, or improve available data quality, the Administrator shall—</text>
<subclause commented="no" id="H0BCDBD6F388442DA909BBBCC155A00BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cease to include that source in the list under subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H339DE464294A43948B51B30D2352A9D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>include instead an additional major source or area source described in subparagraph (A)(ii) to ensure that the list under subparagraph (A) includes not fewer than 100 high-priority sources.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HB3D54C1384BB4AFE87577CC6846180B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Description of reasons</header><text>For the purpose of providing notice, the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register, and seek public comment for a period of not less than 60 days with respect to—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H8FD311E3004747C2A9E8B170DD96194B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any determination to make a substitution under clause (i); and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H850091F0D1864AF69F99ACEC371CACDA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of the reasons for any such determination demonstrating, based on monitoring data or other reliable information, that the substitution is likely to ensure that monitoring under this section occurs at the sources causing or contributing to the highest potential health risks or other impacts from hazardous air pollution.</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H3FBF79218DDD4ACC8486F85AC52E340F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Administrator may include an additional major source or area source under clause (i)(II) only if the Administrator determines that the source is, or is likely to be, contributing local health risks or impacts that are equivalent to, or greater than, those of the source for which the new source is being substituted.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE5F27B270D2A479590C81950E462DEFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Administrator may include a major source or area source described in clause (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) on the list described in that paragraph only if the source—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H69EFB73DD6BC42499ED4674AD07FE780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emits at least 1 of the pollutants described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE7A414709CF470EACED27E0280C11FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HB7DC4AE691AB4C909D15DDAD3E3E8BBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>located in, or within 3 miles of, a census tract with—</text>
<subclause commented="no" id="H3F23C4C015494BACBCC185E2460F8789"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a cancer risk of at least 100-in-1,000,000; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HFE178C22A73D4495BD668823564988E2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a chronic noncancer hazard index that is greater than or equal to 1; or</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HD4A82925D90B4CC7A2F05DA4F56B8E4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a source category with—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H76D3C780D3314A7394A4B7EA3E1EAE01"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a cancer risk that is greater than 100-in-1,000,000 for the individual most exposed to emissions from the source category;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="HB915BAB64B324ED9B92C785F4EFDA44A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a total organ-specific hazard index for chronic noncancer risk that is greater than or equal to 1; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HB6161F8B34084E719271AC53974737C6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an acute risk hazard quotient that is greater than or equal to 1; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H7400C322311E49B7925608C48187014E"><enum>(C)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H63CBD41D92FA4233A5035817F82F0499"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is classified in 1 or more of North American Industry Classification System codes 322, 324, 325, 326, 331, 332, 339, 424, and 562;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H2F4A93CACF7042C3B1BBF852276EC279" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF49A907D40BD466F8A50B37B0E36F4D5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is required to prepare and implement a risk management plan pursuant to section 112(r) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(r)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98E3F10199354B9FA206B514017CAF53" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has had an accidental release required to be reported during the previous 5-year period pursuant to sections 68.42 and 68.195 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act); or</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HC20378EE22244157A30B70F4E4C21DED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is determined by the Administrator to be a high-priority source or facility for emissions measurement because—</text>
<subclause id="HBDAD9589A178403BB6DD154C22B5B9DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the facility is located within 350 feet of a residence, school, childcare facility (including a camp), hospital, park, sports or recreation facility, or other gathering place, community center, or institution where children and families regularly spend time; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFBD863C08BD14AAF85078B9DB686FC2F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>based on the best available science, the emissions of the source or facility are likely causing or contributing to, or have the potential to cause or contribute to, serious acute or chronic, including cancer and non-cancer, health or safety risks or impacts, including adverse neurological, developmental, or other health impacts in utero or childhood.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCC5E1009B2634AC68BB8F8ECDF85B4E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pollutants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pollutants described in this paragraph are—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA69A2052B98B449EB70E76C8A98140D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ethylene oxide, CAS 75218;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H81C855607E444351BAE7FBC755287D9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">chloroprene, CAS 126998;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC5EC666652CA41489DFAEF51D6677DF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">benzene, CAS 71432;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB6747165A00D4DE2BC720FB6ED0EFFEC">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1,3-butadiene, CAS 106990;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7E62025F16D1414FAF0F9D0493923B73"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">formaldehyde, CAS 50000;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H524EA815A22844959971E9EF9A8464BF"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acetaldehyde, CAS 75070;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2D46AFE93D3747B6AB408BCFF4BEABDF"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lead compounds;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H76D7BD0690AE4CBBB2A3DC5276DA3449"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arsenic compounds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BD003B67238468F9CE3E3B6AA06C82C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>antimony compounds;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1D493A3FAC0542FABB6137C5C98459E1"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cadmium compounds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18228BC951DB4C42BA9CEEE4D5148778"><enum>(K)</enum><text>cobalt compounds;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2AAFB7174573472292F004F5F088DACD"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nickel compounds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H19C126EB88D74E11B596459D36F65314"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">manganese compounds;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA05044C10C154FD1935120F324DA482E"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">vinyl chloride;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7D47ED5722E48A0A2315D298BC514CA"><enum>(O)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ethylene dichloride;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H822DE986C2DD4498A0019722161D6A63"><enum>(P)</enum><text>naphthalene;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E027C7DAB334E38A8A08436D7420C6C"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>ethylbenzene;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF2947F8A6E984A71BC98912FC336AE08"><enum>(R)</enum><text>methyl mercury;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20172E681B1D47029ECB4E24A51DFB67"><enum>(S)</enum><text>epichlorohydrin;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF1E51F4A93C74259A7A5529A67AD743D"><enum>(T)</enum><text>xylenes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7D2B8D795024DBE906C94C00FFB8E7C"><enum>(U)</enum><text>acrylonitrile;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEFB74F72AE154B41B8E06AB71BD709DF"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any other hazardous air pollutant included in the list described in section 112(b) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(b)</external-xref>) that the Administrator determines, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, the air emissions of which—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H34D925947230451F850224BE766EA748"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are, or may be contributing to, serious health risks; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H45CE8EB087F04ACF85D6D92C4219E379"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>warrant emissions quantification and measurement due to the public interest in evaluating the emissions and effects of the pollutant; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FF5E52527B545D1A0512592E042A383"><enum>(W)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any pollutant or airborne chemical that is a precursor to atmospheric photochemical production of any other pollutant on the list described in section 112(b) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4D5F5D56E63E47CC85C009D95990E2A0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of information and methods</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H69D040516525456798FC353F3707B672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use—</text>
<clause id="HD851EDA15FA44136A34E5D17C6D9839A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the evaluations and methods of the Environmental Protection Agency for compiling and evaluating information about risks from air toxics in effect on January 1, 2025, that have been peer reviewed by the Science Advisory Board, including chemical assessments developed by the Integrated Risk Information System of the Environmental Protection Agency (commonly referred to as <quote>IRIS</quote>), or the most recent Air Toxics Screening Assessment or other current evaluation or report by the Environmental Protection Agency, acting through the Office of Research and Development, providing similar information about cancer and noncancer risks from hazardous air pollution based on measured or modeled emissions, using evaluations or methods that—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51ABF2D2B6194C4E8A76AE8E1B249347"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account for, and therefore demonstrate higher risks to, the individual or community most exposed to the emissions; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B1E2AFA1E144F37AB90555DB8E61B3B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account for adverse neurological, developmental, or other health impacts in utero, in childhood, and in adolescence;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H47C25221AA6A4F199154F312CCA9F2FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Risk-Screening Environmental Indicators model of the Administrator in effect as of December 31, 2024;</text></clause>
<clause id="HE6BB539473314FDBA90181343A11D4DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a prior health risk assessment that was performed by the Administrator for the applicable source or source category before January 1, 2025; or</text></clause> <clause id="H546AF031909F43A3BFB667EDAD95D733"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a new health risk assessment performed by the Administrator for the applicable source or source category that—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3E9B3F36EF547B6855FA2DCC68BFA60"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is more complete and addresses more or greater risks than previously considered;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF86BBB4116DA45E59FE9C4371DC8C71D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>follows the best available science (including the most recent guidance from the National Academy of Sciences and the most recent assessments under the Integrated Risk Information System of the Environmental Protection Agency (commonly referred to as <quote>IRIS</quote>) that were created pursuant to the document of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>ORD Staff Handbook for Developing IRIS Assessments</quote> and dated December 2022); and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H7363248F1F7B479797D0B81B266823C5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>considers, with respect to the applicable source or facility—</text> <item commented="no" id="HECBE6A28DC404003BE6108327FB4A379"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>cumulative risks and cumulative impacts;</text></item>
<item commented="no" id="H14F4B065939042FCB69BA4C7CDB8E9BF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>increased vulnerability that results from socioeconomic disparities;</text></item> <item commented="no" id="H51146CCE30E24D3B9BCD16E123EB8BB2"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>multiple source exposure; and</text></item>
<item id="H75D5A6BE4DAA4C94B62F02D6E0131AA9"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>exposure in utero, in childhood, in adolescence, and through the age of 85; and</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H17F710A2423D4766B15AB131D4DC8281"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider—</text>
<clause id="H2B41D97BED2D42528BA2ACA768646A7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the most recent emission tests available to the Administrator or received by the Environmental Protection Agency in public comment; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBFA0C95F6313435FB6A22E87B5D9BCED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any fenceline or ambient monitoring data for which an Environmental Protection Agency-approved data quality check has been performed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HF5F11E1E4853413F9156FDD56655BF9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Methods and technologies</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCD6787CFE43043B795EF7659B26370A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (3), in carrying out the program under subsection (a)(1), the Administrator shall, for each stationary source on the list published under subsection (c)(1), employ an emissions measurement system to monitor the pollutants described in subsection (c)(3) emitted by the stationary source, including at least—</text> <subparagraph id="HAEA63720B4EE4D70A5EAA0744F64F5BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the most current Environmental Protection Agency-approved or promulgated emission test or monitoring method, including Method 325A, Method 325B, Method TO–15A, and Method 327, that expands the scope, strengthens the detection limit, or otherwise improves the effectiveness of the test method; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H625C6643073E4467BB358C8CCC3AF163"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each stationary source described in paragraph (2), the best available method for continuous, real-time measurement of air pollutant concentrations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE3E8EDF58C4440EC9591DB6E687A038A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stationary sources described</header><text>A stationary source referred to in paragraph (1)(B) is—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H08676BC776CD473A892AB8AD6F62923D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than each of the 20 stationary sources on the list published under subsection (c)(1) that—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H2F71AF3E2A6E4066B5CBBED2EE507AEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>emits the greatest quantity or rate of pollutants described in subsection (c)(3); or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H730881C1F1D344488752779A69512900"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>causes the greatest health risk to the greatest number of people, based on the emissions of the pollutants described in subsection (c)(3) individually, as a group, or cumulatively, based on—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H25BF56D4C96048B0A1B356C44E2AF092"><enum>(I)</enum> <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1E42463BA0C949A68ABAE16FFA776472"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the latest evaluations and methods of the Environmental Protection Agency for compiling and evaluating information about risks from air toxics, or the most recent Air Toxics Screening Assessment or other current evaluation or report by the Environmental Protection Agency providing similar information about cancer and noncancer risks from hazardous air pollution based on measured or modeled emissions;</text></item>
<item commented="no" indent="up1" id="H240BAB40FE9E424F987CCB970627A863"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Risk-Screening Environmental Indicators model of the Administrator;</text></item> <item commented="no" indent="up1" id="H81E24A6C05C34A158E5E03257E854DCF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a prior health risk assessment that was performed by the Administrator for the applicable source or source category; or</text></item>
<item commented="no" indent="up1" id="H4B1EB4B8A62B4F37AA466A1969BD10A7"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a new health risk assessment performed by the Administrator that—</text> <subitem commented="no" id="H4F9B7F5FC2EB4A54904BB14919F08865"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>follows the best available science (including the most recent guidance from the National Academy of Sciences); and</text></subitem>
<subitem commented="no" id="H1ED4736C4A7F4A1BB3EE0C7F783E6EE6"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>considers, with respect to the applicable source or facility, cumulative risks and impacts, increased vulnerability that results from socioeconomic disparities, multiple source exposure, and exposure in utero, in childhood, in adolescence, and over the course of a lifetime through the age of 85; and</text></subitem></item></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HDBA5036C61AC407C9126EAD8A420F206"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the most recent emission tests available to the Environmental Protection Agency or received in public comment, and any fenceline or ambient monitoring data for which an Environmental Protection Agency-approved data quality check has been performed;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD0535A98A32489AB331F06DEA38132D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other stationary source on the list published under subsection (c)(1) that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3FB5C4A3F50488181A857E371149774"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is regulated under paragraph (7) of section 112(r) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(r)</external-xref>); and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3CD40B5800E49229AF32F7F478C0C26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has had an accidental release or incident that is required to be reported during the previous 5-year period pursuant to sections 68.42 and 68.195 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on January 1, 2025), under that paragraph; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB00186854A9423DA9736549E74FBE22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other stationary source on the list published under subsection (c)(1) for which application of the methods described in subparagraph (A) alone may not be sufficient—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3BE436C7C554E4E8B5DC9A5DA0C7480"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to monitor and report the pollutants described in subsection (c)(3) that are emitted by that stationary source; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA7C97715CAB41ACB7B162B7FDAD7990"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to advance public health and safety.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H1094B3694738428995ADE99528970F45"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE7D9A25D12F4B70AEC322166D1882E8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approved or promulgated methods</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H00177074AB5440AE8E37BFB8071A3E53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, review and, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, update each approved or promulgated test method described in this section to add as many of the pollutants described in subsection (c)(3) as practicable; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H7C8E44B09DEC4D43A1DFCC935EA0A015"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise strengthen the test methods described in clause (i) to support effective hazardous air pollutant measurement and the full implementation of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HADB69C425C0E420DB1E5E6685446EEEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New test methods</header> <clause commented="no" id="HBB5168BD796F4971BC01C0311225FC65"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, approve or promulgate, as applicable, any new test methods that are necessary to ensure effective fenceline monitoring of all pollutants and sources described in this section, including—</text>
<subclause id="HAFDAFF3AEDFE47D29F6F38A867567A02"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at least 1 method that represents the best and most accurate form of continuous, real-time fenceline monitoring based on the best available science; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFADC5705BB5641099E7CC722FF9CFD48"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at least 1 method that represents the best and most accurate form of multimetal monitoring based on the best available science.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HB7129599826B42AD8955B7304C1434D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Updates required</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 6 years, the Administrator shall review and, if necessary, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, strengthen or add new test methods that meet the requirements under clause (i), which shall be based on—</text> <subclause id="H65DD896597B846689D1157F2A2C7963B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the best available monitoring technologies that improve the quality or quantity of information provided by, or improve the precision or other type of scientific reliability of, a method; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H4822C5A3EBA9426E8DC00E9C4CE745C1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the advice of staff of the Office of Enforcement and Compliance, staff of the Office of Research and Development, regional or other staff within the Environmental Protection Agency responsible for, and with expertise on, the enforcement of this Act, and other monitoring experts.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD78ED674720B490DB486B6AEA9EDBB61"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Office of Research and Development</header><text>The Administrator shall act through the Assistant Administrator for Research and Development, and in coordination with the Assistant Administrator for Air and Radiation, to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HA6C05C2FA9AC4EE59E2E1DE5193D97E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Monitor placement and maintenance</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H5B260F5992A44645B59DBA6CF6769A9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days with respect to monitor placement and maintenance plans, place and maintain, or ensure placement and regular maintenance of, all monitors required under this section to ensure effective and reliable emissions measurement pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1DA826EF8B4B427A9F02245BDB04F220"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintenance check</header><text>The maintenance required under paragraph (1) shall include a maintenance check of the monitor not less frequently than once every 180 days, unless—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H85AC0A8A23C54383816B8888A7954DB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the test method used by the monitor requires a maintenance check more frequently; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7F99634082084EC0AF460261159813B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a maintenance check is requested by a member of the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H636A3D8CEE354BBBA75A892BB8F56CD8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public input</header><text>The Administrator shall, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, create a process, including an accessible online resource or website, for the public—</text> <subparagraph id="H761C34D62F784A9BAFE0B52BE2DB73A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to track the maintenance of monitors under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H428C66FB6D3F41A4BC73B8BF4F159397"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to request a maintenance check of a monitor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HCC61BAC8E5E74B998C9FA58550BDA14A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 6 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress and post publicly on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency a report describing the results of the program carried out under subsection (a)(1), which shall include—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3C8D37C097B9419DBEF00851DCD49FA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of emissions measurement implemented under that program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3395CF7EEE7A44ABB69BF1C9D037CF7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any actions of the Administrator taken based on that emissions measurement data or program; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HECE3EF26C710443E9A3825D3DC7CF6FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the Administrator proposes—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H46C4E5386258451E93A827727B4C432F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to continue emissions measurements at any or all of the stationary sources on the list published under subsection (c)(1); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HED8B30C0AC3341C8A28A74CC85F4A26B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement emissions measurements of any additional stationary sources as determined under subsection (g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H3469531EAC804362B7562896AA2EA0FF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Determination regarding additional sources</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 6 years thereafter, the Administrator shall—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA5AEBC50FEDB42829E3154DDED7B6C50"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, make a determination of whether to add or remove sources to the list published under subsection (c)(1)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3825409CE0404250BA30AE758580A262"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure compliance of those stationary sources with existing emission standards under section 112 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HD1777CF633B3418B86B4330FADDF5CD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to prevent and detect accidental releases;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA92ED563DAAA40758164E8F6BEB3AA7B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to protect the health of the communities, including children and other vulnerable populations, most exposed to the emissions of hazardous air pollutants from such stationary sources to the maximum extent practicable; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBC153316FB8A4E2AB6090B2FA77EA789"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to ensure the 100 highest-priority sources or facilities, based on the best available science and the most current data on health risks and impacts (including the most current research on children’s health), have emissions measurement systems in place for pollutants required to be monitored under this section; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA37AD6156C0841FE8B5E45A0BC0B2B13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish a determination under paragraph (1) in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0E6256DDE405472A8CC47041E4AD940D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress and make publicly available online a report that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H556401127E1F4031845E6FCE8EDE63D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the staffing that is available, necessary, and planned to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC28EAC146C654063B11B527AAFE8957E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrates how the Administrator intends to carry out the duties and requirements of this section without impact or delay on any other duty or responsibility of the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4217316207564C98BBB9DA16CEF23943"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No exemption authority</header><text>No exemption from compliance with any standard or limitation under this section may be issued pursuant to section 112(i)(4) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(i)(4)</external-xref>) to any stationary source.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB6D771EF0DAF48EBBD85523A66B3CA01"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $146,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="HB7CD0C808A2E4A09AD45F62A51490DFE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Community air toxics monitoring</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H13581343021140AB9C5C6768DCAC8709"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations pursuant to authority provided by the Clean Air Act, which may include section 103, subsections (d), (f), and (r) of section 112, section 113, and section 114 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7403">42 U.S.C. 7403</external-xref>, 7412, 7413, 7414), for each source category described in subsection (b), that—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HB1A5FDE46A9047118172E2F6E01B8AB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require all sources in the source category to implement, not later than 1 year after the promulgation of the regulations, the best available form of emissions measurement, including continuous emissions monitoring and fenceline monitoring, to ensure compliance with the emission standards for hazardous air pollutants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1F09ADF891CA474B9C3F8652A1D35656"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for facilities in the source category that are required to submit risk management plans under section 112(r)(7) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(r)(7)</external-xref>), require each facility to implement—</text>
<subparagraph id="H506E861CFB6344A487B38B8B7D3485A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continuous, real-time monitoring to provide for effective emergency response and provide information to prevent future releases; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72A565C3554B4935AD563BBA9CC6C1EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emissions measurement, including fenceline monitoring, to provide for effective emergency response and provide information to prevent future releases;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F4DA0A885EA475E90BA1A9CA6B61314"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subject to subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF1D62AE0416402BA209BC3091640F07"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a corrective action level at the fenceline for at least the top 5 hazardous air pollutants that drive the cancer, chronic noncancer, or acute risk for the source category; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5715DA21A0DC461BBA06A06493396A08"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require corrective action for the release of any quantity of a substance listed pursuant to section 112(r)(3) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(r)(3)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94BA7B6C0C56435A8B105FE2E58DBD5F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if any applicable corrective action level under paragraph (3)(A) is exceeded, require—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5FBB696F56CC4527836E78F97A5B82B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a root cause analysis and preventive action report;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A1A4E8707094786BF717C6977CEA2A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>full remedial action, including implementation of all control technologies, practices, processes, operational improvements, or other measures necessary to resolve the exceedance and protect the most exposed or most vulnerable individuals potentially affected by the exceedance (including children) and to make best efforts to prevent the exceedance from recurring, based on and applying input from the most affected individuals and communities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB099D7D678074DE3B7F6132D4BD99002"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a public report that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7630E0D711A8497B81BA18B38DA0B4F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6371F27DA00E49409A6B76AC06F1AF1C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of the root cause analysis and preventive action report under subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71AA8F38841849DF9E471BCA23206829"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the remedial actions taken under subparagraph (B); and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0A62C5A1D614A1EB6597B1915A4B7AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies that a violation of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>) has occurred; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86D37A9D6DF341D28799F06B7CD5359C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">treat any requirement imposed by the regulations under this section as a requirement under section 112 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412</external-xref>) that is enforceable under section 113 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7413">42 U.S.C. 7413</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HD9E89B122DEB4C7886C90867DBCEBD23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Source categories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The source categories described in this subsection include—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5630E68BAAE540998B1C9BAFA0DD7122"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each category or subcategory of major sources or area sources that—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HBA4ED9B961A24027B0A7C605C80F8766"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE65891710E9049429C1F68EBF0D78CB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least 1 of the stationary sources of hazardous air pollutants that are on the list published under section 3(c);</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H3C4E93EE1B9145CA848B8F4D0A6C7DE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>major sources or area sources identified in the most recent National Emissions Inventory of the Environmental Protection Agency as emitting a pollutant described in section 3(c)(3);</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HC84E35EB685B43A6B95ED5DAD4A61981"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>petroleum, chemical, petrochemical, or plastics manufacturing sources, marine vessel loading operations, or other sources that are classified in 1 or more of North American Industry Classification System codes 322, 324, 325, 326, 331, 332, 339, 424, and 562; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H431E569944F741229DBC31CA51433A4C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other major source or area source of fugitive hazardous air pollutant emissions for which the Environmental Protection Agency is subject to a court-ordered or statutory deadline, engaged in a reconsideration proceeding, or subject to a court remand (or is likely within the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act to become subject to such an obligation or action) to review and determine whether to revise the emissions standards that apply to that source category; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H60947C4F16A8423693980EE3691E58E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains any stationary source that—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E1D1BAB18734206AADC99421774A229"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is regulated under paragraph (7) of section 112(r) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(r)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> <clause id="H5E950848CE464092A7C8DBE318D50E80"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has had an accidental release or incident that is required to be reported during the previous 5-year period under that section and the regulations thereunder that were in effect as of January 1, 2025; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H83EA213C1AAF40C9B5A622DBF2E0D958"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other source category for which the Administrator determines that requiring fenceline monitoring is likely to benefit public health or welfare, including children’s health, based on the best available science.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBD0838BF668C492DADB561D18222B144"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of best available form of monitoring</header> <paragraph id="HA8E649382AF643C7B6C145A6254D68CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with the Office of Air and Radiation, the Office of Enforcement and Compliance Assurance, the Office of Environmental Justice and External Civil Rights, the Office of Children’s Health, and the Office of Research and Development, shall, for purposes of the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H67850BD5CCEF46B7A1CB450D95765513"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the best available form of emissions measurement, including continuous emissions monitoring and fenceline monitoring; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE06CBE3C43C450F9CE18B7FD2EBBB1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the methods required under the regulations are at least as stringent as the most current Environmental Protection Agency-approved or promulgated emission test or monitoring method, including Method 325A, Method 325B, Method 327, and Method TO–15A.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C376423CAAD478EAEAD1221A3E5C2C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1)(B), the Administrator shall ensure that 1 or more of the methods described in or promulgated under section 3 or subsection (d) (including multimetal monitoring) is included in the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a) if that method is the best available method for 1 or more of the pollutants for which monitoring is required under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HADFCA86C159C42FEB1433B0F736AF6FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Methods and technologies</header> <paragraph id="H6F40266A0E924C8095BE90BF4425F4B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For all stationary sources in the source categories described in subsection (b), as the best available fenceline monitoring method for those source categories, the Administrator may, in the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7A7617D8320447608BC643485D806E81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require application, implementation, or employment of optical remote sensing technology to provide real-time measurements of air pollutant concentrations along an open-path; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF2E9E3F51A646B2931306FA87E38D6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide an explanation of why application, implementation, or employment of 1 or more of the technologies described in subparagraph (A) is not necessary—</text>
<clause id="H10CF2F8D5C6B41EE871999C43A009AFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with the emission standards established under the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (d), (f), or (r) of section 112 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412</external-xref>), as applicable; or</text></clause> <clause id="H82B986667D0045A6B9000EAF5B7FFD5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to protect the public health, to prevent accidental releases, or to provide for effective emergency response.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0097557902B4E579D4AB5E107BA177A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Multiple-source or facility complexes</header>
<subparagraph id="H95023669182F4CBA91C26458751006FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of multiple-source or facility complex</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>multiple-source or facility complex</term> means 1 or more stationary sources co-located at the same site.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A3FF9BC66B146D88558321868C9066A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Multiple-source or facility complex monitoring</header><text>In the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that the best available form of monitoring for a multiple-source or facility complex that contains not less than 2 stationary sources in 1 or more of North American Industry Classification System codes 324, 325, and 326, or a related chemical or petrochemical sector, is at least a combination of—</text>
<clause id="H0A41569D2AC14132B372FEF19DFE552D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>real-time, open-path monitoring; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0CCC017DD7064F3281743532D0F1FD0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Method 325A, Method 325B, and Method 327, as applicable depending on the types of emissions to be measured.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA18677ED35C548EFA8C9E5C424D09B41"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall consider whether any other multiple-source or facility complexes should be required to employ the combined monitoring methods described in that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H946A77EE68B94F5B8D2E7A6741BAB05D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Health priority approach</header><text>In promulgating the corrective action level for each of the hazardous air pollutants described in subsection (a)(3)(A), the Administrator shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HABFF6FE3B6394D1CA0A82873F6220666"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider the best available science, including applying the most health-protective approach possible and applying a precautionary approach to account for uncertainty;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D13FEA8FF804769856238728F831D36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the owner or operator of the source or facility reduces the emissions of the source or facility to prevent harm if the measured concentration at the fenceline would, or is likely to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD5148884ACCE4FDD91DE5B9F3A7A0911"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase harm to public health or safety (including through an increased health risk to any individual, including a child); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B9259D528E74693AC5E964F30C7E951"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reach a level that may result in short-term, long-term, or chronic human exposure to air pollution (including any exposure that begins in utero, infancy, childhood, or adolescence) that increases the risk of—</text>
<clause id="H7219186259CA4116A2AC99655BB6C5AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>health harms resulting from odors, irritation, sensitizing effects, or any combination of those harms;</text></clause> <clause id="H2F8BB060E247423CB64EADA599C879D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a chronic condition (including neurodevelopmental) or disease (including cancer and other illnesses); or</text></clause>
<clause id="HCD6CD16FC8B8465FBE25D32C389FA019"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>death; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB15375781D374540B0145BBF64657E97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>take into account the aggregate and cumulative emissions and health risks from the facility, including multiple source categories, as applicable, to ensure full health protection from the entire facility based on the best available science.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H60CF99C44D444C3A918848498DE5096F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Maintenance and public reporting</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCCEBF4D1BDD94CC285FEA92C32A0659F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2E89F296ADF24E499DBAC13D9F499245"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the owners or operators of sources subject to the requirements of this section—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="H2221CED276154194B9F141FB7087CB70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>perform regular inspections and maintenance of all measured equipment required under this section; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HD679AD1C166B4D41B11D1E2919FF7FB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the Administrator regular reports that—</text>
<subclause commented="no" id="H12044C25783A4FC097ADF56BB72E901C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>include the measured emissions data collected by that emissions measurement equipment;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H3E5E70D7D28E48BCA519CB3AC3B850AB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the status of that measurement equipment; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H8C9757F200704D878A70D77869331E27"><enum>(III)</enum><text>contain a detailed explanation of the circumstances surrounding a delay in collecting or missing data;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8637F8D93A0445DA8619876543EED3B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the emissions measurement system required under this section is continuous and yields reliable data not less than 95 percent of the time, without any regulatory exemption or extension; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3202C53E8CA549B7B26BC17676487FFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any problem with the fenceline monitoring equipment required under this section is repaired within 2 days of discovering the problem.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8248593941D343B394A2A7EBE5A047F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC58F37FDFCD1450DA0FFAE6E3ACE08B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the owner or operator of a stationary source subject to such regulations to report, with respect to the source, at least semiannually—</text> <clause id="H250EF9FA79194F97BC115D9D542C43A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all exceedances of any corrective action level; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3E4E7FDEA27C4267ABF1C3D7A3B67AE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all corrective action planned and taken; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H028E59BC14684C9B9A9EDEF18C6C1520"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for purposes of imposing penalties, treat each day on which a violation of a reporting requirement under subparagraph (A) continues as a separate violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HF29520ED3289437197C70DA1719EF259"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public reporting</header>
<subparagraph id="HD2FD09FD65744862AFA4FC7EC2D7102B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall make available on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency, in an accessible format that includes multiple languages spoken by residents living near the source where monitoring was conducted—</text> <clause id="HE93CBD38E3F04B2F9E1CB0B8A32E7318"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all emissions measurement plans, reports, and other information collected or required under this section;</text></clause>
<clause id="H521A041D7EF14E73A2FEC144585EC099"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all emissions measurement data collected by monitoring equipment required under this section; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE04FE65E6E264DBBBD9A0B1D77B883AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an option to sign up for community-wide or source-specific alerts that alert the user if the emissions concentrations measured pursuant to clause (i) or (ii), as applicable, exceed—</text>
<subclause id="H47A0090A67444AF78EABDE28DB0C6D3F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a health reference level of the Administrator that has been scientifically peer-reviewed;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4C1748B7CF144550AECF845D06EE115A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a health reference level approved by the Administrator that has been scientifically peer-reviewed;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H1F5D8FA26AB14822824E263891760B59"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a health reference level approved by any State or Tribal government that has been scientifically peer-reviewed; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE94605E02879433792D3CC49CB63174D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the applicable corrective action level under subsection (a)(3)(A).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1FF4EE6D96734A249CF6CCB92B1F9CFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public notice and comment</header><text>The Administrator shall provide notice and receive public comment for not less than 60 days on the format and accessibility of the information required to be made available under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H129F3FC87F4544D8A5BC38FB4D16F9E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Administrator shall publicize the information required to be made available under subparagraph (A) in each community that contains a source regulated under this section through not less than 2 of the most widely viewed local media formats for members of that community that live nearest the regulated source.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB1D280D02D8547F8AF9BB67DC2331E8D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Office of Research and Development</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure that the Assistant Administrator for Air and Radiation coordinates with the Assistant Administrator for Research and Development, as well as any other appropriate offices of the Environmental Protection Agency, to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H590DE7A1C29047C0B1F0FB43546876CA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress and make publicly available online a report that—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E2D2DE1E76E40C08636ABE3077345FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the staffing that is available, necessary, and planned to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96677AADEAAE43F29F081F243BA4A3F1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrates how the Administrator intends to carry out the duties and requirements of this section without impact or delay on any other duty or responsibility of the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H27F071CDD81E402EBA18795673D2A12F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No exemption authority</header><text>No exemption from compliance with any standard or limitation under this section may be issued pursuant to section 112(i)(4) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(i)(4)</external-xref>) to any stationary source.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HE6EDB4B534024621AE676C8AAEB98F3A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 and 2027.</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" id="H73375CB78B3B4348BF697504FDC789D6"><enum>5.</enum><header>NAAQS monitoring network</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="H84A33254097047A7A329FC84D07CD6AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deployment of NCore multipollutant monitoring stations</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H455E02880ED74B70AE5AD9C71D9D0017"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall require the deployment of 80 additional NCore multipollutant monitoring stations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C9000EC52EB4A26A9D71E8009F3B8A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All monitors at the stations required to be deployed pursuant to paragraph (1) that measure pollutants for which the Administrator has established national ambient air quality standards shall—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3084086AE1044B6E925712B3255FACB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be Federal reference method or Federal equivalent method monitors; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAC9FCF6CC0E4B11A156C01E2D817A8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">produce monitoring data that are sufficient for determining whether the relevant national ambient air quality standard is met at the site.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H6A3BC2AFEB1F4CA0BC39E97BE0D0D9A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall ensure that all NCore multipollutant monitoring stations required to be deployed under subsection (a)(1) are—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8B1A1A378542435081FBB9905D314E74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>installed and integrated into the air quality monitoring system established pursuant to sections 110(a)(2)(B) and 319 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7410">42 U.S.C. 7410(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>, 7619); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2E4E573FE6F141198C6BCA86AAFF9E17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after installation, operated and maintained on a continuing basis.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H0395734420B1434EA7D980773D02C090"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Monitoring results</header> <text>Monitoring results from NCore multipollutant stations required to be deployed under subsection (a)(1) shall be used for—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="HFEF1BBE753E54A9F95F363D2642B7CBF">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessments of the compliance of areas with national ambient air quality standards;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="HFD4F3FAD58EC49C7ACA9454DB2B04A3D">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>integrated science assessments in reviews of national ambient air quality standards established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>);</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H90917D6DD7D94682B3EC95E2BEF8027D">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>evaluating disparities of pollution exposures within metropolitan areas; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5E3414B73DB4481A05E75349E7947F5">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>such other purposes as the Administrator determines will promote the protection of public health from air pollution.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HD7B49F00BF974346979CE08844E9AA53"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Locations</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0E945B30B51D4B7D807BE014577A269F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vulnerable populations</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8EF87DA2D764D8AB57537C7850AE652"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that not fewer than 40 of the NCore multipollutant monitoring stations required to be deployed under subsection (a)(1)—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H347AD00C549D4539B9936855B0C270F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are not limited to metropolitan statistical areas with populations of 50,000 or greater; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAD0CBC081D045DDA59F90770BA4A558"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meet the requirement described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F38B0DB7474466CBD4A7E5E76E753ED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement described</header><text>The requirement referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) is that the NCore multipollutant monitoring stations shall be sited in census tracts that each meet 1 or more of the following criteria, with the specific site selected consistent with Appendix D to part 58 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), except that where the provisions of this Act conflict with that appendix, the provisions of this Act shall control:</text>
<clause commented="no" id="H5871330BF806422B91CB4524A4DAD687"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The rates of childhood asthma, adult asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, heart disease, or cancer are not less than 5 percent higher than the national average for that condition in the census tract.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H240118D4231D493BB0EB7AA334E47F2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The percentage of people living below the poverty level, that are above age 18 without a high school diploma, or that are unemployed, is higher than the national average in the census tract.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC433271DD99E41ECAB14250F73A147D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>2 or more major sources (as defined in section 501 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661">42 U.S.C. 7661</external-xref>)) are located within the census tract or adjacent census tracts combined.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8DDC230C49F2463BB28AA115CE097B59"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a higher-than-national-average population in the census tract of vulnerable or sensitive individuals who may be at greater risk than the general population of adverse health effects from exposure to 1 or more air pollutants for which national ambient air quality standards have been established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H175363FE91254880992C9F5565760DE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Siting determinations</header><text>In determining and approving sites for NCore multipollutant monitoring stations required to be deployed under subsection (a)(1), the Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD1A44650494F438595C75105B1026983"><enum>(A)</enum><text>invite proposals from or on behalf of residents of any community for the siting of the stations in that community, which may include inviting proposals through regional or virtual meetings;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H28B7DAD290AC4D05970FCA5C06432C62"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritize siting of the stations in census tracts or counties based on—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H732C48D10DFD4C7E887E14B9C8098389"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the potential for the levels of 1 or more air pollutants to be monitored by the stations to reach or exceed the level of the applicable national ambient air quality standard established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>), including evidence of relevant industrial activity or nearby exceedances;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H51E423A95CE04E76B79E2A4FC9A04207"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of people who live, work, attend school, or recreate in the area or areas for which monitoring by the stations is reasonably anticipated to be representative with respect to air quality and the proportion of those people who are at higher risk than the general population of adverse health effects from the air pollutants monitored;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HF695C693807E40CD849A03EA50C35D7D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the lack or inadequacy of existing air quality monitors for providing representative air quality data for the affected area or areas for the pollutants to be measured by the station; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H8AD856E398E0439FBC6918AB74CFF33E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current designation of the area in which the monitoring station would be located as unclassifiable or in attainment for 1 or more of the pollutants to be monitored by that station; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAABEE32EEF714E978E0E279AA2E1304B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to making siting determinations—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCE1ECB20CF8444F923843E8B79F79BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hold at least 1 public hearing in or near each proposed siting location;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8175A1D8F798421EA8A88787A4073D2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide public notice of the proposed siting locations and the hearings required under clause (i)—</text>
<subclause commented="no" id="H28D85A6BD535436A8D48FDDB6AED2089"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the Federal Register;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H1A4AB060A3DF47A9B4A103E054B42486"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by email to persons who have requested notice of proposed siting determinations;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H58F5B307D8674CDA9D7E1ADA5B2C60F6"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by news release; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HBC8A4DAA2B8447DF9D2D23211E509417"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by posting on the public website of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H6BC02CDC104441A6AA046373E5FDFF0B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for public comment for not less than 60 days after the date of publication of the notice required under clause (ii) in the Federal Register; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7942FCDB604C464AA9542101A79BA8A5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>publish online an explanation and record for the siting decisions of the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F141B266C8D419EAAEA543416E5A1F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reliance on hybrid methods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining under paragraph (2)(B)(i) the potential for an air pollutant to reach or exceed the level of the applicable standard, the Administrator may rely on hybrid methods that combine information from multiple sources, including monitors, sensors, modeling, and satellites.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H0DEC63207D434A0CBB193F5DD47A27E9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional ambient monitors</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFC2A8D7F676C402A8E078880CFE67A6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall deploy not fewer than 100 additional Federal reference method monitors or Federal equivalent method monitors for 1 or more air pollutants for which national ambient air quality standards have been established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>) in areas—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H45F07F4541E34881AD5D5710A4ACF884"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that are unmonitored or undermonitored, as determined by the Administrator; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCB34174E68304EBE8883DE70EB226769"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within which the Administrator determines, after public notice and comment, that adding those monitors is warranted—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="HF1E25D8CF51F4111B6D5A7C2B1C19435"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to detect whether the area is in nonattainment of the applicable national ambient air quality standards; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H3D6E40D9C786484DBF11160A3AE86504"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to improve the publicly available data on air quality for 1 or more of those air pollutants (or precursors to those air pollutants).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC891498FD17E44D7BC41247D3A8E7537"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Siting determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In approving sites for new Federal reference method monitors or Federal equivalent method monitors required under this subsection, the Administrator shall prioritize siting of the stations in census tracts or counties in accordance with subsection (d)(2)(B).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD1DFD05C5B44568A1795AC4CE437CCC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relation to previously deployed or planned monitors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal reference method monitors required under this subsection shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any monitors already deployed or planned for deployment by the Administrator, any State, any other governmental entity, or any other entity prior to the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H8C6F28253A6E4AB0A9EA67B50BB6F3B1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H467B9B69C03E4ADC894A6D3B29FC03C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in coordination with the States, complete an assessment, which includes public input, on the status of all ambient air quality monitors that are part of Federal, State, or local networks and used for determining compliance with national ambient air quality standards, which shall identify—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC46021AF3EC448C0A5BB20D46D993AF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each monitor that is not operating properly and that needs to be repaired or replaced; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16D17DCF41914F6FB591F1C00762CB97"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each monitor that is past the end of its ordinary useful life; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HAC569B90EAC44037AFFE599DBBE0110F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress and make available on the public website of the Environmental Protection Agency a report that includes—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD4F4AF5E283142F7AC1D1968BEC6394E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of all monitors identified under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABB9F8C291AF4E478FD8F197F1839A44"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a schedule and plan to restore to proper operation or replace all monitors included in the list under paragraph (1)(A) and to replace all monitors included on the list under paragraph (1)(B), with all restorations and replacements to be completed not later than 40 months after the date of enactment of this Act, except that the schedule and plan shall not apply to monitors—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DCEAD69C84B4D129578F908A4066699"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that have been discontinued in accordance with section 58.14(c) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act); and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB009475843B744CEAD3594D9B55B133B"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB0B3BF4F02D140C1BF2E6376AD8EE8DC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which such discontinuation is not subject to a judicial challenge; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H4A13E2893CFC4C53A211537B1FCE13A5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which a judicial challenge described in subclause (I) has been fully resolved by a settlement or order that authorizes discontinuation of the monitor.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HB100AE96F223403B88698ED8AF33863A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Designations</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which data are received from a monitor sited pursuant to this section that demonstrate that an area designated by the Administrator pursuant to paragraph (1) of section 107(d) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7407">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)</external-xref>) as in attainment or unclassifiable for an air pollutant is not meeting or is contributing to air quality in a nearby area that does not meet 1 or more applicable national ambient air quality standards, the Administrator shall redesignate pursuant to paragraph (3) of that section that area as in nonattainment for that pollutant unless the designation is otherwise precluded under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HDA7558995599473792043E0747B613E8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Satellite monitoring</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD0915B64A64547099AA84ADDA49207A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of design value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>design value</term> means, for each pollutant, the air quality statistic the Administrator defines in part 50 (including appendices) of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), for comparison with the relevant national ambient air quality standard established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>), regardless of whether the regulation (including appendices) in part 50 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), uses the term <term>design value</term>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6301174F308848879FE8A229F4234004"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Satellite monitoring data</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA157BC59112F45DE976D2A6F27F0D45D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Provision of satellite data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall consult with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration on methods to facilitate the use of data from the satellites of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration or other entities for use in calculating design values under any national ambient air quality standards for PM<subscript>10</subscript>, PM<subscript>2.5</subscript>, ozone, and oxides of nitrogen for purposes of determining compliance or noncompliance with the national ambient air quality standards for those pollutants.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H338E83FC9DFA41679BB8B8A1B1A9D9BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall, after public notice in the Federal Register and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, promulgate regulations to specify procedures (including any modeling techniques) for using data described in subparagraph (A) in combination with information from multiple sources, including monitors and modeling, to calculate the expected number of exceedances per year and the design values for PM<subscript>10</subscript>, PM<subscript>2.5</subscript>, ozone, and oxides of nitrogen for purposes of determining compliance or noncompliance with the national ambient air quality standards for those pollutants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H9B9562F3172149AA996B8AE138B2CC15"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Academy of Sciences report</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1EDBA46D93B44BDBA4ED07E815662A56"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences under which the National Academy of Sciences agrees to submit a report that describes the actions necessary, including new science and satellite assets, to enable the contribution of satellite monitoring to the calculation of design values and nonattainment determinations under any national ambient air quality standards for ozone and oxides of sulfur established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0092309E692F4E03AD14F37975D8D252"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations required</header> <clause commented="no" id="HA5E611C75A8F4155BD1536DA44779408"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in coordination with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall, after public notice in the Federal Register and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, promulgate regulations that provide a plan for the use of satellite monitoring data in calculating design values for the pollutants described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H7BBAF44CB7E242CE88ECCCA842311B4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2028, the Administrator shall implement the plan required by clause (i) and provide for use of satellite data in calculating design values for the pollutants described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HF361D9F05B5146128F2636D4A14E66E6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Monitoring plans</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may not approve a State monitoring plan under section 58.10 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), unless—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC09B13C29FB94663AEA76E8E4E19CC37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State provided, with respect to the State monitoring plan—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H84F9D9DDE29647CF92CFBA7288699F9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public notice of the proposal of the plan in a highly accessible format in multiple languages, including a publicly accessible web page address where members of the public can at any time view the entire proposed plan and supporting materials;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5CD51CBB31744BD19AC75505F84EF0F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 45 days for public comment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDA3881A89D1C4CEC94B04F690F1B7EA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an opportunity for public hearing; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCBB71CDECD1C4ADA9B12379E7F4F619C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Administrator—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H20172FC2BCBC4D789D510B549A053E89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proposes in the Federal Register to approve or disapprove of the State monitoring plan;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA2CDD2D1BB7B4940A0B321C88C8761D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides not less than 45 days for public comment on the proposal described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4BC537CA7BE4894817D61F59E0A14C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>after consideration of any comments received pursuant to subparagraph (B), publishes in the Federal Register the final action on the proposal described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HB889E09E1A304DBB9BB345C8A32B3FD9"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Funding</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H5E773B76BB5B41598DDA625FC5D0D03E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $75,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1F05F49B73F14EC9B8CA41F92CADA660"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H90D278C20E67476CB1397A5EE1A2AA3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may use the amounts made available to carry out this section—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H302576D15DFE449DAAE5BF314C8124C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to directly deploy new or replacement NCore multipollutant monitoring stations required to be deployed under subsection (a)(1); or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H4BD259660F4545B5A1126AC5CC95E008"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to make grants under section 103 or 105 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7403">42 U.S.C. 7403</external-xref>, 7405) to State and local governments for deployment and operation of the NCore multipollutant monitoring stations required to be deployed under subsection (a)(1); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD54D7405A0B74E0EB57CA45E73E72F74"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall use not less than 5 percent, but not more than 10 percent, of the amounts made available to carry out this section to perform the maintenance and repairs necessary to restore to operation NCore multipollutant monitoring stations that are—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="HA58A34675CC74C6AB4AB3C719F93306A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as of the date of enactment of this Act, nonoperational; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF30D5BADA2CD4775863A7566DACE9565"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>located in areas that are designated as in nonattainment of national ambient air quality standards established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>) for ozone or particulate matter.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" id="HB94F4ED99BAA4E11842694A6A30F253E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Community air quality system monitoring</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="HDB5693C32B6B4D4A826FDFF5D0C12145"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deployment of air quality systems</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H1C4E3885FF604B2EA47F2CCA23AF8D12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator—</text> <subparagraph id="H71CF53E4DA2A477480A1D3DA07D59E7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall deploy, in accordance with the prioritization criteria described in section 5(d)(2), not fewer than 1,000 air quality systems, each of which shall cost not more than $5,000;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H52A313F155CB4833A7A73114C443AD98"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall deploy those air quality systems in clusters of not fewer than 5 in each of the census tracts or counties selected;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCEE809968384ED8A4B3CB4979C04592"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before determining and approving sites for those air quality systems, shall invite, through public notice and other means designed to reach communities disproportionately impacted by air pollution, proposals from or on behalf of residents of any community for the sites;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4EAAFE2B498C447FA98149DD7C2C5B1A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may contract with nonprofit organizations (including academic institutions) and State and local air pollution control agencies to conduct air quality system monitoring and report the results; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB99825EC126046B6866A42CBE5D4F6DE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall make data from air quality systems installed pursuant to this section public on an easily accessible data platform.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H9C5F6BE40730471BA2BD2DAFB1CFFB2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall select systems for deployment that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCEBD9318F534486D995C88E7AEB74B2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are available on the market at the time of purchase;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H164E699D38244AA38704478DC4AAEF33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator determines will provide data of sufficient accuracy to provide a reasonable basis for determining whether the location in which the air quality system is sited is or may be at risk of exceeding 1 or more national ambient air quality standards established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H406647060A4C44CD9C3D2E17723CF105"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are the lowest cost available that meet the standards described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3B4C9575D39438EB8154805F6E04571"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception to cost limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if the Administrator determines in writing that a system to measure a particular pollutant is not available on the market at a price at or below $5,000 each, the Administrator may spend an amount above $5,000 to acquire that system so long as the Administrator complies with subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HB703B0C008054700A4F8368B7724CB40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pollutants</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3640A8A31DEE4F94A9F2414982CA56B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H5DF4C3D0F47E4A1E91B76F88352ABD94"><enum>(A)</enum><header>List</header><text>Not fewer than 500 air quality systems deployed pursuant to subsection (a) shall measure 1 or more of the following pollutants:</text>
<clause id="H2D2D6CB701C24661894C40B6C3572CCB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Ozone.</text></clause> <clause id="H3A43177AE46A4619B4863B86ADF07309"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>PM<subscript>2.5</subscript>.</text></clause>
<clause id="H546A3FF75EAB4B7DB87E34060E52F725"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Oxides of nitrogen.</text></clause> <clause id="HDF2F393C40464F5FAF3628E852365678"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Sulfur dioxide.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8E53249E261B4B38927357262185C764"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required sensors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All air quality systems deployed pursuant to subsection (a) may include sensors to measure wind speed, wind direction, relative humidity, carbon dioxide and carbon monoxide, and other inputs that aid with source identification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H894B1718E07F4D0FB55E585BA72AB262"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall determine which air pollutant or air pollutants an air quality system deployed pursuant to subsection (a) shall monitor based on the pollution sources affecting the area in which the air quality system is to be deployed.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HB2C624E7D51C45BC8196FE13CAC597E0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination and installation</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCD192CB509664342982797D822DDFB8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date on which an air quality system deployed pursuant to subsection (a) has been monitoring air quality data for 1 year, the Administrator shall determine whether the air quality systems deployed in the applicable census tract or county reported air pollution levels over the 1-year period ending on the date of the determination that reached or exceeded 98 percent of the level of any applicable national ambient air quality standard established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>) for any air pollutant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5444269EC02F4F098DFCA0CFA7CF6FAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator makes a determination under paragraph (1) that an air pollutant described in subsection (b)(1) met or exceeded the threshold described in that paragraph, the Administrator shall, not later 180 days after the date of the determination, ensure that Federal reference method monitors or Federal equivalent method monitors are installed and in operation within that census tract or county for each pollutant that met or exceeded the threshold.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA9DA32CC0C9845FE92E8A6E7DE0CA0E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall waive the requirement of paragraph (2) if the Administrator finds, within the 180-day period described in that paragraph, and after providing notice and an opportunity for public comment, that based on clear and convincing evidence—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CD42EAB571D473E883BD855AC17F4D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the measurements from the systems supporting the determination described in paragraph (2) were so inaccurate as to provide no reasonable basis for finding that levels of the relevant pollutant reached 98 percent of the level of the national ambient air quality standard established under section 109 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7409">42 U.S.C. 7409</external-xref>) for the relevant pollutant; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H82C478A4DD1341A49ADFB103D368DCE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complementary data, such as information on the ambient matric, meteorology, measurements from other nearby systems or ambient monitors, modeling, satellite data, or other relevant and reliable information, demonstrate that levels of the relevant pollutant could not have plausibly reached 98 percent of the level of that standard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H553AEE366D034B62BF20496EFA9C5065"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, the Administrator shall make publicly available online a report describing additional areas in which data from low-cost air quality systems may be relevant or useful for decisionmaking or for the purpose of increasing public access to information.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HBD00157AC9524C7BA1BCA4F709F5CD64"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $6,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF335D2459FC645B18036076B800AF5BE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Hazardous air pollutant monitoring</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56D55152555B484F990EC68FF0232042"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, for the purposes of improving the quality of the national emissions inventory and advancing public access to information, the Administrator shall, after public notice and a public comment period of not less than 60 days, amend subpart A of part 51 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, to update and expand the requirements under that subpart to require all major and non-major sources to report additional emissions data, including emissions of hazardous air pollutants, perfluoroalkyl substances, and polyfluoroalkyl substances.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF84EF87D66F44899BF4BBF19708E00D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum requirements</header><text>The amendment required under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09121C43F84B4010939879472A79C67C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contain all amendments described in the proposed rule of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Revisions to the Air Emissions Reporting Requirements</quote> (88 Fed. Reg. 54118 (August 9, 2023));</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE2ADC4D1DF14DDCB3FAFDD803AB8714"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure reporting of emissions during periods of malfunction of the source; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71594832233744778E6F6295D7DEE7E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consistent with the proposal to require reporting of emissions of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances in the rule described in paragraph (1), require, in the reporting cycle immediately following the date on which a pollutant is listed as a hazardous air pollutant, the reporting of emissions of that pollutant.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6E996D344A3440EA90F4F14EE169DAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment required under subsection (a) shall take effect for the first inventory year that begins after that amendment is finalized.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H05AF57E1304D49749D77E99F8DCB70D2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Data requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Administrator shall—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC21AC8E4AFDF40DE80E1625EE612F40D"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1553BFD9436E406D9D7AB420F50617D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restore for public access the EJSCREEN mapping tool of the Environmental Protection Agency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D60EDE429A44416AC611CA417B97D05" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create a relevant, nationwide geospatial mapping and screening tool similar to and providing, at minimum, all of the data previously included in the EJSCREEN mapping tool that the Administrator, acting through the Assistant Administrator for Research and Development, shall make available online for public comment not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C4559B9A3164C64BFDD56DCCF123A3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrate into the applicable tool restored or created under paragraph (1) the data collected through the programs established under this Act.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD49BF818C4C34339A3DA11C0749E582B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act amends any other statute or revises or alters any duty or authority of the Administrator under any other applicable law.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

