<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H34C47AF807824DB9AE48DE5C50CD8734" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7100 IH: Sikh American Anti-Discrimination Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7100</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to establish a task force on anti-Sikh hate and discrimination.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H87EAD11BCCE34C7984304E79B2C3CF1A" style="OLC"><section id="HF5453C8773304D11B990055082943653" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sikh American Anti-Discrimination Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAB397610DD794D248045B24B89F6BF90"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Justice Task Force on Anti-Sikh hate and discrimination</header><subsection id="HDC324DEBF9A94DD7B4021337E0EEF89B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6EF45FC155D549A29DC4B68B35DC134A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sikhi is a monotheistic, pragmatic, independent and sovereign world religion that was founded by Guru Nanak in the 15th century in the Punjab region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53B55EA1317E47E6910A0C79506D56AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sikhs are commonly identified by the wearing of turbans, long beards or mustaches, karas (iron bracelets) on their wrists, or kirpans. Kirpans are mandatory Sikh articles of faith carried by Amritdhari (initiated) Sikhs at all times. The word <quote>kirpan</quote> comes from two Punjabi words: <quote>Kirpa</quote> means an act of kindness, a favor and <quote>Aan</quote> means honor and self-respect. While some Sikhs wear a combination of these items; others may be seen without a turban or facial hair.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5677B7FFB604B5188CD53952A4FCDED"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Anti-Sikh hate and discrimination refers to any act, practice, policy, or conduct that denies, restricts, or infringes upon the rights of individuals based on their actual or perceived Sikh faith, identity, ancestry, or expression. This includes incidents or crimes targeting Sikhs, individuals perceived to be Sikh, Gurdwaras (Sikh houses of worship), Sikh organizations, and property. It encompasses various forms of violence, threats, and harassment that are primarily motivated by religious or racial hostility, bigotry, hatred, or prejudice against Sikhs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H009F226B77A14496BDAE54E8C6733909"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Sikhs have experienced bias-based violence since their arrival in this country more than a century ago. From the 1907 Bellingham Riots to the surge in hate crimes following the September 11th attacks, Sikhs have experienced targeted violence in the United States for generations. While some instances of anti-Sikh violence have been linked to mistaken identity, there are several documented cases where Sikhs have been specifically targeted due to their faith or other aspects of their identities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37297C7F7D034473ABEE0FEA36672196"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One of the most violent manifestations of anti-Sikh hate and discrimination in the United States occurred on August 5, 2012, when a white supremacist gunman with neo-Nazi ties carried out a mass shooting at a Gurdwara in Oak Creek, Wisconsin, killing six worshippers and injuring others; a seventh victim later died in 2020 from injuries sustained in the attack. This targeted assault, one of the deadliest assaults against a house of worship in the history of the United States, remains a stark example of the extreme and violent forms anti-Sikh discrimination can take.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C740DACF394683A6FCE451DDCBF7A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On August 5, 2025, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (hereinafter known as the <quote>FBI</quote>) released its annual report on hate crime statistics for 2024, showing that Sikhs remain the third-most targeted religious group in the United States, despite comprising less than one percent of the national population. This disproportionate targeting underscores both the prevalence and severity of anti-Sikh hate and discrimination nationwide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H069C05ECCF3E44198B0E6366067CBA40"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The true scope of anti-Sikh hate crimes in the United States is likely greater than Federal statistics indicate, as hate crime reporting is not federally mandated and many jurisdictions fail to submit annual data. Highlighting this gap, on November 15, 2023, the former Director of the FBI noted in a hearing before the House Homeland Security Committee that hate crimes against the Sikh community, among others, are <quote>chronically underreported</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9220897728024EE99757F436ABDDE711"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On December 12, 2024, the White House released the U.S. National Strategy to Counter Islamophobia, which acknowledges that greater efforts at combating anti-Sikh bias and hate must be made to better protect members of the Sikh community. The strategy emphasized the need for increased awareness, understanding, and action to combat hate speech and discriminatory practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0FE9D4713764E4492292F6D55703808"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Hatred and violence targeting the Sikh community in the United States may also originate from, or be supported by, foreign entities and governments and can take the form of transnational repression. The FBI has warned the Sikh community about such targeting by foreign governments. This phenomenon was underscored when the Department of Justice indicted two individuals for involvement in the attempted assassination of a Sikh American in 2023. Such developments underline the ongoing and varied forms of hate and violence that Sikhs continue to face.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H001BA32485B944F591AB2B4F65887517"><enum>(10)</enum><text>On June 3, 2025, following the prosecution and conviction of an individual for making violent threats against employees of a Sikh American advocacy group, Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights Harmeet Kaur Dhillon addressed the issue of hateful rhetoric against Sikh Americans and stated, <quote>The Department of Justice has no tolerance for hate-fueled threats of violence in our country.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB754383F4CC4C889FDC8B282E7CBA08"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Anti-Sikh hate and discrimination comes in many forms and includes—</text><subparagraph id="H5713E73FB84245E8B9D597A89CDFA516"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">physical violence and hate crimes, which can include acts of assault, shooting, vandalism, arson, or other criminal conduct intended to cause bodily injury, death, or destruction of property, where such conduct is directed at Sikh individuals, or Sikh places of worship (Gurdwaras), institutions, properties, or organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE29B96F148F440EB48BAA89FD0E8E57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>harassment and intimidation, which can include the making of violent threats, verbal abuse, hate speech, or other communications that incite, call for, justify, or promote violence, as well as conduct that places a Sikh individual or organization in reasonable fear of bodily injury or damage to property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6172D58D1EB40CFAEEC068B7C8F68EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>stereotyping and vilification, which can include dissemination of false narratives that target Sikhs with a dehumanizing intent, collectively blaming or defaming the Sikh people or portraying the Sikh community in ways that normalize prejudice and incite hostility toward Sikh identity and Sikh expression;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0453B5448FD84DF3A025ECEF47B630C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>civil rights violations, which can include the denial of equal treatment, protection, or opportunity in employment, education, or government services, including the adoption or enforcement of policies, rules, or practices that prohibit, restrict, or penalize the wearing of Sikh articles of faith, or otherwise interfere with the free exercise of religion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3ABD04F254C4426ADB26D34D4D005CC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>transnational repression, which can include acts of harassment, intimidation, surveillance, coercion, threats, or violence, directed at United States-based Sikhs, that are conducted by or on behalf of a foreign government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EC6B0A3DEAE48D0A774983E88CCA993"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Sikhs in the United States endure persistent discrimination, harassment, and violence in their daily lives, facing a unique combination of hate violence, prejudice, religious discrimination, and transnational repression. Addressing this requires a dedicated task force focused specifically on combating anti-Sikh hate and discrimination in all its forms.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CA6AC65946B44578E71AF20733B1306"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Task force</header><paragraph id="H4BC705237FDA452BB30B7DB40A228D71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish a Task Force on Anti-Sikh Hate and Discrimination (hereinafter known as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EBDA5BC2F5642D896127A4D74D65A65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text><subparagraph id="H6B760976B4D24856A205BDF6D743D00E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>draft a definition of anti-Sikh hate and discrimination for the Department of Justice to assist in prosecutorial decision-making and collecting statistics on offenses under section 249 of title 18, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7566DC3BCC4C43EB8A7D29D866F51F56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop an educational program that may be disseminated to local and Federal law enforcement agencies, elementary schools and secondary schools, and institutions of higher education on Sikh and identifying anti-Sikh hate and discrimination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40CF86A782CC419F86C6D11E85731B67"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="H717191055C2247938F38D57914D8F69B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual Report</header><text>The Task Force shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report including an overview of—</text><clause id="H9DCE4C5B0DDF4A1E9C42C3458FC3D9B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hate crimes against a Sikh victim;</text></clause><clause id="H6A8ACC79EC6A4A2B8ECD1372DA1D9DE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any action brought against a perpetrator of a hate crime against a Sikh victim;</text></clause><clause id="H9497778A1F9D42DD87F242B86F92F4FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any ongoing threats and trends in hate against Sikhs, from transnational repression and other sources; and</text></clause><clause id="HA5FFAE01B0CF4196BE41FDECA2A19B7B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any efforts undertaken by the Department of Justice to combat anti-Sikh hate and discrimination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35AB55A850BD47849FBF0A5F4A734DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every five years, the Task Force shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report summarizing the annual reports under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H812E7986DFA644E2B10AD2B6C5D30CE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Translation</header><text>The Task Force shall translate any public resources or materials released by the Task Force into Punjabi.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24B06789C7BC412F988119B850BED5E9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall meet, on a quarterly basis, to collaborate with members of the Sikh community and Sikh organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE42AF5D2DE0E4D91912316F49CD8A81E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall be construed to require the Attorney General to adopt the definition of anti-Sikh hate and discrimination developed under subsection (b)(2)(A) for all relevant purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1394813EB20A4C0D92816D6832297EB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB59D3BE391BE4C479156CA10BCEAC506"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elementary schools and secondary schools</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>elementary schools and secondary schools</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE952AC65D13F4B16BB2730EAC05D576E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institutions of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institutions of higher education</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

