<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H0512C6CB92304CABBF0FF1CCED325880" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5694 RH: Alaska’s Right to Ivory Sales and Tradition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 588</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5694</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–674]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251006">October 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on October 6, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to protect the cultural practices and livelihoods of producers of Alaska Native handicrafts and marine mammal ivory products, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H5829E01117A8426B8ED98201D6A4654D"><section id="HB3C08DAF6E5142319E5E312636E6CC36" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alaska’s Right to Ivory Sales and Tradition Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ARTIST Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H00F84429B45B471398983A9E8CA7A5EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alaska Native handicrafts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(b) of the Marine Mammal Protection Act Of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1371">16 U.S.C. 1371(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H141157FF38E74EBC9506EEE1D57EA693" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H52C50567682F4F00AF3CAF003F607B4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for Alaskan Natives</header><paragraph id="H91D26DA34E8D4C35B8F7707743248B6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H7077F1BDDCF14298BBB34C2FFC80226E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authentic Alaska Native article of handicrafts and clothing</header><text>The term <term>authentic Alaska Native article of handicrafts and clothing</term> means an item composed wholly, or in some significant respect, of natural materials and that is produced, decorated, or fashioned in the exercise of traditional Alaska Native handicrafts by an Alaska Native who resides in Alaska and who dwells on the coast of the North Pacific Ocean or the Arctic Ocean without the use of a pantograph, multiple carvers, or any other mass copying device. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05B21DA6A77B456AABE1020AED55BE26" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Marine mammal ivory</header><text>The term <term>marine mammal ivory</term> includes a tooth or tusk from a walrus (Odobenus rosmarus) or a species of cetacean. <italic></italic></text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A64C815BD804033BDE0FCF1D9EA39DE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Traditional Alaska Native handicrafts</header><text>The term <term>traditional Alaska Native handicrafts</term> includes weaving, carving, stitching, sewing, lacing, beading, drawing, and painting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F4B210493DE492AB88B09601731246D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><subparagraph id="H4DE713004E6E4C75B8491943C780432A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in section 109, the provisions of this Act shall not apply with respect to the taking of any marine mammal by any Alaska Native who resides in Alaska and who dwells on the coast of the North Pacific Ocean or the Arctic Ocean if such taking—</text><clause id="HA31BCF87AFAE45D2A76AA99D504FDAFC"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7146DB00294F4F4099583BA7A4183EEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is for subsistence purposes; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE585783FA4504AA68DDEDE14B2D231D5" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is done for purposes of creating and selling authentic Alaska Native articles of handicrafts and clothing; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBA1534B59637477C87433C49A616ED79"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in each case, is not accomplished in a wasteful manner.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C36E3ACC88E4E2A96E142A86959B626" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules</header><clause id="H8E7E2545E7C54FCDBED10FF4016EA7CB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Interstate commerce of items</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An item presented as an authentic Alaska Native article of handicrafts and clothing may be sold in interstate commerce only if it comports with the definition provided in paragraph (1)(A). </text></clause><clause id="H4EFE0C01A3104233B780314CC492B24C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Edible portion of marine mammal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any edible portion of a marine mammal taken for the purpose of creating and selling authentic Alaska Native articles of handicrafts and clothing may be sold for native consumption or in a native village or town in Alaska. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H388713F4AF2A4E8C8AFE0B3571F07795"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="H69C59F0AFA794F0F9E8AC43E78818F11"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), if, under this Act, the Secretary determines any species or stock of marine mammal subject to taking by Alaska Natives to be depleted, the Secretary may prescribe regulations upon the taking of such marine mammals by any Alaska Native described in this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70103D7B9F004692A05CEEDD87164202"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Content of regulations</header><text>The regulations described in subparagraph (A) may be established with reference to species or stocks, geographical area, the season for taking, or any other factors related to the reason for establishing such regulations and consistent with the purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H114DE21985304B028801D425FFED9458"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice and hearing; removal of regulations</header><text>The regulations described in subparagraph (A) shall be prescribed after notice and hearing required by section 103 of this title and shall be removed as soon as the Secretary determines that the need for their imposition has disappeared.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FE0A9CB9DDF47D78ABB7DF5D3482CA8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Regulations to be supported by substantial evidence</header><text>In promulgating any regulation or making any assessment pursuant to a hearing or proceeding under this subsection or section 117(b)(2), or in making any determination of depletion under this subsection or finding regarding unmitigable adverse impacts under subsection (a)(5) that affects stocks or persons to which this subsection applies, the Secretary shall demonstrate in writing (and make such writing publicly available on the website of the Secretary) that, in consideration of the whole record, including Indigenous knowledge, such regulation, assessment, determination, or finding is supported by substantial evidence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88010F8499644C7398273165A30C7E5A"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The requirement under subparagraph (D) shall only be applicable in an action brought by one or more Alaska Native organizations representing persons to which this subsection applies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5CBD7B770674F799F277C627AE1BC91"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>No State shall prohibit the interstate commerce, importation, sale, offer for sale, transfer, trade, barter, possession, or possession with the intent to sell, transfer, trade, or barter of marine mammal ivory or marine mammal bone or baleen incorporated under this title by an Alaska Native, into an authentic Alaska Native article of handicrafts and clothing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEACA652DAD6455D98F661DBEBEC184F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to—</text><subparagraph id="H3593F34E0B074105983159EB55E2C890"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impact the rights of any Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)) in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alaska’s Right to Ivory Sales and Tradition Act</short-title>; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CB3772352434954A916EBED07308242"><enum>(B)</enum><text>undermine any government-to-government consultation or engagement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

