<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3DFEDEC80AD540059C280111AE8D54C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6336 IH: Fair Allocation of Interstate Rates Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6336</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000482">Ms. Fedorchak</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the allocation of costs for a certain transmission facility to consumers of a State the public officials of which did not expressly consent to such transmission facility, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFA3691379AD1416AB7EC58E6890FC0B6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9FF073E6821C499CAB6966717539F6DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Allocation of Interstate Rates Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9C1419170FA0460E90839A310071A214"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rate and charges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 205 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824d">16 U.S.C. 824d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H99DC9A37379E40FCA7092976D9BE99D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H143AC60E539A4268BDD29F0E3E502F73"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> 
<paragraph id="H7069153AC76744579A3B96605A279D23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no transmission provider providing electric service to consumers in two or more States may allocate costs for a covered transmission facility to any consumer of such transmission provider if—</text> <subparagraph id="H2860360AED1C457CB425C3105D46E05B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the basis for construction or implementation of such covered transmission facility is, in whole or in part, to implement a covered policy of a State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4B403DDAA6D49B699C75A06523CB3E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such consumer is not a resident of the State the covered policy of which is the basis for constructing or implementing such covered transmission facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FC3D0653793484580ED686A2895A773"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A transmission provider providing electric service to consumers in two or more States may allocate costs for a covered transmission facility to a consumer described in paragraph (1)(B) if the State of such consumer, or a designated public official of such State, expressly consents to such allocation of costs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC83CFC9EEF6407286292673D188F9D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Presumptions</header><text>It shall be presumed that—</text> <subparagraph id="H157DF50B6D944828833CF6F5F98FF7A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the benefits of a covered transmission facility accrue solely to the cost causers of such covered transmission facility;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B148D4971D94A8EBA98877AC53695EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>only a consumer that resides in a State that implemented a covered policy that is, in whole or in part, the basis for constructing or implementing such covered transmission facility is a cost causer for purposes of subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC35C97063E343569F00355EF1D0ACF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a consumer that does not reside in the State described in subparagraph (B) is not a cost causer for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8693E44F39D04D3283A66EB0331F0BB2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Commission shall issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary to implement this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F28902DD7624AA18916910C63FCDA8A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC9D465185B304AC4A688C51002784F02"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered policy</header><text>The term <term>covered policy</term> means a policy of a State, including policies of the local political entities of such State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5C6F3D37E46412383FFD62F5D54A106"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered transmission facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered transmission facility</term> means any facility, line, equipment, or system used for the transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce that is planned, constructed, or operated in whole or in part to implement a covered policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

