<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H25E0B7D5ECEE43F98D7CC50819D7C00A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9402 IH: Stop Spying Bosses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9402</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit, or require disclosure of, the surveillance, monitoring, and collection of certain worker data by employers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H78EB390687A743B680DBF778F77EBB37" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H60FB147B2DFE4C0D9CEF95CB1D906C06"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Spying Bosses Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC2D385D3740F46F899DD0C61D38940E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H77F906803EC34DD594B2F6C2C817B2E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Worker Protection and Technology Division established under section 6.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HAC3843A9B82A41F4A1D45537B056080F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregated data</header><text>The term <term>aggregated data</term> means data with respect to covered individuals of an employer that the employer has combined or collected together in a summary or other form that prevents the identification of any specific individual.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2096E2419BC448A885D0F577188E2BB2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term>, with respect to an employer, means an individual who applies, or applied, to be employed by, or otherwise perform work for remuneration for, the employer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFC066E13F2094A6DB2C0BEC38A4A54E4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Automated decision system</header> <subparagraph id="H04E70CBFC7974D8EA03C5A7E8E9CCE75"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>automated decision system</term> means any system, software, or process (including such a system, software, or process derived from machine learning, statistics, or other data processing or artificial intelligence techniques) that—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H720A7A77139A474C9ECBBE2B5C983C87"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses computation to produce a prediction, score, ranking, recommendation, decision, evaluation, metric, conclusion, inference, or profile; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09D3C16E4C9D42348410C91D5095CCA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not passive computing infrastructure.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB31BFED787DB4A8093DD83ADF6C8FAFD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Passive computing infrastructure</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>passive computing infrastructure</term> means any intermediary technology that does not influence or determine the outcome of a decision, make or aid in a decision (including through evaluations, metrics, or scoring), inform policy implementation, or collect data or observations, including web hosting, domain registration, networking, caching, data storage, or cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93B16B0F4EBD4A9CBDEC23591527DBBC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Biometric information</header> <subparagraph id="H24C07367714C40C1858672864D20AFF9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>biometric information</term> means any information generated from the technological processing of an individual’s unique biological, physical, or physiological characteristics that is linked or reasonably linkable to an individual, including—</text>
<clause id="H5C5FE2EB2C0D4A00B428250F50EB74A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fingerprints;</text></clause> <clause id="HAB56795EDA794D8A8C216A66D6109A10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>voice prints;</text></clause>
<clause id="H26013FCAE03E44F88AF4C0D45E30273D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>iris or retina scans;</text></clause> <clause id="H595DE92D24204B04BBAC12F21DF92521"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facial or hand mapping, geometry, or templates; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H93A82A798AB04C898D67641269A7ADE3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>gait or personally identifying physical movements.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACF8AB0B8309485EBF42C3868B4EDDFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>biometric information</term> does not include—</text>
<clause id="H3E92491DB40540CA9ECDA7CDEFE647CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a digital or physical photograph;</text></clause> <clause id="HAF04BD9F76F947ED99F50930CC42D64A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an audio or video recording; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H5476B0178459433E8BCDCFA6703B35CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information generated from a digital or physical photograph, or an audio or video recording, that cannot be used to identify an individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7C5A824E345445BA4A2150B4B377EF0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Collect</header><text>The term <term>collect</term> means, with respect to employee data, to buy, rent, gather, obtain, receive, access, or otherwise acquire employee data by any means.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBEE792890C374C67AF60F95B9C0F11B9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term>, with respect to an employer, means an individual—</text> <subparagraph id="H625D39CBFD8E44F4B6181535C611C9D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is employed by, or otherwise performing work for remuneration for the employer, including such an individual who is—</text>
<clause id="HADACE8CC2C3A47E68AB1D9EFE2BCD01C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employer described in clauses (i)(I) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A);</text></clause> <clause id="H1189DF69FFA64E8DB001865D41D9C0A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an entity described in clauses (i)(II) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A);</text></clause>
<clause id="H9547727098054642B8E7E690E1FE0D8E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing office described in clauses (i)(III) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A);</text></clause> <clause id="H7D82F9B09EB445F28FAB5336C705D938"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing office described in clauses (i)(IV) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A); or</text></clause>
<clause id="H5D038BB05F1043C38612EF514B7D66AB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing agency described in clauses (i)(V) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A) who is not covered under clause (iv); or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDD557DD350F4017A90E00595E3C4770"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is an applicant to the employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7A6052E98E8B4FDDBEA8D824D1C3F153"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Employ</header><text>The term <term>employ</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4B1931F657074D488A25A280B3EC4F8D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Employer</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD3998BE631544042AE40E7296970DFD6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means any person who is—</text>
<clause id="H6D6C5024152747FE8555FFED70BAB963"><enum>(i)</enum>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBE4BD25836DA4B90A28A9A713AACE026"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a covered employer who is not described in any other subclause of this clause;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H939D8599DA4E4342824BDF7358D77DB4" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an entity employing a State employee described in section 304(a) of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16c(a));</text></subclause>
<subclause indent="up1" id="HFF80F7248D4F4D3380B845D9311BDA22"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an employing office, as defined in section 101 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>);</text></subclause> <subclause indent="up1" id="HE06436785AB041869A4E70999E7A9295"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an employing office, as defined in section 411(c) of title 3, United States Code; or</text></subclause>
<subclause indent="up1" id="H140DB3271FE84E69AA7FE5C270098E13"><enum>(V)</enum><text>an employing agency covered under subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H72EC36CA61884E77990B6671350CC097"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engaged in commerce (including government), or an industry or activity affecting commerce (including government).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H605B575D859D4C6D96A817D274848D0A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered employer</header><text>In subparagraph (A), the term <term>covered employer</term>—</text> <clause id="HC36AEECD69A749F6844A3370C0015BEF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means any person engaged in commerce or in any industry or activity affecting commerce who employs or otherwise engages for the performance of work for remuneration, 11 or more covered individuals;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HD7705E185D144FB79A5D316561B95800"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HC3C8945A1E1D42A4A567493D6404F083"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any person who acts, directly or indirectly, in the interest of a covered employer in relation to any individual performing work for remuneration for such covered employer;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H54B95CFFF1CF4E1CB7BF26C145A106D2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any successor in interest of a covered employer;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H5742FFE05A2847FEB0A6FACEAD570F88"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any public agency; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="HB87687C96B3E43F4847E99A7B5BC3ED5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HD725DD62EEEC43439362AD3914FB2D1E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include any labor organization (other than when acting as an employer) or anyone acting in the capacity of officer or agent of such labor organization.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA63B4E0C2CD644ABA5B5163E13606072"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public agency</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, a public agency shall be considered to be a person engaged in commerce or in an industry or activity affecting commerce.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H698E2528FBB247508FF4C660B07C0467"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <term>commerce</term>, <term>person</term>, and <term>public agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA5A58DFDE6C64F5DB146A74395005DE6"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Employee data</header><text>The term <term>employee data</term>, with respect to a covered individual, means any information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with the covered individual, regardless of how the information is collected, inferred, or obtained, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D40E23C7E954C83A6A002FA2D9FFE0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>personally identifiable information with respect to the covered individual, including any name, contact information, government-issued identification number, financial information, criminal background, location information, photographs, biometric information, or employment history associated with the covered individual; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBF7FD2EBC895452EAF58F8949D0EA6B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any information related to the workplace activities with respect to the covered individual, including—</text> <clause id="H8867A5D61FC64AABAF9ED91D29F9FB2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>human resources information, including the contents of a personnel file or performance evaluation;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9E4399DC37084257883B9BD46EBEE378"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>work process information, such as productivity and efficiency information and information on breaks;</text></clause> <clause id="HA66C65045B37447BB392D63B38958C91"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information that captures workplace communications and interactions, including emails, texts, internal message boards, and customer interaction and ratings;</text></clause>
<clause id="HD127EFE5B717435FB2C3A5BACDFC4A72"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>device usage and information, including calls placed or precise geolocation information;</text></clause> <clause id="H82B75FEC5A7E409789BD8472DEBF509B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>audio-video information and other information collected from sensors, including movement tracking, images, videos, and thermal-sensor information;</text></clause>
<clause id="H71C718272F3447DCBD21716FA9B4A1D3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>biometric information;</text></clause> <clause id="H920FC8C6892847DAAFBACFF6A18EF002"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>information from a personality test taken by a covered individual, including such a test given electronically at the beginning of or during a work shift;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF610EFAF237D452AA119B5A9CFE35C08"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>inputs for an automated decision system or any automated decision system output;</text></clause> <clause id="H2CD59F86FED94A95AF9595EB28644290"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>information that is collected or generated to mitigate the spread of infectious diseases, including COVID–19, or to comply with any public health measure; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HD37E4639865E41029A78C6B2761714F9"><enum>(x)</enum><text>online information, including a covered individual’s internet protocol address, private social media activity, or other digital sources or unique identifiers associated with a covered individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE84A29A8367D4831BC7DBC9529FDA41B"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Government entity</header><text>The term <term>government entity</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB480EC661F2348CB8431FEAA0B3BAC9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal agency (as such term is defined in section 3371 of title 5, United States Code);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4621E0EB58664E35AF340B5F66FDB661"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State or political subdivision thereof;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H68F089DDBDC94705B369413829DFAD5F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any agency, authority, or instrumentality of a State or political subdivision thereof; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFCB7AFD77ED741F29AE20FBBF60FCB2D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Tribal government or political subdivision thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2121B02DC0A04E7686EB4AFEF5FBE9FA"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this Act pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD463031F8A2D4D71BB684052FF1CBA7A"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2(5) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152(5)</external-xref>), except that such term shall also include—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDFD75615E21B4C6F89F7726159F0F9C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any organization composed of labor organizations, such as a labor union federation or a State or municipal labor body; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5F69715CC6A4C35B24C83BF6D62388C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any organization which would be included in the definition for such term under such section 2(5) but for the fact that the organization represents—</text>
<clause id="H8F0B479E9590468C829119EE59FD85E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals employed by the United States, any wholly owned Government corporation, any Federal Reserve Bank, or any State or political subdivision thereof;</text></clause> <clause id="H39DBF8261127436DB89C7D42DED2F435"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals employed by persons subject to the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause>
<clause id="HF3F194D142764E7DB1A8F59A43596531"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individuals employed as agricultural laborers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EA4D7F096B748078E812CCECFDC78E6"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Periodic assessment of worker performance</header><text>The term <term>periodic assessment of worker performance</term> means assessing worker performance over the course of units of time equal to or greater than one calendar day.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2A692E6CC3BF4587B9BF0B6A840298EA"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Precise geolocation information</header>
<subparagraph id="H98FF8B13088D4521A6484BBF69EAA01B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>precise geolocation information</term> means information that is derived from a device or technology that reveals the past or present physical location of an individual or a device that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable to 1 or more individuals, with sufficient precision to identify street level location information of the individual or device or the location of the individual or device within a range of 1,850 feet or less.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8242B40B76284B74A1EAD959DBD5AA3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>precise geolocation information</term> does not include information described in subparagraph (A) identifiable or derived solely from the visual content of a legally obtained image, including the location of the device that captured such image.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBA481809E55A4408BE4963881ED0B11D"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Predispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85C31128C86D48E192214186A9C0B4DE"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Predispute joint-action waiver</header><text>The term <term>predispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement, whether or not part of a predispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H49B53B6DFD94465BBDD8985450060C2B"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E236094BCF349AD86B5352B35BB4E9B"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Sell</header><text>The term <term>sell</term>, with respect to employee data, means the transfer of such employee data for monetary consideration or for a thing of value.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB72BA3BE0796430CBC03FE418AF29623"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Service provider</header><text>The term <term>service provider</term>, with respect to an employer, means a person that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE489521E019B4FD29A8CF2B1C0600115"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collects, processes, conveys, or maintains employee data with respect to such employer only at the direction of, in accordance with the direction of, and pursuant to a written contract with the employer (including any terms of service or service agreements);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0E8B4E9DF09A45A480E513F6E6B72579"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not earn revenue from such collection, processing, conveyance, or maintenance of such employee data, except from the employer by providing contracted services to the employer with regard to such collection, processing, conveyance, or maintenance of such employee data; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H935525861E6E4C889B861422ADBC43B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not combine or link data associated with such employer with data associated with another employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE0E1AECAB6AD4DF68313AA0B375D9C7F"><enum>(21)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6AC3AE09A0248009FC275586B300B50"><enum>(22)</enum><header>State attorney general</header><text>The term <term>State attorney general</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF934AFF97DCC45C2A4CF6DBB4F01E7BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a State, the attorney general or chief law enforcement officer of the State, or another official or agency designated by the State to bring civil actions on behalf of the State or the residents of the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA0689019635942A5B6BDF4488C66A43F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a Tribal government, the attorney general or chief law enforcement officer of the Tribal government, or another official or agency designated by the Tribal government to bring civil actions on behalf of the Tribal government or the Indian Tribe of the Tribal government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HB1D7663360364C26AD9F70E60805CFCF"><enum>(23)</enum><header>State privacy regulator</header><text>The term <term>State privacy regulator</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC840ECA0400F4B9FAFD4ADE7B9798A2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chief consumer protection officer of a State; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAF1C2055BF004D85B9C7BCCA637A3944"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State consumer protection agency with expertise in data protection, including the California Privacy Protection Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H70A6A6C4F125445AB643EA687ACBB33E"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Technologist</header><text>The term <term>technologist</term> means an individual with experience in fields related to computational technology, or the technology industry that produces computational technology, such as advertising technology, application development, artificial intelligence, computer science, cybersecurity, data science, digital forensics, human-centered design, product management, prototyping, service design, socio-technical systems, software engineering, user experience, or privacy rights, civil liberties, or civil rights related to technology.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE80987DF00284E2DBA3DAC3BE4E91992"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Third party</header><text>The term <term>third party</term>, with respect to an employer, means a person or entity that is not—</text> <subparagraph id="H40349380FFFB4829963ACA846A0DA11A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such employer;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H420E035EFE854A478EDE72709FCC24DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a service provider of such employer with respect to the employee data being transferred; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B553902F1BD4255AAD44FB11462A692"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a government entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57FCC7EEE56E40608EA23004D26BAD66"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>The term <term>transfer</term>, with respect to employee data, means releasing, sharing, leasing, disseminating, disclosing, making available, or otherwise causing to be communicated such employee data.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39461D154D264A249180A0B99117C90A"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3F03721B677945B1BBF1BC5C36AE55A8" commented="no"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Work-related decision</header><text>The term <term>work-related decision</term> includes a decision by an employer with regard to—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8828AE06F094FA99F76653FF8040CC7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hiring or engaging a covered individual (including any decision with regard to recruiting, screening, interviewing, reviewing, or selecting an applicant);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA33A29048C144A58A4A7E044315594D2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>firing, retaining, taking a disciplinary action against, demoting, deactivating, or reassigning duties of a covered individual; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC57B2985E3A142279368E44A0209B313" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other term, condition, or privilege of employment or other work of the covered individual, such as relating to wages, wage setting, work hours, scheduling, attendance requirements, workload, performance standards, assignment of work, access to work and training opportunities, productivity requirements, promotion, workplace health and safety, health care or long-term care coverage, or other benefits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="HF19DFDB91FFA487E8BD908A086C20155"><enum>3.</enum><header>Employee data minimization</header>
<subsection id="HABD81FF68620473F93E28A193B02A75F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employee data collection and usage prohibitions</header>
<paragraph id="H71DC2BC8CC054298BB22F472B468C840"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise required by law, an employer or, as applicable, a service provider of the employer may not collect or use employee data—</text> <subparagraph id="H8810C655422E410BA41BC180B4BAD6DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify any covered individual to determine if they have or intend to form, join, assist, or seek to form, join, or assist, a labor organization;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE2CB4755451E41B39B93F5A52321B684"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to monitor the activities of any covered individual concerning or related to a labor organization or with respect to engaging in protected concerted activity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB455B326336E47438088EEF4D3E83D59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to ascertain any political opinion or activity, religious view, or other identity marker of the covered individual, that is unrelated to the performance of the job duties of the covered individual for the employer;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDE51DB673AA444D29959B8C9B0C07BB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to identify the health status, any health condition, or disability status of a covered individual that is unrelated to the performance of the job duties of the covered individual for the employer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8D6E3DFBA3B436CB32AF091C4CC9213"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to ascertain the immigration status of a covered individual;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA102DBBE1E774AB084641B9A415C5604"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to monitor the activities of any covered individual concerning or related to reporting the employer, or a third party or service provider of the employer, for a violation of any other law, including monitoring for purposes of identifying a covered individual who has reported or intends to report the employer or such a third party or service provider;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60894C1C4A0A45A5832B9C82CA75632B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to predict any behavior, emotion, or belief of a covered individual that is unrelated to the work of the covered individual for the employer; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A16AED2B3D94E22B88C6994405C1E36"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to threaten the mental or physical health of the covered individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE429AF7D09194E789A1B608E05BE96FC"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Off-duty employee data collection</header> <text>An employer or, as applicable, a service provider of the employer may not collect employee data regarding a covered individual while the covered individual is off-duty, including when the covered individual is off-duty in—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="H09372C04CB544EECBAD1BCD978D3CF23">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a break room or in a sensitive area, such as a restroom or locker room;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="HFEFF87E8A05E4EE2B2ECC471322D6C8B">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a location provided for the covered individual to express breast milk;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="H716AA0F76CC644FDA345D18410A45AA1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a location provided for the covered individual to pray or participate in a religious activity; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="H38D8068B22844D11AD36DB26E513C0A0">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>the home of the covered individual or an alternative location where work is performed that is not the worksite of employer.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA927B9CD9E804FFEA1275AD2521D83A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissible employee data collection</header><text>An employer or, as applicable, a service provider of the employer may collect employee data with respect to a covered individual only if—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4B521279255467AA30CA185FEA0B038"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the collection of employee data is not otherwise prohibited by subsection (a);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H151E795D5DAB43AF9C92071AFFB6BEBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employee data is primarily used—</text> <subparagraph id="HE78760458D644149ACE2A3857F7097EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to allow the covered individual to accomplish an essential job function;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9EA8B364DCE423DB73C4B9F31561253"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to ensure the quality of goods and services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89185749C3F2456C9CD5373F65466944"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to conduct a periodic assessment of worker performance;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H26493DE1C1B34C7A9FFB05EB8805449A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with employment, labor, or other relevant laws;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65DCC4197E14471C9A617AE73E811F10"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to protect the health, safety, or security of a covered individual or the security of the a facility or computer network of the employer; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8070DE1A72CE4D1DB00690A8A42FE69B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to administer wages or benefits to a covered individual;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H608FF58BF33A4CFC8794B123E5FC89E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the employee data is collected and used solely for a purpose disclosed by the employer in accordance with section 4(a)(1)(G);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H56F210490CC24B4A8BC82E1CBAA3AC44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the collection of employee data is strictly necessary to accomplish such a purpose, exclusively used to accomplish the purpose, and is the least invasive means to the covered individual that could be used to accomplish the purpose;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64CF84BB5CF94B279DB666936DB93C54"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the collection of employee data is limited to the fewest covered individuals needed for such collection;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7E1C9DBC64394BFA9497EC5883C079EF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the least amount of employee data is collected;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H335C6A5EA1194252BBED6E295A5A0E5A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>employee data is collected no more frequently than is necessary to accomplish the purpose; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5724BFDB7BB143328E0209E9BEBE6A7D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the employee data is only retained by the employer or, as applicable, the service provider for only as long as it is reasonably necessary for the purpose and, except as otherwise required to be retained by law, is deleted by the employer on the date that is 3 years after the date of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BC9CEB63C5145A8944568B5865EE976"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the separation of the covered individual from employment by or engagement for work with the employer; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F48D5B6E3E24A6F9B914795E37DFE9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a covered individual who is an applicant that was not employed by or otherwise engaged for work for remuneration by the employer, the discontinuation of the application process of the covered individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD29A72D708A44F8EBCB43F780907DF58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of employee data</header> <paragraph id="H37C0667882274889A8FF20741F5A1915"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on selling</header><text>An employer or, as applicable, a service provider of the employer may not sell or license employee data on a covered individual to any person (including a service provider of the employer).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6046B8AF15294FC78E4F295E33306FC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer restrictions to a service provider</header><text>Except as otherwise required by law, an employer or, as applicable, a service provider of the employer may not transfer employee data on a covered individual to any service provider of the employer unless, for each instance of a transfer—</text> <subparagraph id="H1655014449F74AFEBBE5B77841289D78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the employer or the service provider making the transfer—</text>
<clause id="HEB20739501C24622AA7541CBDDF94084"><enum>(i)</enum><text>discloses the transfer to the covered individual; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE2704167D94A408B9D32298C01DF34C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides cybersecurity protections and encryption for the employee data; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H309FEC9BDE484E17BEA99AA11C017B9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered individual opts in to the instance of the transfer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77C697377C4744479D28A443A7F61659"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer prohibition to a third party</header><text>An employer or, as applicable, a service provider of the employer may not transfer employee data on a covered individual to a third party, except as otherwise required by law.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC5AC26D1C2374777849CA40A79B3A2E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employer contracts with service providers that collect employee data</header><text>A service provider of an employer that collects or uses employee data regarding covered individuals of the employer shall include in any contract between the employer and service provider entered into after the effective date of this section an agreement to comply with the requirements of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4323B5A72EBF4D7582B5CC1E272E2E32"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H473A43DEF0CA47029000F56298B727B1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosure of employee data collected</header>
<subsection id="H5F07F203B5C447D7AEFDE6D5EEC50999"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer shall disclose, in accordance with subsections (b) and (c), to each covered individual and publish in a manner that is conspicuous, freely accessible, and readily available for viewing by any such covered individual of the employer (including on the internet in a manner that is freely accessible and machine readable (in a form prescribed by the Secretary))—</text> <paragraph id="H8CB9865D8EB44E0294B4C339C2759EF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any employee data collected on the covered individual by the employer, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H23525EFBAC6D4D5293BF889F1AB36B98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>what employee data are being collected;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27D75357AFAE4AAA93EE87CEBF7B4722"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the employee data are being collected;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H29E75A2F876D43AAB830FFD907F8D30E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>where and when the employee data are being collected;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBCECD0176EAC4D15B517B7B37D7A09B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the frequency of the employee data collection;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H531754E0332C4AF98B2F57580C8E9749"><enum>(E)</enum><text>where the employee data is stored;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37175CF3DC7C44B0B6C38969E63246D8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>who has access to the employee data;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H699FA07535C44CEB9EF51E83528E5F45"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the purposes for which the employee data are being collected and used; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C25F6E4C97F484FAAF5EE6F851065FC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>as applicable, the identity of any third party or service provider—</text>
<clause id="HC9AA7D52CC2B46BFB5441F206A8FD574"><enum>(i)</enum><text>used for such employee data collection;</text></clause> <clause id="H7657A09A2A6045509C0A2C18769D8243"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to which employee data is transferred; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HAF2D74A9B4AC457599295C9BC2AAB71B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>from which employee data of the covered individual is or may be purchased or acquired; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CE92EFA7B9340E684FA86DC52F31448"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how such employee data affects work-related decisions by the employer, including with regard to the assessment of the performance and productivity of the covered individual.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1CB3A1621A80405FA663992A8403C2FC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing of disclosure</header>
<paragraph id="H9A7C175948954D1B8980FE1EBDCC234C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial disclosure</header><text>An employer shall provide the disclosure required under subsection (a) as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H2B9BB8677FC3491D97C2778DEAD34A4A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered individuals other than applicants</header><text>With respect to covered individuals other than applicants, in the case of—</text>
<clause id="HE943F11C481445EBBFB4B2B85CC23D8A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such a covered individual hired by the employer on or after the effective date of this section, to the covered individual upon hiring the covered individual; or</text></clause> <clause id="H5FD72198BECB410AA8476733E0FFDE41" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such a covered individual who is employed by, or otherwise performing work for remuneration for, the employer on such effective date but was hired before such effective date, to the covered individual not later than 30 days after such effective date.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H68B38128004A4E33A7FCB12DEB9B45E3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicants</header><text>With respect to a covered individual who is an applicant on or after the effective date of this section, to such an applicant before the employer accepts an application by the applicant to be employed by, or otherwise perform work for remuneration for, the employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF0D35D9D0BE4F13A01607D6393F08D3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updated disclosures</header><text>With respect to a covered individual who received a disclosure under paragraph (1)(A) by an employer or a covered individual who received a disclosure under paragraph (1)(B) by an employer and is still in the applicant process, the employer shall provide an updated disclosure to the covered individual—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB70F8A01BF5E4EC1A471F5F24D5413D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 7 days before implementing changes to practices disclosed in the disclosure; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B53A7B6D5AA45E1BDD258833A2D4DA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately upon any new information required to be provided in such a disclosure becoming available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8B7BFBBB037B4A0BAAEE22D6A710DDC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures for disclosure</header><text>An employer shall provide the disclosure required under subsection (a) in a manner required by the Administrator that is—</text> <paragraph id="HBAFA1452C6AA448A93C1484306C311B7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accessible to people with disabilities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE182944C3A374E688C2D882026021F65" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in plain language and in the primary language of the covered individual provided the disclosure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF0E6817D9A3473C86BF8DCB1286B4DC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in writing and available electronically;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCADB2F4E333E4995A7D01785EDE0472C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>tailored to the purpose of the disclosure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H204CC9D8252241B782529C4C1C355C9B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>tailored to the job functions of the covered individual; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59B5AA2503AA4DFCA5A95CF35EC08167"><enum>(6)</enum><text>tailored to the level of risk.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H4657996997DC4077B82A85B61A39C05E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H73591DCF184F488FA20A67F0CFFE0904"><enum>5.</enum><header>Employee data access and accuracy</header>
<subsection id="HC22732F0BD03490D899B426D3B27781B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employee data access and correction</header>
<paragraph id="HE727DBB1942C4EA8BCE706D93E343D84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer shall enable a covered individual (in a manner that verifies and protects the identity of the covered individual), upon request by the covered individual or as provided in subsection (b), to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A23C2BDD0AF4518A7146CC361CBBA84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after such request or as provided in such subsection, obtain any employee data collected by the employer on the covered individual; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6F307CEBB24841F8894FCDA505ABD429"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with procedures established by the Administrator, have any such employee data that is incomplete or erroneous updated or corrected at any time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8C84629B8354F829C55D1DD007A29A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of interpretation</header><text>The failure of a covered individual to make a request under paragraph (1) shall not be interpreted to provide a defense for the employer of the covered individual with respect to any allegation of a violation of any requirement under this Act by the employer.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H46B5628160A742B9895DD5E0AB7D0031">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Work-Related decisions</header>
 <text>An employer that makes a work-related decision with regard to a covered individual using employee data—</text>
        <paragraph id="HCFDA294BB8BD47CB83E46FEE4498CB66" commented="no">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>shall, upon alerting the covered individual about such work-related decision, disclose to the covered individual the categories of employee data used to make the work-related decision; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4C1D8AC91E2E42DF81FF26C489E8FCE2">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>shall, for not less than 7 days after such disclosure, enable the covered individual to—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H013E2B80BFB143F0BDB2195087D16BA0">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>review such employee data of the covered individual and related aggregated data for other similarly situated covered individuals of the employer;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HD0B13600BD3C445FAE0B9BFF549F5957">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in accordance with the procedures described in subsection (a)(1)(B), have any employee data described in paragraph (1) that is incomplete or erroneous updated or corrected; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC2152DACDEDD4D2E8B6B709202057377">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>request that the employer reconsider the work-related decision based on the updated or corrected employee data.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H235111053CE94F18BAD6F37E33041FD2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H2DB4C3C4E3C84EDAB7DB2233C9B1265A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Establishment of Worker Protection and Technology Division</header> <subsection id="H7DF7A7941BF64438BB18C2A261C06D71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Department of Labor the Worker Protection and Technology Division.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H90D79E31B89A4D8BB20CB66504D84179"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrator of the Worker Protection and Technology Division</header><text>The President shall appoint an Administrator of the Worker Protection and Technology Division to head the Privacy and Technology Division.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFACD6B18A2104755BBC7B45696EF9C3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employees and advisory boards of the Division</header> <paragraph id="HB3FC2F05BA1444679AE7FEA8C4E69DA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFDBCD1A613E84373B2E67109D8D20320"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may select, appoint, and employ, without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3318 of title 5, United States Code, individuals, including technologists, directly to positions in the competitive service, as defined in section 2102 of such title, to carry out the duties of the Administrator under this Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BDC4C7E0015400E9EF40D697BFDDFB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may fix the compensation of the individuals described in subparagraph (A) without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for such individuals may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H679EA32227A84B749AB8B23B94F7DD64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory boards</header>
<subparagraph id="H3712B8AF03B1421B87810318C8CCD099"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish advisory boards to advise and consult with in the exercise of the functions of the Administrator under this Act and to provide information on emerging practices relating to the treatment of employee data by employers that are the following:</text> <clause id="H62BAEFB26E6E437287F88787F2F9922F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The User Advisory Board, which shall be composed of experts in consumer protection, privacy, civil rights, disability law, labor organizations, and ethics.</text></clause>
<clause id="H5CEEABD1B23840E787DF49606FD93892"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Research Advisory Board, which shall be composed of individuals with academic and research expertise in privacy, cybersecurity, computer science, innovation, design, ethics, economics, law, disability law, labor organizations and public policy and representatives of labor organizations.</text></clause> <clause id="H38E37B71F2274677B13F35DA4ED16FDA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Product Advisory Board, which shall be composed of technologists, computer scientists, designers, product managers, attorneys, representatives of labor organizations, workplace technology experts, and other representatives of employers and employees.</text></clause>
<clause id="H866C46DCED41451EAB36926FB8C54252"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Labor Advisory Board, which shall be composed of representatives of labor organizations and representatives of workers.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5471C56E7124BCE81D088013FCC7BD0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appointments</header><text>The Administrator shall appoint members to the advisory boards established under subparagraph (A) without regard to party affiliation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8F58DC1E6D9C4BB28DF78047B99B94E3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Each advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall meet—</text> <clause id="H07FE982079FB4FFC87912CDA2602A90F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the call of the Administrator; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H361C60BA11CF4AC882BFCEF6E13E3206"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 2 times annually.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31D36456D8974F9B87F2F438CCE55200"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Compensation and travel expenses</header><text>A member of an advisory board established under subparagraph (A) who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall—</text>
<clause id="H3627FAE71FA74F61A5C10589A9C0D595"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be entitled to receive compensation at a rate fixed by the Administrator while attending meetings of the advisory board, including travel time; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCD861DA856EC41F1AE628E71E03A4A46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC78ED525E9764849B8557A770DB312F0"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Exemption from the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>Each advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall be exempt from <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78A901E4E3994EDEA6D42AEA4C891521"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of voluntary services</header><text>The Administrator may, as may from time to time be needed, use any voluntary or uncompensated services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAFF04524474D476EA5AD31D857513DF3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attorneys</header><text>Attorneys appointed under this subsection may appear for and represent the Administrator in any litigation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H02D5CA406A2141C39ACEF9122A918818"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Offices</header> <paragraph id="H497B61A6A676454FA22EE1916ED414B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The principal office of the Worker Protection and Technology Division shall be in the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00C6956C385F4AF9B9723E3112DF7C94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regional, local, and other offices</header><text>The Administrator may establish regional, local, or other offices, including an office in the city of San Francisco, California, or the San Francisco Bay area in California.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3615447C5F3C49469062D7084F96AE73"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Orders and guidance</header> <paragraph id="HB78F18222DE5415A8066D76D5A0D948C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator and the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division, may issue orders and guidance, as may be necessary or appropriate to enable the Secretary to carry out the purposes and objectives of this Act, and to prevent evasions thereof.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEB4D2926C89F452F9FC650396C3534A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In issuing orders and guidance authorized under this subsection, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator and the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division, may consult with Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over Federal privacy laws or expertise in privacy, including the Federal Trade Commission, and Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over labor and employment issues, including the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the National Labor Relations Board, the National Mediation Board, and the Merit Systems Protection Board.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HFD2E7B94FB684F739FBEE0201393B338"><enum>7.</enum><header>Regulations</header> <subsection id="H839EA270E42D4CBB9FB98018D938BBC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HDFD0FDBE1F8E4D1C81B8C2A0B8C1C452"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header> <subparagraph id="H2B6125BCE2744202ACBF72C42F87732A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary, acting through the Administrator in consultation with the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division, may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(7)(A) (other than covered individuals described in clauses (iii) through (v) of such section) and other individuals affected by employers described in subclause (I) or (II) of section 2(9)(A)(i), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H344CB3CA21B547CF825D388B76BAD909"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In prescribing any regulations authorized under this paragraph, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, may consult with Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over Federal privacy laws or expertise in privacy, including the Federal Trade Commission, and Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over labor and employment issues, including the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and the National Labor Relations Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3548303B2C2F4B5082717D6A365898ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Government accountability office; library of congress</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress shall prescribe any regulations described in paragraph (1)(A) with respect to covered individuals of the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress, respectively, and other individuals affected by the Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H923902819B5A4CF1896A250338A8A25B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employees covered by congressional accountability act of 1995</header>
<paragraph id="HAAF5AEC954C242328752118EFECA1FBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance shall prescribe (in accordance with section 304 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1384">2 U.S.C. 1384</external-xref>)) such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(7)(A)(iii) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(III), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57C10223EFB5424A8FC219644C16EB8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7DDD082A6230475BA9BE5320EB9C29D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, united states code</header>
<paragraph id="H2BD30586CB4C4047812045FA71DA11E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the President (or the designee of the President) shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(7)(A)(iv) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(IV), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECB4F3D3764F4027B910938438FD7AD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the President (or designee) may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H489FB41EF30041BC806997F04BC15E48"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, united states code</header>
<paragraph id="H54C4D9D958C945CD8F967A744BC3A650"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(7)(A)(v) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(V), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94C6DB205B954625B15DCB75647CED5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the Director may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H90FDD1F28392415BA7A9D1BB48697C72"><enum>8.</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67A9D25B578B4177BA2BEDDDC0A83CF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer may not discriminate or retaliate (including through intimidation, threats, coercion, or harassment) against any covered individual of the employer—</text> <paragraph id="HA0C29EADA7EF48719A3BF87F76D920E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for exercising, or attempting to exercise, any right provided under this Act; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94385F2BE2A54BDEAC4DA7A5520B218E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>because the covered individual (or another individual acting at the request of the covered individual) has—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H09C8CFC87A2A413A9F1AFBD0CAECA7A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made a written or oral complaint to the employer or a Federal, State, or local government entity of a violation of section 3, 4, or 5;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H42088474698240EEB8FE043F05EF4D35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sought assistance or intervention with respect to a worker privacy-related concern from the employer, a Federal, State, or local government, or a worker representative;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H47CA9B50F8A54A918E9ABC6B11D65264"><enum>(C)</enum><text>instituted, caused to be instituted, or otherwise participated in any inquiry or proceeding under or related to this Act;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H144E7C18124D4540B56E082C5698640F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>given, or is about to give, any information in connection with any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6EEDC7CC443545349378514A18C95CA1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>testified, or is about to testify, in any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H89542615DCDD45D08EFC61B566676689"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Each employer shall provide notice of the protections under subsection (a) to all covered individuals of the employer in a manner that is accessible and in plain language.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3151A3887F45478D9EB68812866C4147"><enum>9.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subsection id="HB78FC63DFD8D430EA5657A8196E73B94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H8109CDC487BC430F9ABAA538A73D00EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph id="H6A2DFC5AD39A420A89BB24BCBE57C87E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means a covered individual—</text> <clause id="HB36F4736A1D54488BC9AD7F0A5ABD69F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in section 2(7)(A) (other than covered individuals described in clauses (iii) through (v) of such section); or</text></clause>
<clause id="HE2C9F6A25F764708AFA87CC74BD18494"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to an employer.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H209AA4454B154FB88E07E2DBBA00F085"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means an employer described in subclause (I) or (II) of section 2(9)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C40009665364500A881CBFF4798E965"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Worker Protection and Technology Division</header>
<subparagraph id="H6A010E4859464AFE8E6172EF216A5DAA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Investigation</header>
<clause id="H2236B109F8FB4B788B2B84AD249BAFB8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure compliance with the provisions of this Act, or any regulation or order issued under this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator—</text> <subclause id="HF7AFF79369C2429A9E80392685522B53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall have the investigative authority provided under section 11(a) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211(a)</external-xref>), with respect to employers, covered individuals, and third parties and service providers with respect to employers; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H6429EBA7B86D4F4384D47E87A2DE32F0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may require, by general or special orders, an employer or third party or service provider with respect to the employer, to file with the Secretary, in such form as the Secretary may prescribe, annual or special reports or answers in writing to specific questions, furnishing to the Secretary such information or records as the Secretary may require as to the organization, business, conduct, practices, management, and relation to other corporations, partnerships, and individuals, of the employer.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H919B83DAA18F4D64BE993EA2585C81C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reports and answers</header><text>An employer or third party or service provider with respect to the employer shall file the reports and answers (including information and records) required under clause (i)(II) in such manner, including under oath or otherwise, and within such reasonable time period as the Secretary may require.</text></clause>
<clause id="H9E19686F8AE94574AA603F24CDE97F1D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Joint investigations</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator, may conduct investigations and make requests for information, as authorized under this Act, on a joint basis with another Federal agency, a State attorney general, or a State agency.</text></clause> <clause id="HB8C747DF48EA455B983D37698CF14B84"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Obligation to keep, preserve, and make available records</header><text>An employer or third party or service provider with respect to the employer shall make, keep, preserve, and make available to the Secretary records pertaining to compliance with this Act in accordance with section 11(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211(c)</external-xref>) and in accordance with any regulation or order issued by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HAD6182C8C04F4A21A035ABB3EF7DC62A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>With respect to employers, covered individuals, and third parties and service providers with respect to employers, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall receive, investigate, and attempt to resolve complaints of violations of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 in the same manner that the Secretary receives, investigates, and attempts to resolve complaints of violations of sections 6 and 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 206 and 207).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEFCC7F2CAAC84A1B993B63BD5B49F6DC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Secretary shall prioritize industries with high rates of employee data collection and at high risk of workplace-surveillance-related health impacts.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA8A6318ECF5941EFB076B8AC98B5021C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Referral for criminal proceedings</header><text>If the Secretary, in the course of the performance of any act or duty under this Act, obtains evidence that any employer has engaged in conduct that may constitute a violation of Federal criminal law, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General for prosecution under any applicable law. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect any other authority of the Secretary to disclose information.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2600BBF71E3480286C4F9B9C8554862"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Litigation</header><text>The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary on any litigation brought under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCCD412DDED4C49AC9FEC355A6DC79845"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private right of action</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3D6F3703B8F44BFBBB590CBCC8261DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header>
<clause commented="no" id="H52159D898E764671A8BB8E43CA7AF5E3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>Notwithstanding any action by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B), any covered individual adversely affected by an alleged violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8, may commence a civil action against any person that violates such section in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HA680DE6D35B243D29883936A42B408D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>Notwithstanding any action by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B), any labor organization adversely affected by an alleged violation of 5 or 8 may commence a civil action against any person that violates such section in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H139E1DCD0CB343EB887CF6491AC2D789"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header>
<clause commented="no" id="HE27AF71FA2394D0981238E6F71F2D55F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the covered individual or labor organization prevails, the court shall award the covered individual or labor organization—</text> <subclause id="HA3B8E38B168E48F4A78546AFFBB33117" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>damages of not less than an amount equal to twice the sum of any actual damages sustained by the covered individual;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H5379A6544D9B45D2857649E577EAA369"><enum>(II)</enum><text>statutory damages described in clause (iv);</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H8B3F0AFF597F47FC890CDD1300315770"><enum>(III)</enum><text>injunctive relief; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="H340259CB1E8D41C190954ECC2BC47B9F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>equitable relief.</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H66D53C21252F4EE289325A504D0BF8A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Attorney's fees</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the covered individual or labor organization prevails, the court shall award the covered individual or labor organization reasonable attorney's fees and litigation costs.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H7F78BC3B1B16481AA319183FB680425E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Temporary relief for whistleblowers</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) regarding a violation of section 8, the court may award the covered individual or labor organization temporary relief while the case is pending, including reinstatement.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HA8F0473622E1476FA2DAF5F3ABF07D26"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Statutory damages</header><text>The court may, in accordance with clause (v), award statutory damages under clause (i)(II) against a person in the following amounts:</text>
<subclause id="H7ED403DC2EE44CD68C5F52282FDFA8C9"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Failure to comply with disclosure requirements</header><text>For a violation of section 4 and section 8(b), the court may award—</text> <item id="HAA3E5817519849949164E87B4F205EB4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for the first such violation, damages of an amount not more than $500 for each covered individual impacted; and</text></item>
<item id="HA1F3D6FD9CE548D09A4A594C9FAD89D9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for any subsequent violation, damages for each covered individual impacted in an amount of not more than $500 more than the amount of the damages awarded per covered individual for the violation immediately preceding such subsequent violation.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H54442865AD024FC085B1A8DBA025DE84"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Violation of employee data minimization requirements or employee data accessibility requirements</header><text>For each violation of section 3 or 5, the court may award—</text>
<item id="H22C4DE0486904F479E3C67D7BC109E81"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>damages of an amount not less than $5,000 and not more than $20,000; or</text></item> <item id="HC9B7EE8D37CF42EC9E99C62AD5460C4D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for any willful or repeated violation, damages of an amount not less than $10,000 and not more than $40,000.</text></item></subclause>
<subclause id="HCBEE90DCDB984902A80A271B09AD5661"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Retaliation on whistleblowers</header><text>For each violation of section 8(a), the court may award—</text> <item id="H56096C5CCC2E475F8508592F7D70D606"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>damages of an amount not less than $5,000 and not more than $50,000; or</text></item>
<item id="H6CDA82DF059D40CEBB97A00C1A133476"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for any willful or repeated violation, damages of an amount not less than $10,000 and not more than $100,000.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HAD4CC3198D4D495CA949A504473290F6"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Considerations for statutory damages</header><text>In determining the amount of statutory damages assessed under clause (iv), the court shall consider any relevant circumstances presented by the parties to the action, including—</text>
<subclause id="H61D140F89D5D4BA3821297383E76E4E1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the nature and seriousness of the violation;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H763FB0D6C7C24552B9388C2075C8D842"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of violations;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HF2C0C901D0314962B6CE64630C8FD519"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the persistence of the misconduct;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFFEDDAA13C364D6BA51E57AD56D39563"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the length of time over which the misconduct occurred;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H2597A721510A4173B30BD33DF0F463A2"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the willfulness of the misconduct of person; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H20CC95BE015C4D2196BC0EDA46EBC141"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the assets, liabilities, and net worth of the person.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8128C8EF739841B68805619672A968C8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remedies for state employees</header>
<clause id="H7D80C71718F1417489B91724059E870C">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header>
 <text>A State’s receipt or use of Federal financial assistance for any program or activity of a State shall constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity, under the 11th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or otherwise, to a suit brought by a covered individual of that program or activity, or a labor organization representing such a covered individual, under this paragraph for equitable, legal, or other relief authorized under this paragraph.</text>
            </clause>
<clause id="H01839E6F45B144DC9FFE2D0AE94D0EE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Official capacity</header><text>An official of a State may be sued in the official capacity of the official by any covered individual or such a labor organization who has complied with the procedures under this paragraph, for injunctive relief that is authorized under this paragraph. In such a suit the court may award to the prevailing party those costs authorized by section 722 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">42 U.S.C. 1988</external-xref>).</text></clause> <clause id="H1FB203E30E204E8CAE3B1A2978B34367"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>With respect to a particular program or activity, clause (i) applies to conduct that occurs—</text>
<subclause id="HF0A355CDACCC447384034C47401B23E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6BFB2B95E248439597B629A036A061F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after the day on which a State first receives or uses Federal financial assistance for that program or activity.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF18EFE5A3C5A45A68ED4A157068B42EB"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definition of program or activity</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>program or activity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FDB5B411D484B2C882F2ACDEB9B3F42"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Remedies for Tribal government employees</header> <clause id="H991AD6CA6E254B0F844633E4985FDE7F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header><text>A Tribal government's receipt or use of Federal financial assistance for any program or activity of the Tribal government shall constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity to a suit brought by a covered individual of that program or activity, or a labor organization representing such a covered individual, under this paragraph for equitable, legal, or other relief authorized under this paragraph.</text></clause>
<clause id="H6E8D114F062541AFA402EA77E04E117B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Official capacity</header><text>An official of a Tribal government may be sued in the official capacity of the official by any covered individual or such a labor organization who has complied with the procedures under this paragraph for injunctive relief that is authorized under this paragraph. In such a suit the court may award to the prevailing party those costs authorized by section 722 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">42 U.S.C. 1988</external-xref>).</text></clause> <clause id="HA5A52F4E5C744BABA8140493C73B84C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>With respect to a particular program or activity, clause (i) applies to conduct that occurs—</text>
<subclause id="H31D82BDBD3DB43DC8A59875124BCFAA2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDE036BE6584443E8BA2006252B752D0F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after the day on which a Tribal government first receives or uses Federal financial assistance for that program or activity.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H892B399B24B340BD84AB45E680E8EC70"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definition of program or activity</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>program or activity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDFAD60A4FF64DBAADB9CD315DF447CF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enforcement by the government accountability office and library of congress</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, in the case of the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress, the authority of the Secretary under this subsection shall be exercised respectively by the Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDC61F458DEC042E7A78E536A3E43BF45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employees covered by congressional accountability act of 1995</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) to the Board (as defined in section 101 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>)), or any person, alleging a violation of section 202(a)(1) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1312">2 U.S.C. 1312(a)(1)</external-xref>) shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to that Board, or any person, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 against a covered individual described in section 2(7)(A)(iii) or described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(III).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAF05ECC6140C47FBB94EEF9D0DF4A824"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, united states code</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code, to the President, the Merit Systems Protection Board, or any person, alleging a violation of section 412(a)(1) of that title, shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to the President, that Board, or any person, respectively, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 against a covered individual described in section 2(7)(A)(iv) or described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(IV).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD9D32AD878BA4AACAF40E3B8582D8063"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, united states code</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in title 5, United States Code, to an employing agency, provided in chapter 12 of that title to the Merit Systems Protection Board, or provided in that title to any person, alleging a violation of chapter 63 of that title, shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to that agency, that Board, or any person, respectively, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 against a covered individual described in section 2(7)(A)(v) or described in section 2(7)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(V).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A88B10C4ACD449D8707DEDDCE89F495"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC347536AD3214E97AAE060B5CE455F92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which a State attorney general or a State privacy regulator has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of a State has been or is adversely affected by any person who violates any provision of section 3, 4, 5, or 8, including a regulation or order prescribed under this Act, the State attorney general or State privacy regulator, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H89D5456345F54535A3E476E5E24CE16A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin further violation of such provision by the person;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H84AB4C10A3C14E5782D8DDD3F3610C53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compel compliance with such provision;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA5717ED7CA264F9C9D0D339FC18A1E28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, civil penalties, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of the residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFC3E996B76BC40C6AAF611F2D5A2A67A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain reasonable attorney's fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6BF07D52283D4B52A64272014FF7C59E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of agency</header><text>Before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the State attorney general or State privacy regulator, as the case may be, shall notify the Secretary in writing of such civil action. Upon receiving such notice, the Secretary may—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEC6A0719F78B466C8E2C01FD4422FAB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intervene in such action; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HAB6E3AFF77D54BFF94BC88A5E5B3DF7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE6A5BA6248864DBEBDC550F1812CE7CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in such civil action; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H12F11FB30B284CD485477EC47BDDDDCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in such action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H42FD641139C44A35B2582683F0454481"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preemptive action by agency</header><text>In any case in which a civil action is instituted by or on behalf of the Secretary for violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act, a State attorney general or State privacy regulator may not, during the pendency of such action, institute a civil action against any defendant named in the complaint in the action instituted by or on behalf of the Secretary for a violation that is alleged in such complaint. In a case brought by the Secretary that affects the interests of a State, the State attorney general or State privacy regulator may intervene as of right pursuant to the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H1828A0337DF94ED1821B2E3EA498BA39"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preservation of State powers</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), no provision of this subsection shall be construed as altering, limiting, or affecting the authority of a State attorney general or State privacy regulator to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCCCD97B3CE974CDDA780983D36C353AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bring an action or other regulatory proceeding arising solely under the laws in effect in that State; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE15631CA3E484A46B66109801767A677"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exercise the powers conferred on the State attorney general or State privacy regulator by the laws of the State, including the ability to conduct investigations, administer oaths or affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H07A8F96DEE1543FFB5E6E0B0FBC04321"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Liability of an employer for a violation by a service provider that collect employee data</header><text>A violation of section 3 by a service provider that collects employee data shall be considered a violation of such section by the employer if the employer knew or should have known about such violation.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB51520BFA9FC4A14893A4F42A7A4367B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Arbitration and class action</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no predispute arbitration agreement or predispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable with respect to any alleged violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD05FAE60466542D2B56F31FB45D93B22"><enum>10.</enum><header>Report to Congress on workplace surveillance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H67786A492EF0485896118F4A0D27EA64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>using technologists and subject matter experts, conduct a study on workplace surveillance and the collection of employee data about covered individuals by employers, including such workplace surveillance through technological means; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE9B247790644DD69393F17D4D7C2E51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report on the findings of the study under paragraph (1), including any recommendations for the President and Congress targeted at reducing harms related to workplace surveillance and the collection of employee data about covered individuals.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HCD97DD77D5934DC49C210B99F28991F1"><enum>11.</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall coordinate with any appropriate Federal agency or State regulator to promote consistent regulatory treatment of employee data.</text></section> <section id="H429EC299179141B899B4A7AF9FF40F63"><enum>12.</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as explicitly provided otherwise, nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt, modify, limit, or supersede—</text>
<paragraph id="H6B7298CD399F462094322179B01F08B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any provision of Federal or State law; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6249C8239C01451BBF027B98B547616C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of the Federal Trade Commission, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, National Labor Relations Board, or any other Federal agency.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HDECDE36E5FA64235926B837AA71E18F4"><enum>13.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provisions of such to all other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

