<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN26213-WTH-6F-335"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4124 PCS: To prohibit funds made available to the Department of Justice from being used to make a personal payment to the President in connection with a claim that is subject to the Federal Tort Claims Act, whether in the form of a settlement or any other payment from the Judgment Fund for the personal benefit of the President.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 359</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4124</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit funds made available to the Department of Justice from being used to make a personal payment to the President in connection with a claim that is subject to the Federal Tort Claims Act, whether in the form of a settlement or any other payment from the Judgment Fund for the personal benefit of the President.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section id="id5fb735019ab04a1fb3ac731063e1911f" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on using funds made available to the Department of Justice for payments to the President with respect to tort claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds made available to the Department of Justice before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act may be used to approve or facilitate a claim that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdfd810606c64419b9814a2260627645"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>); and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56db17d34e674760875412b1183bba1f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">results in a personal payment to the President, whether in the form of a settlement or any other payment issued under section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, (commonly known as the <quote>Judgment Fund</quote>) for the personal benefit of the President.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

