<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H76494F368DA441C5A0F41C20BCFC5611" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6967 IH: Public Company Advisory Committee Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6967</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish within the Securities and Exchange Commission the Public Company Advisory Committee, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7B57DE2AAC8F4757AA642CA6AC4C5FEC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEEB66C826B0340DCB73B43898505BC2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Company Advisory Committee Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE8C59E68F5A643DF807091C5A5B2E289"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public Company Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 is amended by inserting after section 40 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78qq">15 U.S.C. 78qq</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB31F40C511C54B3F80725C61527953A9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H6F5A932F885B4B2D9B7F4B64FA9B1E3F"><enum>40A.</enum><header>Public Company Advisory Committee</header> 
<subsection id="H1410C63FFF284A6DA44E16F18E79F7BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and purpose</header> 
<paragraph id="H3ABA1E49D6D042A28BA5A5B001585971"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Commission the Public Company Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the ‘Committee’).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D109E3A846A4E8FA5CC3C3246DB158B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Committee shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5581365B805947DD81E74D227BBAACA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the Commission with advice on its rules, regulations, and policies with regard to its mission of protecting investors, maintaining fair, orderly, and efficient markets, and facilitating capital formation, as they relate to—</text> <clause id="HDC76F53687024EAEB86CC33022C016AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>existing and emerging regulatory priorities of the Commission;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H62F06F1AFCE34B29BCFB298F9446EF2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>issues relating to the public reporting and corporate governance of public companies;</text></clause> <clause id="H7E4524ECE48D4D0898A5A856DEF7D531"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>issues relating to the proxy process for shareholder meetings held by public companies;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0D3E67DC9D9B4E889F729D85AE3F9BA7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>issues relating to trading in the securities of public companies; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCC8350D616864587BA4F569A294D232D"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>issues relating to capital formation;</text>
                </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H51892A0D86EF49D79D3F62719B7656C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not provide any advice with respect to any policies, practices, actions, or decisions concerning the Commission’s enforcement program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB06AFC4F14E44BABB3C7C335B18A7BCE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit to the Commission such findings and recommendations as the Committee determines are appropriate, including recommendations for proposed regulatory and legislative changes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0793E4841621445EAFF5A3477DC53AE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="HD2260D05BE8344C3A0E74928A3C1552D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The membership of the Committee shall be not fewer than 10, and not more than 20, members appointed by the Commission from among individuals who—</text> <subparagraph id="H59901CE31EE248A8844576C9AC684EDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are officers, directors, or senior officials of public companies registered with the Commission under the Securities Act or 1933 and this Act, except for those public companies that own asset management, fixed income, investment advisory, broker-dealer, or proxy services businesses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2882A42365574A48995AF1E21BBE2A6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are executives or other individuals with senior managerial responsibility in business, professional, trade, and industry associations that represent the interests of such public companies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0A50FF6DB2344CAA114613D76C841E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are professional advisers and service providers to such public companies (including attorneys, accountants, investment bankers, and financial advisers).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BBB7677FC744801AC0DC9B9489B3F80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>At least 50 percent of the Committee membership shall be drawn from individuals who would qualify for membership under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FC8CA30666849F496F97FEE5287FCCC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Each member of the Committee appointed under paragraph (1) shall serve for a term of four years. Vacancies among the members, whether caused by the resignation, death, removal, expiration of a term, or otherwise, will be filled consistent with the Commission’s procedures then in effect.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB15F41890A14215B235EE141079F663"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Staggered terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Committee shall serve staggered terms, with half of the initial members of the Committee each serving for 2 years and half serving 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8C5CABC09A5455E8FDD443169CEF6BD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Members not on other advisory committees</header><text>Public companies and other organizations that are currently represented on any other Commission Advisory Committee are not eligible to have representatives also serve on the Public Company Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4052AFBDD9744DE893CECB654AF6510"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Members not Commission employees</header><text>Members appointed under paragraph (1) shall not be considered to be employees or agents of the Commission solely because of membership on the Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4A82401D487C4BFCBD47BD707294BAA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chair; Vice Chair; Secretary; Assistant Secretary</header> <paragraph id="H6D0BC428A2D6462690048D64F7D692F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The members of the Committee shall elect, from among the members of the Committee—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8CA8EC67A1564D13A584960D84C3A322"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Chair;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8EEFD97694344F0B1E68ECADE1530C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Vice Chair;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E2CF9DA6A1A488D839DB692824755CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Secretary; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B45F1C90C55463CA44AEFF0FDDC0E22"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Assistant Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7080138FD7A346B8BC51928AC506889A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Each member elected under paragraph (1) shall serve for a term of two years in the capacity the member was elected under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D815DABECD44FF0936EE4DE10479E22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><text>The Chair may create subcommittees that hold public or non-public meetings and provide recommendations to the full Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3245BA3249FD4882A874961A4C626017"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header> 
<paragraph id="H4364306713934BCEA7D12113D6FDA55B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency of meetings</header><text>The Committee shall meet—</text> <subparagraph id="H11EAEC8F73C24E639DB6C38F65DE64B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less frequently than twice annually, at the call of the chair of the Committee; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76332C5C6D164DB8ABBE3758A727B675"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from time to time, at the call of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE3634C6FB2744C9912A0610A58DFF60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Chair of the Committee shall give the members of the Committee written notice of each meeting, not later than two weeks before the date of the meeting.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB3E3A0D54D044541A8D6C37A879A0A06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compensation and travel expenses</header><text>Each member of the Committee who is not a full-time employee of the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="H03DCB948EC964C1B8AF871EA3BE7C218"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be entitled to receive compensation at a rate not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for a position at level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code, for each day during which the members is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Committee; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC38271D160E64D1891375BC5698297B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of services for the Committee, be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3DA0D8879DB642DE9C1D9BF4B26D9195"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Commission shall make available to the Committee such staff as the chairman of the Committee determines are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDEA30ED59EED459BB9CE3066F5EECBEF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Review by Commission</header><text>The Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="H588182A8088A47F4B5F0DD2F0A3A1B4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the findings and recommendations of the Committee; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6AE24729DDA4E3C88188016F244588B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each time the Committee submits a finding or recommendation to the Commission, promptly issue a public statement—</text> <subparagraph id="H90CFBBAF5A5C476DB1F9754571BC150F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessing the finding or recommendation of the Committee; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H086FFCA4B23D408D885B0CCE07A9AD3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disclosing the action, if any, the Commission intends to take with respect to the finding or recommendation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8245C6BD9CC542C8BE040FFB12975EE7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Committee findings</header><text>Nothing in this section shall require the Commission to agree to or act upon any finding or recommendation of the Committee.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H145DEEAB21EB4B019B8CB456F5C73CC8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 10 of part I of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Committee and its activities.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

