<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4042FDF32F0E409F89F9AD18013F7E17" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8170 IH: Multilateral Alignment of Technology Controls on Hardware Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8170</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260402">April 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for export restrictions on certain semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components therefor, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H54B7865CE0A7418DA3DA0AF082280DAF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H87C41B1913D64F438B71B0A0ED2DB34A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Multilateral Alignment of Technology Controls on Hardware Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MATCH Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2E9D2CFEF3394A84B3E8A24FE46A6708"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H408272BBCF9F47C0902839E8082D3CE4">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>export controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components represent one of the United States most effective defenses of this foundational technology;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29B166EE2D124F2CA38AE69987A64DD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advanced computing applications like artificial intelligence are transforming military affairs and the balance of power;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D1DB7E79C2147ED9089ED912FD186E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States and its allies have an advantage in the foundational technologies that underpin advanced computing applications, including advanced-node integrated circuits and production, and the equipment and software required to design and produce advanced-node integrated circuits;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9447808EBD14D43BB9DE5B989E033FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>robust controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components have been a bipartisan priority across multiple administrations, reflecting a shared recognition that protecting America’s semiconductor advantage is essential to national security;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5760AD71CAB4D8AB4A3B3D9CD0BD9CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the adversaries of the United States are exploiting gaps in the current export control regime;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B180277280D4510BADA935A5E8C2E93">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certain entities, including ChangXin Memory Technologies (CXMT), Hua Hong, Semiconductor Ltd. (Hua Hong), Huawei, Technologies Co. Ltd. (Huawei), Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation (SMIC), Yangtze Memory Technologies Corp. (YMTC), Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment Inc. China (AMEC), Beijing E-Town Semiconductor Technology Co., Ltd. (E-Town Semiconductor), NAURA Technology Group Co., Ltd. (NAURA), Piotech Semiconductor Equipment Co., Ltd. (Piotech), ACM Research, Inc. (ACM Research), PNC Process Systems Co., Ltd. (PNC Process Systems), Skyverse Technology Co. (Skyverse), Shanghai Micro Electronics Equipment (Group) (SMEE), Kingsemi Co., Ltd. (Kingsemi), and Hwatsing Technology Co. Ltd. (Hwatsing) are engaged in efforts to produce advanced-node integrated circuits and especially crucial for the Military-Civil Fusion efforts of the People’s Republic of China and warrant comprehensive export controls to prevent those companies from accessing items made with United States technologies;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE8E3CDE936243149A7EC72473DB2B03">
        <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>companies located in adversary countries that produce semiconductor manufacturing equipment are critical to adversaries’ efforts to develop advanced-node integrated circuit production capabilities and overcome export controls, and should not be permitted to utilize or benefit from United States or allied technology or components; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75B1A25E430E4107BF90027FA5177242"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Government should work closely with allies and partners of the United States to align export controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components to prevent gaps in controls, reduce the risk of circumvention, and ensure a level global playing field.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H210B4C2C1DC0403E838B191B86AA1AB1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report and application of controls</header> <subsection id="H97325AC982D24A398AA22654BF61290F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identifying chokepoints</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the covered agency heads shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC1EE1620604944BF93980213E96886B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>jointly conduct a review to identify all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment and all covered facilities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1809790A0DBD4F81BA479D5CB0B22FF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of all such equipment and covered facilities.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H89EA50AF7B3E46AEBC07D94C78F56BF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diplomatic engagement</header> 
<paragraph id="HC2239B6358C2454486EB1C582E86BF1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The covered agency heads shall prioritize and upon enactment of this Act immediately engage diplomatically to seek for the governments of allied supplier countries to adopt—</text> <subparagraph id="H658BD130FCF6422AB6BE92473B654143"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">countrywide controls on covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment subject to the allied supplier country’s jurisdiction, or other controls and licensing policies having the same practical effect; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60C0D8D3266349369E7FA176F4C4E4B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>license requirements for the export of all applicable items to any covered facility, and the servicing of all applicable items at any covered facilities, with a licensing policy of denial.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF577916BABA494E9D131F247E4362A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing on diplomatic efforts</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the covered agency heads shall provide a briefing to members of the appropriate congressional committees that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39FC5E18B15D49E2ADAF1A84710F6564"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the status of diplomatic efforts to secure the adoption by allied supplier countries of the controls described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC9F0E5B1E224447979E3ED0C3A1DE3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outlines and assesses incentives to encourage adoption of these controls; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87B60A1E37724543A1B711F4D03AAEB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies—</text> <clause id="H012737FC03224DF3BFF74709627ADEB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allied supplier countries that have not adopted the controls described in paragraph (1)(A);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD26757F2B8E947B9B193B049872D765F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allied supplier countries that have not adopted the controls described in paragraph (1)(B); and</text></clause> <clause id="HB799874AA366441FA290A854896B5171"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures that the United States has taken or plans to take to implement the controls described in paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H49416D075B424BA489E01E44D8A0E909"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exhaustion of diplomatic recourse and application of controls</header> 
<paragraph id="H4CA977586CB440C7A380CB4B75E8BE17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of controls</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the covered agency heads shall publish regulations that—</text> <subparagraph id="H337043D4618045EEA2658934C8A8369F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure all U.S. countrywide controls include all U.S.-origin covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B728369D3C24C53AB32C12AE6CBFF5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure all covered facilities in countries of concern are subject to comprehensive U.S. restrictions.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H438728EBD67D4771B90C6544457540EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exhaustion of diplomatic recourse</header><text>By the date that is 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the covered agency heads shall jointly either—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC010951674304C3A9C7E9378CBCDFEA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify to the appropriate congressional committees that all allied supplier countries have implemented—</text> <clause id="HA8252DD8B8AD41FAA8CE037C62AB153B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">countrywide controls over all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment subject to the allied supplier country’s jurisdiction, or other controls and licensing policies having the same practical effect; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA34AE24DF7F24557A8AD532DBAFCE4BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">license requirements for all applicable items, with a licensing policy of denial, or other controls and licensing policies having the same practical effect; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6E1D8E9A14F42AEA7441865AC5B34F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a list to the appropriate congressional committees of any allied supplier countries that have not implemented all controls described in subparagraph (A)(i) or (ii).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48A8AB992F7748DAAF517EEE3BC3EC79" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension of controls</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless the covered agency heads provide the certification in subparagraph (A), the covered agency heads shall issue regulations that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D32CE2294DE4C7495AD904DCD2471CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish U.S. jurisdiction over and apply countrywide controls to all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components therefor exported from countries identified by the covered agency heads under subsection (c)(2)(B), whether by establishing jurisdiction over such items and applying controls directly, or by restricting the end-uses of essential components of such equipment that are already subject to U.S. jurisdiction, or both;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H70155AA090904935884691F10A15BBF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require a license for all servicing of any applicable item located in any covered facility, and implement a policy of denial for such servicing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9028958F363343A0BBF136EE03EFD1F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish jurisdiction over, and apply end-user or end-use controls prohibiting, the export from countries identified by the covered agency heads under subsection (c)(2)(B) of all applicable items to any covered facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB225886FCD91480A936F66C9C586FF04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text>The covered agency heads may jointly grant a one-time waiver to extend the 150-day deadline under subsection (c) by not more than 90 days, if the covered agency heads, with concurrence from the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, jointly—</text> <paragraph id="H95A38E22F40C4B51B9E1D07802103E4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine and certify to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H85B3666F9CDF49AC9FA4B359E1F91FA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extension is in the national security interest of the United States, despite the risk that countries of concern may take advantage of the delay to further stockpile covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6F18D2DE4584424B024A60179394730"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the governments of an allied supplier country or countries are taking concrete, verifiable steps, pursuant to their domestic laws and regulations and as expeditiously as possible, to adopt and implement controls that are fully aligned with, or more stringent than, the controls that would otherwise be imposed under subsection (c)(3); and</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF950890E9B7648398E476CAF00C294E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees describing—</text> <subparagraph id="H2C9FCDEEC2CD44EFB60F589ED50FCC2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the details justifying the national security interest determination and progress that is intended to be achieved by the extension; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H502F01E0B387499098DF1CC8850592B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the concrete and verifiable interim steps the covered agency heads have taken to prevent stockpiling of covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment by countries of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F82786EB9054CB7A0A64C719C6B271D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the covered agency heads shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC5BC308BC674442D91587E99F7F0F22B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H592CD049D6EC4C18ABF3DD77CEBB0516"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all covered facilities and all entities that own or operate any covered facility;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C083B32909F49BD84AEB4AFF3742D77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the scope of the controls described in subsection (b)(1) imposed by the United States and allied supplier countries for all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment identified pursuant to paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H895EA9615FB143EF99EC7DF17CFBAF65"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>a summary of diplomatic engagements and unilateral actions undertaken in the 12-month period prior to the submission of the report to close any gap in the controls described in subsection (b)(1) among allied supplier countries; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66A2EB42490647BC968ECDFE62204B94"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that the export of all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment to a country of concern, and the export, reexport, or transfer, or servicing of all applicable items to any covered facility, requires a United States or allied license and applications for such licenses will be reviewed under a policy of denial.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H26587E94699441F1838CA1B4D2645565"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination and reimposition of controls upon allied action</header> <paragraph id="HEE4E12ACDD0E4C8DBFC487C5F4774E54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination or modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the covered agency heads determine that an allied supplier country has implemented all the controls in (c)(2)(A)(i) and (ii), the covered agency heads may, upon notifying the appropriate congressional committees of such determination, terminate or modify any control imposed under subsection (c)(3) for items exported from that allied supplier country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0328549D165A4C69A67E426B4382B41F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimposition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, after terminating or modifying a control under paragraph (1), the covered agency heads determine that the allied supplier country has materially weakened, suspended, or revoked the control or licensing policy of denial that justified the termination or modification under paragraph (1), the covered agency heads shall, not later than 60 days after making such determination—</text> <subparagraph id="H38F241AD09F64C2AA8DABAE2D8A8EC68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of such determination; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2FAB4638FA94AB1983CD708DB31B0D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reimpose the control under subsection (c)(2) that was terminated or modified under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE40A7C12288E4338B4B4D5E0A1E6407A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administrative procedure act rulemaking and judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 1762 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4821">50 U.S.C. 4821</external-xref>) shall apply to this Act in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply to the Export Control Reform Act of 2018.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34BDD91D36884776B7217D8623FF3B74"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header> 
<paragraph id="H9ECC95CAC3424562A2BD7C3FAAD36A30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall cease to have effect on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88727278D058426092C7AFCDD02F3270"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation of prior obligations</header><text>The expiration of this Act under subsection (a) shall not affect any action, proceeding, or obligation that was commenced or incurred prior to such expiration.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82E5FEE7FCF54E42A6C4310DC56034CF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H96A82FC609D244EE9F44C8C8997B5263"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced-node integrated circuits</header><text>The term <term>advanced-node integrated circuits</term> has the meaning given that term in section 772.1 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0502289DE9F42A4AEEB5781E83DF886"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allied supplier country</header><text>The term <term>allied supplier country</term> means any country that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FFB785979A84146821108A03BD4E368"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not a country of concern; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5D6941AB8EA401793813EDE033AD591"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is engaged in the production of covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4C06D347021435B817024658F593A69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable item</header><text>The term <term>applicable item</term> means any item that is or can be made subject to the Export Administration Regulations, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED8E745DB73043AF9F81A6342A604D6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a foreign-produced item that is the direct product of, or produced by plants or major components that are themselves the direct product of software or technology subject to the Export Administration Regulations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98AF9B76D47F41C4B176EB803A1AC86A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a foreign-produced item with more than zero percent de minimis controlled United States-origin content; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H729910E64A98459A834F70992613E851"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a foreign-produced item that contain United States-origin or foreign-produced integrated circuits that are presumptively designed or produced, directly or indirectly, with technology, software, or equipment that is subject to the Export Administration Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90FAE81A8D4546C7B7EC4C9E369C9993"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB646D2CF4C204689860A120E66955447"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4233A4B6DAF40E3862FCFCD56DB5596"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A2D2B8F4CF647E4BA56942CB965C390"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H22764D086B544817BDB8518A0C14EA7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the People’s Republic of China, including the Hong Kong and Macau Special Administrative Regions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97319F0CCFF341C1BB9D447106FC778F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Republic of Cuba;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70D2839497DB4EEDAE707C05E9E83572"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H268904D82EE04F7FAB9A841432240299"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F584DC5A262451ABD3EEA099E5DFAEC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Russian Federation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55718E01E0BE4AF8A2FB0314E47CD6C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other foreign country listed in the Country Group D:5 under Supplement No. 1 to part 740 of the Export Administration Regulations, as published on January 1, 2026, that is designated by the Secretary of State as a country of concern for purposes of this section and for which notice of such designation has been published in the Federal Register.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBE6487D198C4BA498DC6C1EADB4C5E6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Countrywide controls</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>countrywide controls</term> means licensing requirements and a policy of denial for the export, reexport, transfer or servicing of all specified items to any destination within any country of concern, excluding exports where the destination is a fabrication facility that existed as of the date of the enactment of this Act and remains owned and operated by a company headquartered, and having an ultimate parent headquartered, outside of any country of concern.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA577871668F64CCFB84944E4DF07E6D5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Covered agency heads</header><text>The term <term>covered agency heads</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security and the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Defense, or their designees.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63CE11FE14284167A785D333DD3C2BFC"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means any facility—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H312E715F5E824F94806768CAB892CF98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is—</text> <clause id="H2DE1002C0DC64EBC9878379FF78B753B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">located in a country of concern;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE0094F2EF16A4E8E82115367F9B63C86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaged in the production of advanced-node integrated circuits; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBAD6533F5CB941A2A9CE6D6D7256C877"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not a fabrication facility that—</text> 
<subclause id="H003A8AA70F1F4EE99B0E60CEB71ED077"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">existed as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDF6734C07FA8433CA1F17C9F2B4C019E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>remains owned and operated by a company which is headquartered and has an ultimate parent headquartered outside of any country of concern; or</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0CAE6590CEB443D58553642A482CBFCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is or ever has been owned or controlled by, under common ownership or control with, or manufacturing at the direction of—</text> <clause id="HC4F49B4129DE4D5BB30A0B0BDD2645FB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any entity described in section 5949(j)(3)(A) or (B);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H55D5E9EFCC8B4EFDBA6011FE53AA922E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Huawei or Hua Hong;</text></clause> <clause id="HA8F1FDCC060741FE9A68AAED177ADD98"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any producer, manufacturer, or developer of semiconductor manufacturing equipment that is headquartered in, or has an ultimate parent headquartered in, a country of concern; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8F7BEACEFE9145E783C6079782164A6B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity that is a subsidiary, affiliate, or successor to, or has a joint venture, teaming agreement, joint development or research agreement, technology transfer or collaboration agreement, or other similar type of arrangement with an entity described in paragraph (10)(B)(i), (ii), or (iii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E97EB62760F48EB81DA4BDF2A2CC319"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment</header><text>The term <term>covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA5B1E439E0AE4D1BA6D8617622B2442D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means semiconductor manufacturing equipment or a component therefor that—</text> <clause id="HDEF4487D1CB8490AAA6B392AECB8D537"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an applicable item; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H14D2218875DD433FAAA59889871D9A66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the covered agency heads determine no country of concern produces in high volume and with capabilities comparable to those of the product sold by the global market leader, as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CDDB8E9EAF84DABB5AAE617628A2064"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes, at a minimum—</text> 
<clause id="H1260158220D846378EEB1D5B420958E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all semiconductor manufacturing equipment, materials, and software that at the date of passage of this Act require a license for export, re-export, or in-country transfer to any destination in a country of concern;</text></clause> <clause id="HDF871DE91F8841FA8508631E66689D73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all deep ultraviolet immersion photolithography machines, through silicon via deposition and etch tools, cryogenic etch equipment, and cobalt deposition equipment, regardless of overlay or other performance characteristics; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF189FB0383B7475BBEFFB1582E5652E4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>presumptively, all semiconductor manufacturing equipment or components specified in Export Control Classification Number 3B001, 3B002, or 3B993 as of the date of the enactment of this Act, except any items the covered agency heads determine are not covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H719C52C2915641619705444C7711A557"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Export; in-country transfer; reexport; export administration regulation</header><text>The terms <term>export</term>, <term>in-country transfer</term>, <term>reexport</term>, and <term>Export Administration Regulations</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 1742 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4332075349284F19B31613E7BBC931C1"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Servicing</header><text>The term <term>servicing</term> means any servicing of equipment or components, whether in-person or remote, including installation, calibration, repair, overhauling, refurbishing, testing, diagnosing, updating software or firmware, training, field services, application support engineering, customization, technical assistance, process adjustments, troubleshooting, and transfer of industry best practices for maintenance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

