<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5422BDD0DAF84E92A2E8E639B1ACF039" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9411 IH: Next Mission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9411</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to provide grants to entities that provide services that supplement the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA45F32C1D3304AC6AFCC010A7DEE8A3C" style="OLC">
<section id="HD8C8D08BBCC2471AB53C2C0D06C19345" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Next Mission Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H69CEBDDBCC364DFC88881C35EECF1524" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program to supplement the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense</header> <subsection id="H0E677194C003402197457B195B37D43D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to award multiyear grants to entities described in subsection (b) that provide to covered individuals the services described in subsection (c).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H187852CC5C1842F4923EAADC5FD830BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the pilot program, an entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB2009A70579A4F349DB7EC667E491622"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be a private, nonprofit organization;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H034DAAB95ABA446DBD73721A59F8B914"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have a record of successfully providing career services (including job placement) or job training;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E05E0BCFBED40238E0F11B81159D3B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have rigorous evaluation practices that indicate efficiency;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBF680DE3C24D4CFCBB9ACCB7348C0F05"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have partnerships with entities (such as employers, governmental agencies, and nonprofit entities) to provide services described in subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AADE61E8E284D20A1755E724586157B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>be able to train online to reach rural participants and reduce costs.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H40397A130DEC4C1DADC67D1B5E30E595"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants awarded under this section shall be used to provide, at no cost to a covered individual, the following services:</text> <paragraph id="H60547049A1D24A6C93872CD4D06B1773"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assessment of education, work history, and employment goals, to determine appropriate employment services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C72F911A45245EBACD92E461FD444E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Preparation for civilian employment, including mock interviews, salary negotiation training, use of professional networking platforms, or company research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H328E3876A174479D9CA59F91EA450D60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing industry-specific learning pathways that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H834B68A15C4A47D8A43D791854D41502"><enum>(A)</enum><text>focus on stable, high-demand fields as determined by labor market information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61CB06DB4C104EF1B2078F099559BD39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>help a covered individual choose a career pathway and navigate training requirements;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5FB8795D55A6406888D73211D29BA763"><enum>(C)</enum><text>help a covered individual apply skills acquired in the Armed Forces to a civilian career;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C39F6E4A30B446FBF5EBBF5AA2EC661"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include one-on-one assistance from a career services professional or academic advisor; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H368A691EF08D4C7F9A16C1571283BEB7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include coursework or other forms of education and training required for industry-recognized credentials and certifications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86605C21DBBA4C48983C5D6FEFB35411"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Job placement.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7FBB8D81015B4E9A8B859E631F10332A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an entity whose program outcomes have been independently verified by a third-party.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC2E33137A0D04368A3480537478C155F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this program, the Secretary of Defense shall consult with other Federal entities, including—</text>
<paragraph id="HB667F1D7DF51494F8BB672DE78BBA0B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Office of Transition and Economic Development of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57C26FB438764570BBEFEFCF3B784E92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Veterans Employment and Training Service of the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H603873F3792E49E787B9DEFB721D8550"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Performance metrics</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish metrics for the pilot program, including—</text> <paragraph id="H0D790B62403949268F086137351710A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of covered individuals who receive and complete skills training;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE232A3CDFF0F4F6F9DB042EDDBF5C7AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of covered individuals who secure employment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F68612993914CEF9431D7826A9CD46E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the job retention rate for covered individuals described in paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H54C64E8B6223458EB0A650AC25A50706"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the median salary of covered individuals described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9A4CD082DFCB476295AADA23C77E2956" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Assessment of possible expansion</header><text>Each grantee under this section shall submit to the Secretary an assessment of the feasibility of expanding the services offered under the grant program to—</text>
<paragraph id="HA7ACE5B9E36E4064B196FA616B891064"><enum>(1)</enum><text>members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA330947B5FB444BF94649F22B590642C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>covered individuals located outside the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFCF1317687BC409F918BFE6CE146A37A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to provide a grant under this section shall terminate on the date that is three years after the date on which the Secretary implements the grant program under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5E4FE2A49AC6499FB750FBBFD710EBC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than six months after the termination of the pilot program, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that includes—</text>
<paragraph id="H2A75E97A54DB4BA5910EDAB57ECFFC00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of specific activities carried out under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74BACEB59AF54EBD8A690AC36F74203D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the metrics and evaluations used to assess the effectiveness of the grant program; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6EB510D332914805951595F9EE1A68C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of the assessments submitted to the Secretary under subsection (g).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H81C7C382DB98496095A8616440E71714"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Covered individual defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means—</text>
<paragraph id="H42D63B1DC6424698B74E158BCDFCDA91"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a member of the Armed Forces participating in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense under sections 1142 and 1144 of title 10, United States Code; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97B30D12FC6E4474B3DE0836326B4BC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a spouse of a member described in subparagraph (A).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

