<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26A85-8D5-JY-RSH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4967 IS: Stop TNR Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4967</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/45">chapter 45</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, by providing for a sentencing enhancement for transnational repression committed against United States citizens or individuals who are physically present in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4bd1e7e4aec4b668b83c4a20390b5d0"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop TNR Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e6ddb4c13704bfeb05bd17051f5a911"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0ee2078ac7e8427eb384b05a0d56d754">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida6b5ce7c65ce4d888bb215f0fc0dd521">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc60c8853dc9448239f42190baf34cc51">Sec. 4. Sentencing enhancement for transnational repression.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4001a6251e73447cade6527f569bc05d">Sec. 5. Centralization of oversight of transnational prosecutions and investigations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id325f38f657ad49bcadd1634e4945eeb6">Sec. 6. United States Sentencing Commission guidelines.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idda05040e2c714fc7a6ca90be41f89766">Sec. 7. Annual reports.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idebc25e4a724d48828c3a13e0adc153fa">Sec. 8. Annual briefings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc54b5446eeec4561a2f0490f036ded38">Sec. 9. Using artificial intelligence to further investigations of transnational repression.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id27fd26779de5420590134cf6042d61fb">Sec. 10. Review and report regarding available responses to transnational repression.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id846b9b5a81664df1b0bc60246a0921d7">Sec. 11. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="id0ee2078ac7e8427eb384b05a0d56d754"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id3bc2c4963e084cf8aceceaeaf1cba057"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The governments of hostile nations, of nations controlled by authoritarian regimes, and even of some nations with which the United States has positive diplomatic relations, have increasingly and aggressively targeted United States persons and foreign nationals present in the United States to silence individuals who are perceived to oppose, or are critical of, such governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id09bb825f17be4956891d3f930de21745"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Officials and agents of such governments, and their proxies, have threatened, intimidated, harassed, surveilled, stalked, silenced, and even plotted to physically harm, kidnap, or kill persons within the United States, including by engaging in targeted attacks against political and human rights activists, journalists, academics, and members of religious and ethnic minority groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8843bafd3efd4c19959bc4e7a2c652dd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A large number of diaspora communities have experienced a rise of incidents of intimidation, harassment, and, in some cases, violence in the United States at the action, behest, or encouragement of the governments of foreign nations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4cf143294775435f9c7b9684d734b4dd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Acts of transnational repression violate national sovereignty, undermine the values that are foundational in relationships within the international community of nations, and violate United States law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0818eb190a04ca188df077d2e3375d4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Transnational repression is often used to silence critics of foreign nations and stifle speech that is protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which makes it more difficult for individuals to exercise their fundamental freedoms and human rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide64569ec63fd47229187272244222c88"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Transnational repression is not limited to physical acts of intimidation and harassment, and has been furthered by the use of online tools and technology to conduct cyberattacks, including commercial spyware and online disinformation campaigns.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id33d94a1bb16d455a85832a9c45d0213e"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Although transnational repression often involves actions that are already prohibited under United States law, the involvement of a foreign government renders such activities more dangerous than the dangers posed by the underlying acts of intimidation or harassment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id685bf49c5b204f93b8533e6a4106a615"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Transnational repression is not explicitly defined in United States law, which hinders the ability of law enforcement officials and other Federal and State officials to identify and address such conduct.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf53efffb5f0541dca961dbd517eb6ae2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Codifying a definition for transnational repression to establish sentencing enhancements will serve as a heightened deterrent for foreign actors seeking to engage in such conduct.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida6b5ce7c65ce4d888bb215f0fc0dd521"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id7637d88c68bf404c88af4da0792b7bce"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id264f28b4878c4b74be834be9c83b8c65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idacffe52a0a234ddc90a8b6030f8f4976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e8d677919ed47a38d27c85a9e161d60"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide490b602d75a43b0a800b1c06cee62ee"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52312944451d4ba8bec736d65ec0b7da">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab9ac40098944a559317ffe3887b138c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d956079c3eb410facd6fbe9c9b59b3e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transnational repression</header><text>The term <term>transnational repression</term> has the meaning given such term in section 968(a) of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 4(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc60c8853dc9448239f42190baf34cc51"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sentencing enhancement for transnational repression</header><subsection id="idf67ef96e27fd4e12b627d888cc5ce91a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/45">Chapter 45</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/967">section 967</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef4d9aefc40647899856ef876ee7b447"><section id="id9f4e9ef21e6b47d3a8d1e89de0317b70"><enum>968.</enum><header>Sentencing enhancement for transnational repression</header><subsection id="idc0c2b94d0f104fbfa4a0d91b676ad824"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this section:</text><paragraph id="idf7d213374b6642aebc016b5ed30c6efc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agent of a foreign power</header><text>The term <term>agent of a foreign power</term> means an individual who operates subject to the direction or control of a foreign power.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fa5c1e9c77745598d931391d56121d0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proxy</header><text>The term <term>proxy</term> means an individual acting on behalf of an agent of a foreign power, with objective and subjective actual knowledge of the foreign power’s involvement in directing or controlling the individual’s actions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b5f6532643c445fa9ac859b506a9097"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transnational repression</header><text>The term <term>transnational repression</term> means any activity by a foreign power, or by an agent or proxy of such foreign power, that—</text><subparagraph id="id1ea8517457a64331914b9aec69296958"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reaches beyond the internationally recognized territorial jurisdiction of such foreign power or the country from which such foreign power primarily operates or receives direction or control;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id436acff7122445a1b9ae51bd81abb63e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involves—</text><clause id="idab791dbf3ec44427a46d55c7d4f2179c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any effort intended to harass, coerce, or threaten a person, including by force or reasonable fear of death or serious bodily injury or imprisonment of a person or an immediate family member of a person;</text></clause><clause id="id504158e6509c4ce49792fbb56acecdc9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any effort intended to harass, coerce, or threaten a person to forebear from exercising rights protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or any other right guaranteed to such person by the Constitution or laws of the United States, or to retaliate against a person for having exercised such a right;</text></clause><clause id="id9d467070899f4301979a1efe68738741"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an extrajudicial killing; or</text></clause><clause id="id4ac90cada5ed432cbf46d63a07c356c9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any attempt or other act intended to further the efforts described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5df8a80b2f824fe3997c0c228fe498b1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is engaged in for a foreign power or in the interests of a foreign power; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc9bbc39d2724561beacea29331d0976"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1c00ccac9516461194ddad7f48d7b906"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occurs, in whole or in part, in the United States, including through the use of, or transmission or unauthorized access to, computers in the United States; or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab3d186a80504593bbab3fdbb31cb8ca"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is committed against a United States person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id904d9ccf4b914d4baf9c18bd2d7a9e80"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idff09affbf05b4ed7afb9545738e8570e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a national of the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida52560f2d762427998162199ecb43703"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alien who has been lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as defined in section 101(a)(20) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ff3cc0667a044a6ad20fcacc2fb296a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person who is physically present in the United States at the time of acts constituting the transnational repression.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfbeefb484dd348b39540a6d23e773774"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sentencing enhancement for transnational repression</header><text>The sentence of a person convicted of committing, or attempting or conspiring to commit, an offense under Federal law, in addition to the punishment authorized for such offense, shall be subject to an enhancement of up to 10 years imprisonment and shall include an additional fine of up to $100,000 if, as part of the course of conduct constituting such offense, the person knowingly committed, or attempted or conspired to commit, an act of transnational repression.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id45c89c51bc3c46ac8880990d67e9a928"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/45">chapter 45</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/967">section 967</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="idbd8af2ec-4ed3-4f32-a657-ae778164490d"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9f4e9ef21e6b47d3a8d1e89de0317b70">968. Sentencing enhancement for transnational repression.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id4001a6251e73447cade6527f569bc05d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Centralization of oversight of transnational prosecutions and investigations</header><subsection id="id5e47ddbdd2d247f78efee208ac3dd0d3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National security division</header><text>The Attorney General shall centralize oversight of prosecutions for offenses involving an act of transnational repression in the National Security Division of the Department of Justice, or any successor organization.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb0d3af03b3304ff6ba461f8d118aa35d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall centralize oversight of investigations of offenses involving an act of transnational repression in the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subsection></section><section id="id325f38f657ad49bcadd1634e4945eeb6"><enum>6.</enum><header>United States Sentencing Commission guidelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As soon as practicable, but not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, pursuant to its authority under section 994(p) of title 28, United States Code, the United States Sentencing Commission shall amend the Federal sentencing guidelines to the extent necessary to provide for appropriate sentencing enhancements under section 968 of title 18, United States Code, as added by section 4(a).</text></section><section id="idda05040e2c714fc7a6ca90be41f89766"><enum>7.</enum><header>Annual reports</header><subsection id="id12b294cc41414a70bee186f4c4a4a3f1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Attorney General for National Security, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of State, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the head of any other department or agency the Assistant Attorney General determines appropriate, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes incidents of transnational repression against, or otherwise impacting, any United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf1bc8297345541e19935c0b7fa75106b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall contain, with respect to the most recently concluded calendar year—</text><paragraph id="idc798a4dd48644d5f90418076751dd1ca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of trends related to transnational repression and the methods and tactics used to perpetrate the aims, including the use of artificial intelligence capabilities and commercial spyware; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3618652f1d4f42c2a6bd6c11dc9d011b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to appropriate protections for sensitive information regarding law enforcement and counterintelligence investigations and operations, a description of efforts taken by the United States Government to disrupt transnational repression, including—</text><subparagraph id="id4234c30bb845431a9ee9c95816ccc1b2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>diplomatic measures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a7da157a5e44f31ac18a8165caba5b3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>law enforcement actions, counterintelligence actions, and criminal prosecutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6b085434b91460fa729762a2d1d7b52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>civil and administrative actions, such as targeted sanctions, fines and penalties, and entry ineligibility of foreign persons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4648cc91cd4b4f498d0cc12916406115"><enum>(D)</enum><text>protective measures provided to victims; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb311f93e9b6c4b8baafb7de1c9c7c6b3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>collaboration of the United States Government with other countries that have experienced similar cases of transnational repression.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4d00332e549648ce88d3963393e850a3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, which shall be made available to the public on a Department of Justice website, but may include a classified annex, if necessary, to provide information that cannot otherwise be conveyed in unclassified form.</text></subsection></section><section id="idebc25e4a724d48828c3a13e0adc153fa"><enum>8.</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><subsection id="id56264108022e4fbf94b2dfcf7fc7a5f2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after each report is submitted pursuant to section 7, the Assistant Attorney General for National Security and a representative of any other department or agency that the Assistant Attorney General determines appropriate, shall provide an in-person briefing to the appropriate congressional committees regarding incidents of transnational repression against, or otherwise impacting, a United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfab9e180f5a64a8f9949d99167dd0e9a"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Items To be included</header> <text>Each briefing required under subsection (a) shall be subject to appropriate protections for sensitive information regarding law enforcement and counterintelligence investigations and operations, and should include, with respect to the most recently concluded calendar year—</text>
        <paragraph id="idfa55063df9bd44e6bc8618f339af1640">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>a detailed description of each instance or related groups of instances of transnational repression that has been reported to, or is otherwise under investigation by, the Department of Justice or another relevant Federal agency, including—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id7f803c2d3cc44f1c9f6e57ec280b56ba">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the nature of the transnational repression;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id192f789db42e429eaf32d1d7187883bb"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the individuals involved in the underlying conduct; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idfa2285de88ea4752a8d961eddcf6a451">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>the location of each incident of transnational repression associated with each such instance; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="ideada52017b814bdabc6e98f2338e10a8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a description of the efforts taken by the United States Government in response to each of the instances referred to in paragraph (1).</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><section id="idc54b5446eeec4561a2f0490f036ded38"><enum>9.</enum><header>Using artificial intelligence to further investigations of transnational repression</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Attorney General for National Security, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of State, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the head of any other department or agency the Assistant Attorney General determines appropriate, shall—</text><paragraph id="id480a44a4aa7b4a95aee1b2af2d39ec65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a whole-of-government strategy for preventing, investigating and responding to acts of transnational repression that are perpetrated through the use of artificial intelligence, including—</text><subparagraph id="id2e82114099634e98ad0f27597e15e882"><enum>(A)</enum><text>outreach to technology companies that are integrating or creating artificial intelligence capabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4b0fa1c01d24d6983134df4e1ec884a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engaging in multilateral efforts to address the use of artificial intelligence in the proliferation of transnational repression; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc312a6d4e23e4cb49417b4385f0bf50d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>launch an education campaign for the public regarding the trends, methods, and tactics by which artificial intelligence is being used for purposes of foreign influence, disinformation, and other forms of transnational repression.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id27fd26779de5420590134cf6042d61fb"><enum>10.</enum><header>Review and report regarding available responses to transnational repression</header><subsection id="id139fd135308046dbbe21f1283a9805eb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Attorney General for National Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a review and submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that assesses the use of existing authorities and provides recommendations for additional authorities that may be used to respond to and deter transnational repression against United States persons, including—</text><paragraph id="id0186127330c94a2d8c4efcde8ef46138"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sanctions available under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>), or under any other Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e18e8aa92784678892bdd04bdc5a4ae"><enum>(2)</enum><text>visa restrictions available under section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note), the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>), or under any other Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb54f7beade6c40bc834ff07373825da0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restrictions on assistance provided to the government of the relevant countries under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) or under any other Federal law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf23a296fee3f4b3f95bfbcb2743a2b07"><enum>(4)</enum><text>restrictions on the export of certain goods to the relevant countries under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id24798e51ab64402aad0e7888cc9fcac5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex, if necessary, to provide information that cannot otherwise be conveyed in the unclassified form.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36bbddfb749d40379931e6f5043bf278"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual review and report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Attorney General for National Security shall conduct an annual review and submit an annual report containing the information described in subsection (a) to the relevant committees of jurisdiction in the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subsection></section><section id="id846b9b5a81664df1b0bc60246a0921d7"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

