<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDE14760BF82E4EF1BB6CFC41DF3C1977" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7817 IH: No Federal Tax Dollars for Illegal Aliens Health Insurance Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7817</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to ensure that taxpayer funds for health insurance coverage are available only to authorized individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HF9D3B0490E784F828D0E733632E059B1" style="OLC">
<section id="H9236FF1E37824EDD831A3A4EB96A7F12" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Federal Tax Dollars for Illegal Aliens Health Insurance Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H41A3080226654F9188BF97F4CAC64CD7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring that taxpayer funds for health insurance coverage are available only to authorized individuals</header> <subsection id="HFBAFAD5106724E7792D982B12AF79C25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1332(a)(2)(B) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18052">42 U.S.C. 18052(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(other than the requirement described in section 1312(f)(3))</quote> before the period.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE956A5CB59BB48E8B295BB9367AE55E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of pass-Through funding for certain individuals</header><text>Section 1332(a)(3) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18052">42 U.S.C. 18052(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>No amounts paid to a State under this paragraph may be used to offset the cost of health insurance coverage (including through premium or cost sharing reductions) or to provide any other benefit with respect to an individual who is not a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully present in the United States.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCB1964418DD7467997AFA0A3D74A5D80"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rescission of certain waivers</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall rescind any waiver approved under section 1332 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18052">42 U.S.C. 18052</external-xref>) before such date that would not have been so approved had the amendments made by this section been in effect at the time of such approval.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


