<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H30CAAECEDDBF4F86A18107A9CA2EE6D2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7754 IH: Take Your Rate Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7754</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a study on the feasibility and potential impacts of portable Federally backed mortgage loans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8407840D4C814B97B61FA18A8973C13A" style="OLC"><section id="H0A633C8B5D7F4B4FB7B73B3B8A7BD78A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Take Your Rate Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF02D9285032B40BCA452C978AA93B253"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on mortgage portability</header><subsection id="H4733C362E10D401F8990DE6DD8991CDF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall jointly conduct a study on the feasibility and potential impacts of mortgage loan portability for Federally backed mortgage loans.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B0DF2AB0A8F4FA095101EB0B08C5AAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required considerations</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="H8AA8581E47A044E9909A2CD54C93DDE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administrative and operational feasibility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27E0E264C18F432EA2146C3FC98F0E7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the effect on the housing market if Federally backed mortgage loans were portable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDA6A0B5C16B44CEA31EFFFF6A7CF1D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any changes to rulemaking and regulations at the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Federal Housing Finance Agency to allow such mortgages to become portable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4EF63AAF87F4BDD8FD14816A36EFAEE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how many current borrowers would benefit from such portable mortgages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H634D242552D04E07BA7867144E4E70B9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the budgetary impact that such portable mortgages would have on the Federal Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D5551ADCEAD47BB977CABA8115CA903"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>the financial safety and soundness implications for federally backed mortgage programs and the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation if such mortgages were portable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF60198358B40EF9589D16C32041675"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any statutory changes needed, if any;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H860BCDF189A04149A9521A2B19FBC5ED"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recommendations on whether a limited demonstration program would be beneficial and how it should be administered;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC02CAE220DB47569638FED9A9D26787"> <enum>(9)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other information the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency finds important to include; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2269F14061504861AAAB3270EC4A6552"><enum>(10)</enum><text>if the Secretary and Director determines that it is not feasible, recommendations regarding similar solutions or alternative program designs that could be administered to provide relief on the housing market.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8E9699E57CA440DBFA3D66A9AA2D4DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency may consult with the following entities if it would be beneficial for the study and report:</text><paragraph id="H28C251FEDB424C148A78EA000475D9F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal National Mortgage Association.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15E763407C874935BB8AC19126102E80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FBBB7D42D894A4A8C552CA0E22CE9C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Housing Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54431CB7802D4257A7146529809B5EB7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF385E879E7143FC981A19062B37B4F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6729C4DC7DF240CAA55DE6A58C9EAE6B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Mortgage lenders and servicers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6BC961ECC78483E8A0F501985A77DB9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other Federal agencies, departments, or outside industries that it sees as beneficial.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9378A470A5FA4D2ABB9EF858357C6494"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Federally backed mortgage loan defined</header> <text>In this Act, The term <quote>Federally backed mortgage loan</quote> means any loan (other than temporary financing such as a construction loan) that—</text>
        <paragraph id="H828A3305DF9048BA97C18AF23F3E8CD0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>is secured by a first or subordinate lien on residential real property (including individual units of condominiums and cooperatives) designed principally for the occupancy of 1 to 4 families, including any such secured loan, the proceeds of which are used to prepay or pay off an existing loan secured by the same property; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA682A960AA634168B17CF733B9560C2D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>is made in whole or in part, or insured, guaranteed, supplemented, or assisted in any way, by any officer or agency of the Federal Government or under or in connection with a housing or urban development program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or a housing or related program administered by any other such officer or agency, or is purchased or securitized by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><section id="H793E4A9C4D2C42F8A3DFE681A703B0DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Director shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a joint report containing—</text><paragraph id="H1AB259ED8E4E47E2A7EF0000F615D750"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the study required under section 2;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76A38CD5D05F4A6BB8FE090FFC47A28B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>policy recommendations, if any;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A0C015FA3B54B6B80F1BDC18421EAB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of risks and benefits to taxpayers and financial markets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27AA6959A0F14ED2886912CA39442CFF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any dissenting views from either agency.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

