<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H7E997E4E7A80415EBD598C2223F08A88" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8897 RH: Improving Travel for American Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 639</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8897</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–735]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 19, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve travel for American families, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HHM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HC6764CB4FAB5432594B6CB35E03B5358"><section id="HAAE4B8CA72904F84B8AC78276BFBFB5C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Travel for American Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC34B38E7B31F4BF3A9F266795AD92314"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving travel for American families pilot program</header><subsection id="HCFC0744CE4CA41419AE8751DF38D481E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), may establish a pilot program at airports to expedite access to security screening for adult passengers and accompanying child passengers twelve years of age and under to support and facilitate the ease of travel for such passengers and such child passengers. The Administrator may carry out this subsection only such access does not compromise security protocols.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C0C58052F514D28AF7BCBA944A575AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Security requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), the Administrator shall carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="H33F2C0BA883940D1B870A0371093D225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ensure each passenger described in such subsection is screened in accordance with the vetting status of such passenger under the Secure Flight program of the Transportation Security Administration, in accordance with paragraph (2) of section 44903(j) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7117DB21C63C4E1BB1F45C52310B7F38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Prevent individuals carrying out screening functions under section 44901 of such title from allowing any passenger into a TSA PreCheck or other expedited security screening lane unless such passenger has received a boarding pass indicating eligibility for TSA PreCheck or such other expedited security screening.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28EAA4A631574F4FB470AE899FAB9A2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Permit local Administration management to open or close checkpoint lanes and reallocate available resources as needed to maximize security effectiveness and efficiency based on passenger volume.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CFBC63BD8B9481982AA78D1183C92AE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of airports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), in selecting airports for such pilot program, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="HB8B6E7217D3A4D82A82A868F17411731" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give priority to an airport the Administrator determines to have a high volume of passengers traveling with accompanying child passengers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BBCF347BE3648EDA0DA2E929F3982D1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider airports with adequate space to accommodate additional or larger security screening lanes and sufficient personnel to aid passengers and accompanying child passengers twelve years of age and under while maintaining adequate staffing of other security screening lanes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCB23399B97C401A8E918E6C8416784D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>use any other consideration the Administrator determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA26125EE0D34C69B3771EC9B23A1673" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), not later than 270 days after such establishment, the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a briefing on such pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5E61C455FAD84A1E94B1C115AFEB8FA9" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), the Administrator shall carry out such pilot program for a period of two years.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

