<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E997E4E7A80415EBD598C2223F08A88" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8897 IH: Improving Travel for American Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8897</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve travel for American families, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H42254D58B4FD46299D273B9C870FEA8D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7ABBB3B89E8A45E09F4E527541A79C06" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Travel for American Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H0268356693AE4C9EB24491E7C832544E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving travel for American families pilot program</header> 
<subsection id="H38DA3C9B14D943C08BC1F1C812E1B148" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including any such provisions applicable to issuance of regulations, such as chapters 5 and 8 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote> and the <quote>Congressional Review Act</quote>), and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>)), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), shall establish a pilot program, to be carried out at a minimum of five airports, to implement alternative security screening lanes and security screening approaches for passengers and accompanying child passengers twelve years of age and under to support and facilitate the ease of travel for such passengers and such child passengers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC6A1559643F54344ADA7DB3983C662E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of airports</header><text>In selecting airports for the pilot program under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE76BA79F53D645649324874B1BBAE9BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give priority to an airport the Administrator determines to have a high volume of passengers traveling with accompanying child passengers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F339C26F81544BD9137FCAA012F519E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider airports with adequate space to accommodate additional or larger security screening lanes and sufficient personnel to aid passengers and accompanying child passengers twelve years of age and under while maintaining adequate staffing of other security screening lanes; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D7130DD83C84310A3860329E38E4346"><enum>(3)</enum><text>use any other consideration the Administrator determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6AFC4BAC602C4E3EA55226C08D352402" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a briefing on the pilot program under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2043AD3C50254D1EAED4A379C71EC974" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Administrator shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) for a period of two years.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

