<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9BBBB5E2F78940359DD96BCA5B1D9ED3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8992 IH: Supreme Court Certiorari Oversight and Transparency Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8992</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a panel to review certiorari petitions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD30D40C0F4845D0912FC1F665D1E828" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA3CBD0A36AF94CE598E2143A2C79A222" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supreme Court Certiorari Oversight and Transparency Standards Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SCCOTUS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H91D370C6A79D49DA9C251DFC2F45FE14"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certification panel</header> 
<subsection id="H0B91276DA6DE4BF1A087B4DE7F4425E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/81">Chapter 81</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1254">section 1254</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H1A9E68E2CA264597BB8CBD72681D6709" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H054C15E2576343FEB3B4EC82D2F97922"><enum>1255.</enum><header>Supreme Court certification panel</header> <subsection id="HD3E0632302BA425D944C21B30C955544"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a body to be known as the Supreme Court Certification Panel (hereinafter <quote>the Panel</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC02235BAEEB4C6BB838697B9DA3D6F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Panel shall consist of 13 circuit judges of the United States courts of appeals.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H1F7E1FA905C447D8B866CC31868A8F25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Random Selection and Rotation</header> <paragraph id="HDBFA61E768E44E57A070CD71D4F9F4C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Term designations</header><text>At the beginning of each term of the Supreme Court, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall, using the random selection process established under subsection (g)(11)(B), designate 1 circuit judge from each United States court of appeals, who shall serve on the Panel for that term.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F4D0FD149A342DB9F555C1CDD1968C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each circuit judge designated under this section shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H88FF0121739E470C920D2B7E99C79608"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an active judge who has served in Federal judicial office not less than 5 years; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7FD174FE6D049278D7ECE7A8D268523"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a senior or retired judge who is listed on the roster maintained under section 294.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H682675B41711469899B28874CB88BD20"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consecutive service</header><text>No judge may serve on the Panel for more than 1 consecutive term.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53A7BE087B2B43A0ADA900804B0505F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assignment</header><text>The Panel shall be assigned all petitions for writs of certiorari for review.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H50830D4D4878475A90FADA036679B66C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Presiding Judge</header><text>The most senior judge shall serve as Presiding Judge of the Panel for that term.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF03706005337458F9EC0A91EA6D9DEAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Support Staff</header><text>The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall provide administrative and clerical support to the Panel.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H8052FD81D482433EB6D2000BADE51907"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>If a member of the panel dies, retires, or is unable to serve the remainder of the member’s term, within 90 days of the occurrence of the vacancy, the vacancy shall be filled by a circuit judge in accordance with subsection (c)(2). The circuit judge so designated shall serve for the remainder of the term of the former member.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07046B8DA69A4D6EB90EEE4CB72B13BD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Jurisdiction and duties of panel</header> 
<paragraph id="H18F9AF9AD1BD46AABE53B0EA8FD0CE10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Primary function</header><text>The Panel shall review all petitions for writs of certiorari filed with the Supreme Court and grant or deny such petitions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC84DD92E79EA48BAAE65F83405FC8925"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reviewing a petition for a writ of certiorari</header> <subparagraph id="H2F956F18F12C4857B9AA9F553B042A09"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A decision to grant a petition for a writ of certiorari shall require the concurrence of 4 members of the Panel.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6AFDC06B2DB340D8B998E7910ADDA4AF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Written statement</header><text>Each decision to grant a petition for a writ of certiorari shall include a written statement briefly explaining the reason for granting such request and identifying the questions presented for review.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A38E3308CD5468DB75611B714BB9434"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consolidation</header><text>The Panel may consolidate petitions for writs of certiorari presenting substantially identical questions of law and certify them jointly.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB1FBB2F5E9046B68AF5EE4633DFBC95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When a petition for a writ of certiorari is denied, the Panel shall enter an order of denial stating that none of the criteria in paragraph (5) were sufficiently met and no further explanation is required.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H231EFA5871004B9BBCDCB8E630050558" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Stays pending appeal</header><text>A member of the Panel shall have the same authority to grant a stay as a Justice of the Supreme Court has under Supreme Court Rule 23 (or any successor rule).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8D5ABB6F83E4351BA6FB6C2BC0C8876"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Criteria for certification</header><text>The Panel may grant a petition for a writ of certiorari only if one or more of the following criteria are met:</text> <subparagraph id="H4D8A80BE2C1546AF8FDD8D30DA3789A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Considerations governing review</header><text>A petition for a writ of certiorari may be granted only for compelling reasons, including—</text> 
<clause id="H678FB8C9B78A45ABB8788CF964451580"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a United States court of appeals has entered a decision in conflict with the decision of another United States court of appeals on the same important matter;</text></clause> <clause id="H4CA5170186214B5EA82E90AC1F4C4735"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has decided an important Federal question in a way that conflicts with a decision by a State court of last resort, or has so far departed from the accepted and usual course of judicial proceedings, or sanctioned such a departure by an inferior court, as to call for an exercise of supervisory power of the Supreme Court;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDC7E40F8F1894964967D7CD7C5633BE5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State court of last resort has decided an important Federal question in a way that conflicts with the decision of another State court of last resort or of a United States court of appeals;</text></clause> <clause id="HC2CDD3D7FA214858A49955D858E424A3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State court or a United States court of appeals has decided an important question of Federal law that has not been, but should be, settled by the Supreme Court, or has decided an important Federal question in a way that conflicts with relevant decisions of this Court.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2E682D06BB9494BA7F389C60FFE9038"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Granting a petition before judgment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A petition for a writ of certiorari to review a case pending in a United States court of appeals, before judgment is entered in that court, may only be granted upon a showing that the case is of such imperative public importance as to justify deviation from normal appellate practice and to require immediate determination by the Supreme Court.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFEC77F53486412792E4480FF4F19556"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Panel may not reexamine factual findings or weigh the sufficiency of evidence in the record.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4A9E25783EF4027B6CAF12D9C249ACE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Operating procedures</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE9C84DB63DBD4D80BC2E58FBD834D569"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Panel shall sit as a motions court, meeting at least once monthly during the term, and may conduct business electronically when necessary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4565F1A6DFB45C1B484C48CEB426648"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Six judges shall constitute a quorum.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00AFE9B165BD4C22ABD5FDCC138865CB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public reporting</header> 
<clause id="H2B64E1CCB00B4D4EB8258CF07AD4DD49"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the close of each term, the Panel shall issue a public report, published on the website of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts and submitted to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate summarizing—</text> <subclause id="HCD58EFB7AA664732B0C394E032544726"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of petitions reviewed;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD10ABEEFE5394D63852F5D309E36AAB7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of petitions granted and denied; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDB081C4BE5954820915A9CFE1D3EE56E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>general statistical data on grounds for granting such petitions.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H01C6D8E07C124914BBF965CE5C97BA95"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No report issued pursuant to clause (i) may disclose confidential deliberations or identifying information about pending cases.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H363942F0EB314586928874D98482BFD6" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transmission to the Supreme Court</header><text>Each petition for a writ of certiorari that is granted shall be transmitted to the Clerk of the Supreme Court to be entered on the docket.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC77C63FF76A64DA39272647913265F33"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Review by the Supreme Court</header><text>A petition for a writ of certiorari granted by the Panel shall be deemed granted by the Supreme Court. The Supreme Court shall set the case for oral argument pursuant to Supreme Court Rules.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H70E36D3D6EBB45CA9E88655F01507D70"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Ethics and disqualification</header> <subparagraph id="H98D27814F0494EB5B84213E20AE42D07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ethics</header><text>Panel judges shall be subject to the Code of Conduct for United States Judges and standards for recusal.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB86FC4B8C4EF4D7D86714769ACED2CEE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disqualification</header><text>A judge who participated in a case in an inferior court shall be disqualified from any consideration of a petition for writ of certiorari with respect to that case.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A5ACF5063114727A870D94238A13D1D"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Implementation</header> <subparagraph id="H37427782692F4B4891711DB67A56EBA8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Judicial Conference of the United States shall promulgate rules governing the administration and operation of the Panel consistent with this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8BC2D85DCF846708EA2E1EE1993D46A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Record keeping</header><text>The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall establish the random-selection mechanism and maintain public records of the selection process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H632F93D7BA8C4C9CB7804269AC93031F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>term</quote> means the term commencing on the first Monday in October of each year and such other adjourned or special term as the Supreme Court may hold.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA69043FD6A3B4CEBA3AE3117E68A77DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1255">section 1255</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H804C8777454648E9AE000BB80A4DF036" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">1254A. Supreme Court certification panel.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HF7657586C1194EC780EAFF83997149D4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such a provision or amendment to any particular person or circumstance is held invalid, the remaining provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such remaining provisions and amendments to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

