<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26423-RP5-CS-LFY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 718 ATS: A resolution commending and congratulating the University of California, Los Angeles Bruins women’s basketball team for winning the 2026 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Women’s Basketball National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 718</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution commending and congratulating the University of California, Los Angeles Bruins women’s basketball team for winning the 2026 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Women’s Basketball National Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on Sunday, April 5, 2026, the University of California, Los Angeles (referred to in this preamble as <quote>UCLA</quote>) Bruins’ women’s basketball team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>UCLA Bruins</quote> or the <quote>Bruins</quote>) won the National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NCAA</quote>) Division I Women’s Basketball National Championship (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>National Championship</quote>) by defeating the University of South Carolina Gamecocks 79–51 at the Mortgage Matchup Center in Phoenix, Arizona;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this is the UCLA Bruins’ first NCAA National Championship title in women’s basketball and second women’s basketball national championship title in program history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bruins' win against South Carolina secured UCLA’s 126<subscript>th</subscript> NCAA team national championship, the second most of any program in the NCAA;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Head Coach Cori Close, in her 15th season leading the team and 18th season on the coaching staff at UCLA, led the Bruins to a 37–1 record, going undefeated in Big Ten conference play and winning both the Big Ten regular season title and the Big Ten tournament title;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 6 seniors—Lauren Betts, Gabriela Jaquez, Kiki Rice, Angela Dugalic, Gianna Kneepkens, and Charlisse Leger-Walker—scored every point for the Bruins during the National Championship game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Betts, who finished the National Championship game with 14 points and 11 rebounds, was named the NCAA Tournament’s <quote>Most Outstanding Player</quote>; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the UCLA Bruins demonstrated incredible fortitude, dedication, teamwork, and sportsmanship throughout the season: Now, therefore be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id71fdc47bd4454c94a40c0dea6179204a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the UCLA Bruins' women’s basketball team for winning the 2026 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I Women’s Basketball National Championship; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08a583f176bb4d84a1b267a9136084a7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates the players, coaches, staff, and managers of the UCLA Bruins’ women’s basketball team for their historic achievement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecb8456123f347e9a31369d6caae0d7b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="id63ba7ef201b840e18a9189b38c831081"><enum>(A)</enum><text>UCLA Chancellor Julio Frenk;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63813c1e0cdf4fee88fd116857a1bd7d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>UCLA Bruins’ Women’s Basketball Head Coach Cori Close; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id369c1c87cf214f828b48300ab6c5137f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>UCLA Athletic Director Martin Jarmond.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

