<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCA29E7DC97C84220B7C0F9A4E2AEC8DA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7478 IH: Patient Debt Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish certain standards and requirements with respect to financial assistance and medical debt collection for hospitals participating in the Medicare program, and to amend title III of the Public Health Service Act to establish a grant program for purposes of medical debt relief.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H03BCDD9B6B80451D8247B5AD9326721A" style="OLC"><section id="HE41C16BA128C46AD940BE2DDE5FAFE76" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patient Debt Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB3CF79E023BA41388C342F8F4BAEC740"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishing standards and requirements with respect to financial assistance and medical debt collection as condition of participation in the Medicare program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1866 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H689CD6AD5B0D483796C26B64C3E4CCE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H63517847F2374636ADE56CE86B80D0B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (X), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFC45C47D946470585D6353FFE809201"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F652DDE1CC9434E9ADCA483BF00A231"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2A48F584A50C4DAFB421D29D3D697DEE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H24A7685E3B2D4854ACFC7658B2D21633" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(Z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a hospital, beginning January 1, 2028, to comply with the financial assistance and debt collection requirements described in subsection (l).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31AE495BD45C40E7A73A9049135E1A72" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H416AFE0A53204D4B85B61E174678B5B6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H4BD39E53A67547F09E6DE3DB560D1E8F" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H21860CFE66354C0990FC2F0CA9498B1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A hospital that fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (a)(1)(Z) (relating to financial assistance and debt collection) is subject to a civil monetary penalty under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA5F3388389242448FFDD9A08277812E" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary may impose a civil monetary penalty in an amount specified by the Secretary (but not to exceed $1,000,000) for each instance of noncompliance with the requirements of subsection (a)(1)(Z), as determined by the Secretary, if—</text><clause id="H4608609445B943B78DF3E0A3FFBBE9C1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary determines such noncompliance exists, the Secretary submits to such hospital a notification of such determination; and</text></clause><clause id="H582683F9C2F24AB48CFBFA74BB16CB42" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as of the date that is 45 days after such notification is sent, the Secretary determines that such hospital has not taken meaningful actions to come into compliance with such requirements.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil monetary penalty under this paragraph in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD07A3EF43C5A4253B07CE69592B38E04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5C43443924A3475FA12FA82B59004C3E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H93FFD0662EC747A0956184EFB1D491E5"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Financial assistance and debt collection requirements</header><paragraph id="H786598F3F42945FFBBDFFD4FCAF2E6E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(Z), the financial assistance and debt collection requirements are, with respect to a hospital—</text><subparagraph id="HA168A151848C4A3BBBABD5415100F6CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the financial assistance and charity care requirements described in <internal-xref idref="HDE4428705D25460DB09504010571CEAB" legis-path="(l)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC85C6DEF7B6433B863796C38517DC8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the medical debt collection limitations described in <internal-xref idref="H8E28E205473D4F65B62465FF7608D823" legis-path="(l)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE4428705D25460DB09504010571CEAB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial assistance and charity care requirements</header><text>For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H786598F3F42945FFBBDFFD4FCAF2E6E7" legis-path="(l)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the requirements described in this paragraph are, with respect to a hospital, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H71F66E3DA10B4A7E8DF5BF8C53060D92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The hospital—</text><clause id="H343DF44A6DEC4694A6BDFAA593E3D5AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has established a charity care or financial assistance policy;</text></clause><clause id="HA9E5CA2E76DC41B387BE9F45AD1BE892"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has established minimum eligibility requirements with respect to such charity care or financial assistance policy, and has made such requirements publicly available; and</text></clause><clause id="H3F82E8A95D604115A6914905F2E694F0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has established a process for screening individuals furnished items or services by the hospital to determine whether each such individual may be eligible for assistance with respect to payment for such items or services pursuant to such charity care or financial assistance policy.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884C355BC313415C9C865F25A4FA2AC9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to items or services furnished by the hospital to an individual who has applied for charity care or financial assistance under the policy described in <internal-xref idref="H343DF44A6DEC4694A6BDFAA593E3D5AB" legis-path="(l)(2)(A)(i)">subparagraph (A)(i)</internal-xref>, the hospital—</text><clause id="H6780E940931D4D619E4F32F1DA433C5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determines, not later than 30 days before the date on which payment for such items or services is due, whether such individual is eligible for assistance with respect to such payment pursuant to such charity care or financial assistance policy;</text></clause><clause id="H33F369F61A7C49339AD38B43AA779FF1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case that a hospital determines pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H6780E940931D4D619E4F32F1DA433C5C" legis-path="(l)(2)(B)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> that an individual is ineligible for such charity care or financial assistance policy with respect to such payment, permits such individual to appeal such determination; and</text></clause><clause id="HE745C7E6F14E44E6B4BF1DAA16CC8EA3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not seek to collect such payment from such individual until the determination under <internal-xref idref="H6780E940931D4D619E4F32F1DA433C5C" legis-path="(l)(2)(B)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> with respect to such individual has been made.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8A4A5B572604096874441C17C2F57D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The hospital includes with any bill for payment with respect to items or services furnished by the hospital to an individual—</text><clause id="H15EE564682654474B20320D31C15C568"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the minimum eligibility requirements described in <internal-xref idref="HA9E5CA2E76DC41B387BE9F45AD1BE892" legis-path="(l)(2)(A)(ii)">subparagraph (A)(ii)</internal-xref> with respect to the charity care or financial assistance policy of the hospital;</text></clause><clause id="H3320F61C8F564737A726BED2C19F7080"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notice of the medical debt collection limitations described in <internal-xref idref="H8E28E205473D4F65B62465FF7608D823" legis-path="(l)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref>, including the repayment program described in subparagraph (C)(ii) of such paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H52657B9A537E47CAA9CCDC087E287D22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructions for the individual to submit to the hospital any information that would be necessary for the hospital to make a determination with respect to the household income of such individual at the time such items or services were furnished for purposes of carrying out subparagraph (D) of such paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E28E205473D4F65B62465FF7608D823" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medical debt collection limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H786598F3F42945FFBBDFFD4FCAF2E6E7" legis-path="(l)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the limitations described in this paragraph are, with respect to a hospital and medical debt owed to the hospital by an individual, that—</text><subparagraph id="H659C7FC8E7D84C53880BC982EB77B50A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the hospital does not seek to place a lien on or foreclose upon the home of such individual in order to collect such medical debt;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB02BB4C6BEC142B89999235D3FEFF6B9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the hospital does not seek to garnish the wages of such individual in order to collect such medical debt;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6320B7EBC0A499B96D751CE7CB2C668"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to <internal-xref idref="H0907B0DD70B34D01BCCC83B7F2EB23B6" legis-path="(l)(4)(D)(ii)">subparagraph (D)(ii)</internal-xref>, the hospital does not sell or assign such medical debt to a debt collector unless—</text><clause id="H86DA931B9B2C42CAA2A5DA4F3BEFFC52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 1 year has elapsed since the date on which payment for such items or services was due;</text></clause><clause id="HBF2AE4E855C14A0AB1D3347F08EA2613"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the hospital makes available to the individual a repayment program under which the individual may make minimum monthly payments (provided that each such payment does not exceed 4 percent of the gross monthly income of such individual) toward the medical debt, and such individual fails to make 4 or more consecutive monthly payments under such repayment program or otherwise declines to participate in such repayment program; and</text></clause><clause id="H39BEE9B73C2E4A3F89F677EC24715566"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such debt collector agrees to abide by the limitations described in subparagraphs <internal-xref idref="H659C7FC8E7D84C53880BC982EB77B50A" legis-path="(l)(4)(A)">(A)</internal-xref> and<internal-xref idref="HB02BB4C6BEC142B89999235D3FEFF6B9" legis-path="(l)(4)(B)"> (B)</internal-xref> for such hospital with respect to such medical debt; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA3DB1AB6D8743A88077B47DB2BBECCD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that the hospital has received the necessary information to make the determination described in <internal-xref idref="H52657B9A537E47CAA9CCDC087E287D22" legis-path="(l)(2)(B)(iii)">paragraph (2)(C)(iii)</internal-xref>, if the hospital determines that the household income of such individual was not in excess of 250 percent of the poverty line for the size of the family involved for the most recent taxable year at the time the items or services that are the subject of such medical debt were furnished, the hospital—</text><clause id="HF0124C904BD84B20987E280DEA26F5B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not impose an annual interest rate with respect to such payment; and</text></clause><clause id="H5112C97915E84890A416FBA835F66018"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not sell or assign such medical debt to a debt collector.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C039AB7096A4C64A190FD47D70FD4AE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Monitoring compliance</header><subparagraph id="HBB7B1FF0B9A042E7A873EAE9D08C6A21"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary shall conduct an audit of a random sample of hospitals to determine whether each such hospital is in compliance with the requirements of <internal-xref idref="H786598F3F42945FFBBDFFD4FCAF2E6E7" legis-path="(l)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAE0AAAE87394B7DADAAEEEB49E54556" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Online portal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2028, the Secretary shall establish a secure internet website portal (or other successor technology) to permit individuals to report the noncompliance of a hospital with the requirements of <internal-xref idref="H786598F3F42945FFBBDFFD4FCAF2E6E7" legis-path="(l)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, including noncompliance with the limitations described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <internal-xref idref="H8E28E205473D4F65B62465FF7608D823" legis-path="(l)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref> of a debt collector to which the hospital has sold or assigned medical debt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0907B0DD70B34D01BCCC83B7F2EB23B6" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H04BB92F6ABDD4EFD89AB1A83864D075A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Debt collector</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>debt collector</term> has the meaning given such term in section 803(6) of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1692a">15 U.S.C. 1692a(6)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09F50510501B49A988BBDC2173C97E05" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Medical debt</header><text>The term <term>medical debt</term> means, with respect to items or services furnished by a hospital to an individual, the debt (as defined in section 803(5) of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1692a">15 U.S.C. 1692a(5)</external-xref>)) of such individual for such items or services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HCA38CA99511E4587A2F7435366D9E9A9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Medical debt relief program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6FC34AD0F74E4165988189EB7D9A5E89" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H5C07F6C6C6A7426F94EDEC386A1F0F50"><enum>399V–8.</enum><header>Medical debt relief grant program</header><subsection id="HD7B7E25AEC9148BDACF1B5E1265BC1CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary may make grants to not more than 1 eligible nonprofit organization to acquire and discharge the medical debt (as defined by the Secretary) of eligible individuals in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F992A41A93242B6A3A2FA75B8904EED" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible nonprofit seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC7B01F242890499182292760195F84FE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts provided under a grant under this section shall be used to—</text><paragraph id="H4D99F6834CC441C8A2CC902E86F6C5E7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify eligible individuals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H675F8F479DA841A78A09FC59609FF6DE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acquire and discharge the medical debt of such individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H512D5BFDF26A4C17942FFEC8386C7D17"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice and reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="H290C48EABEEA4CC190194A40EEEAAA58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice requirement</header><text>Not later than 60 days after an eligible nonprofit organization that has received a grant under this section acquires and discharges the medical debt of an eligible individual under <internal-xref idref="HC7B01F242890499182292760195F84FE" legis-path="399V–8.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, such eligible nonprofit organization shall notify such individual of such acquisition and discharge.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89E12B7A3D8148E9837B6F14C74172C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not less frequently than once per calendar quarter, an eligible nonprofit organization that has received a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary a report containing the following information with respect to the preceding calendar quarter:</text><subparagraph id="HCBD5E811DF824C60BB98D3B27C059686" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The actions taken by the eligible nonprofit organization to identify eligible individuals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6688F99ECF94D369B592D4B42BE429F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of eligible individuals whose medical debt was acquired and discharged by the eligible nonprofit organization, and the amount of medical debt so acquired and discharged.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H339EA53C76B24DEDBEB9CBE28A228A2A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9F998F081CC440CA1A1389ECA0C6DD8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H458034A96DAF469680D38EA745F54F2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual with medical debt if, for the most recent taxable year—</text><subparagraph id="H785E6A637B5541918C11E6E62DB9D3A4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such medical debt is equivalent to 5 percent or more of the modified adjusted gross income of such individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4598893BB8364EDBB5E848C03F8169CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the household income of such individual is not in excess of 400 percent of the poverty line for the size of the family involved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D09F319867243A4934358D55330A87A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>eligible nonprofit organization</term> means a nonprofit organization with the mission of relieving individuals of their medical debt, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA70230EEB70C485F98C336C86B94BD16" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>IRC terms</header><text>The terms <term>household income</term>, <term>modified adjusted gross income</term>, and <term>poverty line</term> have the meaning given each such term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">26 U.S.C. 36B</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAE32FE9A7BC43DEB2AF5D857073598E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for purposes of carrying out this section $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2027, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

