<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26165-D1T-YL-3PG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3889 IS: American Lending Fairness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3889</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To restore and clarify the intent of the Federal interest rate exportation parity for State-chartered banks by allowing States to opt out of preemption only with respect to loans made by their own chartered institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Lending Fairness Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id83fd973e914f40ebbf8c66d4241dd861"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interest rate applicable to out-of-State chartered financial institutions</header><subsection id="id24c1a36b07b14c8ea1ffd10e8e3d2529"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Insured depository institutions</header><text>Section 27 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831d">12 U.S.C. 1831d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d670e17d8f14418b24e4931abf37f72"><subsection id="id9a83b19a56374d6fa78ed5eb60f1b2de"><enum>(c)</enum><text>If a State adopts a law or certifies that the voters of the State have voted in favor of any provision, constitutional or otherwise, that states explicitly and by its terms that the State does not want this subsection to apply with respect to loans made by institutions chartered by that State, subsection (a) shall not apply to loans made by (or for which a commitment to make such loan was entered into by) such institutions after the date on which that law is adopted or such certification is made.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idd72808e54f33468b9737b02cc399a7c1"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Insured credit unions</header> <text>Section 205(g) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1785">12 U.S.C. 1785(g)</external-xref>) <quote>is amended</quote> by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id92ce8a968fa2439fb04818e46094ec50">
                    <paragraph id="ida4bfa59075f745ca8b474ead8365e9ef" indent="up1">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>If a State adopts a law or certifies that the voters of the State have voted in favor of any provision, constitutional or otherwise, that states explicitly and by its terms that the State does not want this subsection to apply with respect to loans made by institutions chartered by that State, paragraph (1) shall not apply to loans made by (or for which a commitment to make such loan was entered into by) such institutions after the date on which that law is adopted or such certification is made.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idb3a018acfd8d4ecb823e023c421844cc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeal</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03e802203ad645e0a8ff7898d4e5f114"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Section 525 of the Depository Institutions Deregulation and Monetary Control Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1730g">12 U.S.C. 1730g</external-xref> note) is hereby repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9db5f5f1419c42b48e1d934ce2d43f45" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply with respect to, and govern the legal effect of, any State law adopted or certification made pursuant to section 525 of the Depository Institutions Deregulation and Monetary Control Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1730g">12 U.S.C. 1730g</external-xref> note) before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

