<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25C16-KPS-JC-7TT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3107 IS: Upholding a Secure Postal System Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3107</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251105">November 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to submit reports to Congress on theft of mail and United States Postal Service property, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0FE19040F5964749A50C81A7BC00EE51"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1ED86F785F644B479374B4BA8ADD60C2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Upholding a Secure Postal System Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>USPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H354FB8C7CB32441C8B5F60322C5235C1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on mail and Postal Service property theft<editorial></editorial></header><subsection id="H0F9D5C53E8F441A1844D3E5D3C763564"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and each year thereafter for 5 years, the Comptroller General of the United States shall investigate nationwide patterns and instances of theft of mail and United States Postal Service property and submit a report on each such investigation to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection><subsection id="H00C017046EB94627B308141F929B9574"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report under subsection (a) shall include a description of any measures the Postal Service has in place to address such theft, and recommendations on how the Postal Service and Congress can combat such theft.</text></subsection><subsection id="H55CC4DA6D0A849AE9348306BF31779A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Comptroller General shall consult with the Inspector General of the Postal Service and the United States Postal Inspection Service.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

