<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E7BC96CADAC485A90C7B3D4D8EC1598" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6096 IH: Newborns Essentials Support Toolkit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6096</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title V of the Social Security Act to include as a special project of regional and national significance the purchase, acquisition, and distribution to mothers of newborn infants newborn supply kits, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D3A62F40D144E6AB917456107B24D19" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H91C1A55813AF40209482333EC070C1CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Newborns Essentials Support Toolkit Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NEST Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H4A9DF26B8C334F76A27BBD892C20D0DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Newborn supply kits</header> <subsection id="H3E3C02B6644743A48F6E16F666C893D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 501(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/701">42 U.S.C. 701(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2B48B1EBCBB54B5D9BE8DE1918140769"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and for evidence-based programs</quote> and inserting <quote>for evidence-based programs</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E3DA50887CF4D1796905C6104DF5DDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before <quote>; and</quote> at the end the following: <quote>, and for the purchase, acquisition, and distribution of newborn supply kits distributed in accordance with subsection (d)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA09A0A8B09EC4E1A8A672285B94FF440"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Newborn supply kit defined</header><text>Section 501(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/701">42 U.S.C. 701(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="traditional" id="HB51464E6904A48C3A42849BB08E50D67" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HEA063D74D5F046FEBE080E5393F70540"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>newborn supply kit</term> means a kit composed of essential goods to help mothers recover from childbirth and care for newborn infants that includes the following items:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4566C8C6683B4B65803B63A29B3D808E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Diapers, wipes, hygiene items, blankets, and thermometers for newborn infants.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0694265CB6314D4C97C863F57C3D8156"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Postpartum pads, lotion, cold packs, breastfeeding supplies, information on the National Maternal Mental Health Hotline established under section 399V–7 of the Public Health Service Act, information on the National Women’s Health and Breastfeeding Helpline and additional educational material on breastfeeding, information about Federal programs providing support to postpartum women and children, such as the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966, and evidence-based educational material on the use of low-dose aspirin to address hypertension, preeclampsia, and preterm birth.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D0A41AD63834591993870C64791842A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A blood pressure monitor. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A75A0370A03436E96F7B7DA715416A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Other items necessary to support infant and postpartum health (as determined by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27C0DDB15C844812B407114FE158F033"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Set-aside</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 501(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/701">42 U.S.C. 701(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H974655424486488295B5696F01E3ECCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (6); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA6932F310C64E02AB8A59BBCD3CE68D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDFFE6FD6706742DAB58923C18B0C434B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H03C57B23D2C64600B3F4B0481168145B" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, of the funds made available under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve not more than $5,000,000 for the purpose of enabling the Secretary to provide for special projects of regional and national significance for the purchase, acquisition, and distribution of newborn supply kits in accordance with subsection (d). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H69BF79DEBA104867BCC1ED69367B7B4B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 501 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/701">42 U.S.C. 701</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9B0C746563024E7E9EB4FEFDFCEB2667" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HD23C50FA872647778BFDF6AACD171065"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph id="H11DC47B82CD346D8BBBC7860274FEDE3" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In purchasing or acquiring newborn supply kits using funds made available under subsection (c)(5), the Secretary shall make grants or enter into cooperative agreements with nonprofit entities that have a multi-state presence to procure such newborn supply kits for new mothers, such as community-based organizations, Federally qualified health centers (as defined in section 1861(aa)), Tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)), and birthing hospitals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H457513AD1F1240CDB85203380E6D315B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In distributing newborn supply kits purchased or acquired using funds made available under subsection (c)(5), the entity that distributes such kits shall, as a condition on the receipt of such funds—</text> <subparagraph id="HB882834DDCBE4D3BBFFF87BEE2459BAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>partner with a local organizations that serve the locations where such newborn supply kits are to be distributed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C94B330A1F64CF297CB432357FD7F89"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the maximum extent practicable, ensure the geographical diversity of the recipients of such newborn supply kits;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F000C3A69F74E56BD38DB7677BD3619"><enum>(C)</enum><text>give priority to geographic areas with the greatest need, such as maternity care deserts, rural communities, and communities with the highest maternal mortality rates (such as the Delta region); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74DB70A4332540E68C3DE71836BC73A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give priority to mothers or newborn infants whose family income does not exceed 185 percent of the poverty line (as defined in section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>)) for a family of the size involved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H6EC8283F82F84D4593633F4377E0C12D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H2DEE87D2EDA1425CB2E648B0ED696580"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which the first grant or cooperative agreement is awarded pursuant to the amendment made by subsection (a), t<italic></italic>he Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the progress of the grants or cooperative agreements so awarded, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8FD0F467574A4C10A9F0340B0927FA34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of mothers served under the grants or cooperative agreements during the period covered by the report (disaggregated by race, family income level, and number of individuals in the household);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B2046C68FD24EDBA9D894B3DEBD3BBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the regions in the United States in which newborn supply kits are being distributed through such grants or cooperative agreements;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9107C6F7EEF4E2D89BC51BC7E31E270"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">feedback from mothers who have received newborn supply kits through such grants or cooperative agreements; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD1E512BB8AE4E56880961D70FD6784D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other information, as determined necessary by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB447E9384828424A9E37CDC73EDC468F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the last grant or cooperative agreement is awarded pursuant to the amendment made by subsection (a) for fiscal year 2030, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the results of the grants or cooperative agreements awarded pursuant to the amendment made by subsection (a) with respect to maternal and infant health outcomes.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCA3491A489A434C82BCD41F4A54150F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6022F2A58D3C498BA93B9E4673DC5313"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A40526BE4964C73A95C5FB0AA997890"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09B30D0912504FD3AED11C315AAF3B51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E64CC9FC4BB4DC4881ED140568E8921"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

