<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E83DE2417C942579428F0C2AA9ECB5F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8571 IH: Terminating Restrictive Enforcement of Youth Settlements Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the enforcement of certain contractual clauses that restrict disclosure of sexual abuse of minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC6E3D24541A94F91B7205CE07A7CB08F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE4CB2DBCCA7E4FC39A980018DBB2EC29" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terminating Restrictive Enforcement of Youth Settlements Law</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>TREY'S Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCB197E8EBBDD427083E19F54B419A73B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="H4E20383B69284D348E78C3DCC3666EE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header> <paragraph id="HF559042E0763456AA00500BB11849EFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Instrumentalities of interstate commerce</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H9A033DA09DA1491C909943C864843C6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Sexual abuse of minors, including abuse facilitated through instrumentalities of interstate commerce, is a matter of national concern.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF7C058CF1A44DB0B8A7E53B262D6E9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Agreements containing nondisclosure and confidentiality provisions, frequently concluded through the instrumentalities of interstate commerce, have been used to silence survivors of sexual abuse and conceal ongoing or repeated abuse.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBD6D77D7693E474FBC9DDD8A9858E19B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The enforcement of such provisions interferes with reporting to law enforcement agencies, child protection authorities, Federal regulators, Members of Congress, and the courts, and frustrates the enforcement of Federal criminal and civil law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C07D3EA4B0A4B2190ABFF08276435CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Necessary and proper clause and enforcement of Federal criminal law</header><text>Congress further finds the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H26C5B713FC0B4A86A2897C8AB88891F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Sexual abuse and trafficking of minors are prohibited under Federal criminal law, including <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/110">chapter 110</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, and section 1591 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA816E436012D4A53BDC3E161DC52B85E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Nondisclosure and confidentiality agreements that prohibit or restrict disclosure of sexual abuse of a minor interfere with reporting to law enforcement, child protection authorities, courts, Federal regulators, and Members of Congress.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF600DF6FE5EF497D8BE3B4570B5A4C20"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such agreements frustrate the investigation and prosecution of Federal crimes, chill cooperation with law enforcement, and function as private mechanisms to obstruct justice.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79EDE71B39014D8AB1A374840558F8B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Congress has authority under clause 18 of section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States (commonly known as the <quote>Necessary and Proper Clause</quote>) to ensure that private agreements are not used to impede the enforcement of Federal criminal and civil law protecting minors from sexual exploitation and abuse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H918EB80470E849C7B3D71865C650DDD7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>State action and section 5 of the 14th Amendment</header>
 <text>Congress further finds the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H730BE2CD7425443FB8DA2597F33B0D68"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>Survivors of child sexual abuse possess fundamental constitutional interests, secured by provisions of the Bill of Rights as incorporated against the States through the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, in reporting crimes, seeking redress through the courts, cooperating with law enforcement, and petitioning the government for protection and enforcement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H17661BB2BA9D44E58595AA65BD3B1E84">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>When State courts or other governmental authorities enforce nondisclosure or confidentiality provisions that prohibit or restrict disclosure of sexual abuse of a minor, such enforcement constitutes State action for purposes of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7187D8EDF0AD4A72BCC56895BE47AC00">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Judicial enforcement of such provisions may deprive survivors of due process of law, equal protection of the laws, and meaningful access to courts, including rights derived from the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and incorporated against the States, in violation of the 14th Amendment.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H24F87D71553E4724AE5B91E69671D8F0">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>Agreements that obstruct justice, suppress the reporting of crimes, or conceal criminal conduct have long been regarded at common law, including at the time of the founding of the United States, as void and unenforceable as against public policy, and fall outside the traditional scope of protected contractual liberty.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8CAAB00F9170499EBD2E12C5D7EB1D4A">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>At the time of the founding of the United States, private agreements purporting to suppress prosecution, conceal felonies, or restrain the reporting of crimes were not recognized as valid or enforceable contracts, and no party possessed a vested right in their judicial enforcement.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H02E3B39719484ECD9A9DB3998476F7E7">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>Congress has authority under section 5 of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States to enact appropriate remedial and preventive legislation to prevent and remedy constitutional violations arising from State judicial enforcement of private agreements that suppress disclosure of criminal conduct involving minors.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H92F03E44E8624468968D8EF073A46957"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is—</text> <paragraph id="HE760C858927F430389A361EB20038EC6"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>to enforce the guarantees of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, including the right to petition the government for redress of grievances and the right of access to courts, by preventing State courts and other governmental authorities from enforcing nondisclosure or confidentiality provisions that suppress disclosure of sexual abuse of minors;</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF352FC822CA4C8291464C672F389681"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure, pursuant to the authority of Congress under article I of the Constitution of the United States, including the Necessary and Proper Clause, that private agreements are not used to obstruct the investigation or prosecution of Federal crimes involving the sexual abuse or trafficking of minors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H407D9D051D264DFCA188C4C4A3E5D556"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to preserve access to courts and the right to petition the government for redress of grievances; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H08700EBE35E845BB9F56883ACD8E2A23"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to ensure that survivors of sexual abuse of minors, and persons with knowledge of such abuse, may disclose such abuse freely and without fear of civil liability.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H465BAE1274ED490FA0BD89EB9EE2DEFD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB93960A27CF14B98A11A49673B20C412"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Minor person</header><text>The term <term>minor person</term> means an individual who has not attained 18 years of age.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H340D0157DB5C4B40A83EBA6C1DC6A197"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nondisclosure clause</header><text>The term <term>nondisclosure clause</term> means a provision in a contract or agreement that prohibits 1 or more parties to the contract or agreement from disclosing conduct or information covered by the terms and conditions of the contract or agreement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA93793EE65634305A2FC046C119420C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sexual abuse against a minor person</header><text>The term <term>sexual abuse against a minor person</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C259FE14D5D4DCE9450AD8805BD75BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct that constitutes or allegedly constitutes—</text>
<clause id="HA336721BBE134EB09CEE0B2D7CB89E3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an offense under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/110">chapter 110</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code; or</text></clause> <clause id="HB37DD54D80254FE9B9B26E073A0773E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sex trafficking of a minor person under section 1591 of title 18, United States Code; or</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23FCD11EE92E4599BB1716421288F8DF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any sexual act or sexual contact involving a minor person that constitutes a criminal offense under Federal law or the law of the State in which the act or contact occurs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H4749D29DABD14E8581927D08293FBCC9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nondisclosure agreements void and unenforceable</header> <subsection id="H90830514A4414BB596AD812D5788B4DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A nondisclosure clause shall be void and unenforceable as against public policy only to the extent that the nondisclosure clause prohibits—</text>
<paragraph id="H3104C3E381914213A863EF65FC140ABF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a victim or alleged victim of sexual abuse against a minor person from disclosing—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB34C2E970832472C804D94F9C2BEA316"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that act of sexual abuse against a minor person; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD4A967014AB4BF194893FDAA5BD6F48"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facts related to that act of sexual abuse against a minor person; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7311393BE0374E28A8536D7D1A2431A3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other person from disclosing facts related to sexual abuse against a minor person described in paragraph (1) in support of, in furtherance of, or consistent with the right of a victim or alleged victim to disclose under that paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0C6014970AB147C7AAE7F60CBBF8C283"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissible confidentiality</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a person, including a victim or alleged victim of sexual abuse against a minor person, from entering into a contract or agreement that restricts the disclosure of information, including the amount or payment terms of a settlement, by another party to the contract or agreement, including an alleged perpetrator, so long as such restriction does not prevent disclosure protected under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD0AE75026828471B97DA09E0E419A8A4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Retroactive application</header> <subsection id="HE6F2D62F682D4778839309F8B990D2A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act shall apply to any nondisclosure clause in a contract or agreement entered into before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB518924EB1364C6FAB0F9AE3E6578364"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No enforcement actions</header><text>No person may enforce or attempt to enforce a nondisclosure clause described in section 4(a), regardless of the date on which the contract or agreement containing the nondisclosure clause was entered into.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5EA6F87D6B294D2985956ABDA6954E7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preemption</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CB0B6F98EB44BAA89D7E24CBC46E140"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>This Act supersedes any State law to the extent that such law permits enforcement of a provision, the enforcement of which is prohibited under this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E9FF52AA6F941DEAF737836933FE392"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit a State or locality from enacting legislation that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DF9AAC48D564E04AB5C6BAE24D8D3F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is consistent with this Act; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53086F1E1FA643DEBE000F81B9344B73"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides greater protection to a victim of sexual abuse against a minor person than is provided under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

