<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HADA64B04A5B240F197DC2E32BA1DB29A"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 865 IH: Opening the People’s House Resolution</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 865</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide a process for Members to call for an end to certain district work periods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body id="H95F67712459046428B7EF023845A74E4"><section id="HA6E91A4C372F4F25AD3C14466DB937B6" section-type="resolved"></section><section id="H7539AC43AB67432BA223170396436263" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Opening the People’s House Resolution</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7BE0C948648F4336B601994D5B21A715"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement with respect to district work periods</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Clause 13 of rule I of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H30F799ABE552458995EC4ABF5021739F" style="OLC"><subsection id="HA1D21C50BCB14591BD2C7306E45503C3"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEC7D27332F61436D816EAF38F6CC7BF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On any day during a district work period described in paragraph (a), any Member may submit to the Clerk a letter calling for an end to such district work period. The Clerk shall make any such letter submitted a matter of public record, causing the names of the Members who have submitted such a letter during a district work period to be published in a portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose and making cumulative lists of such names available each day for public inspection in an appropriate office of the House. The Clerk shall devise a means for making such lists available to offices of the House and to the public in electronic form.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6A4C47F2B484EE4A1B3C753E9D17464"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If, with respect to a district work period described in paragraph (a), a majority of the membership of the House, duly chosen and sworn, submit a letter described in subparagraph (1)—</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ed3aa6168224c2b9fc62a1797e651b1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>it shall be entered on the Journal and published in the Record;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6428faab43254be89e36e941deffe49e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such district work period shall terminate within 2 days; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id048d29b0e37c45f39c5d326f9509d5a3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Speaker may not designate another district work period under paragraph (a) during the period that begins on the date the House next reconvenes and ends on the date that is 3 weeks after such reconvening.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution>


