<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE1526CCCDF9141F8ABE35660A14D1BAA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9204 IH: Gun Safety Innovation Opportunity Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9204</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Attorney General to make grants to support the development of safe firearm storage devices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2CD51F59C72D49E4BEAF44866589BC75" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H32B289DFEFFB4213AB821B8326639B31" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gun Safety Innovation Opportunity Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H83C7016D7DDA48A8A5007953967C674F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gun safety technology grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF2E2DAACE92D4C5891E7821E50C2F59F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <part id="H7089CE452B904354B09BFD8DF3B40A65"><enum>PP</enum><header>Gun Safety Technology Grant Program</header> <section id="H20E3781995A0472395E2B6FAA107A616"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Grant authorization</header> <subsection id="HBFB03E684E534E88AB5582C0F7C431AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to make grants to institutions of higher education and firearms manufacturers to—</text>
<paragraph id="H58130C5A750A461790A7FB6C48D70F04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct research on, and develop, technology that may be used to improve safe firearm storage devices, including technology that uses biometric data to prevent an unauthorized user from firing or accessing a firearm; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32D4BC4B23B746948D7191B403514B15"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze consumer willingness and attitudes towards, and develop strategies to improve consumer uptake of, safe firearm storage devices that incorporate such technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D4381363D944381836512B0A6FAC27C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education or a firearms manufacturer seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H0653A76053D04F5A820B76D19ED05E0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed plan on how the applicant would use the funding to advance the technology described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57D09604AE014A68AFAF6E9C2D6914EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how the use of such technology would enhance community safety; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF637E20DFBAE4B5384D53E1948817F36"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how such funding will lead to greater consumer access to such technology, including by lowering of the cost of such technology for consumers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9FC74D02B4354E13A47A3C77735A5924"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB709B3D126834C529E808A017F44BD00"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On an annual basis, each recipient of a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General a report on how the grant funds were used.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2844F6E3FE84E88A08E7B50E34FA02B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H672CC354CC6846A2B22F319323AADB14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>safe firearm storage device</term> means a device that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H070038AC48F14C7BADE864C4DDE3FA6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designed and marketed for the principal purpose of denying unauthorized access to, or rendering inoperable, a firearm or ammunition;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H270FCDFC636D4D029805B668965205B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>secured by a combination lock, key lock, or lock based on biometric information which is integrated into the design of the device; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC70176F14E1D48599DB36DCC8EDCFD32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>once locked—</text> <clause id="H67664A7A026D40198C5864422F1D5A8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a device not integrated into a firearm, is incapable of being opened without the combination, key, or biometric information, respectively; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1ACB7FFD235D48688155070BB9C70C32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a device integrated into a firearm, renders the firearm inoperable without the application of authorized information, including biometric information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4D744FF1CD64E4A93489BD15D11BE28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <term>firearm</term> and <term>ammunition</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 921 of title 18, United States Code (without regard to all that follows <quote>firearm silencer</quote> in paragraph (3) of such section).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HE747F0DB974A4D76921BA9ED29EA9CB9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD0047716908B430096A446B8984B504A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ways that Congress can assist in the development of new technology that improves safe firearm storage devices (as such term is defined in section 3061 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE90BE9BDDB564454814E9426FB61E92C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ways that law enforcement officers can deploy such technology in the course of their official duties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3C4B9E354B74D888BDB3721676DB595"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ways that such technology and safe firearm storage devices can be used to prevent self-harm and suicide attempts.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

