<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFD3CD29D8BCB4477B3D54DA1740733DE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9159 IH: Protect Our Homes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9159</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to establish a program under which the
                                    Small Business Administration may make supplemental disaster
                                    loans to homeowner associations to repair common areas damaged
                                    by disasters and implement disaster mitigation measures, and for
                                    other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF5C4BA27C7BA4BF3A1E5287844EF0BB4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H24679317DEA54B7DA3CD3AB1A41A2377" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Our Homes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H8F1E5647862743E8B5E2DEF1B48FA4D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Residential common area repair and disaster mitigation supplemental loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H92E52941EDF44EA192B9B938EDA03875" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H7BE7D218C1A94140B0DE7FFFACC93CDB"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Residential common area repair supplemental disaster loans</header> <paragraph id="H781DBD0381A3405DBC7B8FD59F4E7AD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Administration a Residential Common Area Repair Loan program under which the Administrator may make, in cooperation with banks or other lending institutions through agreements to participate on an immediate or deferred (guaranteed) basis—</text>
<subparagraph id="H82A930CF1E984181879300F782F0196D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>loans to covered entities to make covered repairs to residential common areas; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD2B7C526CD04741B2E39402EF5005FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">loans to covered entities located in recent disaster areas to implement measures to protect from possible future disasters the property of the covered entities that was damaged or destroyed by the applicable disasters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H659721F5D14F4B1A8F60D0F4E63809DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplemental loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity is eligible to receive a repair or mitigation loan with respect to an applicable disaster only if the total amount of loans outstanding and committed to such covered entity under subsection (b)(1) with respect to such applicable disaster meets the applicable limit on such amounts for such covered entity under subsection (d)(6).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B6C33B96AFF4BB382BCFED1A359E13E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Loan criteria</header> <subparagraph id="HC352F4C6B30446E1903A34D52DC523F3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate loan amount outstanding and committed to a borrower under the Program with respect to an applicable disaster may not exceed—</text> 
<clause id="HD60E07B3906C4D4DAEE48567BF46F154"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a borrower that constitutes a major source of employment in an area suffering a disaster, such limit as determined by the Administrator, up to the greater of $2,000,000 or such other amount established by the Administrator under subsection (b)(8)(B) with respect to such applicable disaster; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA98BA7A005FA44888F11FDDB0B62D8DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for all other borrowers, $500,000.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0EC7E859DD24E5EB88B5D2293CDB595"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interest rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interest rate on the a loan made under the Program shall not exceed the average annual interest rate on all interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt as computed at the end of the fiscal year next preceding the date of the loan and adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum plus one-quarter of 1 per centum.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CB90363B4E24F7FBA514D7B17CE16C0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No loan under the Program, including renewals and extensions thereof, may be made for a period or periods exceeding thirty years.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB12C3328BFCA448FB9F5CE84E8BD525E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Small loan collateral exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Administration shall not require collateral for loans made under the Program of $14,000 or less (or such higher amount as the Administrator determines appropriate in the event of a major disaster).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAE9C3DD6484413DA47E73EE5DF6541D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <clause id="HAA82477D396F4FA9BBD67869E64B3F45"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Repair loans</header><text>Amounts made available to a covered entity as a repair loan may be used only for the costs of covered repairs to residential common areas of such covered entity.</text></clause>
<clause id="H40EEBCD105C546D6B45B7A9B67FA953E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Mitigation loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available to a covered entity as a mitigation loan may be used only to implement measures to protect from possible future disasters the property of such covered entity that was damaged or destroyed by the applicable disaster.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DB9F33A0C4446059DF35B41C4127351"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deferment</header><text>The Administrator may defer payment of principal and interest on a loan under the Program to the same extent that the Administrator may defer payment of principal and interest on loans under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3318F3B242B42C8BD4A54588AF48FB0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H50E386938F66460CBFECEAF213C9631A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable disaster</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable disaster</term>—</text>
<clause id="H8BA7933FFA4144E6881CF0BC07DEFA0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a mitigation loan to a covered entity, means the disaster pursuant to which the area in which such covered entity is located is a recent disaster area for the purposes of such mitigation loan; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB4FA92F41A784A3AB22528BE6F2B26EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a repair loan to a covered entity, means the natural disaster or act of God necessitating the covered repairs to residential common areas for which such repair loan has or will be used.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDBFE42B7FB8847C2909D7CC61CB5BEA6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term> means an organization—</text> <clause id="H9159CDA10D3A4EBCA75C7DF1D13C9C5C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the membership of which is comprised of each owner of a dwelling unit of a single residential community; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBDD648EF34FC49A1B724376661C34384" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is responsible for managing the residential common areas of such residential community and enforcing the rules and regulations of such residential community with respect to the dwelling units in and residents and owners of dwelling units of such residential community.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC98B5428C7174EE5BF718ED2BEFA5592"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dwelling unit</header><text>The term <term>dwelling unit</term> means a house, townhouse, or condominium.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23800117A30845859FD24ABACB623569"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Covered repair</header><text>The term <term>covered repair</term> means a repair, rehabilitation, or replacement made necessary due to a natural disaster (other than a natural disaster resulting from intentional, willful, or reckless conduct), or an act of God, including water damage, wind damage, and fire damage associated with such a natural disaster or act of God.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFF91B3A94FD4EE487891C7BB90A3B78"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Mitigation loan</header><text>The term <term>mitigation loan</term> means a loan under the Program described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1E4CF3CC700F4AED86892931A6F8D08F"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program</term> means the Residential Common Area Repair Loan program established by paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C479ACF25C54B0B99BF501059567E1E"> <enum>(G)</enum> <header>Recent disaster area</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recent disaster area</term>, with respect to a mitigation loan to a covered entity, means an area which the Administrator determines has, in the five-year period ending on the date on which such covered entity submits to the Administrator a request for such mitigation loan, been affected by a disaster and—</text>
                                                  <clause id="H48A666A45590456C8940C20E4E086DAC"
                                                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                                                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the Administrator determines that such disaster constitutes—</text>
                                                  <subclause id="HC34DB518DCA84DBE96A9E903A0A74967"
                                                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                                                  <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>a major disaster, as determined by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
                                                  </subclause>
                                                  <subclause id="H737275637B4C4929B63D2936D98AA948">
                                                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>a natural disaster, as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to section 321 of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1961">7 U.S.C. 1961</external-xref>);</text>
                                                  </subclause>
                                                  <subclause id="H4617D006B8BD4CFCB86B73413EF1263E">
                                                  <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>a disaster, as determined by the Administrator; or</text>
                                                  </subclause>
                                                  <subclause id="HCE6D9F046FBA4872AA0EAF8D70DF7BA4">
                                                  <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text>an emergency involving Federal primary responsibility determined to exist by the President under section 501(b) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191(b)</external-xref>); or</text>
                                                  </subclause>
                                                  </clause>
                                                  <clause id="H7CDF2246396E4F9DB995C5A71406DDAC"
                                                  display-inline="no-display-inline">
                                                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the Governor of the State in which such area is located certifies to the Administration, and the Administrator agrees, that the small business concerns, private nonprofit organizations, or small agricultural cooperatives in such area—</text>
                                                  <subclause id="H6D9E0EBACD424253B3FAACC95E2A6586">
                                                  <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>have suffered economic injury as the result of such disaster; and</text>
                                                  </subclause>
                                                  <subclause id="H0258BF6BA8B94F86947BE1516D5F2ACA">
                                                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are in need of financial assistance which is not available on reasonable terms in such area.</text>
                                                  </subclause>
                                                  </clause>
                                                  </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H67B1777718014A88947822A805528D44"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Repair loan</header><text>The term <term>repair loan</term> means a loan under the Program described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6C80B263EB34C288EA9DCEA9B4AD53C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Residential common area</header><text>The term <term>residential common area</term> means an area or space that is operated and maintained by a covered entity for the benefit of and use by part or all of the residents of the residential community that are members of such covered entity, including any services associated with such an area or space, other than any area or space that is located in a dwelling unit in such residential community.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82BD90B220854E22AF8E7E81324097FF" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Residential community</header><text>The term <term>residential community</term> means a group of dwelling units that are proximately located and the owners of which are members of the same covered entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

