<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" dms-id="H55FF53B6C1F645AC8B3B9F89B8052378" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 478 ATS: To authorize testimony, document production, and representation by the Senate Legal Counsel in the case of United States v. Kaminski.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">S. RES. 478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251030">October 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize testimony, document production, and representation by the Senate Legal Counsel in the case of <italic>United States v. Kaminski</italic>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in the case of <italic>United States v. Kaminski</italic> No. 3:25-cr-199, pending in the United States District Court for the Middle District of Pennsylvania, the prosecution has requested the production of testimony and documents from Ian Madigan, and employee of the office of former Senator Robert P. Casey, Jr.;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, pursuant to sections 703(a) and 704(a)(1) of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, 2 U.S.C. §§ 288b(a) and 288c(a)(2), the Senate may direct its counsel to represent current and former employees of the Senate with respect to any subpoena, order, or request for evidence relating to their official responsibilities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by the privileges of the Senate of the United States and Rule XI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, no evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate may, by the judicial or administrative process, be taken from such control or possession but by permission of the Senate; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when it appears that evidence under the control or in the possession of the Senate may promote the administration of justice, the Senate will take such action as will promote the ends of justice consistent with the privileges of the Senate: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEA26FD8FF98D440BA8E56B7A6F017EB7"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE387549EB610437B8655DBAFCAE44D78"><enum/><text>That Ian Madigan, a former employee of the office of former Senator Casey, and any other former employee of the Senator’s office from whom relevant evidence may be necessary, are authorized to provide testimony and documents in the case of <italic>United States v. Kaminski</italic>, except concerning matter for which a privilege or objection should be asserted.</text></section><section id="id8C19BE93D624470EB6D6185BCDD5CDC7"><enum>2.</enum><text>The Senate Legal Counsel is authorized to represent Mr. Madigan and any other former employee of Senator Casey's office in connection with the testimony authorized in section one of this resolution.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

