<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC5D459E7D0448EEA086A475B0A31D5A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1272 IH: Celebrating 200 years of United States diplomatic relations with Peru.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1272</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating 200 years of United States diplomatic relations with Peru.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on July 28, 1821, Peru declared its independence from Spain, led by General José de San Martín, marking the beginning of its sovereign history;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on May 2, 1826, the United States became one of the first countries to recognize the independence of Peru, appointing James Cooley as Chargé d’Affaires, marking the beginning of formal diplomatic ties;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1826, the United States and Peru established full diplomatic relations, inaugurating one of the earliest bilateral partnerships between the United States and a South American republic;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1851, the United States and Peru signed a Treaty of Friendship, Commerce, and Navigation, laying the foundation for long-term bilateral trade and cooperation;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1920, diplomatic relations between the United States and Peru were elevated to embassy-level status, reflecting the growing political and economic importance of the bilateral relationship;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, throughout the 20th century, Peru and the United States worked together in support of economic development and have stood together in moments of global significance;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2009, the United States-Peru Trade Promotion Agreement entered into force, expanding bilateral trade, investment, and supply chain integration and strengthening Peru’s role as a reliable economic partner of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, Peru was formally designated by the United States as a Major Non-NATO Ally, a significant milestone in the bilateral relationship that reflects deepened defense and security cooperation and recognizes Peru as a strategic partner in advancing regional stability, democratic governance, and shared security interests;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the strong people-to-people ties between Peru and the United States are reflected in the vibrant Peruvian American community, which has enriched the cultural, culinary, scientific, and economic life of the United States; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, the United States and Peru will commemorate 200 years of diplomatic relations, honoring a longstanding and strategic partnership rooted in shared democratic values, mutual respect, and a commitment to regional peace and prosperity: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF829A4AD28B14D48B78925DB883E784C"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8F6E043282DB4AE1ABE6B2409417BAA9"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H6663CDE2A7314973AB3FBCE1B064169C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates the 200th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the United States and Peru;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8666B918A6EC47D1B25A79B78D5B109D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes Peru as a long standing critical partner in advancing stability, democracy, and prosperity in the Western Hemisphere;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFD31181CAD2497E918D6B13A568CFF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the contributions of Peruvian Americans to the social, cultural, and economic fabric of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F48608F9220440AB19708AF64E9805C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to deepen cooperation with Peru in pursuit of shared goals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7064EC0385F14982897487B64C6BA74C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages continued partnership to address shared regional and global challenges, including the defense of democratic institutions, regional security and stability, and economic prosperity, while also reaffirming the deep cultural, social, and people-to-people ties that have long strengthened the friendship between the United States and Peru.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

