<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H708F99D40FCD47A89335FE9D7AF107E2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1091 IH: Expressing support for declaring 2026 the “Year of Math” in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1091</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for declaring 2026 the <quote>Year of Math</quote> in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas research in the mathematical sciences is an exciting and active area of intellectual pursuit;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas education in the mathematical sciences is foundational and serves as a connecting fabric for all advances in science and engineering;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advances in mathematical and statistical sciences enable understanding of complex systems and design of new technology, with implications for societal challenges in health, defense, energy, transportation, and other areas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mathematical research yields applications every day in fields such as medicine, cybersecurity, manufacturing, artificial intelligence, energy, biotechnology, agriculture, weather prediction and disaster preparedness, and business;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the national mathematics community is working together to maintain the global preeminence of the United States in the mathematics sciences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many, if not most, people in the United States have developed a negative relationship with math because math can be tough, but math is also fascinating, rewarding, and incredibly useful;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the national mathematics community is working together to engage young students, parents, and educators in hands-on activities that will inspire future generations of talent in mathematics and all sciences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the International Congress of Mathematicians (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>ICM</quote>) 2026 will be held in Philadelphia, from July 23 to July 30, 2026;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the first ICM was held in 1897, and since 1900, ICMs have taken place every 4 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas only twice before has the United States been chosen as the host country for an ICM, the 11th in 1950 and the 20th in 1986, and hosting one is a source of pride for host country mathematicians and politicians;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an ICM showcases what is going on in contemporary mathematics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the scientific prizes awarded by the International Mathematical Union are the highest distinctions in the mathematical world and are awarded every 4 years at the opening ceremony of the ICM, and the most famous is the Fields Medal, which was first awarded in 1936 and is considered the <quote>Nobel Prize</quote> of mathematics; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hosting the ICM 2026 provides a platform for the United States to declare 2026 the <quote>Year of Math</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H913AB279A4F941F6B1B5AE6E083090F7"><section id="H814CE19F95B043D69B8C0FE1939F131A" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H86A656F0BC7746CF9DDE7954F3A9734C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the declaration of a <quote>Year of Math</quote> in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9C56CE306D54389B592CCE6A12DA7F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">celebrates the United States being selected as host of the International Congress of Mathematicians 2026 and using this platform to increase the visibility of mathematical sciences as fields of study and to communicate the myriad benefits of education in mathematics and statistics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0559EF37DB1043F5BFAD27AA0779DB3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes that mathematics underpins all of the STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) disciplines, which are critical to the national security and economic prosperity of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FE8FB7824CC448990D8277B875C8354"><enum>(4)</enum><text>celebrates the role that mathematics and statistics play in the everyday lives of all people of the United States, including in technology, news, games, literature, and music.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

