<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26207-7GK-78-J0W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 681 ATS: Relating to the life and death of Chuck Norris.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Relating to the life and death of Chuck Norris.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Carlos Ray <quote>Chuck</quote> Norris was born in Ryan, Oklahoma, on March 10, 1940, and passed at the age of 86 on March 19, 2026, in Hawaii;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, at age 12, Norris moved to Torrance, California;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1958, Norris enlisted in the United States Air Force and was given the occupational specialty of air police, now called Air Force Security Forces;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Norris spent 1 year at an Air Force base in Arizona and then deployed to Osan Air Base in South Korea;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, while stationed in South Korea, Norris learned the disciplines of Judo and Tang Soo Do, eventually earning a black belt in Karate;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1962, Norris was honorably discharged from the military and resumed Judo training;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1968, Norris won his first Professional Middleweight Karate Champion title;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1968, Norris made his acting debut in <quote>The Wrecking Crew</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1972, Norris starred in his first major film, <quote>The Way of the Dragon,</quote> alongside Bruce Lee;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1974, Norris decided to retire from martial arts after winning his sixth consecutive Professional Middleweight Karate Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Norris continued to act in more than 20 movies, including <quote>Missing in Action,</quote><quote>The Delta Force,</quote> and <quote>Sidekicks</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1993, Norris made his television debut in the series <quote>Walker, Texas Ranger</quote> and starred in the series for 9 seasons;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2005, Norris reprised his role as Ranger Cordell Walker, starring in <quote>Walker, Texas Ranger: Trial by Fire</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Norris started a charitable organization called <quote>Kickstart</quote> to provide martial arts training to middle-school students, teach them respect and discipline, and improve their self-esteem;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1990, Norris created a new martial arts style called <quote>Chun Kuk Do</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2001, Norris received the Veteran of the Year Award from the United States Air Force;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Norris paid his respects to veterans, oftentimes visiting troops overseas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2007, Norris was made an honorary marine by Marine Corps Commandant General James T. Conway;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2010, former Texas Governor Rick Perry named Norris an honorary Texas Ranger, and in 2017, the Texas Senate named Norris an honorary Texan for his role in <quote>Walker, Texas Ranger</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Norris was known for both his inspirational and humorous quotes, including—</text><paragraph id="ide4ebe462d66c4db4af42212485478048"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>When I accepted Jesus Christ as my Savior, it changed my life forever.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id875bcf306b31411aa0c7ee0f46f7ba5c"><enum>(2)</enum><text><quote>There is no substitute for hard work. Always be humble &amp; hungry.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id30a3017fc1f54d31a03ce764a334d112"><enum>(3)</enum><text><quote>When the boogeyman goes to sleep he checks the closet for me.</quote>; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Norris leaves behind his wife, Gena, children, and grandchildren: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3df1cc2def8245daa49603b66385c842"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the death of Chuck Norris; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5eee2e7e4e424369a7058dd5aabc974f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate communicate this resolution to the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

