<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF26143-CGW-6K-GDX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3813 IS: Copyright Labeling and Ethical AI Reporting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3813</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a notice be submitted to the Register of Copyrights with respect to copyrighted works used in building generative artificial intelligence models, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HEF6F53A41E884389A16C4935EBFD8362"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6584491B1BB0491BAFD96295A970667B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Copyright Labeling and Ethical AI Reporting Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9794C806CFD421A8112A67CDBA440BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notice to be submitted to the Register of Copyrights with respect to copyrighted works used in building generative AI models</header><subsection id="H15F72D7D761347B7AB37D28A624DD7C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H7BCA6418F8FE419F893FC14563FB6544"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> means an automated system designed to perform a task typically associated with human intelligence or cognitive function.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2c9bf4ab45b49d4a10e54725dc26d42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Copyrighted work</header><text>The term <term>copyrighted work</term> means a work that is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d71eb61358a4d7997c129579abd64a4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protected under title 17, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7320b40951454941b4da3a47dfda3f48"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">registered under section 408, or scheduled pursuant to section 1401, of title 17, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF96F0B0850204B16AA01B9A00331EDD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Generative AI model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>generative AI model</term> means a combination of computer code and numerical values that is designed to use artificial intelligence to generate outputs in the form of expressive material, such as text, images, audio, or video.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB2C4D055FBB4BA484D5C433AD7E8D6D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Register</header><text>The term <term>Register</term> means the Register of Copyrights.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C9F24BD9E5E4E978C6A5C249B0B264E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Training dataset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>training dataset</term> means a collection of individual units of material, including any combination of text, images, audio, video, or other categories of material, and annotations, if any, describing that material.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE8F0B66481A4BD2A2D3DD2A8982CE3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice</header><paragraph id="id058e0f09a50e47eb82e0792c797c28c4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A person that uses a training dataset in connection with the training or release of a generative AI model shall submit to the Register notice that contains—</text><subparagraph id="H9A63595CFC3D4297825960E14A54D9D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a sufficiently detailed summary of each copyrighted work in the training dataset; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78D2E0E87A5C47658D8B5CFB793E0457"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Uniform Resource Locator for that training dataset, if the training dataset is publicly available on the internet at the time the person submits the notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3BA9A0BEACC4D6BA6EF34FE718620C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time for filing notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted—</text><subparagraph id="HA3E4CEFC2235419B8BA2F7A2650BAA63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days before the date on which the applicable generative AI model is used commercially (including when that use is internal to an organization) or released (without regard to whether that release is commercial in nature or whether that release is to the public or to a third party), in the case that the generative AI model is first used or released on or after the effective date of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7877872da964890a446d837d3eb5ac9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date on which the Register issues regulations under paragraph (3), in the case that the applicable generative AI model is first used or released before the effective date of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideec959b8ad3549bb9ab3d246bc92f704"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the effective date of this Act, the Register shall issue regulations establishing the form, content, and filing procedures for the notice required under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D37DFFFA69E4D61BDA1CBBE7B144228"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83954cfd1b1a46c98a365803dba34a35"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cause of action</header><text>If a person uses a copyrighted work in a manner described in subsection (b) without submitting the notice required under that subsection, the owner of the copyrighted work may bring an action in an appropriate district court of the United States against that person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71dd95a425b14941a186f476a882404f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), in an action brought under paragraph (1), the court may—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf57f53673e3a47febac8dfc0caab1d79"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impose a civil penalty, to be paid by the person against which the action is brought—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id173e4c56f25941dd8eff104e3606cfc5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an amount that is not less than $5,000 for each instance in which the person against which the action is brought failed to submit the required notice; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cc53e53e8374728b4385dc6cc2a5fa1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which shall be paid to the Register, who shall use the penalty amount to offset the operating costs of the Copyright Office;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc647a66f959345cba6db5a4e01ccae7a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue an injunction that requires the person against which the action is brought to stop using the applicable work in the manner described in subsection (b) until that person submits the notice required under that subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide378b43ff2fa42dfa821c41602cf0fa2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>award to the owner of the applicable copyrighted work attorney’s fees and expenses with respect to the action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9be6a742add748edb8084641b0dacc2a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id758bf9c795544667b2fcf53f8cc5a9cb"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>In any year, a person may not be subject to more than $2,500,000 in total civil penalties imposed under paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc78a9bb43b154157add9ac87ef06c9af"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other penalties remain available</header><text>The limitation under subparagraph (A) shall not affect the ability of the owner of a copyrighted work, during the period in which that limitation applies, to obtain a remedy described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (2) with respect to an action brought by the owner under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD06D5A12515444719A0FC7A14D150CE4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Database</header><text>The Register shall establish and maintain a publicly available online database that contains each notice submitted under subsection (b)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="H970A770347464E9EB037E40325A9F146"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

