<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA4D7680FB9164A6695642635C1604F1F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6672 IH: Mental Health Professionals Workforce Shortage Loan Repayment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6672</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize a loan repayment program for mental health professionals to relieve workforce shortages, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6527E92EC33A4A9F95738F630D8E7520" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HF71F5389B3344E84BE0D1F949465FAC3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Professionals Workforce Shortage Loan Repayment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H83A736AB7772497391D2388E9A7B17D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loan repayment program for mental health professionals in shortage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Public Health Service Act is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H98AD47B2A6444B219F4E1FA4A0825284"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating part G (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295j">42 U.S.C. 295j et seq.</external-xref>) as part H; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F7767710C764CEC9CE8BD369E5CC336"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after part F (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n et seq.</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EB6672D9A364309B3A86201D82BFBF6"> 
<part id="H8A0307BDD3754E539B8D5C05A3C1BAE2"><enum>G</enum><header>Mental Health Professionals in Workforce Shortage</header> 
<section id="HB59836A0DF0B40AE98100D0C5CB0248F"><enum>783.</enum><header>Loan repayment program for mental health professionals in workforce shortages</header> 
<subsection id="HBBD459ABFEB541479648F0447807DF32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall carry out a program under which—</text> <paragraph id="H65F80AE0AFC14777BD90E402F185C45A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary enters into agreements with individuals to make payments in accordance with subsection (b) on the principal of and interest on any eligible loan; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4DFD599F0D645C1BF579A1905A4731C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individuals each agree to complete a period of service in a mental health professional shortage area.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8FCD15DE95844DDEBAFF68011827FDFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments</header><text>For each year of obligated service by an individual pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make a payment to such individual as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFEDB8D3801E4AB3801B6EE651E35182"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Service in a shortage area</header><text>The Secretary shall pay—</text> <subparagraph id="HA7C33F227537470096D23C2E99B3667B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each year of obligated service by an individual pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a), <fraction>1⁄6</fraction> of the principal of and interest on each eligible loan of the individual which is outstanding on the date the individual began service pursuant to the agreement; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BDA6CC930E84D11834056A62D878D9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for completion of the sixth and final year of such service, the remainder of such principal and interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B517C627EC04C89B6A5B0E148E71E89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The total amount of payments under this section to any individual shall not exceed $250,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H989D5844FF0D467D8B07A6295C94F773"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible loans</header><text>The loans eligible for repayment under this section are each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAFCB14F65D564AFAB169D273E9F769FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any loan for education in mental health or a related field leading to a master’s degree, leading to a doctoral degree, or consisting of post-doctoral study.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0AC0A691F6848969B355B60A4364BBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any Federal Direct Stafford Loan, Federal Direct PLUS Loan, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, or Federal Direct Consolidation Loan (as such terms are used in section 455 of the Higher Education Act of 1965).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65D8B4535EF64D01B8B1546F3F4AAEE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any Federal Perkins Loan under part E of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90B2604C6566431EB4D89E52C7C1A141"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other Federal loan as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE12768CDCB1F45E4B61419DF81B62279"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of service</header><text>The period of service required by an agreement under subsection (a) shall consist of up to 6 years of full-time employment, with no more than one year passing between any two years of covered employment, as a mental health professional in the United States in a mental health professional shortage area.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9B7DCEEB6B041F29801666E54B33298"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Ineligibility for double benefits</header><text>No borrower may, for the same service, receive a reduction of loan obligations or a loan repayment under both—</text> <paragraph id="HA7BD94AA566348DB9F29D650703D7C74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC085058B0AC74E95AD2C4E00E11FF590"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any federally supported loan forgiveness program, including under section 338B, 338I, or 846 of this Act, or section 428J, 428L, 455(m), or 460 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H114C3F8FE48247758F0E68D94C62841B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Breach</header> <paragraph id="HB6F942B581F04F2F920489893B4290F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Liquidated damages formula</header><text>The Secretary may establish a liquidated damages formula to be used in the event of a breach of an agreement entered into under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DABBADB197149378C5D84B3E8AA9FF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The failure by an individual to complete the full period of service obligated pursuant to such an agreement, taken alone, shall not constitute a breach of the agreement, so long as the individual completed in good faith the years of service for which payments were made to the individual under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H712AAA3853E34D72B7C063B35ABF993B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional criteria</header><text>The Secretary—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5F1B8BAF59B3432BAC9330FB03877997"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may establish such criteria and rules to carry out this section as the Secretary determines are needed and in addition to the criteria and rules specified in this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC68D7D40C144C3481C442EAB3AB7C29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall give notice to the committees specified in subsection (h) of any criteria and rules so established.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF23BAF02EC9041C78C7BE71C8292E587"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Mental Health Professionals Workforce Shortage Loan Repayment Act of 2025</short-title>, and every other year thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on—</text> <paragraph id="H487F83C272F949D883E201E0DD393615"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and location of borrowers who have qualified for loan repayments under this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F65F65ED78A407A960A8C5C85AA5FC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impact of this section on the availability of mental health services in mental health professional shortage areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H58C25FD672414B049BDEB184DA997B49"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H45494A4217124BBD9C077F1B6D27A419"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mental health professional</term> means a full-time job (including a fellowship) where the primary intent and function of the job is the direct treatment or recovery support of patients with or in recovery from a mental health disorder, such as a physician (MD or DO), psychiatric nurse, social worker, marriage and family therapist, mental health counselor, occupational therapist, psychologist, psychiatrist, child and adolescent psychiatrist, or neurologist.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E70E00580344DB78BEE06A8BB2148AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mental health professional shortage area</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H47F7485B7EE94F4FB79356743166FC5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an area designated under section 332 with respect to a shortage of mental health professionals; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E25E6BB51C348F4A91A3C543965C39D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any facility, program, center, or clinic as determined appropriate by the Secretary for purposes of this section because of a shortage of mental health professionals, including private physician practices and other medical facilities designated under section 332(a) as having such a shortage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97C7AE86A7F04F2AA767FA5231C3033B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2035.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill> 

