<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4F3B50D23AC543C996C69967A474B419" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1203 IH: Recognizing the 200th anniversary of the heroic Exodus of Missolonghi and commemorating its historical significance to the Greek War of Independence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1203</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 200th anniversary of the heroic Exodus of Missolonghi and commemorating its historical significance to the Greek War of Independence.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, the world commemorates the 200th anniversary of the Exodus of Missolonghi, one of the most heroic and consequential events of the Greek War of Independence, when the people of the city of Missolonghi chose to break free of the siege;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this act of defiance and sacrifice was a defining moment in Greek history, inspiring the philhellenism movement across Europe and America;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the city of Missolonghi endured 3 sieges between 1822 and 1826, culminating in the heroic Exodus on April 10, 1826, when its defenders and civilians chose sacrifice and honor over submission;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Exodus of Missolonghi exemplified the universal ideals of liberty, altruism, human dignity, and sacrifice for the greater good, leaving a lasting imprint not only on Greek history but also on global consciousness;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the resistance and ultimate sacrifice of the people of Missolonghi inspired the Romantic movement across the world, influencing poets, artists, writers, and thinkers who championed freedom and self-determination;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the sieges of Missolonghi galvanized international support for the Greek cause and inspired thousands of sympathizers known as philhellenes to contribute financially, materially, and militarily to the struggle for Greek independence;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Greek War of Independence resonated deeply with the people of the United States, who viewed the struggle as a fight for liberty and as a revival of the democratic ideals of ancient Greece, which helped inspire the founding of the American Republic;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas numerous philhellenic societies were formed throughout the United States in the early 19th century, organizing fundraising efforts, collecting supplies, raising public awareness, and advocating for support of the Greek cause;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas prominent Americans, including Presidents Thomas Jefferson and James Madison, expressed strong support for the Greek struggle for independence;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many American philhellenes traveled to Greece and fought alongside Greek freedom fighters in Missolonghi, including George Jarvis, William Townsend Washington, and Jonathan Peckham Miller, who took part in the Exodus of Missolonghi and offered invaluable assistance to its besieged population; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the shared history of sacrifice and solidarity between the peoples of Greece and the United States continues to serve as a foundation for the enduring friendship and strategic partnership between the 2 nations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HC81DF4472937428B8788DD2725479C1B"> <section id="HEC067FB3312D436D8FE337F83E1CA702" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC0A902E9F1244DF6A47A5F9E357F09AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and honors the 200th anniversary of the Exodus of Missolonghi as a defining moment in the Greek War of Independence and a landmark event in world history;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FB35A152FB846E3ACF7143F65ECDC29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pays tribute to the men, women, and children of Missolonghi whose courage and sacrifice embodied the universal struggle for freedom and human dignity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83B647F912D54619B930E39BAA873FD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors philhellenes, including American philhellenes, who supported and fought alongside the Greek people in their struggle for independence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14FEED55727A482AB1958FC9643FB105"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms the shared democratic values and historical bonds between the United States and Greece, rooted in a common commitment to liberty and self-determination; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1480AD4986974CEE84913BA6F7C66222"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages educational, cultural, and commemorative activities to mark the 200th anniversary of the Exodus of Missolonghi and to promote greater awareness of its historical and moral significance.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

