<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BEF54B8E88543F38545ADE295BD9960" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8970</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct research to advance the understanding of gambling disorder, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4952D4023CAF44F7B1E1643E09F21874" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8D789C8B1F3A4965ACCBCBCBAE63F038" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gambling Disorder Health Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H81D4DED3E7C0464DBF3E4749EAB111F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8A816BEC0B994CE8BC2A50DEE54F06FD">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">gambling disorder was categorized as a
                    behavioral addiction in 2013 in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental
                    Disorders (5th ed., text rev. 2022) published by the American Psychiatric
                    Association;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D5F146811904748A7DD05EDAB98FE40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>although gambling disorder is categorized along with substance-related and addictive disorders that include alcohol, tobacco, and drug-related addictions, no Federal agency has been designated to fund and guide research, programs, or policies addressing gambling disorder in the United States on a national level;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H215F5E20326347109C9C405A5B65C503"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">this absence of Federal funding and guidance has resulted in a lack of research and resources available to address gambling disorder and gambling harm;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFF33A0992F84BAFAA0BA59B9E13424C">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in Murphy v. National Collegiate Athletic
                    Association, 584 U.S. 453 (2018), the Supreme Court overturned the Professional
                    and Amateur Sports Protection Act (Public Law 102–427), allowing States to
                    legalize and regulate sports betting; and</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA218B77A97A64849A1505E09999045F3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>following the Supreme Court’s ruling in that case, 38 States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico legalized some form of sports betting, consequently making sports betting and other forms of gambling more accessible and popular and garnering billions of dollars of revenue for the gambling industries.</text></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="HA791A1718A1A4D509FF77A464FFB2201"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research on gambling disorder</header> 
<subsection id="H9FA676E4C0004DB8A4A10B6C32F0598D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall carry out a program (in this section referred to as the <quote>program</quote>) under which the Secretary shall conduct research, either directly or through agreements with other public or nonprofit private entities, to advance the understanding of gambling disorder, including its origins, manifestations, and long-term effects.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD16E318AC66F41FB935C4195A9C31E39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The research to be conducted under subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA42795A968414A768238A0AB490E6355">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to identify the initial
                        emergence or earliest documented cases of gambling disorder and the
                        developments leading to its categorization as a behavioral addiction in the
                        Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (5th ed., text rev.
                        2022);</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H079B5CB22456492588BC760708B5EC8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigation of the long-term psychological, social, economic, and behavioral impacts of gambling disorder on affected individuals, communities, and public discourse;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC43DE53798C4BFA89D422A759D0C1E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analysis of the effects of mobile, online, and app-based gambling technologies on the prevalence, development, and progression of gambling disorder;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF94162F814EF418590E81395568C789F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examination of the implications of related technology mediated behavioral activities, including video games, social media, in-app purchases, and virtual reality platforms, on the prevalence, development, and progression of gambling disorder;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD4C8397EE1B467E9C21CA9BDCA3B44D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analysis of the contributing factors to, and the policy implications of, the development and spread of gambling disorder, including sports betting legalization, media exposure, political polarization, and social dynamics;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7DBF57D8B0141C09712FEC519F0CB86"><enum>(6)</enum><text>exploration of potential interventions, treatments, coping mechanisms, and strategies to mitigate the adverse effects of gambling disorder, as applicable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F89B00130D04A79A930F549F742DF96"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analysis of the demographics of those individuals who are susceptible to gambling harm or already diagnosed with gambling disorder, as well as the demographics of individuals who partake in individual gambling types; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H163479CE211644DC9A90C163AFDD4146"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comparative analysis of the regulatory and public health frameworks of other economically developed countries with respect to gambling, including the effectiveness of any prevention policy approaches and risk reduction measures for individuals exhibiting signs of gambling disorder, and the circumstances under which such countries have modified or reversed policies that had liberalized gambling and the outcomes of those actions.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3154DAAB4F684E8B9EC6F9D0AB439E69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participation of Federal agencies and other entities</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out subsection (a)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H032385E343794761B24B9897DFDD6E50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with the National Institutes of Health, the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02E448D657764F38BB6D3C75B2178FE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in collaboration with the heads of other Federal and State agencies, academic institutions, and relevant organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6412213EE3B64DF18BD9772E478C767C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter during the term of the program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on the progress of research conducted under this section, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H175064F1B0D04C98B524B1BAB906C9B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>findings relating to the initial emergence, demographic analyses, public health impact, and long-term effects of gambling disorder and engagement with gambling types; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42FCB85078E04687875299E52AD5EA7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for further research, public health actions, treatments, preventative measures, and public policies relating to gambling disorder and mitigating gambling harm.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8DBFD0F0C11B4E608E6D224FA1E5025A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0410A590EA9D4B7F8DFC20FC4D54D163">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Gambling disorder</header>
                    <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>gambling
                            disorder</quote> has the meaning given such term in the Diagnostic and
                        Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (5th ed., text rev. 2022) (or a
                        successor edition) and includes—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H0F749584A4AC44A2968B3F18F445A187">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <text>pathological gambling;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H7FB221D6906F4569A1935DFB09EDF3F2">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <text>gambling addiction; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H4DD62B16BAA846CCACF5B3729334582A">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
                        <text>compulsive gambling.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1742B353AA1C4464B10B19E205506CB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gambling type</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>gambling type</quote> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF91D971BFE734394A369A91C2BC5C226"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lotteries and scratch-offs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE339F523147D41CE8A8CDED94C1C14B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sports betting;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD8EDA43756A4366AF859A826A37F32D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prediction markets;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H816978F79B9A44BBA91682374AD3B2CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>casino games;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35B85E4F04D843FBBA197CA1E5B92E68"><enum>(E)</enum><text>horse racing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC266226AC99D418CA2CBDA84A4A26C93"><enum>(F)</enum><text>online gambling;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A4230FE59574DA8BB35C27AFBCF1DE4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>social gaming with virtual currency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AB21C0B793A47879789E20750C0D06F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>betting on esports; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H087E76ED07ED4EA49DBD9D52E81D007C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other activities that involve risking money or other stakes in a game or bet, as determined by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF784ABC31654ABEAA1EFF589C0A2260"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2029 the amount that is 10 percent of the amount estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the amount of taxes received under section 4401(a)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 during the preceding fiscal year. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>
