<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5071C1927E324DCB91FF6CC20E426532" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>104 HR 8586 IH: Americans First Immigration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to protect American workers and values.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8888DC9D662645EFBFC684AFCAA2E06D" style="OLC"><section id="HBECAF3418AA1404CBAEE545673DA2FD3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Americans First Immigration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC47D072F92894CC4B64F16220E7BD371"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protection of American workers and values</header><subsection id="H4D3E0A114EB542759530FF2E610C212C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Protection of American workers</header><text>Chapter 2 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1181">8 U.S.C. 1181 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 5(d), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30478D6600C64E3AA9D47A5E253340B1"><section id="HC8A7968608D44C6AB03C4BA8D183FE00"><enum>220A.</enum><header>Protection of American workers; employer attestation</header><subsection id="H523C7FC864C241D798547CAC7529A828"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8716FE5BD8574E57A2133339B7094A42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Area of employment</header><text>The term <term>area of employment</term>, with respect to the job for which an employer made a bona fide offer of employment to an alien, means the area within normal commuting distance of the worksite or physical location at which the work of the alien will be performed. If such worksite or location is within a Metropolitan Statistical Area, any place within such area is deemed to be within such area of employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF848FFF94671445D90EDEE9511601836"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Essentially the equivalent</header><text>The term <term>essentially the equivalent</term>, with respect to a job for which an employer made a bona fide offer of employment to an alien, means a job that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD52D4FA5B894D3CB3EF700FD6EA3A28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is held by a United States worker with substantially equivalent qualifications and experience to such alien;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC9BB4D36624404F8287549D37DCE7AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involves essentially the same responsibilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H211F9248C4E94C28B48C25BA75A6C0B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in the same area of employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CC7E846ED6A4D0AB7B396DA36F1DF78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lay off</header><text>The term <term>lay off</term>, with respect to a worker—</text><subparagraph id="H98B4580853DB46609C2BAC44CC439BF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means to cause the worker’s loss of employment, other than through a discharge for inadequate performance, violation of workplace rules, other cause, voluntary departure, voluntary retirement, or the expiration of a grant or contract (other than a temporary employment contract entered into in order to evade a condition of the employer’s attestation); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B47046364D2476E98F25FA278BD47C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any situation in which the worker is offered, as an alternative to such loss of employment, a similar employment opportunity with the same employer at equivalent or higher compensation and benefits as the position from which the employee was laid off, regardless of whether or not the employee accepts such offer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8EC2CEAC621422F8905E57839185105"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States worker</header><text>The term <term>United States worker</term> means an employee who is—</text><subparagraph id="HDB79682361964E1F89B1147065AF86D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a citizen or national of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19BBA3843FDA4FE68812073799F14C41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FAE2CD72459410B84F84D66C6F68D9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required attestation elements</header><text>An employer’s attestation meets the requirements described in section 204A(a)(2) if the employer—</text><paragraph id="HBD2ADB9CE38D456281A19B73C10135A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>attests that the employer, before making a bona fide job offer to the alien—</text><subparagraph id="H05478663AAD64BED93AF5C89368E565A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>took good faith steps to recruit United States workers for the job for which the alien has been made an offer using procedures that meet industry-wide standards and offering compensation that is not less than the compensation offered to the alien; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA8C1F6A8F2A45068BAF8E55136C2999"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offered the job to any United States worker who applied and was equally or better qualified for the job offered to the alien than such alien;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15655F8727AE489ABCA3076F097F1680"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides a summary of the recruitment efforts described in paragraph (1), including—</text><subparagraph id="H8A62E25E1E97474EA19D64265F5CBCE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the good faith steps taken to recruit United States workers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E29AE6E39964D98A539E28B03DD6581"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name, address, and contact information, and resume (if provided) of each United States worker who applied for the job;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20946DBAAAE442629B815AB05F68E395"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the name, address, and contact information of each United States worker who was offered the job, the proffered wage to each such worker, and whether each such worker accepted such offer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16CA8D83A0E64B169314F1433D8AC8F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for each United States worker who was not offered the job, the reason why the job was not offered to such United States worker; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC27646A4802D42238B642E78AD1FDB08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>attests the employer—</text><subparagraph id="H54CB132BF2634439AE485D04D030870B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>did not lay off and will not lay off any United States worker employed by the employer from a job that is essentially the equivalent of the job for which the employer made a bona fide offer of employment to the alien during the period beginning 90 days before making such attestation and ending on the last day of the employer’s employment of the alien;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81EF24DFF0B646F0B474BE13DA1D66D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will not place the alien with another employer for which the alien performs duties, in whole or in part, at 1 or more worksites—</text><clause id="H89B33911AA144CB1A7576621ACCD0159"><enum>(i)</enum><text>owned, operated, or controlled by such other employer; or</text></clause><clause id="HCB4D36ED1B7E471289DA40A862366042"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>physically located within, adjacent to, or in close proximity to, a worksite described in clause (i) for the purpose of avoiding the requirements under this subsection; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE277C8EF08C644FA85B9EDBA24F00E7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>will employ the alien at not less than the promised wage rate for 3 years unless—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB3566DBD3D6432B99C06C55508066E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien is discharged for inadequate performance, violation of workplace rules, or other cause; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9FDB766FB7C40FB85CFC0474825FB67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien voluntarily departed from the job or voluntarily retired.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17ED04BE2DBA446AB28D117AF19D2170"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance with attestation</header><paragraph id="H43E2FCF4B14840788FB521B23208500B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigations</header><subparagraph id="H439679502723493587159701E285407B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CC2A65C24174786A976427DA4025823"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Grounds for initiation</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may initiate an investigation of any employer that has signed an attestation described in subsection (b) if the Secretary has reasonable cause to believe such employer is not in compliance with the terms of such attestation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE23E03C0600D469AA2F05149E9CF1767"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall notify an employer with respect to whom there is reasonable cause to initiate an investigation under clause (i) before commencing such investigation. Such notice shall be provided in such a manner, and shall contain sufficient detail, to permit the employer to respond to the allegations before an investigation is commenced.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H629030F42D974E4684E8C917FE009145"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor is not required to comply with clause (ii) if the Secretary determines providing notice to an employer would interfere with an effort by the Secretary to secure compliance by the employer with the terms of its attestation described in subsection (b).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D6C25935888463C9B786E8FACDE3701"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>No judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be no judicial review of a determination by the Secretary under this subparagraph.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAB39EB73429457FBC06FE672F51C664"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines, after an investigation conducted pursuant to this subparagraph, that a reasonable basis exists to determine the employer is not in compliance with the terms of its attestation described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall provide for—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A9873329E0D42EA9A9DBF2BA748BF09"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notice of such determination to be sent to the interested parties; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF381886F296E42A5BB4BF1C3A52DC1CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with section 556 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H913A763CBB2746FC83ED4A6416B9924C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Complaint-based investigations</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish procedures for—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD824C241536B463390A9FE13A4993036"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals who have applied in a reasonable manner for a job that is the subject of an employer’s attestation described in subsection (b) or has been laid off in noncompliance with the terms of such an attestation to file a written, signed complaint respecting the alleged violation of the attestations; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D376D4503FB40B7AF70B1253D1FA654"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the investigation of complaints described in clause (i), which have a substantial probability of validity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C6651DBFB2B4BE5B1F003DF0AE32B36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Binding arbitration</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B45A77179DE4C68B8D01B1B9530CE4E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB7175F17A6F410EA776D2F1A948B7B4"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initiation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Labor determines there is a substantial probability of validity of a claim in a complaint filed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(i) that an employer is not in compliance with the terms of an attestation signed by the employer, the Secretary shall initiate binding arbitration proceedings by requesting the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service to appoint an arbitrator from its roster of arbitrators.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FF64125CEAA4DFFBAB06F0FA7158E86"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedure; rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The procedure and rules of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service shall be applicable to—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C07CC0C56AC433E9E6BB2F816373A55"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the selection of such arbitrator; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H712B5F5D9EFA465FB0279F59237E2B9D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such arbitration proceedings.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC72071CBE0D4938912B20154639119C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Fees; expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall pay the fee and expenses of the arbitrator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8C0CC80A1DA4117928BE5387AE9C2C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Findings</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A37B032278647FBA163BE775920E973"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The arbitrator shall determine whether the employer is not in compliance with the terms of the attestation signed by the employer. If the arbitrator determines that the employer willfully failed to comply with such terms, the arbitrator shall make a finding to that effect.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEEF96C2FB12458EBD4AD5BC313BC4AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Distribution of findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The arbitrator shall submit any findings described in clause (i) in the form of a written opinion to the parties to the arbitration and to the Secretary of Labor.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCEBE6EC1ED24902B3A20C4E19864F3A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitations on review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The findings submitted pursuant to clause (ii) shall be final and conclusive. Except as provided in subparagraph (C), no official or court of the United States shall have power or jurisdiction to review any such findings.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28C88D73CFC74689A65E6558EBB65D7E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B5A3EDE501C4B3CA689348A6FA2C287"><enum>(i)</enum><header>By the secretary of labor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor may review and reverse or modify the findings of the arbitrator only on the same bases as an award of an arbitrator may be vacated or modified under section 10 or 11 of title 9, United States Code.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BE3F7E2FB8542B191FD28377384E8AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>By a court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A court may review only the actions of the Secretary under clause (i) and may set aside such actions only on the grounds described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 706(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, judicial review under this clause may only be brought in an appropriate United States court of appeals.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02C68C5F3A5449188B5BC762E25FB6A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H720BB1FFFF3A401AAA6E3DB677B95608"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subparagraph (B) if—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89A61B5AE64F4E1394EEEB73933312F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Labor—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B1FD7D10DCF4C5DAC11C7F6864A2264"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing pursuant to paragraph (1)(A)(v)(II), that an employer is not in compliance with the terms of a signed attestation described in subsection (b); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25237B192398463498CF0692D01153B8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives a finding of an arbitrator that an employer is not in compliance with the terms of such an attestation; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA9678930EEF44A2939FDA0BEC197588"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary has not reversed or modified such finding pursuant to paragraph (2)(C)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92494632796341FC9E45B8DE10EF7897"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalties described</header><text>The Secretary of Labor—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23DFC36449A7451DA0D8ACC06C982F9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall require each employer described in subparagraph (A) to cease and desist from any noncompliance with the terms of a signed attestation described in subsection (b);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0BE58AEA8544C909B6CF601D95E7239"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may, at the discretion of the Secretary and subject to clause (iii), require such employer to pay a civil monetary penalty in an amount that is not more than—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE7EDD284FFC4C9B8A6CE8AFC0BF4BA7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000 for noncompliance with any term of the employer’s attestation;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA593A4A6938B4595B3C901527B49E2CF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$15,000 for each willful noncompliance with a term of the employer’s attestation; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85692678BB43440688BF07123B7E7F97"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000 for each willful noncompliance with a term of the employer’s attestation that resulted in a United States worker being laid off; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2742A639A0A4CC7BECED8D352411DD3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on January 1, 2028, and annually thereafter, shall automatically adjust the amounts described in clause (ii) for violations committed after the effective date of each adjustment based on the cumulative annual percentage change in the unadjusted Consumer Price Index for all Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor between January 1, 2027, and the date of such adjustment;</text></clause><clause id="HA035B9C036BC4CE5B196F6FDCC8AE9FD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may disapprove any petition filed by any alien desiring to be classified as points-based immigrants under section 203(b) that includes a bona fide offer of employment made by such employer—</text><subclause id="H40B3B865500D4C51AFCF4072A897F6FD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>during a period of not more than 1 year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6D65BC917E2546AF8829456BC83CEA50"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of willful noncompliance, during a period of not more than 15 years;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB1ED23D4B0E1482BAD5174F2EF3B4259"><enum>(v)</enum><text>if the attesting employer failed to offer a job to a United States worker in compliance with subsection (b)(1)(B), shall order such remedial action as may be appropriate, including—</text><subclause id="H3A47F79B613844A0BFB29DB01A6EC25C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the hiring by the attesting employer of the United States worker for the job for which the alien had been made an offer which the United States worker was not, but should have been, offered, with compensation that is not less than the compensation offered to the alien; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA8A9AE0DEAE2402CA1F2EDF38A1F13C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>payment by the attesting employer to such United States worker of compensatory damages;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H86B67BBF2AD149D0AE6BF5F5F2B83923"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>if the attesting employer laid off a United States worker in violation of subsection (b)(3)(A), shall order such remedial action as may be appropriate, including—</text><subclause id="H9500ADF72DF04EC59F4F76DD8C03046F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reinstatement by the attesting employer of the United States worker to his or her former position and compensation (including back pay), terms, conditions, and privileges of such employment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H70C4F326760D461597292AE2168348D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>payment by the attesting employer to such laid off United States worker of compensatory damages; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE891D7F89B5D46A2B5D85B417BACE015"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>if the attesting employer placed the alien with another employer in violation of subsection (b)(3)(B), and the other employer consequently laid off a United States worker, shall order payment by the attesting employer to such laid off United States worker of compensatory damages.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H838D09A9EA4A4CB785438EEE33E7F0EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protection of American values</header><text>Chapter 2 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1181">8 U.S.C. 1181 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a) and section 5(d), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA5DBAD4248D4605A3A79A59BE742136"><section id="H94F4CAAE817242E7ACD6E0405B47EEF0"><enum>220B.</enum><header>Protection of American values</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the attestation required under section 204A(a)(2)(A), the alien petitioner shall attest that he or she—</text><paragraph id="H57E64C102B5E4AC3B235EF9D417419BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>will remain—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA18224794BC4DD09C734980A838320B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attached to the principles of the Constitution of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H965537AD3A9F40AB996C878C65A7C02D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">well disposed to the good order and happiness of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAF22C3BED674F1EA04E5918A5979195"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has not ordered, incited, advocated for, assisted, or otherwise participated in (including by writing, publishing, or causing to be written or published, by knowingly circulating, distributing, printing, publishing, or displaying, by knowingly causing to be circulated, distributed, printed, published, or displayed, or by knowingly having in his or her possession for the purpose of circulation, publication, distribution, or display, any written matter (including through electronic means, such as the internet and electronic text and mail) or printed matter for the purpose, in whole or in part, of carrying out such order, incitement, advocacy, assistance, or participation)—</text><subparagraph id="H4B8E6114048941FC8DF51211E3F781BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>genocide (as defined in section 1091(a) of title 18, United States Code);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E0F19BAB1E3449B81454A921B3225F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the civil or criminal punishment of a person on account, in whole or in part, of such person's actual or perceived religious apostasy or blasphemy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2ED188B888C42059553E927EDCD562C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the establishment of any governmentally enforced religious law in the United States that would—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CF3C01A291849A6A386467C949AD216"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operate in place of, or in addition to, any Federal, State, or local civil or criminal law; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H794C2524C72640708AF4B1FB8AB6B529"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apply to—</text><subclause id="HDEA2BBA664A844BBB268ADDB6553364B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all persons in the United States; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3D54CD1B2EE94B71A4325B254CF7F1DF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>persons of a particular religious faith in the United States (regardless of whether adherence to such law is voluntary or mandatory);</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B51FA4C43A445E1A1A97E6201FC9DF0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the persecution of any person on account of, in whole or in part, race, religion, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E68601958EA4899B1961F83A24EE0B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>female infanticide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE85E78EB8DCE4F99922F0C75022905B7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>sex-selective abortion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73D392EA74C14416A5079A1DD70B5C63"><enum>(G)</enum><text>honor killing; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4790B1F4242D42E39D4266E691881779"><enum>(H)</enum><text>female genital mutilation (as defined in section 644(c) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1374">8 U.S.C. 1374(c)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6A3948525925470580010F54A12B610A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>will not engage in any activity described in paragraph (2) in the future; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF58F78094D49069B9A1DCA6FF353C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is not, has not been, and will not become, a member of, or affiliated with, any organization that carries out or has carried out 1 or more of the actions described in subparagraphs (A) through (H) of paragraph (2) when the alien petitioner was a member of, or affiliated with, such organization.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2F26BE5722654084AD469D14F71FA351"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents for the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5FF0F6D39C74FDB82A0D8AF9AC18645"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after the item relating to section 204 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFC7B3FAEDAD143A38B082685F7683036"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H8888DC9D662645EFBFC684AFCAA2E06D">Sec. 204A. Procedure for granting immigrant status for points-based immigrants in the American interest.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text indent="paragraph" continuation-text-level="paragraph"> and</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DA2CBBED91E4F7D95FDCA7D79F27CB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after the item relating to section 219 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4F052CCE7AB44EE1A85F2CAABCBE01F5"><toc><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 220. Points-based Immigrant Visa Program in the American interest.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 220A. Protection of American workers; employer attestation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 220B. Protection of American values.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD038E4D9CFD3484BBFC4F71BC5655A94"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBF091AA301F3413392D03C48262F1329"><enum>3.</enum><header>Elimination of Diversity Lottery Immigrant Visa program</header><subsection id="H14E552B9BFCB457FABB5D3F318F17B10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DFED652DA634D25A17F44717948BB37"><subsection id="HD757D64DA1844C84BC7E72E4D154C30C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation for religious workers</header><text>Aliens subject to the worldwide level specified in section 201(e) for religious workers in a fiscal year shall be allotted visas in accordance with section 204(a)(1)(E).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H768ECB75D703446F9A418D3B54D85D21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF1B61A634FA249E883F1984A42276B4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 201 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H63575725A26B461AAFDA9B81E204C841"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FD4B65D0ADC45D6847DE9861BCFA9DD"><paragraph id="HFB602645553B472385CF068826D36051"><enum>(3)</enum><text>special immigrants described in section 203(c), in a number not to exceed the number specified in subsection (e) during any fiscal year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DD761F8ACC2497E8A3042DAB81F1875"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FE203D7137C469EA4F3EB7932645798"><subsection id="H2F56995A3B644E65AAAD81145863FE21"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Worldwide level of religious workers</header><text>The worldwide level of religious workers under this subsection for a fiscal year is equal to 3,000.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02DC29DC88CF447F9722A26DC47DDBD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 203(e) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(e)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H05C00F65F1434E2983D0E9526A75766F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>or (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (b) or (c)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53457952F46C4AF2B51D80112B2BB0A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62CA92131E7C44308391DBFBACBEC604"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6071EE8DE4034D8D8D7E71A5E41FE651"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="H685FB4D20CAD4104852F233E73061A49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE287D25F6D1C494EA046D2795467D5EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Validity or invalidity of certain petitions and applications</header><subparagraph id="H4F37C9121A1B4A3C8D97479334F93711"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No persons may file, and the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State may not accept, adjudicate, or approve any petitions under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>) filed on or after the date of the enactment of this Act seeking classification of aliens under section 203(b)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(4)</external-xref>), as in existence immediately before such date of enactment. Any applications for adjustment of status or immigrant visas based on such petitions shall be rejected, denied, or made invalid.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9A65ED7B4A442B5B9A686FC21AC4F93"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pending petitions for religious workers and other special immigrants</header><clause id="HDC2CA7F16170497D9A5F355028C39B06"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Religious workers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall adjudicate or approve any petitions under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act pending on the date of the enactment of this Act seeking classification of aliens described in section 101(a)(27)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)(C)</external-xref>) under section 203(b)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(4)</external-xref>), as in existence immediately before that date of enactment, as petitions seeking classification of aliens under section 203(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>), as amended by this Act.</text></clause><clause id="HAEF9C9AFB3A944678C9DB7BE48C862A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other special immigrants</header><text>Neither the Secretary of Homeland Security nor the Secretary of State may adjudicate or approve any petitions under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act pending on the date of the enactment of this Act seeking classification of aliens not described in section 101(a)(27)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act under section 203(b)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(4)</external-xref>) as in existence immediately before such date of enactment. Any applications for adjustment of status or immigrant visas based on such petitions shall be rejected, denied, or made invalid.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE34FDB435429401A850B624CD59613B2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability to waitlisted applicants</header><subparagraph id="HE910F114F48744F39B25C5100C1317F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Religious workers</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendments made by this section, visas may be issued to aliens described in section 101(a)(27)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)(C)</external-xref>) who are beneficiaries of petitions approved under section 203(b)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(4)</external-xref>) before the date of the enactment of this Act as if they were issued to beneficiaries of petitions under section 203(c) of such Act, as amended by this Act. Such petitions shall retain their original priority dates.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A3FECF805A6449BB33DF468B70DDE18"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other special immigrants</header><clause id="HA390CAFFAD0A4382A1F33813713B1728"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendments made by this section, aliens not described in section 101(a)(27)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act who are beneficiaries of petitions under section 203(b)(4) of such Act approved before the date of the enactment of this Act may be issued visas pursuant to such paragraph in accordance with the availability of visas under clause (ii).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B1DD01D5DD94DE6B81785FF5799ADB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Availability of visas</header><text>Visas may be issued to aliens not described in section 101(a)(27)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act who are beneficiaries of approved petitions under section 203(b)(4) of such Act, but only until 6,940 visas have been issued. When all of the visas authorized in the previous sentence have been issued, no additional visas may be issued under such section 203(b)(4).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA9414958A37149DB9D961A363B48A8B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preserving nuclear family immigration</header><subsection id="H584996BE6E2544AAB7394343A25391D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Immediate relative redefined</header><text>Section 201 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(b)(1), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H536741C9EFA24D1486E82C4DE12BD100"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(A)(i), by striking <quote>children, spouses, and parents of a citizen of the United States, except that, in the case of parents, such citizens shall be at least 21 years of age.</quote> and inserting <quote>children and spouse of a citizen of the United States.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB06122A548D404E87309A9B9D167F6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8203500F829E438AB3A146F0BD0F525F"><subsection id="HA1025B6DCD9E4A8A9505C13F1BAC9AD0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Worldwide level of nuclear family-Sponsored immigrants</header><paragraph id="H22782DDCF2D14519BB3D2B981B773452"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The worldwide level of nuclear family-sponsored immigrants under this subsection for a fiscal year is equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H277123BF40734E3780133DEB9EAC1159"><enum>(A)</enum><text>87,934; minus</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46D3F78C0C8C4884B22DF0D3066177BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number computed under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB96B0F9FF49F4080B94C4388AC0DD7B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number computed</header><text>The number computed under this paragraph for a fiscal year is the number of aliens who were paroled into the United States pursuant to section 212(d)(5) in the second preceding fiscal year who—</text><subparagraph id="H24749EF8A33D4F19A6A1F9CC356E328F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>did not depart the United States (without advance parole) during the 1-year period beginning on the date on which such parole was granted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36466C2B16B24CFA9652D62288D8845C"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H75204D6615304D858E25DE921636C6BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>did not acquire the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence during the 2 preceding fiscal years; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H56F1384369444F68A2411BEB6A885F88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>acquired such status during such period under a provision of law (other than subsection (b)) that exempts adjustment to such status from the numerical limitation on the worldwide level of immigration under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F7DF0D09C6B410BAC6504BE161706F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph id="HB8D5B358FF784818AA826FDD2C446F20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>section 203(a)(2)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 203(a)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE28BD93D96494CEB919B911035EF796A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>striking paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H574E788E403C4EAA90DE24CC5250E2C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C72A82F994D49B1AC0E3F46DF31C94E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), as redesignated, striking <quote>(1) through (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) and (2)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3CE2C55CC2C4960A54F6F90142095F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nuclear family visa preferences</header><text>Section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78EDE5459F134B81B3F8A2D9FE0CEAED"><subsection id="H96BF8570A6424C49ABE736F67D2ABA9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Spouses and minor children of permanent resident aliens</header><text>A family-sponsored immigrant described in this subsection is a qualified immigrant who is the spouse or child of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence. Such immigrants shall be allocated visas in accordance with the number computed under section 201(c).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H268ADC300F014AEABD7154406D80744A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Aging out</header><text>Section 203(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC55507607094450BA52511054B718E85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E88FC15E3E143CC99E1983EAD6E08B0"><paragraph id="H17A4A121093544229996174D2A15B51C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), for purposes of subsections (a) and (d), a determination of whether an alien satisfies the age requirement in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of section 101(b)(1) shall be made using the age of the alien on the date on which a petition is filed with the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HB89E47C25BDD4C8BB94DBB5BA28E41AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) as paragraphs (3), (4), and (5), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA1AB4C64EC340E5B7670C9E7B100D88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9D3E996C7974DB0AA63C79FB80D3224"><paragraph id="H47F723010851477194ADF1AC35F01652"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding the age of an alien on the date on which a petition is filed, an alien who marries or attains 25 years of age before the date on which a visa is issued to such alien pursuant to subsection (a), (b), or (c) does not satisfy the age requirement under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H93FD044B2FF54681B2998268EC752E14"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraphs (3) and (4), as redesignated, by striking <quote>(a)(2)(A)</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>(a)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4980E681D8C54BBAB542E74B03402977"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), as redesignated, by striking <quote>(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>(4)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D40561AD4564E5AA01495A489FFA64B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H348D3FD7F6614929920AAB0BF41176EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 101(a)(15)(V) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(V)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 203(a)(2)(A)</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>section 203(a)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC8544F59F9044F669193943136493601"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 202 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6F44724503214ED29D5EF1B7B9A345FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26B678986C0E4FE0A51EA1F267070914"><paragraph id="HECD73C8069AA4BD48E977B65798CEB13"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule for spouses and children of lawful permanent resident aliens</header><text>Of the visas made available under section 203(a) in any fiscal year, 75 percent shall be issued without regard to the numerical limitation under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5FB49A4359D4E9295A752DF3BE1BBB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><clause commented="no" id="HC8F97AC988C346CE928ABE5711412B07"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the semicolon and inserting a period;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44847D9503284285A1D4147E25949DE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraphs (2) and (3);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4F9CA31CE1C46C18448BEDA0E540C55"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42FF8576B85B48959F399E9966BE41DB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in a manner so that—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>the ratio</quote> in paragraph (1) and inserting <quote>in a manner so that the ratio</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H782E8527A0514C85B3A0FEB893D3B24C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>If it is determined</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8D0CB8CCCE24DC9857DBF1C7FAE32A2"><paragraph id="HC4EDEB97111C4207BAB6EB3B03AD0E80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If it is determined</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H917B83965C584EC29BA6172116DF5DAE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the undesignated matter at the end—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAFB3E3A825D4CF9A1477F3F6B477C22"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>, or as limiting the number of visas that may be issued under section 203(a)(2)(A) pursuant to subsection (a)(4)(A)</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H931AA7E2815F4C978F18F871E917C97D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Nothing in this subsection shall</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4F7FFBAC15743AA9562CBA642776929"><paragraph id="H205BC2578C064BE3A7CF7F8BBF8017C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) may</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2583542BE1D74456BBDCF3A1D9B89893"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 204 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H12453645F0B541B19878A7E823DEE219"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><clause id="H20B8EC85AFFB456F94032094D8645439"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3225A4DDE2B4949985C5C7D5A5286B5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), by striking <quote>to classification by reason of a relationship described in paragraph (1), (3), or (4) of section 203(a) or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46427B82EFCE42DD94161AFAD8D98CD2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by moving clause (viii) 6 ems to the left;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H01B048FD4DCB40DD849F461E8DAFF89E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subclause id="H57CF6CAC714F41719343E0205F2592CD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text><item id="H3CC78B7406F54F87A9D4963C1A023F3E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the first subclause (I), by striking <quote>203(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>203(a)</quote>; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBF7766C8AD14B7FA13E836BB437CAC3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating the second subclause (I) as subclause (II) and moving such subclause 6 ems to the left; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6852DA48180B465589C5704F4B4BFCE3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>203(a)(2)(A)</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>203(a)</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5785FB32039A42359C3E1A382EC0407E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(i)(I), by striking <quote>a petitioner</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section 204(a)(1)(B)(iii).</quote> and inserting <quote>an individual who is younger than 21 years of age for purposes of adjudicating such petition and for purposes of admission as an immediate relative under section 201(b)(2)(A)(i) or a family-sponsored immigrant under section 203(a), as applicable, notwithstanding the actual age of such individual.</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E8CF2B28FB743C8833D897B3973A5EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), by striking <quote>, 203(a)(1), or 203(a)(3), as appropriate</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8301ED74F7774DA8A4F5962E76FB283B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (k); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6217A9986FA44E628837FB077CBFEB2B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (l) as subsection (k);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF67315018D9E4637BEEB5131357615EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 212 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H711C03DA83A241E08D2F6546C34C2EFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(6)(E)(ii), by striking <quote>section 203(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 203(a)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75BD590FDFF641A789187FCE3012ED19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(11), by striking <quote>(other than paragraph (4) thereof)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE0D544E265340168357843FF0D207F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 213A(f)(5)(B)(ii) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1183a">8 U.S.C. 1183a(f)(5)(B)(ii)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 204(l)</quote> and inserting <quote>204(k)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF006F713AFD42CF9E568D1E1D327EF4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 214(q)(1)(B)(i) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(q)(1)(B)(i)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 203(a)(2)(A)</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>section 203(a)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H379CDB231C214C8089C1EA4CD65A8A8B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 216(h)(1)(C) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1186a">8 U.S.C. 1186a(h)(1)(C)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 203(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 203(a)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB72C8AA10EB48478B5921118D7CB093"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in section 237(a)(1)(E)(ii) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(1)(E)(ii)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 203(a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 203(a)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H843A22D2BBCA45C6852AC0CDE7112A03"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><paragraph id="H9B7A14E0797E4FE68CD0A5639341A26D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H548ACA4ED063499A8E228BC78D12B1BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Invalidity of certain petitions and applications</header><subparagraph id="HD77368F0361745E7BA7934447D1732CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person may not file, and the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State may not accept, adjudicate, or approve, a petition under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>) that is filed on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and seeks the classification of an alien—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD01C4E0A6244CD880E6FB691055C50E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a parent of a citizen of the United States under section 201(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before such date of enactment); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C148C8F5A75473680332DB32F565645"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a family-sponsored immigrant under paragraph (1), (2)(B), (3), or (4) of section 203(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before such date of enactment).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0239F05AE5C47F3A2F023F688873578"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applications for adjustment of status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any application for adjustment of status or for an immigrant visa based on a petition described in subparagraph (A) shall be rejected, denied, or made invalid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EAA3CE0BFCA4028AB37A263C4E497AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pending petitions</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2040944349D6454EA31A0813BAD4A86B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Neither the Secretary of Homeland Security nor the Secretary of State may adjudicate or approve any petition under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>), pending on the date of the enactment of this Act, seeking the classification of an alien under section 201(b)(2)(A)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act) or under paragraph (1), (2)(B), (3), or (4) of section 203(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7948E409861345499799ED6272CB16AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applications for adjustment of status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any application for adjustment of status or for an immigrant visa based on a petition described in subparagraph (A) shall be rejected, denied, or made invalid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50C98C0FD0124BC9AA01BF2464BAF471"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability to waitlisted applicants</header><subparagraph id="H9A456CA3B13D416E90358F27D070B29A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendments made by this section, any alien who is a beneficiary of a petition under paragraph (1), (2)(B), (3), or (4) of section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act) that was approved before such date of enactment may be issued a visa in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29F7D6EE386746699EB7BCE397A2EF3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of visas</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendments made by this section, visas may be issued to any alien who is the beneficiary of an approved petition under each paragraph referred to in subparagraph (A) until the number of visas that would have been allocated to aliens in the applicable paragraph for fiscal year 2028 have been issued.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H033267E6109B471FB94A251E7855D258"><enum>5.</enum><header>Replacement of employment-based immigrant visa categories with points-based immigrant visa program in the American interest</header><subsection id="H82261B8045C64C39AA7A5899F740AB26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Worldwide level of points-Based immigration</header><text>Section 201 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>), as amended by sections 3(b) and 4(a), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HB43AE96CD5CC4EC69B9696FC8BB80A16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8656C3A1B38C4056B96A1F482100C1EB"><paragraph id="HA1B3E393EDB945B4BCC45C5186107D56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>points-based immigrants described in section 203(b), in a number not to exceed the number specified in subsection (d) during any fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9960D85DE4A4307A962D726F0A52F5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3C7786A4C1B4B1E92B80AD9BEF66E7D"><subsection id="H219367A4441E4780845E5A0CC4285571"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Worldwide level of points-Based immigrants</header><text>The worldwide level of points-based immigrants under this subsection for a fiscal year is equal to—</text><paragraph id="H4271D94DFD8A42DC850F3932AAF35D46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>192,000; minus</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7564854006C472FABE826A2901B0541"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of aliens who were never detained or who were released from detention during the most recently concluded fiscal year despite being subject to mandatory detention under paragraph (1)(B)(ii), (1)(B)(iii)(IV), or (2)(A) of section 235(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41C72C4B251446168A6AFEAB71A4435E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Replacement of preference allocation for employment-Based immigrants with points-Based immigration</header><text>Section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37EB4B8DF7DA454AA8EDE6CFB72CE8DB"><subsection id="HFE79C015B1DF4A51B926A3EF66317FFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation for points-Based immigrants</header><text>Aliens subject to the worldwide level for points-based immigrants in a fiscal year specified in section 201(d) shall be granted visas in accordance with sections 204A and 220.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H42F0A35075274DD6AAE47F99B2E2744A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedure for granting immigrant status for points-Based immigrants in the American interest</header><text>Chapter 1 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 204 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12EBC3CF74D246A482B0FC0CFB283363"><section id="H577EDDEF3DBA479FABB6E089427C31A3"><enum>204A.</enum><header>Procedure for granting immigrant status for points-based immigrants in the American interest</header><subsection id="H52C38E41212C436FBB38457CC7F5B581"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Petitions for immigrant status for points-Based immigrants</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F812A8768ED44B685DA06AD4CE453EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any alien seeking classification as a points-based immigrant under section 203(b) shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security a petition that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55035BF8DA41425FAE457D183471B254"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the requirements described in paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H790297A3E53C40F7B99DEF5D3AA846F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is formatted and submitted in such form and manner as the Secretary of Homeland Security may require; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD7567DB541641719E72A4938D4F7732"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H034EE86F07D9478F8F4A299CD2621E98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum requirements for petitions</header><text>Each petition submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H64DB981028EE4F4681ADF32BDBA60796"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an attestation described in section 220B that has been signed by the alien;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2CF5A9C30CD4C0AA8D55FFA9CEC9A22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evidence of a bona fide offer of employment in the United States by any employer described in paragraph (3), (4), or (5) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3121">section 3121(h)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including an attestation described in section 220A that has been signed by the employer that is offering to the alien a salary of—</text><clause id="HBF3EC5579DBA4EA2B93276D5BA967844"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 200 percent of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed if the alien has not received a bachelor’s, master’s, professional, or doctoral degree, or a doctorate of medicine, from an institution of higher education in the United States not later than 1 year after the date on which the petition is filed; or</text></clause><clause id="HC0E4F575982C412688C671F5C0667C29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 150 percent of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed if the alien has received or will receive a bachelor’s, master’s, professional, or doctoral degree, or a doctorate of medicine, from an institution of higher education in the United States not later than 1 year after the date on which the petition is filed;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77063AE156BB4F328123EEA5C249E7D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a certification that the alien is eligible to receive not fewer than 16 points under the criteria described in section 220(a), accompanied by sufficient evidence, as determined by the Secretary, of the attributes and achievements establishing eligibility for such points;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB73A56A6C84F44769C55D5AA869CE2A7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sufficient evidence, as determined by the Secretary, that the alien is not younger than 18 years of age or older than 51 years of age on the date on which the petition is filed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FA13DBE87E64D0C98D4EE499AE7E7BD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sufficient evidence, as determined by the Secretary, that the alien has a score on an English language proficiency test in the 5th decile or higher.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EAB8522A32F44389D8BF937FDB3F4B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amendment of petitions</header><text>An alien may amend a petition previously filed by the alien under this subsection by—</text><subparagraph id="H00ED6B0B9C73409AA9E4A8F6CBBB545C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submitting to the Secretary of Homeland Security a new bona fide offer of employment described in paragraph (2)(B) by any United States employer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2371089E1DE4B17A71F308344A13CE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>certifying the alien is eligible for additional points under the criteria described in section 220(a), accompanied by sufficient evidence, as determined by the Secretary, of the attributes and achievements establishing eligibility for such additional points.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B554AA414F5409BBE2413E99D2DCB86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible applicant pool and selection of aliens</header><paragraph id="H571DC39BD8054FD59AE87B94C4FB4DE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA190FAE31B0D4E4CA592875A8E761EBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">classify all aliens who have filed petitions meeting the requirements set forth in subsection (a) as eligible points-based immigrant candidates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61C9589F130D442AAD020A4B4FED1712"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rank such candidates based on the total number of points for which such aliens are eligible under section 220(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B718CB04A1B46978371AD0E4FEAED3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tie-breaking factors</header><text>The Secretary shall distinguish between groups of aliens who are eligible for an equal number of points—</text><subparagraph id="HA7F0FC8EB9AB41689C5A0936B5877B8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by giving preference to aliens who are eligible for more points under section 220(a)(1) (employment);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E00E61686704DB98301BC8FBAF55A1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to aliens who are eligible for an equal number of points under section 220(a)(1), by giving preference to aliens who are eligible for more points under section 220(a)(2) (extraordinary achievement);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6DDB7C639E147C6B30DE0A510E3ACFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to aliens who are eligible for an equal number of points under paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 220(a), by giving preference to aliens who are eligible for more points under section 220(a)(3) (educational attainment);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAFA827B81874942BDEFE32AC0FE88FA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with respect to aliens who are eligible for an equal number of points under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 220(a), by giving preference to aliens who are eligible for more points under section 220(a)(4) (English language proficiency);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87C0DB29654C4124947D7EC2D922C887"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to aliens who are eligible for an equal number of points under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of section 220(a), by giving preference to aliens who are eligible for more points under section 220(a)(5) (military service); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8046FA0102B34703A2057A4CFC357095"><enum>(F)</enum><text>with respect to aliens who are eligible for an equal number of points under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (5) of section 220(a), by giving preference to aliens who are eligible for more points under section 220(a)(6) (age).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47F147F191E8484398146D7095275F95"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Visa issuance</header><text>Not fewer than 4 times during each fiscal year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD719EC3CACD84211A4ABC974711E22B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compute the number of points-based immigrant visas authorized to be issued during the applicable period from the worldwide level total available in such fiscal year under section 201(d);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA939CAA137C043E5B103A2C247AB4CEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify up to the number computed pursuant to subparagraph (A) of aliens who—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF616BA94489149438E281DA4756EDF09"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submitted a petition under this section during such fiscal year that meets the requirements described in subsection (a);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68EC362FEAB243F38932524E7DA3E1F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have not been issued a point-based immigrant visa; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1530ABB046E54565A9841E0DB0A1E6AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are eligible for more points (but not fewer than 16 points) under section 220(a) than any of the aliens not selected for such a visa, subject to the tie-breaking factors set forth in paragraph (2); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F77F5AE66E240F3BAF65E33236BC30E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a points-based immigrant visa to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABFFD8B20C114746ABE8182A0D748D97"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each of the aliens described in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71A560C75B0B4424AA5FC8EB68377D8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the spouse and any children of each of the aliens referred to in clause (i) who are accompanying or following to join such an alien, in accordance with section 203(d).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0CFD36CC51DF40498F69B865BE1EDB5C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Establishment of a points-Based immigrant visa program in the American interest</header><text>Chapter 2 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1181">8 U.S.C. 1181 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CD8D2F683E446D58AED15F1577C2BDC"><section id="HB4706F28EDFD48698BAEE71AECE421F6"><enum>220.</enum><header>Points-based Immigrant Visa Program in the American interest</header><subsection id="H1A8AF218B61D462990A1A40E8A6AEE61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien seeking to be classified as an immigrant under section 203(b) shall submit a petition, in accordance with section 204A, that includes such information as the Secretary of Homeland Security may require, in order for the Secretary to determine the number of points for which the alien is eligible under this subsection.</text><paragraph id="HE1A17FEF2AB04F22A46E54AA26DD0CF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employment</header><subparagraph id="H3B3A9701A0824A91B421C1AAAB9EEACB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No college degree</header><text>If the alien is not expected to receive a bachelor’s, master’s, professional, or doctoral degree, or a doctorate of medicine, from an institution of higher education in the United States within 1 year after filing a petition under section 204A, the alien is eligible for—</text><clause id="HC112DEC27BF64B0F856CD4B581DF1E98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>5 points for a salary of at least 250 percent, but less than 300 percent, of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed;</text></clause><clause id="H5FABA78486DC4B74A90D3550E05CDF2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>10 points for a salary of at least 300 percent, but less than 400 percent, of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed;</text></clause><clause id="H0CF5DD4B865E42C397FA22CAC1C4C898"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>20 points for a salary of at least 400 percent, but less than 500 percent, of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed; or</text></clause><clause id="H5592AFBA475B45568406E8253A5232B7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>35 points for a salary of at least 500 percent of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE079E70ECA0247DB95D370AD208D7FE6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>College degree</header><text>If the alien is expected to receive a bachelor’s, master’s, professional, or doctoral degree, or a doctorate of medicine, from an institution of higher education in the United States within 1 year after filing a petition under section 204A, the alien is eligible for—</text><clause id="H2E61E1D487C1493D8ED16ADFC5B479EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>5 points for a salary of at least 200 percent, but less than 250 percent, of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed;</text></clause><clause id="HF6F581A6D7DE4A898D5F6B506E10CE53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>10 points for a salary of at least 250 percent, but less than 350 percent, of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed;</text></clause><clause id="HBC1C268E58E947539CC299C1ADBDDF18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>20 points for a salary of at least 350 percent, but less than 450 percent, of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed; or</text></clause><clause id="H79CD4468A2444FEFB3B76BC680A2FCDC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>35 points for a salary of at least 450 percent of the median wage in the State in which the alien will be employed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC256FE33E89240B596C6FAC3978A4C45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extraordinary achievement</header><text>An alien is eligible for—</text><subparagraph id="HFE582C0B3E364F94A55760535118DBFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>10 points if, during the 8-year period immediately preceding the filing of the petition, the alien earned an individual Olympic medal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F3C9DD6ABBB45BDB0BFB01A747C6EA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>between 10 and 50 points, at the discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security, for having extraordinary ability in the sciences, arts, education, or business, which has been demonstrated by sustained national or international acclaim and whose achievements have been recognized in the field through extensive documentation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF07513F2DF64B6DA05A4DEC39EE5696"><enum>(C)</enum><text>70 points for being a Nobel Laureate in a field of scientific or social scientific study;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D4E7C7C4F31404A8C320FA3891A0BAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Education</header><text>An alien is eligible for—</text><subparagraph id="H7A1ADBD7072E4E25A6F858A754AA90FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 points for a degree from a recognized postsecondary credential (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)), including a certificate of completion of an apprenticeship (including an apprenticeship registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D4D3FF59E4B44F8A5676BCA53C806D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>4 points for a bachelor’s or master’s degree from a foreign institution of higher education that is comparable to a United States institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4282107AB3A342AF885D67C355275051"><enum>(C)</enum><text>5 points for a bachelor’s or master’s degree from a United States institution of higher education, if the alien took all the required courses for such degree, including any courses taken by correspondence, telecommunications, or distance education, while physically present in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2551CAD66044DAAAFEEF4DA30A3C5DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>6 points for a professional degree from a foreign institution of higher education that is comparable to a United States institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE602136BD5A94DFC936B78FBA38192B4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>7 points for a professional degree from a United States institution of higher education, if the alien took all the required courses for such degree, including any courses taken by correspondence, telecommunications, or distance education, while physically present in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63E936D1C2C64E02B2E5D8AC9B0A3B1B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>8 points for a bachelor’s or master’s degree in a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics from a foreign institution of higher education that is comparable to a United States institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H010463CA71FF4C86B5274DC116E9FA09"><enum>(G)</enum><text>9 points for a bachelor’s degree in a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics from a United States institution of higher education, if the alien took all the courses for such degree, including any courses taken by correspondence, telecommunications, or distance education, while physically present in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D7765061DFC4E61A952DFC9D76ADFE0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>20 points for a master’s degree in a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics from a United States doctoral institution of higher education, if the alien took all the required courses for such degree, including all courses taken by correspondence, telecommunications, or distance education, while physically present in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3154EEEB426041E8ABF2EC203826C3AA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>20 points for a doctoral degree from a foreign institution of higher education that is comparable to a United States institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE62E3C7C8864583BAAF80A0F3EC5B56"><enum>(J)</enum><text>23 points for a doctoral degree from a United States institution of higher education, if the alien took all the required courses for such degree, including all courses taken by correspondence, telecommunications, or distance education, while physically present in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB645B539C2214965AB581B997B2FCDF0"><enum>(K)</enum><text>30 points for a doctoral degree in a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics from a foreign institution of higher education that is comparable to a United States institution of higher education, or a doctorate of medicine from a foreign graduate medical school that is comparable to a graduate medical school at a United States institution of higher education; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE7EDF39D9A41B7B4E394AEEB9E8B42"><enum>(L)</enum><text>35 points for a doctoral degree in a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics from a United States institution of higher education, or a doctorate of medicine from a graduate medical school at a United States institution of higher education, if the alien took all the required courses for such degree, including all courses taken by correspondence, telecommunications, or distance education, while physically present in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBDE6CE0ED0E4918B78C439EB4B9B3C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>English language proficiency</header><text>An alien is eligible for—</text><subparagraph id="H21B96DB26C354678AB101B4568691B95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2 points for an English language proficiency test ranking within the 6th decile;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BAAADC26A8146D1BE1DB0598D2B7983"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3 points for an English language proficiency test ranking within the 7th decile;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D23E7A7343E4CD78755D9F6ADCA644B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>4 points for an English language proficiency test ranking within the 8th decile;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0219C98DCB994FB8A1B6A5E3EB3B3DF1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>7 points for an English language proficiency test ranking within the 9th decile; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE36C7AA3653B41F483AF31DD92489754"><enum>(E)</enum><text>8 points for a English language proficiency test ranking within the 10th decile.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H074CDE9B9C90422294975C5777D929AE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Military service</header><text>Except for aliens eligible for naturalization under section 329, an alien is eligible for 6 points—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA55FDE1CCA544085A937116DA0DA9535"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for service of not less than 3 years as a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve or in an active-duty status in the military, air, or naval forces of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D068DA174F14EB49BE39923C68B9312"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if separated from such service, was separated under honorable conditions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93E8762C8462482384C6D74DC18F8B13"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Age</header><text>An alien is eligible, based on his or her age on the date on which the Secretary selects aliens for points-based immigrant visas, for—</text><subparagraph id="HFA58AC5DC00C46009CEAD76CB1CC1BB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2 points for being at least 36 years of age and younger than 45 years of age; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DB4199B5B9A41EFA25CFC00346CF64C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>6 points for being at least 18 years of age and younger than 36 years of age.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A02EACF3C1C4B749C38199667132E67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H680CC4D5070D453FADB3BC2A094A7F26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>English language proficiency test</header><text>The term <term>English language proficiency test</term> means a test to measure English language proficiency that, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security—</text><subparagraph id="HA92BE4B748864049B7C97610E85A8A12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requires test takers to demonstrate their ability to use English to communicate through the language skills of reading, listening, speaking, and writing and utilizing test tasks that require the integrated application of 2 or more such language skills;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H555471E92C194375B25BCE6CCEEA9316"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilizes robust internet security protocols;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FB15BB00DE341BD812AB9A34A72D6DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>verifies test takers’ identity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11790DB7684B4AB590501C6EE508C998"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prohibits the individuals scoring such tests from knowing or having met the individuals whose tests they are scoring.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF5EF25A05D4D7AA270AF5C43D2613F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>English language proficiency test ranking</header><text>The term <term>English language proficiency test ranking</term> means the decile ranking of the applicant’s English language proficiency test score, when compared with all other persons who took the same test during the same period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC326EF5ACEA94B428EF6EE53CF7E2C2B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics</header><text>The term <term>field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics</term> means a field included in the National Center for Education Statistics’ 2020 Classification of Instructional Programs taxonomy within the series 11 (computer and information sciences), 14 (engineering), 26 (biology and biomedical sciences), 27 (mathematics), 40 (physical sciences), 45.0701–.0799 (geography), 51.0401–.0599 (dentistry), 51.1201–.1499 (medicine), 51.3801–.3899 (nursing), 60 (oral and maxillofacial surgery residency programs), and 61 (medical residency/fellowship programs).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDDAE9B9ECF5445339725709FCC4A761D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States doctoral institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>United States doctoral institution of higher education</term> means an institution that is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD17B187650740F997F142463DE1EB56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States institution of higher education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD82B9809C7F04D079861FC27048CA0F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>classified by—</text><clause commented="no" id="HCF851B636989479CB4E6C239B7A11BE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching and the American Council on Education on February 13, 2025, as a very high research spending and doctorate production institution of higher education or as a high research spending and doctorate production institution of higher education; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H595D54D6DF8B4D9290BDBA53ED79650F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation as having equivalent research spending and doctorate production to an institution of higher education described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5B2669203D442C59EC433FEFEB032A9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>United States institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term <term>institution of higher education</term> in section 102(a)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(a)(1)</external-xref>), except that such term does not include an institution outside the United States described in subparagraph (C) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H02347268B98E405E9F0DF7486999C458"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE18248717B46438182DF04421BCAE403"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immigration and Nationality Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H253FF868B1AA469BB22E699094899901"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 202 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="HAE50CC8AF6A74A719C0ECF2B96AB81FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subclause id="H7A70215D00F44D37ADC48AB9BF69F492"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by amending the paragraph heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Per country levels for nuclear family immigrants, points-based immigrants, religious workers, and other special immigrants</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8C421FD75E944559BAD7BF6ED51982AA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><item id="HF25BDB05A3F84A51B1B3998DBBFC82F1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Employment-based</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Points-based immigrants, religious workers, and other special</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></item><item id="HCD7CF3F21EF34505B49A1F42F6320478"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subitem id="HB474A6EAD0AC40498EE7BFED73F07044"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Employment-based</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Points-based immigrants, religious workers, and other special</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subitem><subitem id="H1C5AAE5286D24276ADA10E4E386FFA99"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>by striking <quote>paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (5) of section 203(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b) or (c) of section 203</quote>; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H18F0BEA0C9C74577BAC416AD3007C2DE"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>by striking <quote>under that paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>under such subsection</quote>;</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCF165BAB9CE4F88BB5D1BCB1CB78C79"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 204(a)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="H079EF708EC8747658FC2AD956B335A1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (E), (F), and (H);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE19F1DA836B49F9876AD920B84C3887"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (G), (I), (J), (K), and (L) as subparagraphs (E), (F), (G), (H), and (I), respectively;</text></clause><clause id="HD48DDB822BF246EB8A48E080CB1E5BAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), as redesignated, by striking <quote>203(b)(4)</quote> and inserting 203(c);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA133E2D76BDF47CB808C99AF49F43F67"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), as redesignated, by moving clause (iv) 6 ems to the left; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H085EDD15223A45879F00BCDB70DD0FCF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by moving subparagraph (I), as redesignated, 4 ems to the left;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA11E682202642F99742BDF2A42048E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 212(a)(4) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(4)</external-xref>), by amending subparagraph (D) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC2CEB83807140C99806D29953BBBEDE"><subparagraph id="H67600F1BA59948898DB64CFCB88F80AE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Certain points-based immigrants</header><text>Any alien who seeks admission or adjustment of status under a visa issued pursuant to section 203(b) while relying on a bona fide offer of employment by a relative of the alien (or by an entity in which such relative has a significant ownership interest) is inadmissible under this paragraph unless such relative has executed an affidavit of support described in section 213A with respect to such alien.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05E604D2797744F2B0EB6094BA5D648D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 213A(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1183a">8 U.S.C. 1183a(f)</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="H988DEF151C4F4AD3B9E14CBFF8251086"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subclause id="HB3CAC3F7A6F84740990635918039E807"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Employment-based</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Points-based</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1D053102268C4D9DA2F7269797963F9A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45B724B3F6314E0EAE1D1712AD485B67"><subparagraph id="H227D6A86DFE247DBA8821506CE9F99CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who does not meet the requirement under paragraph (1)(D), but has made a bona fide offer of employment, or has a significant ownership interest in an entity that made a bona fide offer of employment, to an alien who filed a classification petition as a points-based immigrant under section 203(b) and is a relative of such alien; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="HC6C112FE73E246B5ACF6062F5FE59B65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A), by striking <quote>employment-based</quote> and inserting <quote>points-based</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8204E6E1294445BEAD95EB16A671C2EC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in section 245 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C97CA861F6847A192557821CB8E0FCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by striking <quote>subject to subsection (k),</quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32757F0973B3496DA81C17D3681CDC59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (k); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F946854819C41A69BC9CC33DC12A3E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (l), (m), and (n) as subsections (k), (l), and (m), respectively; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H091DF0C8022E409C81ADEE4292263EB8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in section 286(u)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(u)(2)</external-xref>), by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FB75A5518D54461B412B6C4E06BFFB3"><subparagraph id="HAFC34D48022C463F8822D682679666E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>points-based, religious worker, and other special immigrant petitions filed by or on behalf of aliens described in subsection (b) or (c) of section 203;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA840468C07343858D9AC9A7ECF0A5C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>EB–5 Reform and Integrity Act of 2022</header><text>Section 107 the EB–5 Reform and Integrity Act of 2022 (division BB of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153a">8 U.S.C. 1153a</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD648FBDBC5AD41CF9AF9774D32308F14"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><paragraph id="H56B97133FB6C4B47A4BD040420BF296C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF10EABABD2443C4AA761F73EF165087"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Invalidity of certain petitions and applications</header><subparagraph id="HEE9183D48B4247D68EDDCEA5E4BE4EEE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person may not file, and the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State may not accept, adjudicate, or approve any petitions under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>) filed on or after the date of the enactment of this Act seeking classification of an alien under paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (5) of section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>), as in effect on the day immediately before such date of enactment. Any applications for adjustment of status or immigrant visas based on such petitions shall be rejected, denied, or invalidated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FB3B356FD1A433A8AB2CE5A0F2B6D12"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pending petitions</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State may not adjudicate or approve any petitions under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act that are pending as of the date of the enactment of this Act and are seeking classification of aliens under paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (5) of section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>), as in effect on the day immediately before such date of enactment. Any applications for adjustment of status or immigrant visas based on such petitions shall be rejected, denied, or invalidated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB69B141A1198428C8EA2CE88189CA6D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability to waitlisted applicants</header><subparagraph id="H7EFE9CF8DA3C41A9B4D0BCA2DBF8F382"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendments made by this section, aliens who are beneficiaries of a petition under paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (5) of section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>) that was approved before the date of the enactment of this Act may be issued visas pursuant to the applicable paragraph in accordance with the availability of visas under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4BD7DE9B4F34CE98D9D1D6469A5FBDA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of visas</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendments made by this section, visas may be issued to any alien who is a beneficiary of an approved petition under any paragraph referred to in subparagraph (A) until the number of visas that would have been allocated to the applicable visa category during fiscal year 2028 have been issued. When all of the available visas described in the previous sentence have been issued for each paragraph referred in subparagraph (A), no additional visas may be issued for the visa category authorized under the applicable paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H004B2F5F23914D62943D4E979641A836"><enum>6.</enum><header>Conditional permanent resident status for certain immigrants, spouses, and children</header><subsection id="H77F9C8EDA1B547CBB5F96707B6B24074"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 2 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1181">8 U.S.C. 1181 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 216A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1186a">8 U.S.C. 1186a</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC21A8FE5E294980A34A92A024028399"><section id="H6B0B8AB5A02D4D6D987F779DA87DD1E0"><enum>216B.</enum><header>Conditional permanent resident status for points-based immigrants, spouses, and children</header><subsection id="HDE68CEBE5AE84B8CADB682B37C6BBE57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9A7B1FD6C1EF47A7A91C471D120DEC96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alien spouse; alien child</header><text>The terms <term>alien spouse</term> and <term>alien child</term> mean an alien who obtains the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence (whether on a conditional basis or otherwise) by virtue of being the spouse or child, respectively, of a points-based immigrant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F36055AA184ADC970F1A0A190881E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Means-tested public benefit</header><text>The term <term>means-tested public benefit</term> means a public benefit (including cash, medical, housing, and food assistance and social services) from the Federal Government or from a State or political subdivision of a State in which the eligibility of an individual, household, or family eligibility unit for benefits, the amount of such benefits, or both are determined on the basis of income, resources, or financial need of the individual, household, or family eligibility unit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE18295536C5A45CB88E4B6F2AE23010C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Points-based immigrant</header><text>The term <term>points-based immigrant</term> means an alien who has obtained the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence on a conditional basis under section 203(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45A436A1CB5D47E38FBDA9A0091CFEA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H66BE31C6D84942D8AFAE71B820590544"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conditional basis for status</header><text>A points-based immigrant, alien spouse, and alien child shall be considered, at the time of obtaining status as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, to have obtained such status on a conditional basis subject to the requirements under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62A8EA600B754492996E1CF79BC634ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of requirements</header><subparagraph id="H6B383D82E68447C8A4644E9D6A01E7FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>At the time of obtaining permanent residence</header><text>At the time a points-based immigrant, alien spouse, or alien child is granted permanent resident status on a conditional basis, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify such alien of the requirements under this section, including the requirements under subsection (d) for removing the conditional basis of such status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7919B2C8AFA14B019F4C8D7A67478622"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal of conditions</header><text>Not later than 90-days before the date that is 2 years after the date on which a points-based immigrant, alien spouse, or alien child is granted permanent resident status on a conditional basis, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify such alien of the requirements for the removal of the conditional basis of such status described in subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5432EDEE871447686F280FD4B52C1E1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of failure to provide notice</header><text>Failure by the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide the notice required under this paragraph shall not affect the authority of the Secretary to enforce this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0F5B6059831405B861C918B3E03AC22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of permanent resident status for failing To fulfill requirements</header><paragraph id="H80B0F195D1D8465E99BB28436FD396BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, at any time before the date that is 2 years after the date on which a points-based immigrant is granted permanent resident status on a conditional basis, the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that such immigrant is an alien described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B055E2F17924C3D8D4386E932FB79B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to paragraph (3), terminate the conditional permanent resident status of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB55B8C095DDD4202AA8615613BBEFC8B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such immigrant;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FA8BE6253D142A4BF6F6631C91C7CFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien spouse of such immigrant; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H056751F4AD5140F69A668998245084DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each alien child of such immigrant; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53EDAD4FDF344E54A3B079CF62437167"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify each such alien of such termination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0CC56301709407BAF37FF47B183489F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alien described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien described in this paragraph is a points-based immigrant who—</text><subparagraph id="H3DFC2CBAE5C74B1894818D2397E3C672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has not complied with his or her attestation under section 204A(a)(2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C8D201A11FA47C6B9B03C611CF0CC19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been convicted of 1 or more offenses for which such alien has been sentenced to an aggregate term of imprisonment of more than 1 year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CA92DAFF8AF4FEC9632912257F54681"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has received a means-tested public benefit; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA445EFE359174064A5F6422AF220FAFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not employed in—</text><clause id="H0C6DB243FDD44F418574FAA8481F0B2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the job for which the employer of the alien made a bona fide job offer described in section 204A(a)(2)(B); or</text></clause><clause id="HDA544095A9644426A01571AF0176270A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another job for the same employer, or a new employer, for which the immigrant is compensated at a salary that is equivalent to or higher than the salary of the job for which the alien received such bona fide job offer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB059C58CB82F47449A19E6F4C227CC06"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hearing in removal proceedings</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A5E8846EF7C4944B95943C0A4345F05"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien whose permanent resident status on a conditional basis is terminated pursuant to paragraph (1) may request, while in removal proceedings, a review of the determination upon which such termination is based.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03F56B0C54A64FF8A9488FE13BA8A775"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any review under subparagraph (A), the burden of proof shall be on the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the alien concerned is an alien described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1166473E1444715A449B5F50FECC9FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement of timely petition and interview for removal of condition</header><paragraph id="HE1BDF78A5C9E45208188EF7BE3C3A1C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The conditional basis established under subsection (b) for a points-based immigrant, alien spouse, or alien child may be removed if—</text><subparagraph id="H3C6BE5C0FABB4F65A065490FD17ED4ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the points-based immigrant, during the 90-day period ending on the date that is 2 years after the date on which the points-based immigrant was granted permanent resident status on a conditional basis, submits a petition to the Secretary of Homeland Security that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73B60E16D573474595C2E8940BCDC922"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requests the removal of such conditional basis; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BDC15B8F9614F45B99E1492E371CDD5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">states, under penalty of perjury, the facts and information described in subsection (e)(1); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8552527293F541FD9B2CC8AC38EB481F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with subsection (e)(3), the points-based immigrant appears for a personal interview before an officer or employee of the Department of Homeland Security respecting the facts and information described in subsection (e)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H412046564E84405BA372E2CE236EC776"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of permanent resident status for failure to file petition or have personal interview</header><subparagraph id="H4F0740CED0844039980217087C3DF3DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall terminate the permanent resident status of a points-based immigrant (and such status of the immigrant’s spouse and children obtained on a conditional basis under this section or section 216) on the date that is 2 years after the date on which such alien was lawfully admitted for permanent residence if—</text><clause id="H82E6B928BFE846EA9E325179FC8551A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>no petition is filed with respect to such alien in accordance with paragraph (1)(A); or</text></clause><clause id="H9475B00309744A6FB36838E0AA95AF61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alien fails to appear at an interview described in paragraph (1)(B) and required under subsection (e)(3), unless the alien shows good cause for such nonappearance.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD023E031554420990ED8AA9AA70FD01"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hearing in removal proceedings</header><text>In any removal proceeding concerning an alien whose permanent resident status is terminated under subparagraph (A), the burden of proof shall be on the alien to establish compliance with the requirement under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEDA5FEE2E53476A9B8794026316ABA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination after petition and interview</header><subparagraph id="H28FF7A9C63B54AB58511E55D527C7B15"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the later of the date on which a points-based immigrant files a petition pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) and the date on which such alien is interviewed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall determine whether the facts and information described in subsection (e)(1) and alleged in the petition are true.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31A01FDA3B4B417B867292F2309B512A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal of conditional basis</header><text>If the Secretary determines the facts and information contained in a petition submitted pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) are true and the points-based immigrant complied with subsection (e)(1)(B)(i), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="HB300B2EF2CA54B3CBD63F0314B7E3065"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notify the alien involved of such determination; and</text></clause><clause id="H2BE7FA76BBBA428D8A734A2456D0D9C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remove the conditional basis of the alien’s status effective as of the date that is 2 years after the date on which such alien was lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5EF21BD08694BD98E6C40A2B1DEDECA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Termination if adverse determination</header><text>If the Secretary determines such facts and information are not true or the points-based immigrant failed to comply with subsection (e)(1)(B)(i), the Secretary shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6308BA88F5824D1496B32CA1A6145DB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the alien involved of such determination; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EC7294D24FE42AC9F782D4C53CBEF29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (D), terminate the permanent resident status of the points-based immigrant, alien spouse, and alien child as of the date of such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05459F50D4DC4673BF224597C9CC16CF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Hearing in removal proceeding</header><text>Any alien whose permanent resident status is terminated pursuant to subparagraph (C) may request a review of such determination in a proceeding to remove the alien. In such proceeding, the burden of proof shall be on the Secretary to establish, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the facts and information described in subsection (e)(1) and alleged in the petition are not true.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE03A06A13A8746508068B8543FA1B76F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Detail of petition and interview</header><paragraph id="HC08294C3F7824818B7923CA212DE35A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Content of petition</header><text>Each petition submitted pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(A) shall contain facts and information demonstrating the alien is not described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD071BEB635CE400693FF4142FDA9FDE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period for filing petition</header><subparagraph id="H6AB1D4C349044932B58B6E53C7E02774"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ninety-day period before second anniversary</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a petition shall be filed pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(A) during the 90-day period ending on the date that is 2 years after the date on which the points-based immigrant was lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C41246D4F8B4207AF0AAA840D145323"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Date petitions for good cause</header><text>A petition required under subsection(d)(1)(A) may be considered if filed after the date referred to in subparagraph (A) if the points-based immigrant establishes, to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Homeland Security, good cause and extenuating circumstances for failure to file the petition during the period described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59DB3F6AC42D422CBF29C7672EB3A51F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Filing of petitions during removal</header><text>The Attorney General may stay removal proceedings against an alien who is the subject of removal hearings as a result of failure to file a petition on a timely basis in accordance with subparagraph (A) pending the filing of a petition pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D803A77C3C24643906EE67A5330E5B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personal interview</header><subparagraph id="HE23824623D6644E0862AE65975FEE759"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The interview required under subsection (d)(1)(B) shall be conducted not later than 90 days after the date on which a petition is submitted pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(A) at a local office of the Department of Homeland Security that has been designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security and is convenient to the parties involved.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA9326420EFA4B31A19B054D6E344FDE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H774150D1110E402A8EE4315FAF8C5697"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under clauses (ii) and (iii), the Secretary of Homeland Security may waive the deadline for an interview under subsection (d)(1)(B) or the requirement for such an interview according to criteria developed by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, in consultation with the Fraud Detection and National Security Directorate and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D0556EAF74B4E29975AF00221929CF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing waiver criteria pursuant to clause (i), the Secretary may not use as criteria reducing case processing times or allocating adjudicatory resources.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H566777E6DB4B44A38630AF412FE69680"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A waiver may not be granted under this subparagraph if the alien to be interviewed is in a class of aliens determined by the Secretary to be a threat to public safety or national security.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D24BB8F4A1C42599B1ECE2E0790662C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Treatment of period for purposes of naturalization</header><text>For purposes of title III, an alien granted lawful permanent resident on a conditional basis shall be considered to have been admitted to the United States, and to be present in the United States, as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4885FA97E7864F95887AB7FF61DEBFD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 216A the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79C095B3B5DC477484BF9EEA3D95801B"><toc><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 216B. Conditional permanent resident status for points-based immigrants, spouses, and children.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H7555E58223864CAEA4E47E038FE5C54D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Protection of United States taxpayers and college students</header><subsection id="HD41B65CDAB4B4B67A43E1B3C597646EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National policy</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10F13D99BC2942A19710DE16D0266715"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 400 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/193">Public Law 104–193</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1601">8 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8A8999F73BF4782ACE5EB9FA8B2DE2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">welfare</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">public benefits</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H812C56FD576D401B989A48D615A24F4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Congress</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H745623F3F74E4098BE5FFD4D33AF7165"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E6354A204154A679D77B70F8BD30EB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of national policy concerning welfare and immigration</header><text>Congress</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66C0371B79C046B4B2F61CB5B5CAA537"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76B7185CE4F2481CB51D85265209FED6"><subsection id="HD1A4B9E0EA0F44F2A12F33D97CD115D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of national policy concerning public education and immigration</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A25F3DC56F64A8FB4EF6C05630F462E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that the right to a free public education for aliens who are not lawfully admitted for permanent residence—</text><subparagraph id="HC8D8393E0B4B43BF9242B0BF897B3F5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>creates a significant burden on the budgets of States and local governments by depleting their limited educational resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H053E5BCF2BF8405DAA3F68A46955DF36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promotes violations of the immigration laws inconsistent with Federal law and policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF10D7C713C7B4F59A7244A07AEFB36FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H598DAC1F7637415799D023D5A1465350"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States that—</text><subparagraph id="HFB4D5C92B1E0444787D62F28CE10568A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>aliens who are not lawfully admitted for permanent residence should not be entitled to public education benefits in the same manner as United States citizens and aliens who are lawfully admitted for permanent residence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF124F5380B084859849125AA7E74C52A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>States should not be obligated to provide public education benefits to aliens who are not lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4ABB39362EE14BDEABE625D274485927"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on eligibility for preferential treatment of certain aliens for higher education benefits</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9502EA37E184440B9D4198237A0353F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1623">8 U.S.C. 1623</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71CD7BD2FF604BFABE051F7AB99C2098"><section id="H3AA5D39D6B8A4AA9A0FB196FB9392CE8"><enum>505.</enum><header>Limitation on eligibility for preferential treatment of certain aliens for higher education benefits</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A6D62F4E7B44F768394687873379A65"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC08C8E57169D440789B4B96968A3B17F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lawfully admitted for permanent residence</header><text>The term <term>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63FC6F9DB2F24A24AD0ACD30ECC387A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Postsecondary educational institution</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary educational institution</term> has the meaning given the term <term>institution of higher education</term> in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FBBDBA1FB224D99A2170C7BCA502A40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADDFC436908F4ACBA73B50CF5C78409A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any alien who is not lawfully admitted for permanent residence shall be required to pay to the postsecondary educational institution at which such alien is enrolled not less than the amount of tuition, fees, and other costs charged to any student carrying the same academic workload who is not a resident of the State or political subdivision in which that institution is located; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7474BCA927B5495DAE8CDEFCAE37EE6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no citizen or national of the United States may be charged a higher amount of tuition, fees, or other costs as a student carrying the same academic workload than the amount of such tuition, fees, and other costs charged to an alien who is not lawfully admitted for permanent residence, with such tuition, fees, and costs determined net of any discounts or benefits provided by any level of government or by the postsecondary educational institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D7F04543D8B48539B2BBF01592F200A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to all tuition, fees, and other costs paid by students after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>America First Immigration Act</short-title> to attend any postsecondary educational institution.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA7F35A178AD4AAD9AD907434742AD7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>; 110 Stat. 3009–546) is amended by striking the item relating to section 505 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7CEBD10671A499F8705D930A6C94434"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 505. Limitation on eligibility for preferential treatment of certain aliens for higher education benefits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A7F29CB573E44BD9041034E3BB4A5C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act. The amendments made by subsection (b) shall apply to all tuition, fees, and other costs paid by students on or after such date of enactment to any postsecondary educational institution.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

