<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26540-VWK-44-0R3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>102 SRES 739 ATS: Honoring the life and legacy of John Seymour, the late Senator for the State of California.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 739</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor>Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and legacy of John Seymour, the late Senator for the State of California.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour was born on December 3, 1937, in Chicago, Illinois;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour enlisted in the United States Marine Corps, serving his country in uniform from 1955 to 1959;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour attended public school in Mt. Lebanon, Pennsylvania, and graduated from the University of California, Los Angeles in 1962;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a southern California businessman, John Seymour greatly contributed to Orange County’s vibrant real estate and housing marketplace, serving as president of the California Association of Realtors in 1980;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1974, John Seymour was first elected to the Anaheim City Council, representing the city of Anaheim as a council member from 1974 to 1978, and later serving as the Mayor of Anaheim from 1978 to 1982;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as Mayor of Anaheim, John Seymour led efforts to secure the relocation of the Los Angeles Rams to Orange County in 1980, championing his community in the process;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as Mayor of Anaheim, John Seymour further led initiatives to establish greater trust and public accountability between Anaheim law enforcement and the wider community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour, during his time as a State Senator in the California legislature, as well as in the United States Senate, demonstrated leadership and commitment to causes dearly held by California residents, including special education, women’s rights, and environmental stewardship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour was appointed to the United States Senate in 1991 by California Governor Pete Wilson and served in the Senate until 1992;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, while serving in the Senate, John Seymour served on the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, working alongside Senator Alan Cranston, John Seymour helped pass into law a landmark transportation bill, the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/240">Public Law 102–240</external-xref>; 109 Stat. 1914), securing billions of dollars in funding to benefit the State of California;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour led congressional efforts to preserve California’s natural beauty, protect its ecosystems, wildlife, and national parks, and stimulate California's industries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour served with distinction, developing a reputation for candor, bipartisanship, and putting people and communities first;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour, in his advocacy as a public servant and private citizen, devoted particular attention to supporting affordable housing initiatives in southern California through steadfast engagement with nonprofit organizations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Seymour was a beloved son, husband, father, grandfather, and great-grandfather; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the State of California and the United States have lost a compassionate lawmaker and dedicated public servant: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That—</text><paragraph id="idaadabb8881ad493fba079193750987bc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Senate—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id643d38cdcbd2404d80caa064b688e1d4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the death of John Seymour, the late United States Senator for the State of California; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1a18247b40d4bfd9fb47f267365aef1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate communicate this resolution to the House of Representatives and transmit an enrolled copy thereof to the family of John Seymour; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc8e7f26bbc784904b19311e2452b75c1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when the Senate adjourns today, it stands adjourned as a further mark of respect to the memory of the late John Seymour.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

