<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25782-85P-K1-KY5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3273 IS: American Allies Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3273</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit awarding grants to States that arrest certain foreign officials in cooperation with the International Criminal Court, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id77fa29afee1949dda1b751b58c79fb87" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Allies Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb48ab0eb542d493fa93e958586e3e9f7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Penalties on state or local enforcement of icc actions</header><subsection id="id43c6829e580a42cba3091742ef16293f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), if any public official, employee, or agent of a State, a territory, or the District of Columbia, or any political subdivision thereof, arrests, detains, or otherwise deprives the liberty of a current or former foreign government official of a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or of a government designated as a Major Non-NATO Ally based solely on a warrant, indictment, summons, or other process issued by the International Criminal Court or cooperates with, or provides assistance to, the International Criminal Court in effectuating such an arrest or detention, with respect to the fiscal year beginning on the first October 1 occurring after the date of enactment of the Act, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Attorney General may not award, renew, or extend a grant to the State, territory, the District of Columbia, or any political subdivision thereof, for a four-year period.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbe7ecadd83434da48d912b32abfd74f4"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Waiver authority</header> <text>The Attorney General may waive the application of subsection (a) to a grant award if the President certifies to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that an act described in subsection (a) is essential to the national security interests of the United States, including a detailed justification for the necessity of the act.</text>
            </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

