<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H98E620F50FF4441A8ACC43D9DDFD7517" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8670 IH: Stop Oil Exports to Lower Gas Prices Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8670</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the prohibition on exports of crude oil, gasoline, and diesel fuel during period of military operations against Iran.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H47AE78709265469A962389D7157258D3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H48C68885073D4BC0AC65EC607154E817" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Oil Exports to Lower Gas Prices Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H5F535F2CC49A4E069580CCF80E62BC66"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on exports of crude oil, gasoline, and diesel fuel during period of military operations against Iran</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101 of division O of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6212a">42 U.S.C. 6212a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H04F8D408C8BD475D81C937ED11BDAFF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>subsections (c) and (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c), (d), and (f)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44F642E4B7A548C2AF446F7EB17BA15A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF0BB44B956004795981510417BB399EC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HA294417CD4444DCF878F3AC70390FE77"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional exception</header> <paragraph id="H766D248B82E74FDB8C09F511E9761117"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including the other provisions of this section), except as provided in paragraph (2), the export of crude oil, gasoline, and diesel fuel shall be prohibited during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subsection and ending on the date on which the President—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB9070069D7EC43969C045B6836BBE092"><enum>(A)</enum><text>declares that military operations against Iran which began in March 2026 have ceased; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6CAC9D00AA674BB89F522A82D14C2BAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determines and certifies to Congress that the Strait of Hormuz is fully open and global shipping through the Strait has resumed; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H246A142E0EAA4B0C8618333B63F74F8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a proposed export of crude oil, the President may waive the prohibition in paragraph (1) if the President determines that crude oil cannot be efficiently refined in the United States. If the President issues a waiver under this paragraph, the President shall issue a license for the export of crude oil from the United States pursuant to such waiver and further require that such crude oil is to be refined abroad and imported back into the United States. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

