<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H74C76600DB3B47419C157614E6473834" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1291 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of May 3 through May 9, 2026, as Wildfire Preparedness Week, the national event educating the public on fire safety and preparedness, and supporting the goals of a Wildfire Preparedness Week.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1291</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of May 3 through May 9, 2026, as Wildfire Preparedness Week, the national event educating the public on fire safety and preparedness, and supporting the goals of a Wildfire Preparedness Week.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Wildfire Preparedness Week increases awareness of the threat of wildfires and knowledge of lifesaving tactics;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Wildfire Preparedness Week, like other designated weeks or days for natural disasters, promotes educational initiatives, encourages community programming, and increases overall knowledge and preparedness;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the effects of long-term exposure to wildfire smoke will harm more people, as particle pollution triggers asthma attacks, heart attacks, and strokes, and can kill;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas firefighters are on the frontlines and are at an increased risk of developing cancer and respiratory diseases because they are exposed to smoke and hazardous chemicals in the line of duty;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, 77,850 wildfires burned in the United States, consuming a total of 5,131,474 acres, and in California there were 8,232 wildfires that burned for a total of 507,817 acres;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas nearly 85 percent of wildland fires in the United States are caused by humans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, so far in 2026, 24,066 wildfires have burned 1,848,210 acres across the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States experienced a large number of wildfires from West Coast to East Coast; </text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas preventative measures exist to help individuals and communities increase their fire resilience through—</text> <paragraph id="HA831152E3F42413792C39BE2EA5B657B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evacuation planning and assistance for people and their animals; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E6909DC7C274D41BB55B5FB4A63FB86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>vegetation and forest management; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3611627160649798B4D58A6319CB6D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limited use of combustibles during high heat or drier seasons, including fireworks, exhaust, and open flames; and</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas we commit to working together to financially support communities directly during and after a catastrophic firestorm: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H59304DB808FA4C59BAC8131B8C889653"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H773A2FB23137412C9AD6F665765458AD"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB2930E53A6F04D62A224B51D156315B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals of Wildfire Preparedness Week;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DAF7F8726854821B3B43B683A50ADAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports resources and educational initiatives that communicate how affected communities can take preventative measures such as instituting early warning systems and reducing unplanned human ignitions, as well as how to safely and efficiently evacuate people and their animals; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H547079DAB6C745EDACF7FCA00C279A06"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages increased awareness of and preparedness for the threat of wildfires and subsequent suppression efforts.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

