<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCA5D1BAD3DAD46358B4A87C37ECD0BF0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7368 IH: Riley Gaines Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7368</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize civil actions against institutions of higher education and athletic associations that negligently or recklessly permit a biologically male student athlete to compete in an athletic competition intended exclusively for female student athletes, resulting in harm.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFB684E2CC2844D339D783EB41A231D05" style="OLC"><section id="HA8A6ED9D7F954E1297E93171F14ADB56" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Riley Gaines Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H26BC2260C6F448DCA3F1226AAA43AB48"><enum>2.</enum><header>Civil action for harm caused by biological men in female athletic competitions</header><subsection id="HC988ADAF38EC45F1BB45D8B1A012404C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an institution of higher education or an athletic association negligently or recklessly permits a biologically male student athlete to compete in an athletic competition intended exclusively for female student athletes and a female student athlete is physically injured due to the inherent physiological advantages of the biologically male student athlete, such female student athlete may bring a civil action for damages (including the value of the loss of a scholarship or professional opportunity) in any Federal district court of appropriate jurisdiction against such institution or athletic association.</text></subsection><subsection id="H53B4A9D412FF4C6A90B9A60C6D9059A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees for plaintiff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee to a prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

