<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26654-C65-7V-05C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4434 IS: Correcting Lapsed Enforcement in Antitrust Norms for Mergers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4434</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Clayton Act to provide for the divestiture of certain transactions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id2c4a64f3431447a19ad9927d394f5fb9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Correcting Lapsed Enforcement in Antitrust Norms for Mergers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAN Mergers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id459ff6a4bb9144fea69ef8fb46c66456"><enum>2.</enum><header>Divestiture of threshold transactions; review of enforcement-lapse transactions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 7A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e5b64c43eaf44c4851b4dd9c914249a"><section id="ID209F828F35DD4E2381DED83FD5EFEBC3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7B.</enum><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ID24DF32A0F79945FCBF5269E0787A1B0F"><enum>(a)</enum><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="IDAC86A64FF7764EE7A9A56EDBEAA97E07" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agencies</term> means the Department of Justice, the Federal Trade Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Department of Transportation, and the Surface Transportation Board;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf1d85a777594a52b6ed522e78c948b3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>court</term> means any district court of the United States having jurisdiction over parties seeking a declaratory judgment or other relief pursuant to this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb61f6105d3414b8284b8e9085936f3fd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered period</term> means the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on January 19, 2029;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc30eec582eef4fddb39cdd4a2da9367e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>enforcement-lapse transaction</term> means any transaction consummated during the covered period that is not a threshold transaction;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id415603483c6a4fad8db613082330a915"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>the term <term>HHI</term> means the Herfindahl–Hirschman Index;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7f09488c45343e3a55cd6e78991b13e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>relevant market</term> has the meaning given the term in the <quote>Merger Guidelines U.S. Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission</quote> issued on December 18, 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76db394620a24f0185ff3e0b4477e8ce"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>transaction</term> means an acquisition subject to section 7A, including any transaction exempt from the requirements of subsection (c) of that section, during the covered period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd956ca0865ea412699a7a2e30ae86b89"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>threshold transaction</term> means a transaction consummated during the covered period with a value of not less than $10,000,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e3a84aff86a40b48483baa683563f7b"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id111c6ef596a143c18c8b293e99c9187c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the parties to a threshold transaction shall—</text><subparagraph id="id7e24dca9b81146f6b98e9ddc90e10572" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the transaction was consummated before the date of enactment of this section, complete divestiture of such transaction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ed53aa098634bcaa9e6a14a879c73f3" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the transaction is consummated after the date of enactment of this section, hold separate the assets of the merging entities to ensure such assets remain independent, economically viable, and that competition is maintained during the pendency of agency review under subsection (c)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id719b6705cbe9480bba417b235ff9b64e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired may file an action for a declaratory judgment seeking to exempt the threshold transaction from the divestiture requirements under paragraph (1) by demonstrating that all of the following conditions exist:</text><subparagraph id="ide67d71fed77c4cfd93e6347c00746d8b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The threshold transaction did not result in—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id828a956971994558b9e59826052fa89a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a post-acquisition HHI in excess of 1,800; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id801c66ccd863498ebcd8666dcce31546"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a change in the HHI of greater than 100 in any relevant market;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d521e9a95be469e9121a426a5fa19ef"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a market share greater than 30 percent of any relevant market; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddac94b2653324b23af0d34fac1a378de"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an increase in HHI of more than 100.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2b47cd8d6ef41bba59fd262cfb472e3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to any line of business, price increases or quality adjustments were materially consistent with representations made during agency review of the transaction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d90aafe6bf5475faa0bdf2e5c3cc207"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The threshold transaction was not followed by any significant reduction in output by the post-acquisition entity, as compared to the highest level of combined output by the acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired during the 2-year period ending on the date on which the agency began review of the transaction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4bb0075353394f558c850e8454b1f642"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The threshold transaction was not followed by any significant reduction in employment inconsistent with representations made or omitted during agency review of the transaction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39133b53154742899025bdbc1c7aed3f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any divestiture or other condition imposed in connection with the approval of the transaction achieved full and timely compliance without any accusation of circumvention, malicious compliance, or failure of any assets subject to divestiture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09e37d8b6e3446a2bc5cba91e035c7c8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>No lawyer or law firm involved in the transaction offered or provided pro bono legal services in connection with any settlement or agreement with any reviewing agency or executive branch official.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f8f4bc7db78488495b62693c0646a77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In any proceeding initiated pursuant to subsection (b)(2), the Attorney General of any State shall have an unconditional right of intervention.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id762fd0080b43428ba868a587f5cf7378"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9290190e5c4649aabe70306ab3d61e11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the agencies or the Attorney General of any State may conduct a review of any enforcement-lapsed transaction consummated prior to or after the date of enactment of this section to determine whether any of the following conditions existed with respect to the review or clearance of such transaction:</text><subparagraph id="idef82b403a25642a688900012b4bf2897" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conduct constituting a violation of section 201, 208, or 1001 of title 18, United States Code, or section 7A of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b5c6a49180b4c169eae64a737a5d164" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The transaction was cleared, approved, or subject to dismissal, entry of a consent decree, or other final disposition notwithstanding a written recommendation to the contrary by any civil servant in the agency conducting the review, including—</text><clause id="idb43a76b9e25d4c188751101d2ac5a125"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to open an investigation into a transaction;</text></clause><clause id="id569a76dea858471f9469a5a7bcbf7d1f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to request additional information and documentary materials;</text></clause><clause id="id3dee5f72ba5a4c07877ca298f448e418"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that a party withdraw a premerger notification and submit a new filing for a transaction;</text></clause><clause id="id6464cf48fcdd444bb3c19d55a7037cdc"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to challenge a transaction; or</text></clause><clause id="ida094fe0d28c34d3d9c0f140822fc2bfd"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to further modify or condition the transaction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1bbdec54a44e4c4ebbdf96016fa2dc04" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The transaction was approved, cleared, or otherwise disposed of without the completion of an investigation following a request for additional information or documentary material under section 7A(e).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb287ecceb38417fbc8648ff7b62e370" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any political appointee, registered lobbyist, person acting at the direction or on behalf of the acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired, or person with a direct or indirect financial interest in the outcome of such transaction, communicated with any official or employee of the agencies, the Executive Office of the President, or any other Federal agency regarding the review or disposition of such transaction outside of procedures established for public comment or formal party submissions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide194cb8463474451af59f3b01dbfb7c0" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A material misrepresentation or omission related to the transaction was made to the agency at any point prior to or during the completion of any review of a transaction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4cd0085155f04d8a91cedb3797a8c85c" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The President, or any member of the Cabinet, or head of a Federal agency, made statements—</text><clause id="idbf63543b80df4248a601d4adf4fc5a68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indicating a preference for a particular acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired, or outcome in such transaction;</text></clause><clause id="id50bc63df2bba4f6b857438065cc299ea"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>suggesting that commitments, concessions, or promises were sought or obtained from any acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired in connection with the review or clearance thereof; or</text></clause><clause id="id8862241e76d1416ca5fa26ed8e0edada"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>suggesting that the disposition of such transaction was influenced by considerations unrelated to the competitive effects of such transaction under the antitrust laws.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idddbb53d9b6504b4d8acef319f9221500" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The approval of the transaction was materially influenced by a conflict of interest, improper ex parte communication, or other ethical violation or professional misconduct by any official involved in the review.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54919b2d89e845f493b0b3256e97ecf6" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired were represented by any law firm, lobbying firm, or other person that had previously employed a political appointee at a reviewing agency during the 1-year period ending on the date of the appointment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9fdd9f0ad114a009c83dad1b757d917" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any foreign government, foreign state-owned enterprise, sovereign wealth fund, or agent of a foreign principal, as defined in section 1(b) of the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/611">22 U.S.C. 611(b)</external-xref>), directly or indirectly sought to influence the review, clearance, or disposition of the transaction through any communication with any official or employee of the agencies, the Executive Office of the President, or any other Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida30560631bab4b57907a98271b82bef1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idfcbe5839db61475ea0659c7e355949a4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the reviewing agency determines that there is a reasonable basis to conclude that 1 or more of the conditions described in subparagraphs (A) through (I) of paragraph (1) are met, the agency shall provide written notice to the acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired requiring divestiture of any and all transaction assets, including the dissolution of any agreement or venture incidental to the transaction, not later than 30 days after such determination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fdc642f885347af85a49db8bc4b73df"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The divestiture required under subparagraph (A) shall be completed not later than 180 days after the date on which the acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired receive the notice under that subparagraph, unless the acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired file an action for a declaratory judgment under paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c3b6c7ceac64db29d089e29c007fac3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired may file for an action for a declaratory judgment seeking to exempt the enforcement-lapsed transaction from the divestiture requirements under paragraph (2) by demonstrating to the court by clear and convincing evidence that, as to any condition forming the basis of a notice to divest under paragraph (2), such condition—</text><subparagraph id="id61058011ec8440d6bf7f28ac4155323b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>did not occur; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id400c19a325004eac9016a390c43c54de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was so immaterial to any agency action related to the transaction that no reasonable person might consider the condition and agency action related in any way.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ceb38aa875a4f1f8b837a4b11a73fb1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In any proceeding initiated pursuant to paragraph (3), the Attorney General of any State shall have an unconditional right of intervention.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb9f8acd05fba4eff9038e28bb4f312b7"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action under this section, the identification of the relevant market—</text><paragraph id="idea2c84d916274d48bc573c06c0859d4b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not require direct evidence or expert witness testimony regarding prices, output, or substitutability; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0f25e192efc457ebfd55496ca99a76b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall defer to any plausible submarket, which may be adequately defined based on indirect evidence of the boundaries of the relevant market, including practical indicia of market boundaries recognized by the industry, customers or the public, or any potential submarket considered by any agency at the time the transaction was reviewed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfc209f15d05744b0b5486d1ac6b3f977"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idf6d4ab9546ed445fa2274535b0ae44bd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All acquiring persons and persons whose voting securities or assets were acquired during the covered period and any counsel, lobbyist, or other agent of the acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired shall—</text><subparagraph id="id9e10d40b5da745d28a14ec76eeba6d39" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preserve any written or oral communication by or on behalf of such acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired, including any ephemeral message, by any officer, director, employee, or agent of such acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired, or other person, with any officer or employee of the United States related to the transaction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id132c84424ddf45b183f7222e8a7eb497" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preserve any document and electronically stored information described in rule 34(a)(1)(A) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure related to the transaction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id084d94e3b46a411cb8c43f350cff21e4" indent="up1"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>take all steps necessary to prevent the destruction, loss, or alteration of any such document, electronically stored information, communication, and other data or information generated by or stored on the a computer, mobile device, or storage media of an acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0fe2519a7eb43d1a18a52092ebcbcb8" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If a party fails to comply with paragraph (1), in any proceeding before a court relating to the transaction, the court shall—</text><subparagraph id="id7d1c671e3b074955bc3ec4720d99ce31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>instruct the factfinder to draw an adverse inference that the evidence that was not preserved would have been unfavorable to the party that failed to preserve such evidence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fec2731448742a3a88dde5325c3c6fb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sanction counsel and executives to the extent they knew or should have known their actions or inactions would cause such failure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd581c8e20f94a86826e9f01177931f8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make criminal referrals to the extent such failure is a violation of section 1512(c) of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1b9f88bca254d75bd9cbe0a3b0d206d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any records preserved pursuant to this subsection shall be made available to the attorney general of any State upon request.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbe3a1ebc1bd54749a802d813a153ceb3"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id594e26b3fc394c78855609dc66ec5877"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired fail to complete divestiture pursuant to subsection (b)(1) or (c)(2) before the date that is 90 days after the date on which the divestiture is required to be completed, the court shall appoint, or a reviewing agency shall move a court to appoint, an independent divestiture trustee with the authority to effect the sale of assets on such terms as the trustee determines are reasonable, subject to court approval.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida65d2e2d0db54708a2f2c36b117ba135"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If a court finds that any person knowingly violated the requirements of subsection (b)(1) or (c)(2), the court may—</text><subparagraph id="idbd489f600a454b58951ef2ea4aca56d8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impose a civil penalty not to exceed the greater of—</text><clause id="idb01d43ad4e7a4335aaf586b87afa6494"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$100,000 each day during which such violation persists; or</text></clause><clause id="idb9fc1956b17d440880a67e9828fc7aab"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>5 percent of the total value of the transaction;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1de74f068bd4c898017ae9cf4b19d81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose against the chief executive officer and board members of any entity resulting from the transaction, a civil penalty not more than $100,000 each day during which such violation persists; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7dd94e8ebf724b909c164113e3448f40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impose any other monetary or equitable relief, or initiate a contempt proceeding or criminal referral that the court, in its discretion, determines is necessary to effectuate compliance with the requirements of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide73f62f523c64262bf9aa196b834d3fd" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the court finds that the failure to divest pursuant to subsection (b)(1) or (c)(2) was knowing, the court may award damages in an amount equal to 3 times the value of the commercial benefit derived by the parties from the continued operation of the assets subject to divestiture during the period of noncompliance.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf17a1143711e4f04b30425eb3f37765a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If the agencies have probable cause to believe that any person has violated section 201, section 208, or section 1001 of title 18, United States Code, in connection with the review or approval of a transaction, the Attorney General shall appoint a special counsel to investigate and, if warranted, prosecute such violations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cbbdd072c274a799536cd3817aae86f"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3809088e0d9147829fb54bd74838ee8f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), in any action by an acquiring person and person whose voting securities or assets were acquired for declaratory judgment, as to any threshold or enforcement-lapse transaction, structural relief, including divestiture, dissolution, or rescission, shall be the presumptive remedy for restoring competition in any relevant market.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id15f1b7ea5f854f258e099f9d327e5442" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The court may order additional remedies, including the disgorgement of any gain attributable to the transaction, only upon a finding supported by clear evidence that—</text><subparagraph id="id0071d314520b4709b8ea561a875ed50c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a divestiture is physically or technologically impossible; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9897ea2c34b14d848c4498f8dc626012"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other remedy would not fully and effectively restore competition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id8513ac2ced6f434498ca933dd13f18d4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitations for antitrust actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4B of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/15b">15 U.S.C. 15b</external-xref>) is amended, in the first sentence, by striking <quote>four years</quote> and inserting <quote>10 years</quote>.</text></section><section id="idcfb817373f2449288c66fbb88e719a3c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the application of the provisions of such to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

