<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25A79-VCG-77-DRW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3428 IS: Strengthening Agency Frameworks for Enforcement of Cryptocurrency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3428</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a Task Force for Recognizing and Averting Cryptocurrency Scams, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Agency Frameworks for Enforcement of Cryptocurrency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Crypto Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5604f429c16b4cd1b543a7a02a6a0c4a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58e5af550e2c4c39aab237298059648f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital asset; digital asset service provider; permitted payment stablecoin issuer</header><text>The terms <term>digital asset</term>; <term>digital asset service provider</term>; and <term>permitted payment stablecoin issuer</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2 of the GENIUS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5901">12 U.S.C. 5901</external-xref>), respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5e18bd68cad4977a2a13979b85259fe"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c8bf28c6e754dfe9cbbf0676c070ffd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Task Force</header><text>The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Task Force on Cryptocurrency Scams established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id00ec83f785414ec7b168cc917270c178"><enum>3.</enum><header>Task Force on Cryptocurrency Scams</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b06ccf676634622a5d91e9a57f439bd"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a task force, to be known as the Task Force for Recognizing and Averting Cryptocurrency Scams.</text></subsection><subsection id="id95d29743b39a448e925dbadd5f040fe1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79a0d92767174a86b69eca6700f016a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Composition</header><text>The Task Force shall be chaired by the Secretary, or a designee thereof, and shall consist of the following individuals, or the designees of these individuals:</text><subparagraph id="id3a447b66259345e79a25767022ae734d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c925c54da7b4bec8077e73335476cdc"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbfb00b6b36d41ba83fe5476f0a12830"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Director of the United States Secret Service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99dccce708c24854b8839ea23f3c6937" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The head of any other relevant Federal department or agency, as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Task Force.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2c56bab7fa8481daa621677e0e8c84f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Representatives of permitted payment stablecoin issuers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5d18d4bd3f142a69c5f6dd085fa37a7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Representatives of digital asset service providers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb62fa64a00c40f7b84d53c0a9f6cbc2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Representatives of digital asset custodians.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id064822cbd2014ebdbfacb7b25b755709"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Representatives of blockchain intelligence providers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd162692c1f944c3d8d773f69521953b7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Representatives of victims, scam support networks, or other relevant consumer protection stakeholders.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided211b4a5455455b8d4ce2a8a6c26525"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Representatives of Federal, State, and local law enforcement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id380ae2b9ca60483c9b3355d6d401fa38"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Representatives of any other industries, as determined necessary by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb87069d9e8d4d4da51801034645ff59"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Representatives from 1 or more State bank regulatory authorities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf034c4b762e148ecb1d30ce8a1b96dd9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term of appointment</header><text>The term of a member of the Task Force shall continue until the termination of the Task Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5735793cb4c4c7d8fef48c0fbc032c4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>Any vacancy occurring in the membership of the Task Force shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7a9e14779f034aabb1ad2f547e5716f4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Task Force include the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18bcb5cc8923477f8dd5127e641558f5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scam detection and prevention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall examine current trends and developments in the financial grooming scams involving digital assets, identify effective methods for preventing such scams, and issue recommendations to enhance efforts to identify and prevent such activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id125de415853c4ee1ae717c00ba523d62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cross-sector approach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall adopt a cross-sector approach to ensure its recommendations reflect the full scope of the issue, given that scams impact individuals across jurisdictions and a wide range of industries, including financial services, telecommunications, and technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9b098229a6f4013a723aaaf750a1081"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholder insight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall include representation from—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b2a3089f17a456e82fe5c9bacf57a6a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stakeholders with direct experience supporting victims of scams (including individuals forced to engage in the scams and individuals impacted by the scams); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fa477b11ffb4ecd88868359cd3f73d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">industry participants with insight into—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id590bde4f1d334a54ba823ddd7477e294"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the organized crime networks perpetrating the scams;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf33d1364e0ba4736bfb13a05a195d66a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">digital asset ATMs; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id635fbb447d8948d8a3c43f40dfc974e9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevention strategies, including following the money to detect, deter, and dismantle the organized crime networks.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fae20f93e0849059a67b3da06f372b3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information sharing and interdiction networks</header><text>The Task Force, in coordination with relevant Federal agencies, is encouraged to promote participation by digital asset service providers and permitted payment stablecoin issuers in public-private, real-time information sharing and interdiction networks designed to detect, disrupt, and prevent the off-ramping of funds associated with scams, fraud, and other illicit activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf359d7f2ce9248faa59e72f2faaf4689"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Enhanced asset recovery mechanisms</header><text>The Task Force shall work with permitted payment stablecoin issuers to ensure that the permitted payment stablecoin issuers maintain and use technical capabilities to freeze, seize, burn, or reissue digital assets determined to be proceeds of scams or other unlawful conduct, consistent with applicable law and due process protections.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idae5a7ade722f4e5fbc4f531f44d17c02"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Task Force shall meet not less than 3 times during the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, and thereafter at such times and places, and by such means, as the Chair of the Task Force determines to be appropriate, which may include the use of remote conference technology.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5705582968594b2c9c1efbeaf6b173f5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Task Force shall include—</text><paragraph id="id684499c4b97e405c81cd87e0f6854eda"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluating opportunities to use data collected by the Internet Crime Complaint Center database of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the fraud reporting database of the Federal Trade Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1c216d1f2394c58a3c1942bf7aaa1a7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluating best practices for combating methods (such as financial grooming scams, Ponzi schemes, money laundering, organized crime schemes, fraudulent Initial Coin Offerings, and rug pulls) used by scammers, including means of identifying, communicating with, and exploiting victims;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id013ddc029fca4354bd5d57465f6bdea0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assessing how international jurisdictions have tried to prevent scams involving digital assets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe365710772e4e02bed9860635173f34"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifying and reviewing current methods used to scam individuals, including users and consumers, using digital asset intermediaries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ab60a96434e4dfb946e6cce70f0d4dc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>determining a strategy for education programs that better equip individuals, including consumers, to identify, avoid, and report digital asset scam attempts to the appropriate law enforcement or government authorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f143315c22f49f9a3198011d8d96456"><enum>(6)</enum><text>coordinating efforts to ensure perpetrators of scams involving digital assets can be identified and pursued by law enforcement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idce9e42417fd740549ffab68d1abe8b68"><enum>(7)</enum><text>consulting with other relevant stakeholders, including State, local, and Tribal agencies and financial services providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id130f76b3592042d4b3a522baf437a5d1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>determining whether any additional Federal legislation and full-time equivalents would be beneficial for law enforcement and industry in mitigating scams involving digital assets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4de2c683bd54e4a8b88751188d12450"><enum>(9)</enum><text>working with international governments and law enforcement agencies to combat digital asset scams, including by targeting the organized crime networks perpetrating scams, originating abroad.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idae7fb0e174764ceba0a38aeb75a4115b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Each member of the Task Force shall serve without compensation, other than compensation to which entitled as an employee of the United States, as the case may be.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8ebd08fff0db46748b02903396dd2a41"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1bb26f1f8ea54614bf4b244bdcaafc2e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary establishes the Task Force, the Task Force shall submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives</committee-name> and make publicly available online a report detailing—</text><subparagraph id="id1ef2a53d77ec4d418309e4a72ad6d591"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the reviews and evaluations of the Task Force under subsection (e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48b7a9f28cfb4ad49d697620befc7b5c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the strategy identified under subsection (e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd65e41b0d93941959aab0c1a65d3d8c3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any legislative, regulatory, or personnel recommendations that would enhance the ability to detect and prevent scams involving digital assets described in subsection (e); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idadfd988c1d8b4a90aa75f1e78b1e2925"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations to enhance cooperation among Federal, State, local, and Tribal authorities in the investigation and prosecution of scams and other financial crimes, including harmonizing data collection, improving data sharing processes, improving reporting mechanisms and streams, estimating the number of complaints and consumers affected, and evaluating the effectiveness of anti-scam training programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida609751788794b839369b125fc1d0eaa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual updates</header><text>After submitting an initial report required under paragraph (1), the Task Force shall, on an annual basis, submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives</committee-name> and make publicly available online an updated version of the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id48340cc3d50b4bd3a7df2a035bcbcd44"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/4">Chapter 4</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Task Force.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4805e4298dd64eae86dba1079715f9e5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Task Force shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Task Force submits the report required under subsection (g)(1).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

