<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24F6A7B23DC1426F89D6E824423C2973" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9712 IH: Mamas First Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9712</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide coverage under the Medicaid program for services provided by doulas, midwives, and lactation support providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H08B3DB25750C48379227E7B5476FB75B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H764759FA33AC46B291A60F708D3D92BB"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mamas First Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HECDC3E32B02F40C28CA6B723EF7C7CA8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H038F3A3A7B88402E84006D4E34A7FDE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the maternal mortality rate varies drastically for women by race and ethnicity. On average, there are 13.6 deaths per 100,000 live births for White women, 45 deaths per 100,000 live births for Black women, and 13.9 deaths per 100,000 live births for Hispanic women. For American Indian and Alaskan Native women, the National Council of Urban Indian Health estimates there are 54.6 deaths per 100,000 live births. While maternal mortality most disparately impacts Black women and Indigenous women, this urgent public health crisis traverses race, ethnicity, socioeconomic status, educational background, and geography.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F22106E83364E4F872C240643163D73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States maternal mortality rates are the highest among similarly economically situated countries and continue to increase.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23BA7A5C258545C786D0BC866E25E324"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Four out of 5 of these maternal deaths are likely preventable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEFF5DA2257543F892F184A95F54E36A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the National Institutes of Health, individuals who have doula support during their pregnancy are 4 times less likely to have a low-birth-weight baby, 2 times less likely to experience a birth complication involving themselves or their baby, and significantly more likely to initiate breastfeeding.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H075118084AFF438BBBAA547563737342"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Midwifery-led care is associated with cost savings, decreased rates of intervention, lower rates of cesarean birth, lower preterm birth rates, and healthier outcomes for mothers and babies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7600C741B07E486B8DE88739BA853B89"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Midwives may practice in any setting, including the home, community, hospitals, birth centers, clinics, or health units.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H86445216C50D43F0A586863A6358409E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Medicaid coverage of services provided by doulas, midwives, and lactation support providers</header> 
<subsection id="H743BB17E72DF4287A7454784F5EFEE43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4471DB74CEC34BDA8350F99C62A4205E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEAE1A222ADB6460AA8D9EC0F9E578BB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (31), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC205707057FF42C3B1C26B654D9F2286"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (32) as paragraph (33); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7A1EFE340404B0A824D763E1C6AA2BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (31) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB2AD50A25F0641D9A74C791A6E88B3E8"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD2FEBD460FEC43F9A60470CD5959EB92"><enum>(32)</enum><text>services and care, including prenatal, labor, and postpartum care, that is provided in a culturally congruent manner by doulas, midwives, tribal midwives, and lactation support providers (as those terms are defined in subsection (ll)), that is provided in the home, community, a hospital, birth center, clinic, or health unit, or is furnished via telehealth to the extent authorized under State law; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3680E84AA144E028E79BC3C9B08A738"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6435470F11124684B5B4BA0E9433D882"> <subsection id="H1A6E581BD2F64420B78B153C8F5BA468"><enum>(ll)</enum><header>Doulas, midwives, tribal midwives, and lactation support providers defined</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(32):</text> 
<paragraph id="HAC960EC8F5D047F0A5D14F9D005EDB6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Doula defined</header><text>The term <quote>doula</quote> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H032E02AF785C46F2853CE176D5E6ABBD"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB5EEBF27BDFF4B1FADA3CE498B9D9B0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is certified by an organization which requires the completion of continuing education to maintain such certification, to provide non-medical advice, information, emotional support, and physical comfort to an individual during such individual’s pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum period; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3D485F7A12C749C8949B948241E401A0" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintains such certification by completing such required continuing education;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H373C789C203B48BC81BD8A86B7242FDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">can provide a recommendation from at least—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD962A3118AB4941A15917BA6113CE9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">three different former clients for whom the prospective doula provided doula services (either paid or volunteer) within the last 5 years; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F4208A0980045FF8522F140A7CF7A47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>two different licensed health care providers (including physicians, midwives, social workers, or nurses) who observed the prospective doula providing doula services within the last 5 years; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF2A131053AF341C393172C6E37B92B32"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is authorized to serve as a Medicaid provider of doula services under the State plan under this title (or a waiver of such plan) of the individual's State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A27F1CCAAC94224A468DE472877C49A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Midwife defined</header><text>The term <term>midwife</term> means a midwife who—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC9E2946A7D24C7885CFB3C27F17A4D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is authorized to serve as a Medicaid provider of midwife services under the State plan under this title (or a waiver of such plan) of the individual's State; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9A9996A83784EA789C4E2D6C9F57697"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets at a minimum the international definition of the midwife and global standards for midwifery education as established by the International Confederation of Midwives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD38ECFBF115E432DA785B9E9D2DFB1EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal midwife defined</header><text>The term <term>tribal midwife</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H578793921F5A4E3AA1D8C06E0CA04D75"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is authorized to serve as a Medicaid provider of tribal midwife services under the State plan under this title (or a waiver of such plan) of the individual's State; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBC2CBD0039D490BBCCEEFB43F5343BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is recognized by an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>)) to practice midwifery for such tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAA26F1E8DB14D4FA42BC4CEFD08397D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Lactation support provider defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lactation support provider</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74CFD7DA0CDC44B588732E977748F3E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is authorized to serve as a Medicaid provider of lactation support services under the State plan under this title (or a waiver of such plan) of the individual's State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81BBEE1799B84CECAF4B4A1B69B5B390"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has completed at least 20 hours of foundational training based on the World Health Organization/United Nations Children's Fund lactation counseling training blueprint, or an equivalent training; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB264507413344720B1825D52E35D23ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is recognized within any category on the Lactation Support Provider Descriptor chart published by the U.S. Breastfeeding Committee-affiliated Lactation Support Provider Constellation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H298474F8733746C2965E24446B56219D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requiring mandatory coverage under State plan</header><text>Section 1902(a)(10)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>and (30)</quote> and inserting <quote>(30), and (32)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB85AF5CDCCC54773862E536C438EB39E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost sharing prohibition</header><text>Title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95F34402A9174EEE9C35753251576757"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsections (a)(2)(B) and (b)(2)(B) of section 1916 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o">42 U.S.C. 1396o(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>, (b)(2)(B)), by inserting after the comma at the end <quote>and services and care (including prenatal, labor, and postpartum care) provided by a doula, midwife, tribal midwife, or lactation support provider (as those terms are defined in section 1905(ll)),</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H162A174FD9184DF88779B5DE46BA8642" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1916A(b)(3)(B)(iii) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o-1">42 U.S.C. 1396o–1(b)(3)(B)(iii)</external-xref>), by inserting before the period at the end <quote>, and services and care (including prenatal, labor, and postpartum care) provided by a doula, midwife, tribal midwife, or lactation support provider (as those terms are defined in section 1905(ll))</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBF62FD557D5A42E4AE25A2676A5ADB51"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="HFA422B005AC446F6A21DE34BFD5BD31F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to medical assistance furnished on or after January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63E4C807513F43FB88B725EAA3808CF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for State legislation</header><text>In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the respective plan to meet any requirement imposed by amendments made by this section, the respective plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet such an additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

