<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF312E61682324611BB33AC1B5701D537" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6897 IH: Thyroid Disease Coverage, Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6897</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance research, promote awareness and education, and improve health care, with respect to thyroid disease, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D8D731591414AA5AF0C33E79B5522C6" style="OLC"><section id="HBF88FFD195DD432B8D57445C97754879" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Thyroid Disease Coverage, Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Thyroid Disease CARE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H592D26FCD1A54162869FFF7811212110"><enum>2.</enum><header>Thyroid disease research</header><subsection id="H3320D7903A3849A885899865D2F76825"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, shall—</text><paragraph id="H35AE565466D34184BE9F4F13DB048D3A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct or support research and related activities regarding thyroid disease, including research—</text><subparagraph id="HD6160B2285994CE18B8F27172E9735A0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to investigate the root causes of thyroid disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H297977227DA54A1D93B5988C9E38618D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve diagnostic techniques and develop improved treatments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC652BEDF78904E31A4E01738901F7EE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve thyroid cancer-related care, including the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of thyroid nodules and thyroid cancer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3991C3D7B78E45BD8E192AA65AFC26FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to enhance the quality of thyroid cancer survivorship, including understanding how a thyroid cancer diagnosis impacts women of reproductive years and beyond;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93EAB8E963A04DAD94035C1E049BFE49"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to understand the symptoms of patients treated for thyroid disease and to design studies to improve symptom management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H221D962E395F401482681B03B1343F81"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assess—</text><clause id="H21DC108F4D8C452EB7F01FF9DA026CF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>thyroid disease prevalence, detection, treatment, and outcome disparties by race, ethnicity, geography, primary language, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability status, and insurance status, and related topics as determined by the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="H0B462ABE79E74F449B1056345EE0367F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to thyroid cancer patients, such disparities relating to primary tumor site, tumor morphology, stage at diagnosis, and first course of treatment; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A9997C054AB480EBDCC962E8C4E216C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to study the effects of thyroid disease, including subclinical hypothyroidism, in patients who continue to experience symptoms despite their test results becoming normal; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9724F11677444BD8A5A9831873E01B53" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>propose recommendations on how to address research gaps relating to disparities referred to in paragraph (1)(F).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H194049B8AC434D36823CB00958A2FD6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H163CEE05963749F58937E10E862E5242"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, transmit an interim report on the status and results of the research and related activities under this section to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF06374310C2C4185B8DC44CA6A020303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such report publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00F882E5138E4939ADCF885315917604"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC7754D251B054F5CA1F2057C536659F3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Analyzing research gaps and disproportionate impacts with respect to thyroid disease</header><subsection id="HF209BE68ACF34C6182A0A5C2FEC592FA" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HF330E1C1DCB84EF2BA8A30C45E9A2DDF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify and analyze gaps in research on diagnosing and treating thyroid disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55A594F603C84FAE8CF6065A812292D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyze—</text><subparagraph id="H78E2C0A502444537B02E0864CC0B33E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the disproportionate impacts of thyroid disease on specific populations, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, geography, primary language, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability status, and insurance status, with a particular focus on such disproportionate impacts on women;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD38170C320F54B0A9F03D077EEB12FC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasons for the disproportionate impacts referred to in subparagraph (A) in such specific populations, including with respect to disproportionate access to specialized care; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8C6FF1B660B45DD9C09754B39CC98EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the level of knowledge of health care professionals about such disproportionate impacts; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA02A6D68DC642DD8CD8B8085E54DFA2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze, and formulate recommendations with respect to, better options for—</text><subparagraph id="H0E42FD48CE344B7C8F7E20B965165904" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>diagnosing and treating thyroid disease in such populations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB2027577ECC43AAA6D083E1A7F00184" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>paying for such diagnosis and treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90E546414F714CE79D80C35107DC249A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Topics</header><text>In carrying out the analysis under subsection (a), the Secretary may assess—</text><paragraph id="H356801BD36AB419DAB8225704B81E8DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data from the Transformed Medicaid Statistical Information System related to services furnished to individuals diagnosed with thyroid disease for the treatment of thyroid disease symptoms under State Medicaid programs and State children’s health insurance programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AB05E1654FC4DCDACE9B361B0934513"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data collected through the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) program of the National Cancer Institute;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B6609886A294B0B9E987E198D78B6E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>data collected through the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1E47BEF147C43938461E6275F80AB05"><enum>(4)</enum><text>data related to services furnished to individuals diagnosed with thyroid disease for the treatment of thyroid disease symptoms under group health plans or group or individual health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8C90B10D1084C91831EB4D0967F7C71"><enum>(5)</enum><text>data from nationally representative sample surveys (such as the National Health Interview Survey of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (or any successor survey)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F176FB6E9494327929E5529430F4B6F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other data as the Secretary determines relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H969AF8B2D88D4E67925F24B170AF95FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>To carry out the analysis under subsection (a), the Secretary may request—</text><paragraph id="HA6A615248F00463FBFA34F734BA135A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>group health plans (as defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)), health insurance issuers offering group or individual health insurance coverage (as so defined), and health benefits plans offered under the Federal Employee Health Benefits Program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to provide such information as may be required to assess barriers that individuals diagnosed with thyroid disease face in accessing treatments for thyroid disease symptoms, including a lack of insurance coverage and cost-sharing requirements for such treatments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB99D66C24244DC7A041CD64430AE737"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State Medicaid programs and State children’s health insurance programs to collect and report, through the Transformed Medicaid Statistical Information System, data related to services furnished to individuals diagnosed with thyroid disease for the treatment of thyroid disease symptoms, including data stratified by relevant demographic characteristics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E6E62B6F1994E47B250F14FB899A233"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header><text>In carrying out the analysis under subsection (a), including making requests under subsection (c), and in submitting the report under subsection (e), the Secretary shall ensure that the privacy and confidentiality of individual patients are protected in a manner consistent with relevant privacy and confidentiality laws.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEADDD1ED77DD4C51BB3E2911211A5C7C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H639FFC10D8D24B31BF135FA41E5CF60D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services a preliminary report on the analysis carried out under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F5732DDBC334FF98BF31C412AC00BBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than the end of fiscal year 2030, submit to Congress and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services a final report on such analysis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB27580D954CA475C840A55E19F9E88F8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE700200EC9AC4B3B91A01D83B67AC7E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public awareness campaign with respect to thyroid disease</header><subsection id="H63E8E6652128431BAFA461DBCDAB1AB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a public awareness campaign regarding thyroid disease, including by developing and disseminating information on—</text><paragraph id="HBF728EB31590449A8FD49DF7516ED815"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the awareness, incidence, and prevalence of thyroid disease and associated impacts, with a particular focus on the disparities and disproportionate impacts described in sections 2(a)(1)(F) and 3(a)(2), especially on women;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8261E0327B1E498E9879ED3513FEB8F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the availability, as medically appropriate, of the range of treatment options for symptoms of thyroid disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EF1D70BAFE048F2B0FF9F7A4F6FD54E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how patients can better recognize the signs and symptoms of thyroid disease; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8A184A6D2B24A63BBC0BAD34147DE42"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether there are benefits of routine screening, especially during pregnancy and reproductive stages.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A1B638FEC7A4010BD464F656F33CBF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information to health care providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the public awareness campaign under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with relevant health care professional societies and associations, shall disseminate information to health care professionals, health care-related organizations, and health systems to promote evidence-based care for individuals with thyroid disease, including information related to—</text><paragraph id="H5614D5FEF33C4749BBC0F6D9D7E73879"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detecting and diagnosing thyroid disease with an emphasis on better addressing thyroid disease in populations at increased risk for the disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5029BC3882C4A919CEEAE7802ACC28A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing care for individuals with thyroid disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57BC4074F5594E6C8C20E98FE0577A92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>communicating with patients about thyroid disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA660BCC6AEDD4E98A9D3F15098EB3118"><enum>(4)</enum><text>enhancing the prevention of implicit bias in the provision of care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0485E4019EB4B9F96DB11D31EA8D098"><enum>(5)</enum><text>related topics, including research on the reasons why thyroid disease occurs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13A20B7B2B5B4F0C984C31BB2B0044A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><text>The Secretary may disseminate information under subsection (a) directly or through arrangements with intra-agency initiatives, nonprofit organizations, consumer groups, institutions of higher education, or Federal, State, or local public-private partnerships.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE30B183CA33444DB87BCC3BDD8534444"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3B54DE1D202B42E48DAE0C052669D482"><enum>5.</enum><header>Collaboration with relevant professional societies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this Act, the Secretary shall collaborate with—</text><paragraph id="H5106883E56FA4991B717EB161A8B3A76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relevant professional societies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92F11BAED4A2475CB61B6AB736C0984C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant agencies of the Department of Health and Human Services, including the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0423D3C10C614905A30BB8BE5705A92F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H710073133C8847198856BFAE52A79B80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A23E4211AB4434B85AD4DD74588E2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Racial and ethnic minority group</header><text>The term <term>racial and ethnic minority group</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1707(g) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1945E59648EF48A2BB1412CEC0D99059"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD93F138871BC4EFD9B397F674D61DDF2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Thyroid disease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>thyroid disease</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H34C8A4BBB3F346579EDF5FE7FDBEB79B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disorders and abnormalities of thyroid gland function; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68A8A475490C47C89FC817F2739ADE73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>abnormalities of thyroid structure, including thyroid nodules and thyroid cancer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

