<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H56F80877ECAB407893F1CB1772133644" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 933 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the critical role of victim service providers in the response to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, by supporting victims through the physical, mental, emotional, financial, and legal challenges they may face in the aftermath of violence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 933</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251205">December 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the critical role of victim service providers in the response to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, by supporting victims through the physical, mental, emotional, financial, and legal challenges they may face in the aftermath of violence.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, section 40002(a)(43) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(a)(43)</external-xref>), defines the term <quote>victim service provider</quote> to mean a nonprofit, nongovernmental, or Tribal organization or rape crisis center, including a State or Tribal coalition, that assists or advocates for domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking victims, including domestic violence shelters, faith-based organizations, and other organizations, with a documented history of effective work concerning domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers are often the first people a victim may come in contact with when they reach out for help after experiencing trauma;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers are trained to provide trauma-informed care that meets the unique needs of victims;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers help connect victims and survivors to community-based organizations and services including legal guidance, counseling, housing assistance, mental health support, and immediate and long-term medical care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers help victims navigate the complexities of—</text><paragraph id="HE1D3837549B249568EC65CFD08D23C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the criminal justice system, including seeking protection orders or restraining orders, family matters such as divorce, child custody or child support, administrative agency proceedings, and consumer or housing matters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56606EB942634CC0B98B02AFFB01C286"><enum>(2)</enum><text>criminal justice investigations, including prosecutions of the offender, and post-conviction matters that impact victims’ safety, privacy, or other interests as a victim;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A3F9900A7F418085B924459FB4A7F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>alternative dispute resolution or other processes that promote victim safety, privacy, and autonomy, and offender accountability; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H951244F2483142E68AF0753142723C30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>post-conviction relief proceedings in State, local, Tribal, or territorial court;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers coordinate and collaborate with the law enforcement, health care providers, schools, and community-based organizations to provide comprehensive support to survivors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers need sustainable and proper funding to deliver consistent, quality, and often lifesaving care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers help victims create safety plans that establish comprehensive and achievable assessments to reduce the risk of further harm;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers are crucial to ensuring that victims get the help, support, and justice they deserve;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers have been historically underfunded and under resourced, which in turn impacts the quantity and quality of services they can provide; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victim service providers are put in positions to do critical, often lifesaving work, without adequate resources: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H671F11C615034BA8B442D5359369C02E"><section id="H21FEF4049E9B4E63A9DE122E7DB7CFEA" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H1F8CDBA7D0E84F3EA508A6E301A1E1A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deeply values and supports the essential work of victim service providers in helping victims and survivors heal mentally, physically, and emotionally from trauma; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF45BDA0C925B4E90B3674EB7FE612665"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the need to meaningfully invest in the work of victim service providers.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

