<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BDF78A929AF4E01B73D43B08B82FDF4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8534 IH: Small Business Territories Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8534</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to establish an Office of Territorial Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1B65D8C019D9484F9730FD06B9917459" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H35C3D58624A048FDABE59396CFEAFC6F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Territories Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0ACB828AB31D4EBB908D2D0CDC3F80E4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of territorial affairs of the Small Business Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4B598B8A74164A84907ADDA345A5F2F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>redesignating section 49 as section 50; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FDF90C051044A2BBC63144F867DCFA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>inserting after section 48 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H148378E7E8FE44498757C131320930A3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HB5E6ECDD47A14C53A7CD1F1493B3C1DF"><enum>49.</enum><header>Office of Territorial Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HBFE03590A41E4064B0846149590D6420"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Administration an Office of Territorial Affairs (hereafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>), which shall establish a working relationship with small business concerns in the United States territories by targeting programs of the Administration relating to entrepreneurial development, contracting, disaster assistance, and capital access.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBB1BFB6325414E859E7A475C9023CCEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistant administrator</header> <paragraph id="H1AF1CAD1ABBA414B9F9CE33F06A26BE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be administered by an Assistant Administrator who shall be an employee in the competitive service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5081497572A844E58A5EB57A2E72EF99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The Assistant Administrator shall have—</text> <subparagraph id="H74D443E1AAFD4558B829B3C1A3D178AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>knowledge of the governmental affairs, socioeconomic conditions, and political relationships of the territories; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D27AA1C03FD424CA0940012FE6ACE81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experience providing tailored small business development assistance to small business concerns located in the territories.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41FDFFC3B59A4A39857B65503DD5779A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Assistant Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF4E6317C1DBF4096829618FDAB1E4065" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>formulate policies, and promote policies and existing programs, to better address entrepreneurial development, capital access, disaster assistance, and contracting needs of small business concerns located in the territories;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CF14A84B345496F919958AD548C4032"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve as a liaison between small business concerns located in the territories and the Administration, resource partners, lenders, Federal and State agencies, and other interested persons;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE59556AC80AF4910B9F742DEE7177077"><enum>(C)</enum><text>periodically review and assess programs administered by and services from the Administration that are available to small business concerns located in the territories to ensure that—</text> <clause id="H0010889C6E114E16A6F615BE2501872C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the services offered under a lending program, entrepreneurial development program, or disaster assistance program administered by the Administration are adequate to address the challenges such small business concerns face; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H53BACB67395248179F289378187058BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such small business concerns have adequate access to contracting opportunities with the Federal Government and procurement programs administered by the Administration; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84F7B96B951C4B1EBFDAA720283E640A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>host webinars and outreach events in the territories. as appropriate, including inviting representatives from district offices of the Administration, resource partners, Federal and State agencies, and other interested people to participate in such webinars and outreach events.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF7323D30050C46AB88E05A10E16B0849"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Assistant Administrator shall submit to the Committee of Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report on the activities of the Office during the one year period preceding the date of submission of the report, including—</text> <paragraph id="H94801A1D5D284D40942D1D9F4D9DC344"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operational details of the activities of the Office;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FBDE00462DD424398FB32A40121A66E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of the activities conducted by the Office;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83FA900DB42A4FB29E8E0F18FC8596A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total number of small business concerns assisted by the Office, disaggregated by the type of assistance provided by the Office and by territory;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28B07947DF904658A682B9C18A1FB859"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, the total number of new businesses established as a result of assistance from the Office, disaggregated by territory; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7646AA763CDC4329947D5FA5282DBCC3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommendations to help improve assistance provided by the Administration in serving the needs of small business concerns located in the territories.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC722D3B39C542CB98D4BBAEB35CD1A3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HA608DD6C5E8C4C939AAAB09161DE4548"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant administrator</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Administrator</term> means the Assistant Administrator of the Office of Territorial Affairs appointed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08FCECEA95F943A1870AFCA2EFBBF817"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resource partner</header><text>The term <term>resource partner</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H898001AC63624244A685EA09155FE886"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a small business development center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55DE8F4F058649CEB6AC3A2E18878013"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a women’s business center described in section 29;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1601A0E6AA24CF3B3F3341BB29A7AD1"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>a chapter of the Service Corps of Retired Executives authorized by section 8(b)(1); and</text>
                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBCF76AD7BD14C92B04CB0FA81936CB9">
                                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>a Veteran Business Outreach Center described in section 32.</text>
                                </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81DE78A6106E435D82733B2CD2C7C98B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Territories</header><text>The term <term>territories</term> means Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

