<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB6336FC5FEE4B43AB16556BF10E1591" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9392 IH: Medicare Advantage Cost Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9392</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require the inclusion of certain information in Medicare Advantage encounter data.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCD009D2EE82B4CD8ACD26044CFC9F527" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF2FAE8A8475A408BAC210E6ECBE52D0C" commented="no" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Advantage Cost Transparency Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H9691F867EBEC452C8FA6632009EE3956"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring the inclusion of certain information in encounter data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1859 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H287E39E6A3EF4F23832754EA04BB5C9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HEF4A37C25C134474AD945DCC3CAE754E" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain information in encounter data</header> 
<paragraph id="H72787602B7974831B66EBD32D96A072F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any encounter data submitted by a Medicare Advantage plan with respect to an item or service furnished to an individual under such plan during a plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall require that such data include—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B4E1A1A54D34EF5ADC40A0C505A0B30" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the allowed amount for such item or service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC67B61D2752446A48DC5E68E855BB860" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of cost sharing (including deductibles, copayments, and coinsurance) imposed for such item or service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3736E6E8A38440D695BA078BCDDA55DD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case such individual was furnished, during such plan year before such item or service was so furnished, an at-home health risk assessment from a specified assessment entity, an indicator that such individual was so furnished such an assessment by such an entity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DFD8A026F67475BBF0E03DB11C174CD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case such individual was furnished, during such plan year before such item or service was so furnished, an at-home health risk assessment from an assessment entity not described in subparagraph (C), an indicator (distinct from the indicator described in such subparagraph) that such individual was so furnished such an assessment by such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E981E4E82054978A8DC7D8FE78CF575" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE75CBB6FD5FE4CE892DEBC96AC33D121"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assessment entity</header><text>The term <term>assessment entity</term> means an entity with a focus on furnishing in-home health risk assessments, as specified by the Secretary. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB330D6535C241B2B5744E13874376B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified assessment entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specified assessment entity</term> means, with respect to an MA organization and a plan year, an assessment entity with respect to which such organization (or any person with an ownership or control interest (as defined in section 1124(a)(3)) in such organization) is a person with an ownership or control interest (as so defined).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

