<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H325DE4BBE7584D96A4D104FCA797C485" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8454 IH: To provide for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over certain Federal land in the State of California, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over certain Federal land in the State of California, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H203CB28503E14E23AB2D98F5E801BB4D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H2469C813195D435682C9EC5B8B592593"><enum>1.</enum><header>Transfer of administrative jurisdiction over certain Federal land in the State of California</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34699A826545465994361F201DB78735"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transfer of administrative jurisdiction</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2C0508478AD6489B9BF3DA1A6E90A341"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National forest system land</header><text>Administrative jurisdiction over the approximately 160 acres of National Forest System land more particularly described as T.1 S., R.19 E., sec. 24, SE<fraction>1/4</fraction>NE<fraction>1/4</fraction>, NW<fraction>1/4</fraction>SE<fraction>1/4</fraction>, NE<fraction>1/4</fraction>SE<fraction>1/4</fraction>, and SE<fraction>1/4</fraction>SE<fraction>1/4</fraction>, Mount Diablo Meridian, Tuolumne County, California, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Ackerson Meadow Land Interchange</quote> and dated February 24, 2022, is transferred to the Secretary of the Interior to be managed as part of Yosemite National Park, in accordance with laws applicable to the National Park System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD557248F9503406F808501F0919BCC53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National park system land</header><text>Administrative jurisdiction over the approximately 170 acres of National Park System land more particularly described as the SE<fraction>1/4</fraction> of sec. 23 and the land to the north and west of Road 1S25 within the NW<fraction>1/4</fraction>SE<fraction>1/4</fraction>NW<fraction>1/4</fraction> of sec. 24, T.1 S., R. 19 E., Mount Diablo Meridian, Tuolumne County, California, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Ackerson Meadow Land Interchange</quote> and dated February 24, 2022, is transferred to the Secretary of Agriculture to be managed as part of Stanislaus National Forest in accordance with laws applicable to the National Forest System.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H555433D9D6DF42989B6957813D73829B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Corrections</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD8A7F00B108D455EBCC86CDF5A4E5BA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minor adjustments</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior may, by mutual agreement, make minor corrections and adjustments to the Federal land transferred under subsection (a) to facilitate land management, including making a correction or adjustment to any applicable survey.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H52B3BE6468D745A19ED724232D7A5923"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publications</header><text>Any correction or adjustment made under paragraph (1) shall be effective on the date of publication of a notice of the correction or adjustment in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H98120EAD765E47159010C80203EFA20D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hazardous substances</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6053BDF2B1B140AA8AEDF3CDCC0D997D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall, with respect to the land described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), respectively—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3FBC8B0F5D6437FB51059B0DF6DBAE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify any known sites containing hazardous substances; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H30EF888744C745C4A63E1D707888C412"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide to the head of the Federal agency to which the land is being transferred under subsection (a) notice of any site containing hazardous substances, as identified under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HC3A7EF3A48AD4C04B232F69DD2654587"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cleanup obligations</header><text>To the same extent as on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, with respect to any Federal liability—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H82C6B4EDFD3E44D891E45E9A21C84F3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture shall remain responsible for any cleanup of hazardous substances on the Federal land described in subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3300FAAF287547CFB006887F09D0349D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior shall remain responsible for any cleanup of hazardous substances on the Federal land described in subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H3D9187D11BA5446FB520BA3D0C65B924"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect on existing rights and authorizations</header><text>Nothing in this section affects—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H36445706628145799107A98D489D8F4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any valid existing rights; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5E6A4C04156418D91CF801B1F7886D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the validity or terms and conditions of any existing withdrawal, right-of-way, easement, lease, license, or permit on the land to which administrative jurisdiction is transferred under this section, except that beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the head of the agency to which administrative jurisdiction over the land is transferred shall be responsible for administering the interests or authorizations in accordance with applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

