<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26A59-465-H3-585"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4966 IS: High Court Gift Ban Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4966</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit Federal judges from receiving certain gifts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HAFC8A3708BA04048AA51F317144DA3F6"><section section-type="section-one" id="H00FEB066C0B84191A8B2A143761B8159"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>High Court Gift Ban Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H866F26CEA8904B1FAB8CF5716C823964"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on gifts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80f7e92cd6944c118df3b70480e408db"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="USC" id="HFAEA946A21C1455B80675ADA3BF7AFE0">
                    <section id="H5D6D46F2CAB74F85A044245B355BE5EA">
                        <enum>7354.</enum>
                        <header>Gifts to Federal judges</header>
                        <subsection id="H85F30EE3DF474B5D8C39C34D17E60AC0">
                            <enum>(a)</enum>
                            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H064C58810AF7425EAF1DB9F90BABDF6A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Gift</header> <text>The term <term>gift</term> means any gratuity, favor, discount, entertainment, hospitality, loan, forbearance, or other item having monetary value (including services, transportation, local travel, lodgings, and meals) whether provided in-kind, by purchase of a ticket, payment in advance, or reimbursement after the expense has been incurred.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" id="H398ACF8B05294B52B40D936C764597E8">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Judicial officer; relative</header>
 <text>The terms <term>judicial officer</term> and <term>relative</term> have the meanings given the term in section 13101.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" id="HFE3385D675474A30A25AE42261A72CA0">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
                                <header>Personal hospitality from an individual</header>
 <text>The term <term>personal hospitality from an individual</term> means hospitality extended—</text>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B112F1B2AD744EF8A9A911684F4E672">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>by an individual for a nonbusiness purpose;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB1F66FDB8739425E8A3D16A5C00B774E"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>at the personal residence, property, or facilities owned by the individual or the family of the individual;</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" id="H070A6F4D90BE40B59FEC6A86115DE5A0">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>without payment or reimbursement from any other person (except the judicial officer or a relative of the judicial officer) for such hospitality; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9929DD7A64B542979ADF4B89A3A49BEF">
                                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with the individual or the family of the individual present on the property at the time in which a judicial officer is being hosted.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" id="H0AFAFA5A87A44693A13D96F3640784C2">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
                                <header>Prohibited source</header>
 <text>The term <term>prohibited source</term> means any person—</text>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" id="H456410FD184849F0B5BA1EC08E38A9F2">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>who has, or is likely to, come before the judicial officer; or</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF2972DEE8FBF497EB779EF596696C729">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>whose interests have, or are likely to, come before the judicial officer.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef895863adf94313b03b4e364585d8e3">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition</header>
                            <paragraph id="HC7F8292BEB66430694F5E1C9E3327FC5">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>A judicial officer may not accept a gift from any source unless—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="HDDBB8DF819194DDAB8B4D6198AAB8A5B">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the judicial officer reasonably and in good faith believes the gift has a value of less than $50; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H42D3133E605C44E790BB7AC1C89ED76E">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the aggregate value of gifts the judicial officer has received from the source in that calendar year is $100 or less, including the value of the gift.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HC73843A1EE1541AB9334DCA4A80B9324">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Exceptions</header>
 <text>The prohibition under paragraph (1) does not apply to any of the following circumstances:</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H417FAD35ED2D452BB0EB053A8AC8EAC0">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Anything for which the judicial officer pays the fair market value.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H47DE7CF91B3F4BAC9EC56D2EB426FDC1">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Anything for which the judicial officer does not use and promptly returns to the person who provided the gift to the judicial officer.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H04FE1D7CC06043E5A7A593AA72779A93">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>A gift from a relative.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23F24E558B884E3AB117F3639D8676E4"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>A gift from another judicial officer.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HE09884D1824A4ED5986563B9D5F10B83">
                                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Honorary degrees (and associated travel, food, refreshments, and entertainment) and other bona fide, nonmonetary awards presented in recognition of public service (and associated food, refreshments, and entertainment provided in the presentation of such degrees and awards) paid for by an educational institution if the educational institution pays for, or sponsors, the award and invites the judicial officer.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H6FECC715F1C74152A1AFE935BFE36229">
                                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>Opportunities and benefits that are—</text> <clause id="H3628CF0632A645B8886241EE3E8894B5"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">available to the public or to a class consisting of all employees;</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause commented="no" id="HC63FBC38ADF44D2987A0A2182EBBD307">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>offered to members of a group or class for which membership in such group or class is unrelated to service as a judicial officer;</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H4B76FCF4B8DF43D390CA798B350E74CD">
                                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>offered to members of an organization open to all judicial officers;</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H0150C400338C45B4B50938B28532D9F8">
                                        <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>in the form of loans from banks and other financial institutions on terms generally available to the public; or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="HD411CE07CB13492CBFF6816B4CA94434">
                                        <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>in the form of a reduction in membership fees or fees for participation in activities of an organization if such reduction is offered to all employees and the organization is a professional organization in which its membership is solely contingent on professional qualifications of the prospective member.</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H7A25139FC2B8403D9EC5C281E9149630">
                                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>Reimbursement for reasonable expenses for transportation, food, lodging, and entertainment at a seminar or event relating to the law, the legal system, or the administration of justice if—</text>
                                    <clause id="H3859E66943C542B88D847FC49AFF0375">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the judicial officer was not invited to the seminar or event by a prohibited source;</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H6BCEF95A1F0441118FA1AC287FC98BFD">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the seminar or event is not organized, paid for, or sponsored by a prohibited source; and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause commented="no" id="H4CBFA58620424701B85A66A960D7E957">
                                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the total amount of reimbursement for the seminar or event is—</text>
                                        <subclause commented="no" id="H65B5D94A1075461F9E42653F22441B54">
                                            <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>$2,000 or less; or</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H904C8DD6B2474E3EA151440B4FF02E08"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>greater than $2,000 if such judicial officer received a written waiver from—</text>
                                            <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0532471d39cc4663b3b1f68ae8731554">
                                                <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a justice of the Supreme Court of the United States, the Chief Justice of the United States; and</text>
                                            </item>
                                            <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc42a0d758a34444e8a2143f9f54a6cc5">
                                                <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a judge, the chief judge of the circuit or district of the judge.</text>
                                            </item>
                                        </subclause>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H3FCFDC8AA11C47F2BC4A3CAC141677F5">
                                    <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>Personal hospitality from an individual, who is not a prohibited source, in an amount that does not exceed the dollar amount established under paragraph (1) of section 2503(b)(as adjusted under paragraph (2) of such section) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/2503">26 U.S.C. 2503(b)</external-xref>) with respect to such calendar year.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HC826B154E93B45B8B4A4DE76454B25BC">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
                                <header>Gifts to relatives</header>
 <text>A gift to a relative of the judicial officer shall be considered a gift to the judicial officer if—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H7DB3A285FEA1420E964206E04DF3369D">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>it is given with the knowledge and acquiescence of the judicial officer; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HA27461AB66B24285B5A0B20F9576B87B">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the judicial officer has reason to believe the gift was given because of the official position of the judicial officer.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection id="HE9C7B70A081548A79D4845ADAAA6A469">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Enforcement</header>
                            <paragraph id="H4A48067090704F2BAF979DD1684DDAF7">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
                                <header>Referral</header>
                                <subparagraph id="HF3D5C4167ED2459D95251B18DFBA5C9E">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                                    <header>Attorney General</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Judicial Conference of the United States, or any official designated by the Supreme Court of the United States or Congress to assist the justices of the Supreme Court in maintaining compliance with the Code of Conduct for Justices of the Supreme Court of the United States issued by the Court on November 13, 2023, or any successor rules or regulations governing ethical or conduct standards for justices, shall refer to the Attorney General the name of any individual who the Conference or the official has reasonable cause to believe has accepted a gift prohibited by this section or any other law or regulation.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HD23175B7853C45E4BB9DE08B41EB7571">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                                    <header>Notification of referral</header>
 <text>Whenever the Judicial Conference of the United States refers a judicial officer to the Attorney General under this subsection, the Conference shall notify the judicial council of the circuit in which such referred judicial officer serves.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H887DDDA7CB5B4A6399F0A9D6A8FD3C09">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Penalties</header>
                                <subparagraph id="HDCC2913ED89D4F8C99ABBBD546F21672">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                                    <header>Civil penalties</header>
 <text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court for a violation of this section. The court in which such action is brought may assess against such individual a civil penalty in any amount, not to exceed $50,000.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="HDAE279E0643D4FD585DEF68E66494056">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                                    <header>Criminal penalties</header>
 <text>Any person who knowingly and willfully violates this section shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection commented="no" id="HCBF7AD88554041A880584E592335BA3B">
                            <enum>(d)</enum>
                            <header>Implementation</header>
 <text>Within 180 days of the enactment of the <short-title>High Court Gift Ban Act</short-title>, the Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference of the United States shall each promulgate regulations to carry out this section and ensure compliance.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <subsection commented="no" id="H97721E0475DF48CEB56A1B4C24AA8954">
                            <enum>(e)</enum>
                            <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to make it permissible for a judicial officer to accept a gift or other item of value that the judicial officer is prohibited from accepting under any other law, rule, or regulation.</text>
                        </subsection>
                    </section>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc261b595ba324d94a52387a829999bd2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/73">Chapter 73</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id4a51cb9d-632b-495a-967c-8d3a4125f2d0"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H5D6D46F2CAB74F85A044245B355BE5EA">7354. Gifts to Federal judges.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

