<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87D8331D41E94B4D98B928BC5BCA916B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1278 IH: Reaffirming congressional support for the Taiwan Relations Act and longstanding bipartisan Taiwan policy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1278</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Reaffirming congressional support for the Taiwan Relations Act and longstanding bipartisan Taiwan policy.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Taiwan Relations Act of 1979 is the cornerstone of the United States-Taiwan relationship, which has been characterized by broad and enduring bipartisan support;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Taiwan Relations Act established key elements of United States policy that have stood the test of time, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEDE502928A7341AD9CEC10D61A69B2CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preserving the extensive commercial, cultural, and other ties between the United States and Taiwan as well as the people on the China mainland and all other peoples of the Western Pacific area;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40E4F89C73BA444EAE2EBB5686144D61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>declaring that peace and stability in the region are in the political, security, and economic interests of the United States, and are matters of international concern;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CE96B5339B5425AB4C95FE684A1B18D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>underscoring that the United States decision to establish and maintain diplomatic relations with the People’s Republic of China rests upon the expectation that the future of Taiwan will be determined by peaceful means;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D67611DBB1941B4A0A7A2E33A084874"><enum>(4)</enum><text>considering any effort to determine the future of Taiwan by other than peaceful means, including boycotts or embargoes, a threat to regional peace and security, and of grave concern to the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H409AC69B8CC94EE583F4BC470AF2A30C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing Taiwan with arms of a defensive character; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA174205AC2CD47EEBBC2A4AD2A98BACB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>maintaining the capacity of the United States to resist any resort to force or coercion that would jeopardize the security, or social and economic system, of the people of Taiwan;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has a longstanding one China policy, which has been guided by the Taiwan Relations Act, the three Joint Communiqués, and the Six Assurances, in which the Reagan administration made clear in 1982 that, in the context of the United States-China Joint Communiqué on United States Arms Sales to Taiwan, the United States—</text> <paragraph id="H40E7DC43D1BB4C4FA1211ED3FBA64052"><enum>(1)</enum><text>did not agree to set a date for ending arms sales to Taiwan;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B7AD1A52BCB4F6E9808A59883306AC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>did not agree to prior consultation with the People’s Republic of China on arms sales to Taiwan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D22CE2A956D49C985B76B66CD966E86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>did not agree to play any mediation role between Taiwan and the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H838234D6B78140D8A77282D132B75B08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>did not agree to revise the Taiwan Relations Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CEC279135574E1ABC0F51932B22F9AF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>did not agree to take any position regarding sovereignty over Taiwan; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7D493A0485542388E7A2D5CCA846C32"><enum>(6)</enum><text>will not exert pressure on Taiwan to enter into negotiations with the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, since the passage of the Taiwan Relations Act, the United States and Taiwan have further strengthened commercial, cultural, and other ties;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Taiwan has become a key part of the global economy and a significant trading and investment partner of the United States; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Taiwan has transformed into a robust democracy on the world stage: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H576E8860051F4350A0A21EDD432582D0">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"
      id="H902A16905C4B41DF88FCF5D2C45CD2C1">
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives reaffirms the Taiwan Relations Act (96–8), the three Joint Communiqués, and the Six Assurances as cornerstones of United States policy regarding Taiwan and supports the longstanding bipartisan United States policy toward Taiwan, which includes support for Taiwan’s self-defense and opposition to efforts to determine the future of Taiwan by other than peaceful means.</text>
    </section>
  </resolution-body></resolution>

