<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT26585-8F2-HK-36J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S5008 IS: Grid Connection and Congestion Management Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 5008</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require Regional Transmission Organizations and Independent System Operators administering an open access transmission tariff to offer basic access service for energy-only delivery, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grid Connection and Congestion Management Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf43b799fd34455da385f279299cb7bd"><enum>2.</enum><header>Basic access service for energy-only delivery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part II of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824">16 U.S.C. 824 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc907b9451f0c4d14a9503930d60cdc24"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idb3da13104c3f4f008ba8993842bae368"><enum>224.</enum><header>Basic access service for energy-only delivery</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaaf990ebc68948458f1a3929ce0e832e"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id79d8d046483b4e77b89468871edf98fc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basic access service for energy-only delivery</header><text>The term <term>basic access service for energy-only delivery</term> means interconnection service that permits a generating facility to interconnect and inject at the point of interconnection up to the level approved through an evaluation described in subsection (d)(1), subject to that evaluation and the conditions described in subsection (f).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ba5b9ccbfb24a29b875736ad4405570"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1ea372192fc461994668c7249cf4fc4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deliverability</header><text>The term <term>deliverability</term> means the ability of a generating facility to deliver electric energy to load, market, or transmission service points without congestion-related curtailment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id30bcaf0991d54c86a7826b788d62e6de"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Generating facility</header><text>The term <term>generating facility</term> means a device of an interconnection customer for the production or storage of electricity, as identified in an interconnection request submitted under a Commission-jurisdictional tariff.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcad116df7c514e23ac82f864b283f51d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interconnection customer</header><text>The term <term>interconnection customer</term> means any person that proposes to interconnect a generating facility with the transmission system of a Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3038913b4b6f4834982da3a10d3a2ea5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Open access transmission tariff</header><text>The term <term>open access transmission tariff</term> means a tariff providing for transmission service that complies with the provisions of section 35.28 of title 18, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe6fb811a2e1405fb3bd5d75ed607dea"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reliability standard</header><text>The term <term>reliability standard</term> has the meaning given the term in section 215(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idabe5e43d9b4f4f0899f66d925e0d4dd2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transmission system</header><text>The term <term>transmission system</term> means the facilities of a Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator that are used to provide wholesale transmission services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b8a18bd656340ccb7313e5aa9533410"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unjust and unreasonable practices</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4be3198ddaba42f5bca097173ad649c6"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), beginning 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, it shall be unjust and unreasonable within the meaning of sections 205 and 206 for any Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator to maintain rates, terms, or conditions of service that do not provide for basic access service for energy-only delivery.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5053164108242f192b08c10df2b93dc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of timely tariff filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator submits a tariff filing by the applicable deadline under subsection (c), including any extended deadline under paragraph (3) of that subsection, paragraph (1) shall apply to that Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator beginning on the later of—</text><subparagraph id="idaf864ba68e86457b99417e16d473ebdf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id017fa141d4ea441eb5b741e124f03d3d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the Commission accepts the filing or fixes rates, terms, and conditions of service under subsection (j).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide36eaee4ad1e4e88a22415a7831153fd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tariff filings</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc06c2c4793774acdad1f85caf1246cc5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (3), not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, each Regional Transmission Organization and Independent System Operator shall submit to the Commission pursuant to section 205 conforming revisions to the open access transmission tariff of the Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator to offer basic access service for energy-only delivery.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4347493b6f8d473fa8454d3372e16563"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Revisions to an open access transmission tariff under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ca0b766c6cc4919b1f6d0c43d61e937"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a study process, including proposed timelines under subsection (i), for evaluating requests for basic access service for energy-only delivery meeting the requirements of subsections (d) and (h);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f0f05bc0bb042248180399aa3a4c43a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grant interconnection rights in accordance with subsection (e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfae330be9b6e44328c2d0566aaa91dc5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>condition service only to the extent permitted under subsection (f); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1fdebd7e716478c96ecbfb8cf0ed1dc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide a pathway to transition from basic access service for energy-only delivery to other types of interconnection service offered by the Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator, in accordance with subsection (g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a89d6e92568490cb4d2bca7668f9795"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>On a showing of good cause, the Commission may extend by not more than 180 days the deadline for submission of revisions under paragraph (1) by 1 or more Regional Transmission Organizations or Independent System Operators.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd634e50513f54d829856f85fa43cdc89"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation of request</header><paragraph id="id7a1e1122e541410ebacecbf0cf28f11b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The evaluation of a request for basic access service for energy-only delivery shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd505701350c944a7a29d9d752280b838"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consist of only the set of steady-state (thermal and voltage), short-circuit, stability analysis, and facilities studies, as provided for under section 35.28 of title 18, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation) (and the corresponding generator interconnection procedures), that are necessary to determine whether additional transmission facilities or upgrades to existing transmission facilities are needed to reliably interconnect a new or modified generating facility to the transmission system of the applicable Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator in compliance with applicable reliability standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2abc98c5ecda48d1a9bbe6aac04cdc5f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reflect the expected operating characteristics of the generating facility, including any operating limits, curtailment provisions, or modifications to the generating facility proposed or agreed to by the interconnection customer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe566109e439422ca7b1590dca7b0a2d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Findings</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ff07cdf060f4f6db4a448faf9894ec4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation under paragraph (1) shall identify—</text><clause id="id79e4567edb034d87b5a938fcfb38c321"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the maximum level of injection at the point of interconnection that can be accommodated without additional transmission facilities or upgrades to existing transmission facilities;</text></clause><clause id="ide9633be47ea840eaa9cda17f890996bc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any additional transmission facilities or upgrades to existing transmission facilities necessary to accommodate injection above the level identified under clause (i), up to the level requested by the interconnection customer; and</text></clause><clause id="id47a602c31d4945caa0351a1a69bc3d4d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each constraint assumed under paragraph (4) to be managed through operational measures.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ec4c30f4bb64c458262752c7f656020"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Election</header><text>An interconnection customer may elect to receive basic access service for energy-only delivery—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab87c1c3cca44ca38f2f1750cbf9ffdd"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the level identified under subparagraph (A)(i) without additional transmission facilities or upgrades; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2dbafc7b11ed4664a643d49368d10549"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at a higher approved level, subject to subsection (f)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id63276ae031cf44a887ac8e6f5079ca78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deliverability limitation</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id769b661803ca4f5c9561973a4a7dea53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The evaluation described in paragraph (1) shall not be used to identify facilities or upgrades, or require the construction of facilities, for the purpose of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78bfa26fa0f4468c8a8c6f432deddf1b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enabling the deliverability of electric energy from the generating facility to load, market, or transmission service points; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54638a78485e45a9a8b88783a4834edb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that the generating facility will not experience congestion-related curtailment.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae3838f94f2c48b2b8f0f6cd56d0a079"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Incidental effects on deliverability or congestion-related curtailment</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) prohibits the identification of facilities or upgrades that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id355dc191821b4cca845a5af82b8f715f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are necessary to reliably interconnect a generating facility in compliance with applicable reliability standards; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85e304eb71464b41ba19ae70e9e6273d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may have incidental effects on deliverability or congestion-related curtailment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7b6ec4ce7cb4d4189818b5acbefd1a9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Operationally manageable constraints</header><text>An evaluation under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72dbb4678ee8437aa90e74fd54651e26"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall assume that a constraint identified in the evaluation will be managed through operational measures, including redispatch, curtailment, operating limits, and remedial action schemes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id967c672b2133451d9e574aec178956f9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may identify facilities or upgrades for a constraint only to the extent that operational measures cannot maintain compliance with applicable reliability standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id352fb086148f434d99ea149272e4452c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Study timelines</header><text>The applicable Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator shall establish procedures to complete the evaluation of a request for basic access service for energy-only delivery not later than 1 year after the date on which the request is submitted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id29db7ff93dec45039fce7577173616fc"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interconnection rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Basic access service for energy-only delivery shall be subject to operating limits, curtailment provisions, and the terms of the applicable interconnection agreement, so long as those limits, provisions, and terms are not unjust, unreasonable, or unduly discriminatory or preferential.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ee1418dd4b4409fb33cf287763b2131"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conditions of service</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddcb23ea3454c4dfda29b8ae5d05f8346"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congestion-related curtailment</header><text>Basic access service for energy-only delivery may be subject to congestion-related curtailment, including curtailment associated with constraints identified in the evaluation under subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53273852f681492b9efcb41386a1d60f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Upgrade identification and cost responsibility</header><text>Construction and cost responsibility for basic access service for energy-only delivery shall be limited to facilities or upgrades identified as necessary through the evaluation under subsection (d)(1), unless such identification is based solely on the facility or upgrade—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47873404aff44552b1be8fd7cec75cb0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing deliverability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id968b0bee3b5c42c8bf84e3af4f30aa68"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing congestion-related curtailment; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19875a01b0524b84bd5842d5609ebd8a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">satisfying a deliverability, capacity deliverability, or congestion-impact screen not required for the evaluation under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4eefab97af014366a50d896579274ad0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transition path</header><text>An interconnection customer receiving basic access service for energy-only delivery may transition to any other interconnection service, including network resource interconnection service—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddda018771d674bf09ec09fb0e72ca88a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the process and terms provided to interconnection customers that are not receiving basic access service for energy-only delivery; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76ec68233d324dccb78665becb34ec8b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without forfeiting the right to continue operating under this section until the applicable generating facility begins receiving any other interconnection service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2bcdfcb12e84358aa2ca60b63ac6de2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Independent study election</header><paragraph id="id7ff10e6eb4ac4eee8c38024d4d8f026f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An interconnection customer requesting basic access service for energy-only delivery may elect to have the evaluation described in subsection (d)(1) conducted independently of any grouped study process, such as a cluster study that evaluates many interconnection requests simultaneously.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5b76b4536204303ae8184040061431a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator may not—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida10fee7c0b774b01be670b1e57b81522"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condition the availability of basic access service for energy-only delivery on participation in a grouped study process described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9124c865654e4a29ab2452a5ec4a0a43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the evaluation or provision of basic access service for energy-only delivery contingent on the completion of any grouped study process described in that paragraph, including any interconnection study process of the Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator used for other types of interconnection service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe95680e4ac94cc5a6d3654fc323934f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>delay the commencement or completion of an evaluation described in subsection (d)(1) pending the commencement or completion of any grouped study process described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0e0c034074242c98153f266030fa99e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permitted conditions</header><text>In order to facilitate the evaluation and interconnection of interconnection customers requesting basic access service for energy-only delivery in a manner that does not slow the completion of any grouped study process described in paragraph (1), a Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator may condition the basic access service for energy-only delivery for that interconnection customer on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f8ec4b93ad443268d0ac80c0203286d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">curtailment by the interconnection customer to mitigate system impacts revealed in the evaluation carried out pursuant to subsection (d)(1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e1efd9a1b21482aadd361c64bc30b31"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifications to the generating facility proposed by the interconnection customer to be interconnected to the transmission system of the Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator to mitigate or avoid those impacts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7604ad6d43d54c28af937ac785bb62b9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Study timelines</header><text>Each tariff filing under subsection (c) shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e3bfafad8d04b278708db0c4b29ba90"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposed timelines for completing the evaluation under subsection (d)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc5b0274dd5b484ba43d6cc335334e21"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting information that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida338cc0acdab47fcb40269c02cef90b2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates that those timelines are reasonable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4dd4b1e950e41b791e2c33a01a5cf3d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accounts for the scope of review needed to reliably interconnect a generating facility under that subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id10a95031c51d4af9912d1c975c986777"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Commission action on tariff proposals</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba14cc4aa2de4238b2cd17f14112b5cf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the filing of a tariff proposal under subsection (c), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="id3d97c7aaf5e14cff800c380b1acca7e2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accept the filing, if the Commission determines that the filing complies with this section and is otherwise just, reasonable, and not unduly discriminatory or preferential; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2348ebaa1172426a8ad4fc2bb80b540f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fix such rates, terms, and conditions of service as the Commission determines to be just, reasonable, not unduly discriminatory or preferential, and in compliance with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c46c4c52f5d40569c55a5b114eb4b69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timelines</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Commission may accept, reject, or modify a proposed timeline in the tariff proposal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd3bdf715f97f4c58a361f2485016c5ca"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Commission establishment of pro forma tariff</header><paragraph id="id8efce50275084c46b0547781123360c7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission shall revise the pro forma open access transmission tariff to integrate basic access service for energy-only delivery into that pro forma tariff in a manner that meets the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff9b82f5af1c4ed4a59ce5c91ef43bdf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Variation</header><text>The Commission may permit a Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator to seek variation from the pro forma tariff revised under paragraph (1) to the extent that the variations—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91b36f26e4034408ae7a1e5073af6f2e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are consistent with or superior to the pro forma tariff; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43f0ddfddb83424db874ecd52387e026"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet all requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id00269cd6dab54371b0a1adc084294847"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of acceptance of tariff</header><text>Acceptance by the Commission of a tariff proposal submitted under subsection (c) shall not, on its own, establish compliance with the requirements of the pro forma open access transmission tariff revised under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf6b152391e34de3afbde297ceae99ef"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In revising the pro forma open access transmission tariff under paragraph (1), the Commission may establish—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id841e8263a29c4b9f9a759ca7c72b5b58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>benchmark timelines, timeline-review standards, and best practices for completing the evaluation under subsection (d)(1), including standards for modifying timelines established pursuant to this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1596c8183a154c119d8d599785037801"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">standards for transparency with respect to constraints identified under subsection (d), including the operational measures and operating limits applicable to basic access service for energy-only delivery; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18e775b3f0d14e529fbe5f2db228413f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other process or policy that is at least as stringent as the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1bbb0f6cfaed4c0fa4a6695127aa7159"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Complaints</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide412318a3ba14c37b45e7915c9c86070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall act on the merits of any complaint filed pursuant to section 206 alleging noncompliance with this section not later than 180 days after the date on which the complaint is filed.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbe4b537ed1a4a6e87cb347732584bd0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consolidation</header><text>To maximize administrative efficiency, the Commission may consolidate and act on related complaints with respect to a given Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf186cbe2333c403b860e13a5abceef0d"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any provision of this section, or the application of any provision of this section to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this section, and the application of the provisions of this section to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

