<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25B73-0T5-DN-HTT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3349 IS: PBM Disclosure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
 which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To clarify the requirement to disclose direct and indirect compensation from entities providing pharmacy benefit management services or third party administration services.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id9541e6c0adea4e05860f00715b9bea70" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PBM Disclosure Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1805d460ff244c4c9c268888e33bd5b2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarification of requirement to disclose direct and indirect compensation for brokers and consultants to employer-sponsored health plans</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3ecc8887b6749198ce0fd35a19e67b3"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb)) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5BDA3F5E842E4C639E88392E2CCE4BB3"><subitem id="id7cff8bac84d8437fb426ba2c813d0b66" indent="up5"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>Pharmacy benefit management services provided by pharmacy benefit managers or other service providers and related services provided by third party administrators (or other entities providing such services) for which the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive indirect compensation or direct compensation described in item (dd).</text></subitem><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ddf887b73544431b2a4dbda8fc8417f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall promulgate regulations, through notice and comment rulemaking, clarifying the requirements of section 408(b)(2)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)</external-xref>) with respect to covered service providers providing services described in subitem (CC) of subclause (I)(bb) of such section, as amended by subsection (a). Such regulations shall apply with respect to any plan year that begins on or after the date that is 6 months after such regulations are promulgated.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84e6768d08aa49e3a13a2cef9383c136"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the amendment made by subsection (a) clarifies the existing requirement of covered service providers with respect to services described in section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb)(BB) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb)(BB)) that were in effect since the application date described in section 202(e) of the No Surprises Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108</external-xref> note), and does not impose any additional requirement under section 408(b)(2)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

