<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25660-7JM-MW-VDD">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3092 IS: Affordable Housing Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3092</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251103">November 3, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To amend subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code,
            regarding prevalent wage determinations in order to expand access to affordable housing,
            and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Housing Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id1d56e9fd32ad4de798094195be12fc95">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Updates to wage rate calculations</header>
            <subsection id="id903cbcaf4a2a40b1a0dc27f27a0e2e41">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Section 3142(b) of title 40, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf687ff753c0d4b68ba44beba0db3618c"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>work in the civil</quote> and inserting the following: “work—</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb82c25386db1402c9f4e9ebe328f6052">
                        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id278076732f8042828715ae78354af422">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9968cb57acd74c0c97190bcb612a8fa4">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the civil</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46170fe054944c6588159e6bd7f4bd8c"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>by striking <quote>, or in the District</quote> and inserting the following: “; or</text>
                    <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d4e790dda654a17bcbfc9d76ed56ce6">
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbe1c4bac04c4b529138b6101c576c69" indent="up1">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>from geographic groupings other than civil subdivisions of the State (which may include metropolitan statistical areas or other groupings determined appropriate by the Secretary), as long as projects in metropolitan labor markets are not used as a source of data for a wage determination in a nonmetropolitan labor market; or</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id7a90c0e6680b4f21ba8d78bc0cde8e6b">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the District</text> </paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="id2d0112a73160486087c3fbea36193207"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Changes to survey methodology</header> <text>Section 3142 of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
                <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id629E181FCA38408BB538035BB60D2A5F">
                    <subsection commented="no" id="id7A7B86FCBE2E4208BA22FE98B2B9EDE0">
                        <enum>(f)</enum>
                        <header>Survey information collection</header>
 <text>By not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Affordable Housing Expansion Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall—</text>
                        <paragraph commented="no" id="id100A5F345DAC4D7EAF2D1440F8593BD2">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>review the Secretary's method of collecting survey information for determining prevailing wages for purposes of subsection (a); and </text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph commented="no" id="id82C9A6878133403995D3EAFB3C9EA19B">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>revise how such survey information is collected, following a public notice and opportunity for public comment, by—</text>
                            <subparagraph commented="no" id="idFBC7699F8C1645469F643430CAE43CB9">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>including surveys that allow for reliable and objective sources of data and a defendable methodology, which may include information collected through Bureau of Labor Statistics surveys; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph commented="no" id="id487BF3BC52474DE18AF208C13A966542">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>improving the percentage of businesses choosing to participate in prevailing wage determination surveys and ensuring proportional representation of businesses represented by labor organizations and businesses not represented by labor organizations in the prevailing wage determination surveys that are completed.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="id2d51eb92dffd4c5a96a377363105935d">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Multiple wage rate determinations</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3142 of title 40, United States Code, as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
            <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e875da9771c4bacba6c2522c6c6a95b">
                <subsection id="id8ab5b690557d4db2b92dd52fb29e95b2">
                    <enum>(g)</enum>
                    <header>Federal Housing Acts</header>
 <text>A determination of prevailing wages by the Secretary of Labor applicable under section 212(a) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715c">12 U.S.C. 1715c(a)</external-xref>), section 104(b)(1) of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4114">25 U.S.C. 4114(b)(1)</external-xref>), section 12(a) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437j">42 U.S.C. 1437j(a)</external-xref>), or section 811(j)(5) of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013(j)(5)</external-xref>) shall be limited to 1 wage rate determination under subsection (b) of this section that corresponds to the overall residential character of the project.</text>
                </subsection>
                <after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
        <section id="idc290e37689184905ade48ad5f88f2efe">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group</header>
            <subsection id="idfde693441baf4be6bc856bfe2c50d939">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Definition</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group</term> means the working group established under subsection (b)(1).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1a1bfead6b424f25842b76e1e9e1fff7">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
                <paragraph id="id78527a8ac5cf4f248480b662b0bce54b">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall establish, within the Department of Labor, a Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group to recommend the update and modernization of certain requirements under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, as described in subsection (c).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id552ace8024184d58bd71c59e3f313f04">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Date of establishment</header>
 <text>The Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group shall be considered established on the date on which a majority of the members of the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group have been appointed, consistent with subsection (d).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id592d34dfff714c739e7a1ca4542dfbd9">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Duties</header>
 <text>The Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group shall—</text> <paragraph id="id7869606a5cb645b0bab6d5ca8bc56d44"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>recommend whether, and if so by how much, the residential classification can be applied to affordable housing units with 5 stories or more for purposes of prevailing wage determinations under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id080f3879f38c48f287bf1a5c32835812">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>develop administrative and legislative recommendations of ways, and for what specific circumstances in which, the prevailing wage rate requirements under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, could be waived or streamlined for certain affordable rental Federal Housing Administration new construction projects; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="id1E0F2F5BC4364962938869B60A0EF727">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>review the potential positive and negative outcomes of directing the Bureau of Labor Statistics to determine prevailing wages (rather than the Secretary of Labor under section 3142(b) of title 40, United States Code), in a way that would not rely on the collection of voluntary surveys from businesses but rather on data that is already collected by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idf361df97ea724eae8c5e9c9b53db7f57">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Members</header>
                <paragraph id="id0963D6B513B549E59174A69CA73FA08B">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group shall be composed of the following representatives of Federal agencies and relevant non-Federal industry stakeholder organizations:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id14ba820e704747ccae2efb0262e47681">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>A representative from the Department of Labor, appointed by the Secretary of Labor.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idfdca51c0a95c471f95c007c0b937eebc">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>A representative from the Department of Housing and Urban Development, appointed by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id092abb35159c4c2297250e2241c0fe8b">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>A representative of a housing construction industry association, appointed by the Secretary of Labor in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id363cf3191b0b463194e23829db4d7c4c">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>A representative of a financial services industry association, appointed by the Secretary of Labor in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id7189a8ec7f314afa8bef4176a1b14550">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>A representative of an affordable housing industry association, appointed by the Secretary of Labor in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id963c24a96550477b966bd47a5a317bc5">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>A representative of a State public housing agency, as defined in section 3 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a</external-xref>), appointed by the Secretary of Labor in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id4f1cf975f59b4cff8b4e22c0c605378e">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>A representative of a tribally designated housing entity, as defined in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>), appointed by the Secretary of Labor in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id9d77b838eac341769cf49930b1102a08">
                        <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>A representative of a labor organization representing the housing construction workforce, appointed by the Secretary of Labor in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id63b71871a2ee4fe7b12c3d0ea3d5044c">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Chair</header>
 <text>The representative from the Department of Labor appointed under paragraph (1)(A) shall serve as the chair of the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group, and that representative shall be responsible for organizing the business of the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="iddd082f5039ec4274899e756f8f39b384">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Other Matters</header>
                <paragraph id="idfd095230a79f43799cec4267cd6655d4">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>No compensation</header>
 <text>A member of the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group shall serve without compensation.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idd97315f99e6b4c0690b5256fe9c40b64">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Support</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Labor may detail an employee of the Department of Labor to assist and support the work of the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group, though such a detailee shall not be considered to be a member of the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idc8372d77cbc348b19409a04531aa15fc">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
                <paragraph id="idbf49c721048645cfafc59e72bc00ba41">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Reports</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group is established, the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group shall submit a report containing its findings and recommendations under subsection (c), including recommendations resulting from the review under subsection (c)(3), to the Secretary of Labor, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id5b65bec0a90a476f8890b006f1acfaf9">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Majority support</header>
 <text>Each recommendation made under paragraph (1) shall be agreed to by a majority of the members of the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0b88f6141c1749218c733166e2c64f13">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Nonapplicability of FACA</header>
 <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id11ca7fefa3f942de81bfb5deb382001c">
                <enum>(h)</enum>
                <header>Sunset</header>
 <text>The Davis-Bacon Modernization Working Group shall terminate on the date the report is completed under subsection (f)(1).</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="ide0e283ab35b240479bd7a81ed50c22ff">
            <enum>5.</enum>
            <header>National Housing Act</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(a) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715c">12 U.S.C. 1715c(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>similar character, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with the Davis-Bacon Act, as amended (40 U.S.C. 276a—276a–5)</quote> and inserting <quote>residential character, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, that is applicable at the time the application is filed</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="ida8826eea32304e86bcc3c1a09e465e5d">
            <enum>6.</enum>
            <header>Housing Act of 1959</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202(j)(5)(A) of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q(j)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>similar character, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with the Act of March 3, 1931 (commonly known as the Davis-Bacon Act)</quote> and inserting <quote>residential character, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, that is applicable at the time the application is filed</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id8c7e876db15d49b986a5ee0de054c903">
            <enum>7.</enum>
            <header>Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 104(b)(1) of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4114">25 U.S.C. 4114(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, as predetermined by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to the Act of March 3, 1931 (commonly known as the Davis-Bacon Act; chapter 411; 46 Stat. 1494; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/276a">40 U.S.C. 276a et seq.</external-xref>),</quote> and inserting <quote>for corresponding classes of laborers and mechanics employed on construction of a residential character, as predetermined by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, that is applicable at the time the application is filed,</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idc9258fdf5e344851aa6b8cc8dd517c04">
            <enum>8.</enum>
            <header>Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 811(j)(5)(A) of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013(j)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>similar character, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with the Act of March 3, 1931 (commonly known as the Davis-Bacon Act)</quote> and inserting <quote>residential character, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, that is applicable at the time the application is filed</quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id04ea064f03ab4bffb0249db85fde063e">
            <enum>9.</enum>
            <header>United States Housing Act of 1937</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12(a) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437j">42 U.S.C. 1437j(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, as predetermined by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to the Davis-Bacon Act (49 Stat. 1011)</quote> and inserting <quote>for corresponding classes of laborers and mechanics employed on construction of a residential character, as predetermined by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, that is applicable at the time the application is filed</quote>.</text>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

