<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H68FA2F441D74457A99EC7FBD8BEEAB69" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1356 IH: A resolution commemorating the Day of Portugal, Camões, and the Portuguese Communities, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1356</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution commemorating the Day of Portugal, Camões, and the Portuguese Communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Luís Vaz de Camões is considered one of Portugal’s greatest literary figures;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Camões is revered for his transformational influence on the Portuguese language, similar to that of Shakespeare in the English language;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the tenth of June honors the legacy of the poet Luís Vaz de Camões;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every tenth of June the Portuguese celebrate their national holiday known as the Day of Portugal, Camões, and the Portuguese Communities (known colloquially as the Day of Portugal, or Portugal Day);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Day of Portugal has been celebrated for decades in Portuguese-American communities throughout the United States, including those in California, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, and New Jersey;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Day of Portugal is a celebration of Portuguese heritage and culture commemorated throughout the Portuguese communities around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has a rich history of cultural diversity and appreciation, including that of the 1,300,000 Portuguese Americans and descendants living in the United States today;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Portugal was the first neutral nation to establish diplomatic ties with the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas through signing of a formal memorandum of understanding, the Embassy of Portugal in Washington, DC is officially part of the America250 celebration marking 250 years of United States independence; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the relationship between Portugal and the United States is one of deep friendship and steadfast alliance: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE5CD9C3953144175B91100A976D100F1"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA3EBE155F3CC41BC9457D9CB71A44078"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H7527D48AA7D144E1BC0D6559D879D42C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and commemorates the Day of Portugal, Camões, and the Portuguese Communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50DF3762395747AE922CDEED244034E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and honors the contributions of Portuguese Americans to society; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFFFFC537F68481CAB2C92B46525CF95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms our commitment to the partnership between the United States and Portugal.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

