<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBB5BF9E8EBFC451B928F5769ABE0B96D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6542 IH: First Home Savings Opportunity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6542</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow the establishment of down payment savings accounts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB450BE4586CD4CD28B6F440D13055951" style="OLC"><section id="H01D34000F25348DB88AA1D20DCC8AF16" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Home Savings Opportunity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1F771377CFE745D09AC4CF4A48ECCDA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Down payment savings account</header><subsection id="H3F32A09021A84F56B2387B8346CF5D04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VII of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 223 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB0D4F31609BF4249A33B703FDE707474" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H11EE01C2F86841D78249ED047017AE3D"><enum>223A.</enum><header>Down payment savings account</header><subsection id="H671ADAAED4074DE5B260F18AFEC47440"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deduction allowed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an account beneficiary, there shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year an amount equal to the aggregate amount paid in cash during such taxable year by such individual to a down payment savings account of such individual.</text></subsection><subsection id="H59598E872221414B9EC510E0EA13B472"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H5DDA573DBB45459ABB53E1064408E78B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Down payment savings account</header><text>The term <quote>down payment savings account</quote> means a trust created or organized in the United States exclusively for the purpose of paying the qualified down payment expenses of the account beneficiary (and designated as a down payment savings account at the time created or organized), but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H93D4863698A942DBA2DBDDC6EC8CF646" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No contribution will be accepted—</text><clause id="H27BB60F2A21C4BFA96A3081B7747A7F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if such contribution is not made by the account beneficiary,</text></clause><clause id="H1074648D1F5140F19A324F56C0B5218B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the account beneficiary had an ownership interest in a principal residence at any time during the 3-year period ending on the date of the contribution, or</text></clause><clause id="HC66633DF91084B21A1486260D3D0E9A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>unless it is in cash.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3C58217211C4B8BB03AB5E3C0E03DC4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The trustee is a bank (as defined in section 408(n)) or another person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which that person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7597CCF3B6A4B6D92958336D7AD2BD3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of the trust assets will be invested in life insurance contracts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A3611635DCA434F99E30A6763E59BC5" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assets of the trust shall not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA06FDB28DD04EBDA3F1EE883890C600"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The account beneficiary has attained the age of 18.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DF0750AAFF44F9A9A65E2EB6706DF5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified down payment expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified down payment expenses</quote> means a down payment or closing costs for the purchase of the principal residence of the account beneficiary of a down payment savings account if such account beneficiary is a first-time homebuyer (as defined in section 36(c)) with respect to such purchase.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D755757CED04FF483E86B5020FA1D51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Account beneficiary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>account beneficiary</quote> means the individual on whose behalf the down payment savings account is established.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE19C407E64E74EA39EF75160AC42BDC2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain rules to apply</header><text>Rules similar to the following rules shall apply for purposes of this section:</text><subparagraph id="HD01E83E5F3824532A70FDA69BB0F794F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 219(d)(2) (relating to no deduction for rollovers).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0B7100301344FB2BD6AAC9D8B72DEE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 219(f)(3) (relating to time when contributions deemed made).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H240A3421B27B41839566A035FE09E700"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 219(f)(5) (relating to employer payments).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40E4FAF62440475286F5BE489F751BD8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(g) (relating to community property laws).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55A2965C532D48B2A328C7F8342370DF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>The term <quote>principal residence</quote> has the same meaning as when used in section 121.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H433367F4B0964CE2AD822855F0508B10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="H08B12B6D3A3F44B6AD2D24AFB3E8187B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contribution limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount allowable as a deduction under subsection (a) to any individual for any taxable year shall not exceed the lesser of—</text><subparagraph id="HEFA4AB18606A49779808C35AA38595C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s earned income (as defined in section 32(c)(2)) for the taxable year, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D0B544087EC412F8B3BDBFE1DF87359"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$10,000 ($20,000 in the case of a joint return).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCEF1709C59E4E6396D7E0E692A34496"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Phaseout based on modified adjusted gross income</header><subparagraph id="H4B626032DC71430DA8B1E648FB506F7D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The deduction allowable under subsection (a) shall be reduced by an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount of such deduction as—</text><clause id="H0C72DE1CA6714146B805C66587B2D8BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><subclause id="H891ED060C748438B9E74AB29084DEC27"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income, over</text></subclause><subclause id="H8521CCF5B5464D86957630D89C671DBA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$150,000 ($236,000 in the case of a joint return), bears to</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H418C74D403C245E6AA9713F2B66784DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$50,000 ($79,000 in the case of a joint return).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5BA9E072C584577A3C3A01A7300E95E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>modified adjusted gross income</quote> means the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the taxable year increased by any amount excluded from gross income under section 911, 931, or 933.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H752A4C3316754C39AA523CEBC2A8E586"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denial of deduction to dependents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction shall be allowed under this section to any individual with respect to whom a deduction under section 151 is allowable to another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which such individual's taxable year begins.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F5A5E46EB7243448B549090D3AC0D80" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><subparagraph id="H18D7695CD7414069B15A99A6A0953DCC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2025, each of the dollar amounts in this subsection shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="H501EB2B5C45448B28342CB7EBECF0E2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="HD791588D53F847A09175BD77399C62B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2024</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB33E9413714473CA283E62C73DF0E6B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any increase under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $100, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F3D15C7BB0A40A0A8C150876BAD3C15"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of distributions</header><paragraph id="H6C99477D0BC24DCB8AD2F61ADB99EB7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts used for qualified down payment expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount paid or distributed out of a down payment savings account which is used exclusively to pay qualified down payment expenses of any account beneficiary shall not be includible in gross income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H117AD15FC1ED48C8BC9A11F21875BADD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of amounts not used for qualified down payment expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount paid or distributed out of a down payment savings account which is not used exclusively to pay the qualified down payment expenses of the account beneficiary shall be included in the gross income of such beneficiary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1E9CC55E7714058A490138DDD0735E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excess contributions returned before due date of return</header><subparagraph id="H0F4F402478744489AE564CBF4F47EECA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any excess contribution is contributed for a taxable year to any down payment savings account of an individual, <internal-xref idref="H117AD15FC1ED48C8BC9A11F21875BADD" legis-path="223A.(e)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref> shall not apply to distributions from the down payment savings accounts of such individual (to the extent such distributions do not exceed the aggregate excess contributions to all such accounts of such individual for such year) if—</text><clause id="H907F0AF95F1E4F4E827DCEF65311E85C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such distribution is received by the individual on or before the last day prescribed by law (including extensions of time) for filing such individual's return for such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="H1B234370229A4A5EAE304BF09F76C4DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such distribution is accompanied by the amount of net income attributable to such excess contribution.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any net income described in <internal-xref idref="H1B234370229A4A5EAE304BF09F76C4DA" legis-path="223A.(e)(3)(A)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref> shall be included in the gross income of the individual for the taxable year in which it is received.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5261220F96F344D297733B585BC1E468"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess contribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H0F4F402478744489AE564CBF4F47EECA" legis-path="223A.(e)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, the term <quote>excess contribution</quote> means any contribution to a down payment savings account (other than a rollover contribution described in <internal-xref idref="HE427E74F909C4B90AA545A8A535F5E72" legis-path="223A.(e)(5)">paragraph (5)</internal-xref>) which is not deductible under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1060109D6D3F4B8EA5260F6BF9921BCB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional tax for distributions not used for down payment expenses</header><subparagraph id="H173DC501F3D240409F1B2AE6525F81F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tax imposed by this chapter for any taxable year on any taxpayer who receives a payment or distribution from a down payment savings account which is includible in gross income shall be increased by 20 percent of the amount which is so includible.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B88B3947A3545DA9F2201FE2665B2DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><internal-xref idref="H173DC501F3D240409F1B2AE6525F81F7" legis-path="q:HB0D4F31609BF4249A33B703FDE707474:223A.(e)(4)(A)">Subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> shall not apply if the payment or distribution is—</text><clause id="HFBA366A99C0145A08A1D7AF7A20AD499"><enum>(i)</enum><text>made to the account beneficiary (or to the estate of such account beneficiary) on or after the death of such account beneficiary, or</text></clause><clause id="HC634CEBF9C8146F09CBAA2179AA4AF56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attributable to such account beneficiary’s being disabled (within the meaning of section 72(m)(7)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE427E74F909C4B90AA545A8A535F5E72"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rollover contribution</header><text>An amount is described in this paragraph as a rollover contribution if it meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HE526FFE618F9411389B897C1ECF42D6E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><internal-xref idref="H117AD15FC1ED48C8BC9A11F21875BADD" legis-path="223A.(e)(2)">Paragraph (2)</internal-xref> shall not apply to any amount paid or distributed from a down payment savings account to the account beneficiary to the extent the amount received is paid into a down payment savings account for the benefit of such beneficiary not later than the 60th day after the day on which the beneficiary receives the payment or distribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73E7286430354D7EA7A8D9774746566B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This paragraph shall not apply to any amount described in <internal-xref idref="HE526FFE618F9411389B897C1ECF42D6E" legis-path="223A.(e)(5)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> received by an individual from a down payment savings account if, at any time during the 1-year period ending on the day of such receipt, such individual received any other amount described in <internal-xref idref="HE526FFE618F9411389B897C1ECF42D6E" legis-path="223A.(e)(5)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> from a down payment savings account which was not includible in the individual's gross income because of the application of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H251D1FCF99D14E8C9F847109C2CED96F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rules for death and divorce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (7) and (8) of section 223(f) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7EF27F4D2A41A391CABB70C2C557E4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Disallowance of excluded amounts as deduction, credit, or exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction, credit, or exclusion shall be allowed to the taxpayer under any other section of this chapter for any qualified down payment expenses to the extent taken into account in determining the amount of the exclusion under <internal-xref idref="H6C99477D0BC24DCB8AD2F61ADB99EB7A" legis-path="223A.(e)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6A574D4DEEA4D419F55F751CD994032"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Account termination</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2) and (4) of section 408(e) shall apply to down payment savings accounts, and any amount treated as distributed under such rules shall be treated as not used to pay qualified down payment expenses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE210FEB0FB1E4430A1CED36A11CF89FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H77CCB37FE7B34B249419B48090B00348"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The trustee of a down payment savings account shall make such reports regarding such account to the Secretary and to the account beneficiary with respect to contributions, distributions, and such other matters as the Secretary may require. The reports required by this subsection shall be filed at such time and in such manner and furnished to such individuals at such time and in such manner as may be required.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC0E9D2B92348ABAA22CFA6B0066631"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rollover distributions</header><text>In the case of any distribution described in <internal-xref idref="HE427E74F909C4B90AA545A8A535F5E72" legis-path="223A.(e)(5)">subsection (d)(5)</internal-xref>, the officer or employee having control of the down payment savings account (or their designee) shall provide a report to the trustee of the down payment savings account to which the distribution is made. Such report shall be filed at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require and shall include information with respect to the contributions, distributions, and earnings of the down payment savings account as of the date of the distribution described in such subsection, together with such other matters as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HAE08EA29F60344828A60041783166F80"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Deduction allowed to non-Itemizers</header> <text>Section 63(b) of such Code is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HC7BF8BC3A7884FA5B9FF855B56B2FB62">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>and</quote> and inserting a comma,</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H62E17986B62341438FE653C10618B558"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H32E82EB4D2384C75B32265FB0584CAA8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HACFCDC1AFA3D4F88B6AE4C82D2172F33" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H7F9517CDA88B4F57BB7ECA52AEE5C4AF"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the deduction allowed by section 223A.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF609EC7BCC574E908332979F5F300320"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tax on prohibited transactions</header><paragraph id="HD18C97AE47C446A6BF33229ACCB17834"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 4975(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA91630BC188A46A0AC377E684599D72E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H4A6D81AD46E94A1D8DAA8D3D73BF15C4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Special rule for down payment savings accounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual for whose benefit a down payment savings account (within the meaning of section 223A(b)(1)) is established shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this section with respect to any transaction concerning such account (which would otherwise be taxable under this section) if, with respect to such transaction, the account ceases to be a down payment savings account by reason of the application of section 223(c)(8) to such account.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E9C31384EE04A32B851D6889FDF92F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4975(e)(1) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (F), by redesignating subparagraph (G) as subparagraph (H), and by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H898357A8A8C1491EB2562FFCCD920D3C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H7EA8E33BD6764BCE8114D25812F771AC"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a down payment savings account described in section 223A(b)(1).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H349293B02B0B4E788E42745E28899D5A"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Penalty for failure To file reports</header> <text>Section 6693(a)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (F) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following new subparagraph:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9FA800E17FA7491CB771E18F6F462400"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <subparagraph id="HC3D42D5BED2C48A39525AFD24D67E46B">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 223A(g) (relating to down payment savings accounts).</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H36A82FBAEFB3465D890F933BECC25914"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H82ED58C029DA4C81B54AF45016DD600B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 26(b)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (Z) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (Z) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB21229539BA8426A81BB75BEF30A0365" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H95032C2B75FA43958016AA336669249F"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 223A(c)(2) (relating to additional tax on down payment savings account not used for qualified down payment expenses).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBFC7D7DBADE4D0FA2A2F141CB16AE03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 877A of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H66DAE15E92374247B4CAB8ED629FF239"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)(2) by inserting <quote>a down payment savings account (as defined in section 223A),</quote> after <quote>section 223),</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FC325D5510746F8A57D2434A3495097"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (g)(6) by inserting <quote>223(e)(4),</quote>, after <quote>529A(c)(3),</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3394AD969DB24AE3969E2FFD55FD23CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 223 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC66D7A0C4C55429AB76889DA667E9A81" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 223A. Down payment savings account.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5AFDCA9DFAC24708A45B00645055346D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

