<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73E8AF011B46439C8811E50C7C346ACB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>96 HR 7425 IH: Colorado Wilderness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7425</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE9A716599E894DF9ABEC32BE43F59200" style="OLC"><section id="H23E73B1C11F14505B541E786191B2002" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; definition</header><subsection id="H29CDF1C64AF64848845859F97453AAF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Colorado Wilderness Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H03F13F85FCCB4EB284F2C3A0CDFDB17B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary defined</header><text>As used in this Act, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate.</text></subsection></section><section id="H587B589504E94D11905BC4D365698B79"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additions to national wilderness preservation system in the State of Colorado</header><subsection id="H3E78A5B7091C4F419F4D4595D2A8049E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additions</header><text>Section 2(a) of the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/77">Public Law 103–77</external-xref>; 107 Stat. 756; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following paragraphs:</text><quoted-block id="H2B6D14A582E441EFB38F5BFEFDE4D471" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="HC15D330DB4704BE7B6D42F8C55A5E137"><enum>(23)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 20,171 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Bull Gulch &amp; Castle Peak Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated December 30, 2025, which shall be known as the Bull Gulch Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3D3CDF4CA7944532A0B90FA9C11B219E"><enum>(24)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 19,033 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Bull Gulch &amp; Castle Peak Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated December 30, 2025, which shall be known as the Castle Peak Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB65CA22D8C60414999533381A4769B0D"><enum>(25)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 312 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Maroon Bells Addition Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which is hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the Maroon Bells-Snowmass Wilderness Area designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/88/577">Public Law 88–577</external-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAD64CED777D41F291E3888DC72944EC"><enum>(26)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Gunnison Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 38,176 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Redcloud &amp; Handies Peak Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Redcloud Peak Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5928720D96346D78F0972A9F41E4D20"><enum>(27)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Gunnison Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests, which comprise approximately 26,557 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Redcloud &amp; Handies Peak Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Handies Peak Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1129214A6210448C9B3295D6BF8E01D7"><enum>(28)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 17,213 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Table Mountain &amp; McIntyre Hills Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the McIntyre Hills Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H49CB628D68D44E458FEEBCF972F86BDD"><enum>(29)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 11,291 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Grand Hogback Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Grand Hogback Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD3623FF2C550422DBBF562CDA6FEB18E"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the White River National Forest, which comprise approximately 16,305 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Flat Tops Addition Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, and which are hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the Flat Tops Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/146">Public Law 94–146</external-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDDC919C4305046BBA45701C43B2C7905"><enum>(31)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office, which comprise approximately 25,897 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Demaree Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Demaree Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB0361872C85548CBABDF6841446DDADF"><enum>(32)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office, which comprise approximately 29,045 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Little Books Cliff Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Little Book Cliffs Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F7D27FF317C4921A51E470822082F43" commented="no"><enum>(33)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Tres Rios Field Office, which comprise approximately 24,475 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Bug Canyon &amp; Cross Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated September 28, 2023, which shall be known as the Cross Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H851DDF3716FD4A91A20DB355180BE274"><enum>(34)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Tres Rios Field Office, which comprise approximately 4,782 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Bug Canyon &amp; Cross Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated September 28, 2023, which shall be known as the Bug Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC87F30DFFFBD41D4ACDF490345548A84" commented="no"><enum>(35)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Tres Rios Field Office, which comprise approximately 21,220 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>McKenna Peak Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated October 16, 2019, which shall be known as the McKenna Peak Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4183DF5673184612B15532F852377D96" commented="no"><enum>(36)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Tres Rios Field Office and Uncompahgre Field Office, which comprise approximately 56,206 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Dolores River Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 14, 2023, which shall be known as the Dolores River Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3420FB2539314B2FB163C38D7E2BAA7F" commented="no"><enum>(37)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Uncompahgre Field Office and Grand Junction Field Office, which comprise approximately 39,919 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Sewemup Mesa Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 14, 2023, which shall be known as the Sewemup Mesa Wilderness.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0DE9E4F730BB4B9BACF4192056BFD6B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Further additions</header><text>The following lands in the State of Colorado administered by the Bureau of Land Management or the United States Forest Service are hereby designated as wilderness and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HB684DD336875411882AE629E1E654610"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Colorado River Valley Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the White River National Forest, which comprise approximately 25,232 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Assignation Ridge Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Assignation Ridge Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD60B574C16024CF5AE5F58ECC9BE6FF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the Pike and San Isabel National Forests, which comprise approximately 25,192 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Badger Creek Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Badger Creek Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7621170D0FF6425C85BFABA19F0A738F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the Pike and San Isabel National Forests, which comprise approximately 38,253 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Beaver Creek Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Beaver Creek Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF3BC5D9A33674DA7A286B418B511C1B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or the Bureau of Reclamation or located in the Pike and San Isabel National Forest, which comprise approximately 35,535 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Grape Creek Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Grape Creek Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H468E622D2E4D454997B5D281A89670C8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 13,351 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>North &amp; South Bangs Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the North Bangs Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83E5C02B8A844DDD833315CF565AC04A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 5,144 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>North &amp; South Bangs Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the South Bangs Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F75CE6E6B024A08ACD634CCBD42C978"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 27,150 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Unaweep &amp; Palisade Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Palisade Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H70A51FD677044ADFB5BBA34B87DBBB62"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Grand Junction Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the Grand Mesa, Uncompaghre, and Gunnison National Forest, which comprise approximately 20,420 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Unaweep &amp; Palisade Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Unaweep Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2452104BF9964A7995B582F651A68493"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Kremmling Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 31 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Platte River Addition Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, and which are hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be part of the Platte River Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/550">Public Law 98–550</external-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD40E6635EF084AB58FB8A4F4D345E034"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Uncompahgre Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 17,660 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Roubideau Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Roubideau Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE6272BD48B094A2EB0395105CDA92218"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Uncompahgre Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the Grand Mesa, Uncompaghre, and Gunnison National Forest, which comprise approximately 12,986 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Norwood Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Norwood Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1EE82E46D4FF4CB2AC86DF898276994A"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the San Juan Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management Certain lands, which comprise approximately 14,339 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Weber-Menefee Mountain Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Weber-Menefee Mountain Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC0523CF379BB47EDBD56B42DB0DD5125"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the San Juan Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the San Juan National Forest, which comprise approximately 10,844 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>North &amp; South Ponderosa Gorge Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the North Ponderosa Gorge Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76083432EC984DD89689B3867270FAB0"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the San Juan Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the San Juan National Forest, which comprise approximately 12,393 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>North &amp; South Ponderosa Gorge Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the South Ponderosa Gorge Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF584F8AFCE6C401EB24C700FBF808316"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management or located in the Pike and San Isabel National Forests, which comprise approximately 22,654 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Browns Canyon Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Browns Canyon Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7A1DAB4FC94E48438820274079C874E0"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the San Luis Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 10,871 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>San Luis Hills Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the San Luis Hills Wilderness.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2FCADC959F6A4A7984ADA0BB0EF062FE"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Royal Gorge Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, which comprise approximately 27,719 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Table Mountain &amp; McIntyre Hills Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, which shall be known as the Table Mountain Wilderness.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEED7402CE59A499AB55CCBCBF062DEEF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>West elk addition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands in the State of Colorado administered by the Gunnison Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management, the United States National Park Service, and the Bureau of Reclamation, which comprise approximately 6,846 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>West Elk Addition Proposed Wilderness</quote>, dated November 22, 2023, are hereby designated as wilderness and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System and are hereby incorporated in and shall be deemed to be a part of the West Elk Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/88/577">Public Law 88–577</external-xref>. The boundary adjacent to Blue Mesa Reservoir shall be 50 feet landward from the water’s edge, and shall change according to the water level.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02248E84899E487499C01FA331C59317"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Blue mesa reservoir</header><text>If the Bureau of Reclamation determines that lands within the West Elk Wilderness are necessary for future expansion of the Blue Mesa Reservoir, the Secretary shall by publication of a revised boundary description in the Federal Register revise the boundary of the West Elk Wilderness.</text></subsection><subsection id="H58B2BC15C4614DCC9B1CE1E5D42D7F15"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maps and descriptions</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of the Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a boundary description of each area designated as wilderness by this section with the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate. Each map and boundary description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the map or boundary description. The maps and boundary descriptions shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, Department of the Interior, and in the Office of the Chief of the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFD3D59A3DA9549979662BC176901DFB3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>State and private lands</header><text>Lands within the exterior boundaries of any wilderness area designated under this section that are owned by a private entity or by the State of Colorado, including lands administered by the Colorado State Land Board, shall be included within such wilderness area if such lands are acquired by the United States. Such lands may be acquired by the United States only as provided in the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H1C320FD6E50649ACADC188B791EAE17E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><subsection id="HE5702892397D4B3E9C1A000D3E1F5675"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, lands designated as wilderness by this Act shall be managed by the Secretary in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) and this Act, except that, with respect to any wilderness areas designated by this Act, any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of the Wilderness Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H976E865A8C4C4579A9F3C3D608B7DA6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>Grazing of livestock in wilderness areas designated by this Act shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>), as further interpreted by section 108 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/560">Public Law 96–560</external-xref>, and the guidelines set forth in appendix A of House Report 101–405 of the 101st Congress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3335E0C411B64799BC20CC3A0A4BBD08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State jurisdiction</header><text>As provided in section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this Act shall be construed as affecting the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State of Colorado with respect to wildlife and fish in Colorado.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB2E2F6B28157426F8C777D84C983B9CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header><paragraph id="H9E2B6A44107540BFB106E898D777DCE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around any area designated as wilderness by section 2.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9865591B6DAD45ABA68EBE3ECE276715"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities outside wilderness</header><text>The fact that an activity or use on land outside the areas designated as wilderness by section 2 can be seen or heard within the wilderness shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the wilderness.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22F89AA0367F462395C5346BFDD141D4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Military helicopter overflights</header><paragraph id="H77DC028692794A1D8194B7BFEE33E8A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act restricts or precludes—</text><subparagraph id="H6CE4A16055B04426886C4281104D9E5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military helicopters over the areas designated as wilderness by section 2, including military overflights that can be seen or heard within any wilderness area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2CBA8A539F843099BFEC311DA0A7829"><enum>(B)</enum><text>military flight testing and evaluation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16104B6260284DF1BF73CC6774A7E5D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the designation or creation of new units of special use airspace, or the establishment of military flight training routes over any wilderness area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H011B787A2974480BA281C86C2CCA7427"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aerial navigation training exercises</header><text>The Colorado Army National Guard, through the High-Altitude Army National Guard Aviation Training Site, may conduct aerial navigation training maneuver exercises over the wilderness areas designated by this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H415F3BF2D21C4307B4F25E9DE8270F37"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a manner consistent with the memorandum of understanding dated August 4, 1987, entered into among the Colorado Army National Guard, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Forest Service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA005DEF7DC16461AAF8E363F8DBBCC6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with a subsequent memorandum of understanding entered into among the Colorado Army National Guard, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H878D699A6947418E98734F4D824433BA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Running events</header><text>The Secretary may continue to authorize competitive running events currently permitted in the Redcloud Peak Wilderness Area and Handies Peak Wilderness Area in a manner compatible with the preservation of such areas as wilderness.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9F55F0F1372E4149B288029199E36042"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Potential wilderness designations</header><paragraph id="H2D06A377551E40F485AB194E8BC90899"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The following lands are designated as potential wilderness areas:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9DB7A819FDAB4835A65D95DA1D8AB077"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office or located in the White River National Forest, which comprise approximately 20,742 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Deep Creek Proposed Wilderness</quote> and dated is December 30, 2025, which, upon designation as wilderness under paragraph (2), shall be known as the Deep Creek Wilderness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE2F3572B43DE40C781CF93E1373B247C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office, which comprise approximately 7,376 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Pisgah East &amp; West Proposed Wilderness</quote> and dated November 22, 2023, which, upon designation as wilderness under paragraph (2), shall be known as the Pisgah East Wilderness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEC5303FFFF448B6B42B47DEA25DECD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain lands managed by the Glenwood Springs Field Office, which comprise approximately 6,828 acres, as generally depicted on a map titled <quote>Pisgah East &amp; West Proposed Wilderness</quote> and dated November 22, 2023, which, upon designation as wilderness under paragraph (2), shall be known as the Pisgah West Wilderness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H572AE9D616A44C5F9F2965C4491E522D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation as wilderness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lands designated as a potential wilderness area by subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1) shall be designated as wilderness on the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register a notice that all nonconforming uses of those lands authorized by subsection (e) in the potential wilderness area that would be in violation of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) have ceased. Such publication in the Federal Register and designation as wilderness shall occur for the potential wilderness area as the nonconforming uses cease in that potential wilderness area and designation as wilderness is not dependent on cessation of nonconforming uses in the other potential wilderness area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6829F730284415AA4CCCED360FD39D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except for activities provided for under subsection (e), lands designated as a potential wilderness area by paragraph (1) shall be managed by the Secretary in accordance with the Wilderness Act as wilderness pending the designation of such lands as wilderness under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF453FD151C324A8E86BB833825331A48"><enum>4.</enum><header>Water</header><subsection id="H9EAAE2204F734F08A38AB61B733C0DF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effect on water rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text><paragraph id="H115EFBA6AD214219AFF83D0508E23327"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affects the use or allocation, in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or interest in water;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61BE5AAF5883407984469614B1D31708"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects any vested absolute or decreed conditional water right in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, including any water right held by the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H956B96377B1349BBB21D4501A7A6EAB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affects any interstate water compact in existence on the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD258994B8456401A9A852B8034C99B17"><enum>(4)</enum><text>authorizes or imposes any new reserved Federal water rights; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7A26F5EF04B40C9A9B8B48E0C857E74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall be considered to be a relinquishment or reduction of any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB355EE6888E41C3A0DB4012AE0CE0B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Midstream areas</header><paragraph id="H62A56C9962CA41D38AF1A4A3324C470F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this subsection is to protect for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations—</text><subparagraph id="HED443BD3F2B24E8DAA92E3EC5F8A8E58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the unique and nationally important values of areas designated as wilderness by section 2(b) (including the geological, cultural, archaeological, paleontological, natural, scientific, recreational, environmental, biological, wilderness, wildlife, riparian, historical, educational, and scenic resources of the public land); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DA5077180784F678436E0ECDC5FDBBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the water resources of area streams, based on seasonally available flows, that are necessary to support aquatic, riparian, and terrestrial species and communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35853FE7BAE849A5A5463E63AAD9B2EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wilderness water rights</header><subparagraph id="HF70351D0949841979A8657EEBD5DD337"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that any water rights within the wilderness designated by section 2(b) required to fulfill the purposes of such wilderness are secured in accordance with subparagraphs (B) through (G).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3889306D2209415F8944140E5DC31C71"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State law</header><clause id="H5609DD398FDE4E8DB95176A5A17151B8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Procedural requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any water rights for which the Secretary pursues adjudication shall be appropriated, adjudicated, changed, and administered in accordance with the procedural requirements and priority system of State law.</text></clause><clause id="HA5B6BF7E885E47E1ABD665BBBF030FEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Establishment of water rights</header><subclause id="H3ECC9F3B6A9D497490508C992F60DF15"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subclause (II), the purposes and other substantive characteristics of the water rights pursued under this paragraph shall be established in accordance with State law.</text></subclause><subclause id="H41887805D04E4A3DA209154CC15908DC"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Not­with­stand­ing subclause (I) and in accordance with this Act, the Secretary may appropriate and seek adjudication of water rights to maintain surface water levels and stream flows on and across the wilderness designated by section 2(b) to fulfill the purposes of such wilderness.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H123DCBAC3A97498999F0F5ABEBF9292D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall promptly, but not earlier than January 1, 2027, appropriate the water rights required to fulfill the purposes of the wilderness designated by section 2(b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96B6D59F23964213A3ABF8C22E619647"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Required determination</header><text>The Secretary shall not pursue adjudication for any instream flow water rights unless the Secretary makes a determination pursuant to subparagraph (E)(ii) or (F).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93B61DC8B04B4495AD939638B06AB583"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Cooperative enforcement</header><clause id="H0205A659586F427FA56833253D468EA3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not pursue adjudication of any Federal instream flow water rights established under this paragraph if—</text><subclause id="H1E2CBF398D224344B8F269247863FE23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary determines, upon adjudication of the water rights by the Colorado Water Conservation Board, that the Board holds water rights sufficient in priority, amount, and timing to fulfill the purposes of this subsection; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H241CB89D9B0740E2AEC1BBB7E498C2B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary has entered into a perpetual agreement with the Colorado Water Conservation Board to ensure full exercise, protection, and enforcement of the State water rights within the Wilderness to reliably fulfill the purposes of this subsection.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8E9F3D397B97400E9A21F9EFEB8861FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjudication</header><text>If the Secretary determines that the provisions of clause (i) have not been met, the Secretary shall adjudicate and exercise any Federal water rights required to fulfill the purposes of the Wilderness in accordance with this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF80A508E38134664B4472D10A2C9C5E7"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Insufficient water rights</header><text>If the Colorado Water Conservation Board modifies the instream flow water rights obtained under subparagraph (E) to such a degree that the Secretary determines that water rights held by the State are insufficient to fulfill the purposes of this Act, the Secretary shall adjudicate and exercise Federal water rights required to fulfill the purposes of this Act in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9C4FA6819924EF998D93842F232C2E9"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text>The Secretary shall promptly act to exercise and enforce the water rights described in subparagraph (E) if the Secretary determines that—</text><clause id="H1919F48D75634FBFBA25A18B942DEE59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the State is not exercising its water rights consistent with subparagraph (E)(i)(I); or</text></clause><clause id="HD7615B5B26124960B51BAF6659CEFE69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the agreement described in subparagraph (E)(i)(II) is not fulfilled or complied with sufficiently to fulfill the purposes of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B00AEB6D3B14296A0B7544858D947A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Water resource facility</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, neither the President nor any other officer, employee, or agent of the United States shall fund, assist, authorize, or issue a license or permit for development of any new irrigation and pumping facility, reservoir, water conservation work, aqueduct, canal, ditch, pipeline, well, hydropower project, transmission, other ancillary facility, or other water, diversion, storage, or carriage structure in the wilderness designated by section 2(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32BB74691B5847D3BD27484E580B9737"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access and operation</header><paragraph id="H8448C6E879EC40239B67FD358166FC63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this subsection, the term <term>water resource facility</term> means irrigation and pumping facilities, reservoirs, water conservation works, aqueducts, canals, ditches, pipelines, wells, hydropower projects, and transmission and other ancillary facilities, and other water diversion, storage, and carriage structures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7979D84CA0124935844F1F49AF024077"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access to water resource facilities</header><text>Subject to the provisions of this subsection, the Secretary shall allow reasonable access to water resource facilities in existence on the date of enactment of this Act within the areas described in sections 2(b) and 2(c), including motorized access where necessary and customarily employed on routes existing as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADF97CA413C44C868D2F67B8F07B24FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Access routes</header><text>Existing access routes within such areas customarily employed as of the date of enactment of this Act may be used, maintained, repaired, and replaced to the extent necessary to maintain their present function, design, and serviceable operation, so long as such activities have no increased adverse impacts on the resources and values of the areas described in sections 2(b) and 2(c) than existed as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC25EA79542943D3901ED39CB7CDE75A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of water resource facilities</header><text>Subject to the provisions of this subsection and subsection (a)(4), the Secretary shall allow water resource facilities existing on the date of enactment of this Act within areas described in sections 2(b) and 2(c) to be used, operated, maintained, repaired, and replaced to the extent necessary for the continued exercise, in accordance with Colorado State law, of vested water rights adjudicated for use in connection with such facilities by a court of competent jurisdiction prior to the date of enactment of this Act. The impact of an existing facility on the water resources and values of the area shall not be increased as a result of changes in the adjudicated type of use of such facility as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7490E11B570B42B4B02CEA6118659820"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Repair and maintenance</header><text>Water resource facilities, and access routes serving such facilities, existing within the areas described in sections 2(b) and 2(c) on the date of enactment of this Act shall be maintained and repaired when and to the extent necessary to prevent increased adverse impacts on the resources and values of the areas described in sections 2(b) and 2(c).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

