<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H56AADB41F0E14755864F9DBA7FBF6BB8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 3482 RH: Veterans Community Care Scheduling Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 496</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3482</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–576]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260330">March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260330">March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 19, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish an online program through which an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs may schedule an appointment for a covered veteran with a non-Department health care provider under the Veterans Community Care Program, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HVR00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H181539CC38D74B56B03B9A9EEAA313A2"><section id="H1D3616552AFB4E40BB82578FB72AE5BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Community Care Scheduling Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB7FC53F25D704E9BBEB90E36A9DB4F97" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Scheduling of appointments under the Veterans Community Care Program</header><subsection id="HF8DC00C35A274F309AD7774BAC72E721"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Electronic process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 3101 of the Johnny Isakson and David P. Roe, M.D. Veterans Health Care and Benefits Improvement Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/315">Public Law 116–315</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD35B74A81F0D46889AB7AE4B68A488D6" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><subsection id="H5BB989122B704C71951332D5B76D6B59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Electronic process</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF65F6A4C57FA44B89661A93F4DB3BDEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement an electronic process through which a scheduler of the Department, using an information technology system, may schedule an appointment for health care furnished by the Department or through the Veterans Community Care Program, under section 1703 of this title, by a non-Department health care provider.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD083283D91E42FEA938EB6B0AB5CB59" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The electronic process under this subsection shall allow a scheduler, with regards to appointments described in—</text><subparagraph id="H0ACFEF45B56848428789094CA4EE0CA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either clause of subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(1), to view, search, and sort such appointments by type of care, location, and date; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B0C696D738B4FA486ECBF66A36287D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clause (ii) of such subparagraph—</text><clause id="H1CDBB435341F4432821925EEDC9B9E74"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to schedule such an appointment;</text></clause><clause id="HCC635ED4EC394DBAB2559462887ECF1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to provide referral and authorization documents directly to a non-Department provider; and</text></clause><clause id="H1FD1B8CA3ECC4A5889989EC379053C1E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to perform any other function the Secretary determines necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A398E87BED646A2A89F659544E3A9B6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the electronic process allows a scheduler to schedule an appointment for health care furnished by the Secretary through a health care provider of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H079A12299DE84228B6A72F5F6715D1A8" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement the electronic process through an existing agreement if practicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H074C2DECA029434AAF1621D2EEA144CE" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives the following regarding the electronic process:</text><subparagraph id="H8BCBFB16C92B44B8AD07DA0BB47AD4C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the Secretary makes a determination under subparagraph (B)(iii) of paragraph (2), a briefing regarding the functions the Secretary has determined necessary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05BC9A7092184F4EB90C621BB6A17999"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of <short-title>Veterans Community Care Scheduling Improvement Act</short-title>, and semiannually thereafter during the following three years, a report regarding operation of the electronic process during both the semiannual period preceding the date of the report and the cumulative period since the date of the enactment of such Act. Such a report shall include the following for each such period:</text><clause id="H88B465213C734180B23DDB17EBE425BD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of non-Department health care providers that participated in such electronic process, disaggregated by—</text><subclause id="H14BEEAA448384EEDB9B35EAF411B7DAA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>category of hospital care or medical services provided; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAA0DA926D23B49A4ABB0BF7A8423CEA7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>medical center of the Department; </text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD464068544A849B4801DED8FD5020777"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of appointments scheduled pursuant to the electronic process, disaggregated by—</text><subclause id="HA726F8C39BD44CBEA8F99EE4C5658C4B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">category of hospital care or medical services provided;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9421B250A6554692A07803162D357579"><enum>(II)</enum><text>medical center of the Department; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H35753D96CAB348349D0CCF0F69F82B01"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">month.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD4EB3AD38C2A4C5E915E40F368553A2C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of the average wait time for appointments scheduled through the electronic process and through non-electronic methods, disaggregated by medical center of the Department.</text></clause><clause id="H5F82C8E092A342B982C3627F3C07A5A5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rates at which veterans cancelled appointments scheduled through the electronic process.</text></clause><clause id="HC4CDF67A48CF4160AF2EC22F9E3953B8"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rates at which veterans did not appear for appointments scheduled through the electronic process.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H835A7D115E904515BCF9DDC305A3A2CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="H43A9A543348445089832718DC4F57E41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall implement the electronic process under subsection (d) of section 1703H of such title, as added by this section, not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCC791696FD743A5AFACDB765B7E5F5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish guidelines. Such guidelines shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7792D19568A64A15BC66FE9F0EE00EDF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Procedures for schedulers and other employees of the Department involved in the scheduling of appointments described in such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC02CF171190D4356A0F8218FEEC954D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A directive that employees described in subparagraph (A) use the electronic process to the extent practicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A2BF901747B4EDC9411280C1D0DC2AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A directive that employees described in subparagraph (A), when scheduling an appointment for a covered veteran (as such term is used in section 1703 of such title) for health care furnished by the Secretary, inform such covered veteran of available appointments though providers of the Department and through providers under the Veterans Community Care Program when eligible.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00EB535681A049468ED9E32CD9AE8B2B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Procedures for engaging with non-Department health care providers in specialized cases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE1DC066A166481BA8F486A5D140EBC4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Standards regarding timeliness and accuracy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D22AA9B4A45464986809F5BFBDA450F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Escalation protocols for scheduling failures or delays.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8F283A5CAD54FA399B3C12C8E13EB9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall implement a mandatory training program for employees described in paragraph (2) regarding the guidelines under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DF2CB4C7E7F4FD6A493BA69E6410146" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe performance benchmarks and outcome-based metrics for the electronic process under such section, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB70B3EDDE6F544EA81ADEC01EA6DF5AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>time between a referral and a scheduled appointment; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92693C914F424E829832760FF9748F91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>patient satisfaction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02CB2CF5D4E34989AA3D81E252C54B9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the percentage of appointments scheduled exclusively through the electronic process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06362BF1387845999998C838753D51ED"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall plan and carry out an outreach strategy to encourage non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care providers that participate in the Veterans Community Care Program to participate in the electronic process under such subsection. Such outreach shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7CE2FC915F3E48EFBBCFE5BD166D1B28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include contacting each such provider during such 90 days;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H819F297BE9A442D681FCCE180D5B77AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include seeking to enter into an agreement with each such provider under which the provider shall participate in the electronic process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7172C85D17BE465F89FDEDE194012CAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include collaborating with State hospital associations and rural health associations to promote such participation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EF7C8AB5CFC4C7E832E532FB8EE107D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>focus on providers in specialties or underserved areas, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2896F4F674AC4346A40626CC3C27A04C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include the publication, on a publicly accessible website of the Department, of information regarding—</text><clause id="H6F2433E035D14C09B8ADC2DABC4B6EDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details of the electronic process;</text></clause><clause id="H58A3C1F8A41B47F49A74452477AFB5A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how a provider may elect to participate in the electronic process; and</text></clause><clause id="HAE6D497B37F74675AB2D57DE2ACC2AEE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a point of contact in the Department regarding the electronic process.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C52F98753C0465CBDFC1BFB5329CFDB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives, with regards to the electronic process under such subsection, the following:</text><subparagraph id="HAF65CBABF12A453BA6432C768D843BB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the Secretary establishes guidelines under paragraph (2) of this subsection, a copy of such guidelines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF99811E0BD9549FCA2848C5D8824F5A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the Secretary formulates the plan under paragraph (5) of this subsection, a briefing on the outreach strategy under such paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H911F704DE1954CB8A8DE24A4F512F679"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the benchmarks and metrics prescribed under paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB73237D479CE4A518A1E7E3F98A97092"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expansion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a plan to integrate the scheduling of appointments for health care furnished through health care providers of the Department of Veterans Affairs into the electronic process under subsection (d) of section 1703H of such title. Such plan shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H43B49C03CB83453CA5866C4F4A3C05B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A timeline to implement such plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE259E541B0F49C9BFBBAAFDFD32E28B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Estimated costs to carry out such plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F89A4931B8A465489A13385FE6DD9C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Changes to policies and procedures of the Department the Secretary determines necessary to implement such plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H46AA0F1DBBE14347A1B07F5B030F8DC3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Codification</header><paragraph id="H5ACA1356E4CC4F1D8C521325290C24BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3101 of such Act, as amended by subsection (a), is transferred to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, inserted after section 1703G, and redesignated as section 1703H.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42DCC4546401429ABCB2EC379565726E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1703H of such title, as transferred and redesignated by this subsection, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H582A5889F17F497688D4D92C32C9191F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking any heading that is not a section heading or subsection heading and conforming the margins accordingly;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1145AE0A1BEA4D31B25180A1FB0E0435"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of title 38, United States Code</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>of this title</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98366FAE7B824A05A97A0132B5F0ED66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA7A8FFF856343C1B695A8968B083805"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="HE9155C369ABF44D58849CC44F0FB319A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H128F65C95FD04009BF5D56E62ED1D329"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking subparagraphs (A) and (B) and inserting <quote>The Secretary shall require each medical facility of the Department to use the method or tool described in paragraph (1).</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA498C0FFAAE14F14B2C58053018227C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in the section enumerator, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Sec.</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">§</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F090C9084734CFC8D56945154968C22"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in the section heading—</text><clause id="H7724BEBAB9AA4B5EAE07FE750B44E7FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Process and requirements for scheduling appointments for health care from Department of Veterans Affairs and non-Department health care.</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Scheduling of appointments</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HDFDB0F81A502415DB0C97F02D08908F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by conforming the typeface and typestyle, including capitalization, to the typeface and typestyle used in the section heading of section 1703G of such title.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7569911336814D71A88AE03A6493A8D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting, after the item relating to section 1703G, the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H61C6BCF004C444E6B9F6FA242F1C24A2" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc-entry level="section">1703H. Scheduling of appointments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC5A91B78805E42C2B4CBE370E0FBC101"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of certain limits on payment of pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>January 31, 2033</quote> and inserting <quote>June 30, 2033</quote>. </text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

