<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25228-G42-L0-1TJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 538 ATS: Designating November 2025 as “National Homeless Children and Youth Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 538</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 2025 as <quote>National Homeless Children and Youth Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, public schools identified nearly 1,400,000 enrolled children and youth who were homeless during the 2022 to 2023 school year, a 14 percent increase from the previous school year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every year an estimated 1,200,000 children younger than 6 years of age, and approximately 4,200,000 youth and young adults, experience homelessness as part of the general population, with many of those children, youth, and young adults staying on couches, in motels, in shelters, or outside;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Housing and Urban Development reported a 39 percent increase in families staying in homeless shelters or visibly on the streets in 2024, which was the highest of any population and the second consecutive year of increase;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas infants experiencing homelessness are at a higher risk for certain illnesses and health conditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas families experiencing homelessness are more likely to experience involvement in the child welfare system and difficulty with school attendance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 48 percent of students that experienced homelessness during the 2022 to 2023 school year were chronically absent, a rate 22 percent higher than that of other students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, high school students experiencing homelessness were nearly twice as likely to have seriously considered suicide or made a suicide plan, and such students were more than 3 times as likely to have made a suicide attempt within the past year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals without a high school degree or general educational development certificate are over 4<fraction>1/2</fraction> times more likely to report homelessness than their peers who completed high school, making the lack of education and diminished opportunities for financial stability key risk factors for young adult homelessness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2022, the high school graduation rate for students experiencing homelessness was 68 percent, compared to 80 percent for low-income students and 85<fraction>1/2</fraction> percent for all students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the rate of unaccompanied youth homelessness is the same in rural, suburban, and urban areas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 29 percent of unaccompanied homeless youth between 13 and 25 years of age have spent time in foster care, compared to approximately 6 percent of all children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas youths transitioning out of the juvenile justice system or foster care system often do so without reliable social, educational, financial, employment, or housing opportunities, putting them at increased risk of homelessness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas homelessness among children and youth is a complex issue that may be correlated with deep poverty, low education and employment levels, substance use disorders, mental health disorders, lack of affordable housing, and family conflict; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas awareness of child and youth homelessness must be heightened to encourage greater support for effective programs that help children and youth overcome homelessness: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id8afeeb083e874299b0d18a859d0e9c72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the efforts of businesses, governments, organizations, educators, and volunteers dedicated to meeting the needs of homeless children and youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idae9752dd42be4f5e81b1a945703b5daf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>applauds the initiatives of businesses, governments, organizations, educators, and volunteers that—</text><subparagraph id="ida85e72e1be3346d28f27c87b8643d580"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use time and resources to raise awareness of child and youth homelessness, the causes of child and youth homelessness, and potential solutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id960e3b8f8b144aefa55801af540799f0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work to prevent homelessness among children and youth;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd006296a242644e5acf7e5f015910472"><enum>(3)</enum><text>designates November 2025 as <quote>National Homeless Children and Youth Awareness Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc10e1b560d34046a66db0de489aee23"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages businesses, governments, organizations, educators, and volunteers to continue to intensify their efforts to address homelessness among children and youth during November 2025.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

