<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42968E0027C442299FF0D8C7209CBAE9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6996 IH: Full AI Stack Export Promotion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6996</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260109">January 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate the export of United States artificial intelligence systems, computing hardware, and standards globally.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB5BF2957AE59444D958287FA9DD47848" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H30EAC790C306411CB754B17A76E6B023" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Full AI Stack Export Promotion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H019FEB83A59B48EBA10AB4EB6DF70818"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2DB94129724C492D8AE33673879AD376"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States is in a race to achieve global dominance in artificial intelligence, the winner of which will reap broad economic and military benefits.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F5004A71F8343759B5E67392FE29853"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Winning the AI race will usher in a new golden age of human flourishing, economic competitiveness, and national security for the American people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA63122D4A34148399595196DB09E6E4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Establishing United States AI as the gold standard for AI worldwide and ensuring our allies build AI on United States technology will help the United States win the AI race.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE40534DEBF8745E9BA0900A3A3B83A2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Advanced AI compute is essential to the AI era, enabling both economic dynamism and novel military capabilities. Denying our foreign adversaries access to this resource, then, is a matter of both geostrategic competition and national security.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H468BAB17081E42D1A3835EED38B6DB52"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H89B60505659C43E09D9D47F39C4E8C1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain United States dominance in the global deployment of artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3A78BD7303B4FCEAC11D577DA65C133"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">drive adoption of the U.S. full AI stack by allies and partners;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEA1B2DC1FC044739968E49B94FFD737"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure global deployment of artificial intelligence is based on United States-developed AI models, run by United States cloud operators, run by data centers owned or operated by United States firms, and functioning on United States-designed artificial intelligence semiconductors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DB6EF887F17475EAE07D4640A3B6DFB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce the barriers faced by United States firms to export the U.S. full AI stack;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4401173A5046490D898D2F78B1748A68"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">counter Chinese influence in international governance bodies and ensure the global deployment of the full AI stack strengthens United States values abroad;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H744C2D403A4E40BA826883B2A53C5525"><enum>(6)</enum><text>prevent illicit foreign adversary access to the U.S. full AI stack deployed abroad;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F24F6A1ACE94D978D3F0558EFA0296D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure the global deployment of AI strengthens the qualitative military superiority of the United States and its allies over foreign adversaries; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EEA10BBB03B40A5800893D08664ECBB"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a majority of globally deployed artificial intelligence computing capacity and memory bandwidth in the United States.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8016009DB6A74C2AB65E05B8A946AA3F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Industry consortia for exporting the full AI stack</header> 
<subsection id="HC1333094F8094C19BC5198500D2FFBC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall establish and carry out a program to identify and receive proposals that meet United States-approved security requirements and standards from industry consortia to facilitate the export of the U.S. full AI stack to allies and partners. An industry consortia shall be eligible to submit proposals under this subsection if the consortia is established only for the purposes of participating in the program under this subsection.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H0E7099EC2340482F85219A291F755B84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the program required by subsection (a) is established, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the status and results of the program.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB0999C3CFA024B4381513EABE448CD95"><enum>5.</enum><header>Eliminating foreign barriers to the U.S. full AI stack</header> 
<subsection id="H5C69553E6A864736BA1A0FF8D7C84C22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall work to increase efforts to eliminate foreign barriers to the export of the U.S. full AI stack, including—</text> <paragraph id="H0D85A1FEA1A54EF7BDA64DF7FA26E940"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carrying out activities such as holding regular industry listening sessions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H009A446F2DA640EF9A75B05A222FFEE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing a hotline for industry to communications barriers to exporting the U.S. full AI stack;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9D3CF6C668844F6BEF1E8044529B323"><enum>(3)</enum><text>elevating appropriate diplomatic channels; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D561E1533D943509FBA18498E329A01"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carrying out other relevant actions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2F6C3EE892BC419F8D560BD82404D818"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diplomatic strategy</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall establish a diplomatic strategy outlining how the United States will address the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD4D5470EA10C465F9850B6601F19318C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Easing United States AI companies’ access to foreign markets.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E8D77E16A824870A00A6793D37F936E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Communicating to foreign countries the importance and benefits of using the U.S. full AI stack to deploy artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53C00EFEF8D74C27992C6038DC292AB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Leveraging the United States position in international diplomatic and standard-setting bodies to advocate for international AI governance approaches that promote innovation, reflect American values, and counter authoritarian influence.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8C3A68F9B50E4643AD2A77BF03CF9579"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the strategy required by subsection (c) is completed, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the strategy and an update on efforts to implement the strategy.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H58FE66DB95D843939B10B8B61277C5DB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study on global AI deployment</header> 
<subsection id="HC048F429EC83445DB04DB7DF00E613A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence and the Secretary of Commerce, shall conduct a study on the benefits and impact of the global deployment of artificial intelligence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA85C748CF6D64FF3A7022B8F546DBD45"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Matters To be addressed</header> <text>The study required by subsection (a) shall address the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H196E803D86684F528AB77CE7AC894EB9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The economic, diplomatic, and technological impact for the United States and its allies from the global deployment of the U.S. full AI stack.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H80DE0B284BBB49FBBDE2032C7AD67502">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The impact on U.S. economic, diplomatic, and technological leadership from the global deployment of the U.S. full AI stack.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE3E906F49CEC421FA51BE5BB296D12C3">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the global deployment of the U.S. full AI stack assists countries worldwide in achieving economic prosperity, improving quality of life, expanding healthcare and educational access for their citizens, and growing access to AI.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3AB0094C23B14CA1A67866AF30FCFD88">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The competitive position of the U.S. full AI stack globally, compared to similar technology developed by foreign countries.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H82F22CC17B1F4855AC9165395D64E455">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>How the global deployment of the U.S. full AI stack enhances or affects United States and allied security, including the qualitative military superiority of the United States and its allies over foreign adversaries.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5C5DB467C693449BB76EA500C97AE15F">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Priority regions and countries for exporting the U.S. full AI stack abroad.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H20A4040C47514E3293FC70325080BF93"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H8E4E62E6D9C24F5C85410D94BD3384F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State submit to appropriate congressional committees a report on the results of the study required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3ACBD104E3FA410BAAC4F2970A1360A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBDC1B534CF1540D2BCC667CFD6243DC5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Security of U.S. artificial intelligence semiconductor products</header> 
<subsection id="H181A477B6E624226A12EB52287427C9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, shall work with foreign purchasers of the U.S. full AI stack to institute security measures to prevent illicit or unauthorized foreign adversary access to the U.S. full AI stack.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB447538EEC59402AAC24523A2B86D5D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="HB760177E7FF84AD1A34E6C9DC0F1966C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the development and implementation of the security measures described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21631DEBFBCD419698F2290CBC324242" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAA5540C8A54B45D78B3C23E1D8CFE92A"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Matters To be addressed</header> <text>The report required by subsection (b) shall address the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H25D78B55D1CC4648A27C3E1DFC9A977F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Plans of the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, to increase the speed and security of the deployment of the U.S. full AI stack, such as creating standardized security requirements for the U.S. full AI stack deployed in third countries.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDA270637037B4FB69178E57466BDC0D4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Agreements reached with countries designed to promote adoption of the U.S. full stack, including efforts to prevent illicit or unauthorized foreign adversary access to the U.S. full AI stack.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H830EED60D2984AB7880320F9432BD9E8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The security measures that foreign purchasers of the U.S. full AI stack must undertake to prevent transfer of the U.S. full AI stack to foreign adversaries, including by remote access.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4BFF5C6CBED84D66B968BAA2B857780A">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The presence of foreign adversary hardware and software within the artificial intelligence supply chains of foreign purchasers of the U.S. full AI stack, and supply-chain security measures that foreign purchasers of the U.S. full AI stack take to eliminate that presence.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCF723D4D45414516B6C7D20D78CBF13D">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Any other relevant information regarding the security of the U.S. full AI stack.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H5F6052BDEBA34DBBAF44CB17777A9532"><enum>8.</enum><header>AI full stack confidence initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, and the public, including the industry consortia identified in section 4, shall develop generally applicable practices, product offerings, or related standards to help demonstrate confidence and reassurance to major national purchasers of the U.S. full AI stack of the privacy, confidentiality, security, and effectiveness of the U.S. full AI stack for achieving the economic and security goals of major foreign purchasers.</text> </section> <section id="H0E1D28433BE74E7ABE3A399459FE4DB0"><enum>9.</enum><header>AI full stack export success tracker</header> <subsection id="H1EB6673AE4054EF4912DE80549B93A53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter for five years, the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence and the Secretary of State, shall complete an estimate of the success of the export of the U.S. full AI stack (in this section referred to as the <quote>AI export success tracker</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE43DED259D6447DC9377E89F3ADFBDAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The AI export success tracker shall contain the following elements:</text> <paragraph id="H9D88983629124191A00179C76760ED92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An estimate of each country’s installed artificial intelligence, measured by total national computing capacity and total national memory bandwidth.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H063EDED9E66B4568B739E7D40F934DA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An estimate of what proportion of globally installed artificial intelligence integrated circuits are designed by United States firms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9830DD55B4DC495895288233AF500FC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An estimate of what proportion of globally installed artificial intelligence is installed in data centers owned or operated by United States firms, with appropriate descriptive breakdowns for each region or country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD64DD28092634F17B3F58F30339D9106"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An estimate of the proportion of global artificial intelligence model usage, measured by tokens processed, that occurs for models owned or operated by United States firms, with appropriate descriptive breakdowns for each region or country.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H993EB887A8B1465A9E3A8C62D30FC016"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An estimate of the proportion of global cloud computing services revenue and data-processing capacity is attributable to cloud operators owned or operated by United States firms.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97907C6B65C1471A9F967E55512DEBF1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H9449469688D7459D89B59023B810D894"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and make available to the public a report that contains the findings of each estimate described under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF611AF3E82248749DD2EC97801F1B1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDB4E7C740ACF428783C368D00BA4CA08"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HD6C9CD6089F140D291D26DDDB082504B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H25991FB13DA54A8C8CC4D700F7C7E1E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37655AE3D7614DC1A543485DFDB08036"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4378894277A0496792D3539A8A29ACEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>artificial intelligence integrated circuits</term> means any semiconductor device or integrated circuit architecture that is marketed to perform artificial intelligence model training, inference, or acceleration, including but not limited to graphics processing units;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H196285B907D74F629437CF20689BFD3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>foreign adversaries</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19FDA7AEA06D4676AF35CD5BE9C39A4B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>full AI stack</term> means the compute and data infrastructure that enable artificial intelligence research and development, including high-performance computing resources, data centers, the trained algorithms deployed on such infrastructure, cloud services and infrastructure, and the technical standards with which these facets operate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB3BDA00B0DD408CA5BC23FDC9FA4AE4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>national computing capacity</term> means the aggregate maximum number of floating-point operations per second (FLOP/s) or equivalent operations available within a country from computing devices, processors, or systems configured for large-scale artificial intelligence training or inference. Computing capacity shall be calculated as the maximum number of floating-point operations per second (FLOP/s), normalized at a precision level determined by the Secretary of Commerce;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49C17374D67047E285C361795162032D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>national memory bandwidth</term> means the aggregate maximum rate, expressed in bytes per second, at which data can be transferred between processing elements and directly attached memory resources in all computing devices, processors, or systems that are configured for large-scale artificial intelligence training or inference within a country. National memory bandwidth shall be measured as the sum of the sustained aggregate data transfer rates of such systems under standard benchmark conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86AAEADFF0E54F0FB008D7EBA331E61B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>U.S. artificial intelligence semiconductor products</term> means any semiconductor device or integrated circuit architecture for which design activities were conducted in the United States and that is marketed to perform artificial intelligence model training, inference, or acceleration, including but not limited to graphics processing units;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C2ADEAF1FFF473A9204B6785E5B6F3C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>U.S. full AI stack</term> means those parts of the full AI stack with respect to which entities whose ultimate parent company is organized or headquartered in the United States are key developers, manufacturers, or providers across the relevant parts of the supply chain; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC83E46DDAD4F46E6BAC2F51E7271602D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>token</term> means a basic unit of text, code, or other data processed by an artificial intelligence model, typically corresponding to a word, part of a word, or symbol, used for the purpose of measuring the volume of model input or output.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

