<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H657BC06D1D054336BA4E01C3E0E824E1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9667 IH: Securing Healthcare and Income Entitlements for Lawfully Domiciled Citizens (SHIELD Citizens) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9667</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 to restrict eligibility for Federal welfare programs to citizens of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0BBEA286830B444EAB9BD92667E09FC6" style="OLC"><section id="H62CBA36D5DE0432A899404E73245B3E1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Healthcare and Income Entitlements for Lawfully Domiciled Citizens (SHIELD Citizens) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF0C40485FB9F4C24ACCC31D60D8FF6C0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H0D9DBFC448F54D2CA5D36BEB1CFC407B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 400 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, signed into law by Bill Clinton, declares it a policy of the United States that noncitizens should not depend on public resources to meet their needs, and that the availability of public benefits should not constitute an incentive for immigration to the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E08A3F493CC46A0A98F4F03BB615D1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding that policy, there are several areas where welfare benefits are made available to noncitizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A3BA2DD20FB46FCA3F886175235B3FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress intends by this Act to close that eligibility to all noncitizens, so that Federal welfare programs are available only to citizens of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0E6DD08B4E01457E831964850CDF2D2E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H81C9A2AAA0854A6A84FC31E655D4634A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal welfare program</header><text>The term <quote>Federal welfare program</quote> means any of the following, and any successor program:</text><subparagraph id="HC9E42B058FB7498F93D7A0C115384FDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The temporary assistance for needy families program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A25A099089B44E4A3B8B8C180637329"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA5B5E7117C749128F72D1A814AB52B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The supplemental security income program under title XVI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1381">42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63928845CC424DB99DDE3C8E1B3D218D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA466AC7FEF6F4FCF8A9DF7C7D8670884"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Federal housing assistance, including under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>) and other federally funded public or assisted housing programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D37EDFABDF445EC95095AD8675459DF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC) under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19B5033278FE44DEB1428F34BE5079C7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The low-income home energy assistance program under the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8621">42 U.S.C. 8621 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ABDE6AB4A2A4C26904F60F597504DB9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any other federally funded cash, food, housing, medical, or energy assistance program for individuals or households that the head of the administering agency designates by regulation as a <quote>Federal welfare program</quote> for purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3546E564C164864A46471F838948F05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Citizen</header><text>The term <quote>citizen</quote> means a citizen or national of the United States, as defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H74E9C41104BD46FC8B4CF8327A86D98C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Citizenship requirement for Federal welfare programs</header><subsection id="H78C5C080522E41409F3CFAECFD3A8C40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 401 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1611">8 U.S.C. 1611</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE25585F7733149AEA5BA1D1F45845EAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote>aliens who are not qualified aliens</quote> and inserting <quote>individuals who are not citizens</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39F46F16B48E4F2F9E3577D2D7DD7421"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 401(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1611">8 U.S.C. 1611(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (1) and redesignating paragraphs (2) through (5) as paragraphs (1) through (4), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74AF981369A64A1B885861DCBBDEA6C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 402 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1612">8 U.S.C. 1612</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>qualified alien</quote> each place it appears in a provision relating to a Federal welfare program (as defined in section 3(1) of this Act) and inserting <quote>citizen (as defined in section 3(2) of the Federal Welfare Citizenship Requirement Act of 2026)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB3F0F0E4E0E4E0B93214A1B4BC008B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect—</text><paragraph id="HC602DD15F1F14C38B710D3B51F7DD3CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the exceptions preserved in section 401(b) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, as redesignated by subsection (a), for emergency medical treatment, short-term in-kind disaster relief, immunizations and treatment of communicable disease symptoms, and in-kind community services such as soup kitchens, crisis counseling, and short-term shelter; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H402922DB63B642078E29C0E04A2F3F1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>eligibility for a program not defined as a Federal welfare program under section 3(1), including the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance programs under title II of the Social Security Act, Medicare under title XVIII of the Social Security Act, and unemployment compensation, which remain governed by existing law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCCE35749C9E64BDDB8FAE998B61AFEBE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date; transition</header><subsection id="H99D2B5F93D1B4429B8251147E64E598B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act and the amendments made by this Act take effect on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins at least 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H264A2F0678C54941A61749B3F7F25207"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition for current recipients</header><text>An individual who, as of the day before the effective date under subsection (a), is a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, as in effect on the day before that date) lawfully receiving benefits under a Federal welfare program shall remain eligible for such benefits for not more than 180 days after the effective date, to allow for redetermination or orderly transition off the program.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

