<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG26025-GHM-F1-49F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3658 IS: Supporting Healthy Interstate Fisheries in Transition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3658</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To support healthy fisheries in dynamic ocean conditions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Healthy Interstate Fisheries in Transition Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHIFT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id32e434a0e7ab41bf8be4a67fecd453e0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Shifting stocks</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 805(a) of the Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/5104">16 U.S.C. 5104(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1204788b342c4c31965102f0b7241daa"><paragraph id="id58666febf0a4479da0865d6b5245ae22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall encourage the Commission to include data regarding changes to the ecosystem in its coastal fishery management plans or plan amendments, and when establishing or revising quota allocations between any State, Federal, or other management unit in such a plan or amendment, the Secretary shall account for, using the best scientific information available, any impact from ecological changes on coastal fishery resources, including—</text><subparagraph id="id53fa4f8c205a45d5b8c14596e463566a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any change or shifting trend in fish abundance and distribution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b875d50c5e145aeb7314f2614a842b5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any potential ecological impact, including food web and habitat impacts, arising from such revised quota allocations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idf9e5237990e444f9b31bd96c6884de4e"><enum>3.</enum><header>Action by the secretary</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304(f) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1854">16 U.S.C. 1854(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idac43504345b945208384b431bbb32018"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="id3e6606ad0c524ab8aa3ac77b6fcad9c4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>as provided in paragraph (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>as provided in paragraph (2)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idefc84342a25f4a229c9bfd7d92a5c9e2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>No jointly prepared plan</quote> and all that follows through <quote>each Council concerned.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id34958897af054a939e483cc8b1ea8e07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e8e6bb536be4793bf16aafb56e312dc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id443d88fbd689439dacb88ee626141700"><paragraph id="id08cb5b6759a64acead1d1f849f09c072"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5021de495f224ad9bff9d467e78731ff"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If determined necessary by the Secretary or at the request of a Council, based on the criteria described in subparagraph (B) and in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary, the Secretary shall determine whether a substantial portion of a fishery extends beyond the geographical area of authority of any one Council.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id8af2ed025eb8465aa944f8dc50b23275"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Based on the best scientific information available, the Secretary shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e9975e700ac4c4c8c3e30bd3b16b217"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review any indicator of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f335b37fad54a3d93446288fbae9a02"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a documented shift in stock distribution indicating a significant shift of a stock’s average abundance has moved into another council’s jurisdiction;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedaab3e42d96476cb7bda3782847f827"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a significant shift in the average proportion of a fishery’s recreational fishing effort into another council’s jurisdiction;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87b6735f5b674805beb4a8b34d99d819"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a significant shift in the average proportion of a fishery’s landings revenue accruing to another council’s jurisdiction; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideae995fe96c34233ae0310e9e1556154"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any other fishery-specific indicator determined by the Secretary or relevant council; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfdea080fa1da4826aa1f9edd9f11b41d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consult with the relevant council to review any indicator under clause (i) to ensure a shift is not explained by normal fluctuations or non-ecological factors, such as—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e54eabc37514396a0af981f588dd828"><enum>(I)</enum><text>regulatory requirements;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31892a3942b84eacb6f30df12daf83dc"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consumer demand or market forces; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a97fbc831844f438f06d1fc38e3c79f"><enum>(III)</enum><text>socioeconomic factors.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id697f74e990f14d68b659d0d75fb8e454"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the Secretary determines under subparagraph (A) that a substantial portion of a fishery extends beyond the geographical area of authority of any one Council—</text><clause id="id93327beb89da4b4d973ca469fedbebe1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary shall, not later than 6 months after the date on which the request is made under subparagraph (A), notify the Councils concerned; and</text></clause><clause id="id513d65cb910f422ca966fc44f98b61e7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each of the Councils concerned shall, not later than 1 year after the date on which the notification is made under clause (i), by a majority of the voting members, present and voting—</text><subclause id="ide338f077765548159effada7083ad6b0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>designate one of the Councils concerned to prepare a fishery management plan for such fishery, or any necessary amendment to such a plan, if the fishery requires conservation and management under this Act; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id379f6fc808e642ee9f14736fc714f512"><enum>(II)</enum><text>agree to jointly prepare a fishery management plan for such fishery, or any necessary amendment to such a plan, if the fishery requires conservation and management under this Act.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3541c691056d4126ae06be0b3f045ec3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the case that the Councils concerned are unable to meet the requirements of subparagraph (C)(ii) within the time period specified in such subparagraph, or if their recommendations do not agree, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="idb9ab45d403f249d99300d271f23505d8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designate one of the Councils concerned to prepare a fishery management plan for such fishery, or any necessary amendment to such a plan, if the fishery requires conservation and management under this Act; or</text></clause><clause id="id422d1a46d415452bb3b9adb6dffb2ada"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require that such a plan or any necessary amendment be prepared jointly by the Councils concerned, if the fishery requires conservation and management under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b5100b1a8db4ec89701026e43a5cf3e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the last of the Councils concerned makes a decision pursuant to subparagraph (C)(ii) or the date on which the Secretary makes a decision pursuant to subparagraph (D), and at such other times as required under this Act, the Council or Councils designated under subparagraph (C)(ii) or (D) (as applicable) shall establish a fishery management plan, or make any necessary amendment to such a plan, if the fishery requires conservation and management under this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide27788b875a9494baff7f9f9fde18a8c"><enum>(F)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id926c0d76a3a14e1cbfe65fdb930585d0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If determined necessary by the Secretary or at the request of a Council in accordance with the procedures established under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall determine whether a fishery described in subparagraph (C) no longer has a substantial portion that extends beyond the geographical area of authority of any one Council.</text></clause><clause id="id4a73308982574db09efa8301dbfcafcd" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the Secretary determines under clause (i) that a fishery no longer has a substantial portion that extends beyond the geographical area of authority of any one Council—</text><subclause id="idbf520a6607174f5dae455cd3dd30d5da"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary shall determine in which Council’s geographical area of authority the fishery is predominant; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idef215375bc2647e3b866219f0a997f73"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date on which the determination under subclause (I) is made, and at such other times as required under this Act, the Council determined under such subclause shall establish a fishery management plan, or make any necessary amendment to such a plan, if the fishery requires conservation and management under this Act.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id2e968b68841e4bd3b59d34d5359df597" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsection (h), on the date of implementation of a fishery management plan under clause (ii)(II), any preceding fishery management plan with respect to such fishery is repealed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide0d48eb7e8214e8cb3c7cd0fe276d1f6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Secretary shall, through notice and comment rulemaking, identify its criteria in determining under subparagraphs (C) and (F) whether a substantial portion of a fishery extends beyond the geographical area of authority of any one Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ad20c92830d4e5282e40fcddfba157c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78bf31eced1c464cbee64c39d8be7049"><paragraph id="iddda725ab91e14c6793dba6bc1c36c9c2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>No jointly prepared plan or amendment, as described in paragraph (1)(B), (2)(C)(ii)(II), or (2)(D)(ii) may be submitted to the Secretary unless it is approved by a majority of the voting members, present and voting, of each Council concerned.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc506bc2edec84fc4873084827a6e8227"><enum>(5)</enum><text>This subsection shall not apply with respect to any fishery to which section 302(a)(3) applies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id463655962d5b41d6a95ca3475663d3ea"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as modifying or superseding subsection (e), section 302(h)(1), or any other provision of this Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id62ba5f4df6c84d3e9d0eefc985eb2ac0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Fishery authorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 305(a) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1855">16 U.S.C. 1855(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id22c6337248d843d39f2681303f7037fe"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>as to require notification under paragraph (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>under this subsection</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d262482d7844e46a391f0e804b2beb0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (3) and (4) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbd5b267d8c746659c06334a414c5dae"><paragraph id="id8c53c754d2184b139931ae60e8258d1f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary may add a new fishery or fishing gear for inclusion on the list under this subsection only after the Secretary determines that a sufficient analysis, in accordance with the guidance under paragraph (7), has been conducted by an appropriate Council, and the analysis concludes the potential new fishery or fishing gear—</text><subparagraph id="id33a6ccd3f4fb496c891b263ebf9b61e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will have minimal adverse effects (as defined in section 600.810(a) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)) on essential fish habitat; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac7d0341f3a04f8f8ee9b39ebf78a86e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will have minimal adverse effects on existing fisheries, fishing communities, and the marine ecosystem, as determined by the Secretary based on the best scientific information available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idff677219d2014c78af3bd83abad96c1c"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idbd82797137dd49ad8162871cf145117c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the Supporting Healthy Interstate Fisheries in Transition Act, and at least once every 5 years thereafter, each Council shall review the fisheries and gear on the list under this subsection that are under its authority and submit to the Secretary proposed changes to such list, if needed, in specific and narrow terms, including geographic range. Such proposed changes may include recommending new fisheries or gear or removal of fisheries or gear and shall be accompanied by information on the effects of new fisheries or gear or removal of fisheries or gear on essential fish habitat, existing fisheries, fishing communities, and the marine ecosystems, for the Secretary to review under paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idfd0de0e1ef884666818ed25c860f8fd0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>As soon as practicable after receiving a proposed change under subparagraph (A) to add a new fishery or gear to the list under this subsection, the Secretary shall make a determination under paragraph (3). If the Secretary determines that the proposed change is consistent with such paragraph, this Act, and other applicable law, the Secretary shall publish a proposed list under this subsection to include such fishery or gear, along with the appropriate Council’s analysis and the Secretary’s determination of sufficiency of the analysis consistent with paragraph (3), and provide an opportunity for public comment before publishing the final, revised list.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id08fae138da6b4ad284d83a93d81b8472"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary may permit, pursuant to section 318(d), on a limited interim basis, fishing activity that is not included on the list under this subsection, if—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc90eaeeadaf349ee9ae33281a541eb99"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the experimental fishing permit is designed and implemented so as to yield information necessary and currently lacking for the development of a fishery management plan or amendment to such plan under section 302(h)(1) and section 303;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6877ed2622bb4bd9820e20d06879db4c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary collects, evaluates, and, notwithstanding section 402(b), makes public the data generated by the experimental fishing activity at the end of each permit year, and based on such evaluation, the Council renders a determination of whether the fishing activity should be continued, either in the form of a subsequent year of experimental fishing under this paragraph, or in the form of a fishery managed under a fishery management plan pursuant to section 302(h)(1) and section 303; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57649d832592463c9763310d540a4323"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the data collected from, and the evaluation of the Secretary of, the fishing activity are included in any fishery management plan or amendment that is prepared for management of the fishing activity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idae04e189c7734269840357da3cbd8337"><enum>(D)</enum><text>As soon as practicable after publication of a final, revised list under this subsection in accordance with subparagraph (B), the appropriate Council shall, in accordance with section 303, prepare a fishery management plan or a plan amendment, if such fishery requires conservation and management under this Act, and the Secretary has approved and implemented such plan or amendment. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall affect the authority to operate under a permit issued under section 318(d).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id59740be09585411fa25caf8e8f6277b4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>No person or vessel may employ fishing gear or engage in fisheries that are not listed under this subsection without prior written notice to the Council. Upon receiving notice pursuant to the preceding sentence, the Council shall make a determination to either prohibit the person or vessel to employ the fishing gear or engage in the fishery that is not listed or make a recommendation to the Secretary to add the fishery or fishing gear for inclusion on the list under this subsection in accordance with the requirements under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idd20d1b5ff60d4b90bdc938e2772b0878"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide664afdb68ee4354833c5b657f0a6550"><paragraph id="ida8d4c4ae451045c69a8c6aea849176a8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Secretary shall issue guidance for making a determination under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f6bb69fb65a4ba8a0c9a69c47041563"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall restrict the issuance of or requirements for the experimental permitting process under section 318(d), the cooperative research and management program under section 318, the bycatch reduction engineering program under section 316, or other research or data collection activities authorized under this Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id118935121eb74c21949d665483606777"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act and not less frequently than every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit a report to Congress on implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, including metrics on resolved transboundary fisheries and ecological data integration.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id678d09be235046d7be0349566ef13333"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

