<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBD11B9B8418249CD9CBFE0E6D2737182" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7243 IH: Supporting Projects to Unleash Residential Housing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a grant program to provide amounts to developers to offset the State and local taxes associated with the building of housing developments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB36E1209C11240B79CF4C51E0E971886" style="OLC"><section id="HC13D8BF8E86B407CA24368335B1650E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Projects to Unleash Residential Housing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPUR Housing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5ED6E288B44E41C5AF146DD2171EA389" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header><subsection id="HE611C771DB6142F9B0C3765398C58D47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act establish a grant program to provide amounts to developers that such developers may use to offset costs such developer accrues associated with—</text><paragraph id="HB0147B1820EE45C4941502BDF0016123"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State and local taxes associated with the building of housing developments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D540AC11B3744E6A4C8F23B0BCAD80F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impact fees imposed by States and units of local government in association with the building of housing developments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54245B6A9B7E4D1DA40DF9E1BABE07E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive amounts under this section an developer shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8D0D842A704745C592733C6EC814C438"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional eligibility requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive amounts under this section, an developer shall have—</text><paragraph id="H51BC3124AC2749229D830D69BB85FBBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all approvals required from the State government and each unit of local government with jurisdiction over the area in which developer intends to build a housing development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA529796285E84ABA8FF14819A7D39038"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commitments from the State government and each unit of local government with jurisdiction over the area in which developer intends to build a housing development that the State government and each unit of local government shall reduce the property taxes associated with the housing developments to be built by the developer by not less than 50 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F2DE90E1E51401BAA937188902629DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>When selecting developers to receive amounts under this section the Secretary shall prioritize giving grants to developers who are building housing developments that, as determined by the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="HFB648A85C65146B7A9358D626F2F2CEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will increase the amount of affordable housing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB10E6D3627504D93937F09B50CA6E033"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are feasible;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD331180D93F54EFB84793F5950A619E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are able to begin building within 1 year of the date on which the eligible developer submitted an application;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84529295BE594709A9D9580D766E0051"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are to be located in a priority housing area, as identified by the Secretary using housing market indicators and the severe housing cost burden data from the American Community Survey conducted by the Bureau of the Census;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44315241A6394C73BC9310301CE166A1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that will offer affordable or mixed-income housing units;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C53094E702D4E6B9BED34DCD798E190"><enum>(6)</enum><text>are transit-oriented developments or located near employment hubs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32E3BCFD7635494A9BA94FF119D7F26A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>will utilize infill sites within urban growth boundaries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ACCCF5FADB741239EA7FCD7F1C7FD7F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>will target workforce housing needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H817CE695B0974596A3BBF68ACB85F941"><enum>(9)</enum><text>will include senior-friendly units and accessible units;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71BC9F0D73354874A23578C9968E4B29"><enum>(10)</enum><text>will employ adaptive reuse or rehabilitation of existing structures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1EB8B293BD94B168750858E5272C4C7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>will include supportive housing elements for vulnerable populations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB8305C00715424B9D2E1AF612A51222"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide, each year, to each developer to whom the Secretary selects to receive a grant under this section, a grant in an amount equal to the lesser of—</text><paragraph id="H796AC1C77D3744D8B392301E4BDEED2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of the total amount of the taxes and impact fees to be imposed on the developer by the State government and each unit of local government with jurisdiction over the area in which developer intends to build a housing development in association with the building such housing development; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H824EC1CA68F442EE9F218F6CE2A8C869"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$150,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5153139ECA544C31B40DAD8BC89DEBC9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Term of grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide grants to each developer selected to receive a grant under this section for 5 years, unless such developer does not have the commitments from the State government and units of local government that are required under subsection (c) for each of those 5 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB2CD3B78621E42EA836B15B946FD8426"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $300,000,000 in each of fiscal years 2027 through fiscal 2031 to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF0A68D184F44D80BDFF17A4D94BF533"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8F18854148F042189901682A8B53C908"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Impact fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>impact fee</term> means a charge imposed by a local government on a new housing development to help pay for public infrastructure and services needed because of such housing development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BE5B02BE4E14121A60371F5D12FBDE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Developer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>developer</term> means a person that plans, finances, and oversees the creation or redevelopment of real estate or infrastructure projects, from initial concept through completion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5751D6BEB80C464684A73596EBECC41D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Housing development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>housing development</term> means a project involving the building or rehabilitation of 5 or more or more residential housing units and includes mixed-use housing developments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB53DDE527E7844E8B9DBC4303C12A729"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

