<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" dms-id="H11163c62-e350-4162-8969-f5fde25d3399" public-private="public" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 988 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2988) to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to specify requirements concerning the consideration of pecuniary and non-pecuniary factors, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2262) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude certain activities from hours worked, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2270) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude child and dependent care services and payments from the rate used to compute overtime compensation; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2312) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to revise the definition of the term ''tipped employee'', and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4366) to clarify the treatment of 2 or more employers as joint employers under the National Labor Relations Act and the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 988</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260113">January 13, 2026</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2988) to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to specify requirements concerning the consideration of pecuniary and non-pecuniary factors, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2262) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude certain activities from hours worked, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2270) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude child and dependent care services and payments from the rate used to compute overtime compensation; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2312) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to revise the definition of the term ''tipped employee'', and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4366) to clarify the treatment of 2 or more employers as joint employers under the National Labor Relations Act and the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="Haf37bdb1-ba33-4c65-a982-5ad0982f03f8">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7c9e9cab-fd31-408e-9b16-7cef388934aa"><enum/><text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 2988) to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to specify requirements concerning the consideration of pecuniary and non-pecuniary factors, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Education and Workforce or their respective designees; (2) the further amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, if offered by the Member designated in the report, which shall be in order without intervention of any point of order, shall be considered as read, shall be separately debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question; and (3) one motion to recommit. </text></section> <section id="H1FD09CD2D75C425ABFFA90E2EEDECE04"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 2262) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude certain activities from hours worked, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Workforce now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part B of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Education and Workforce or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section>
<section id="H9EF3DDB389C944D5BEBAD29A2DAC087F"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House any bill specified in section 4 of this resolution. All points of order against consideration of each such bill are waived. The respective amendments in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Workforce now printed in each such bill shall be considered as adopted. Each such bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in each such bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on each such bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Education and Workforce or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section> <section id="HF22E820DDC6944D08A888F5C061E3565"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bills referred to in section 3 of this resolution are as follows:</text>
<paragraph id="HA54EF05C00E044BF85BEA7507CB41FEC"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bill (H.R. 2270) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude child and dependent care services and payments from the rate used to compute overtime compensation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8B5B9CD947D48FDA30F742379C9CFDB"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 2312) to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to revise the definition of the term ‘‘tipped employee’’, and for other purposes.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF137C13124D244D49569D58402B298BB"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The bill (H.R. 4366) to clarify the treatment of 2 or more employers as joint employers under the National Labor Relations Act and the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

