<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG26202-88F-G6-D57" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3266 RS: USMMA Athletics Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 434</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3266</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 119–126]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idd28dc18bab384f77ad778caa9b5e6307" section-type="section-one" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>USMMA Athletics Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H82F9D210071E4AEAB7CBFEE84077E84F" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Support for athletic programs of United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><subsection id="HF272CF16F3F243EA8A0737173F611917"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Corporation establishment</header><paragraph id="H28B0F17828224C8B8DED2B6052D0BF72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>) may establish, in accordance with the laws of the State of New York, a corporation (in this section referred to as the <quote>corporation</quote>) to support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1AF0ECD50594FAE873038F313153E44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ownership</header><text>All stock of the corporation shall be owned by the United States and held in the name of, and subject to be voted by, the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86A62698534B40C8A39A09600DC052BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The corporation shall operate exclusively for charitable, educational, and civic purposes to support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H529B8166873C4EABB2D7EEA419E1D954"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Corporate organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The corporation shall be organized and operated—</text><paragraph id="HF8DAF34637244083A2E037EC506B2EBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a nonprofit corporation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39E38EAE69AE417C999C7648FDE1127C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in accordance with this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF527B0542E84505A04E4737CE2B0C7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pursuant to the laws of the State of New York, its articles of incorporation, and its bylaws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D8FD300C20042F2892795157D351E15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Corporate Board of Directors</header><paragraph id="HDDFE5F5944BD46C9AA707C2AF7D47848"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation on compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the board of directors of the corporation shall serve without compensation as members of the board, except for reasonable travel and other related expenses for attendance at meetings of the board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B6B75B5DBA245139B23A177C755E3BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Transportation employee membership</header><subparagraph id="H03B1A4DCD41E4333A6216A49363D890A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize employees of the Department of Transportation to serve, in their official capacities, as members of the board of directors of the corporation—</text><clause id="H63A86E64BA0B4D68960A75CDD8757F7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the sole purpose of providing oversight and advice to, and in coordination with, the corporation; and</text></clause><clause id="HBA51CA867965460CAE455F2D09A67932"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to carry out any activities of the board other than those activities that constitute participation in the day-to-day operations of the corporation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4011B4A7FCB148939FB8EF0118D6D445"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employees serving as a member of the board of directors pursuant to an authorization under subparagraph (A) may not hold more than one-third of the directorships.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85DD4EB0285A4C71BB1A568320A55626"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability of limitation on compensation</header><text>An employee serving as a member of the board of directors shall be subject to the limitation on compensation under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F229C884185400CB89CD879EEF8C519"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contracts and cooperative agreements</header><paragraph id="H4F302F56CF6549ADB344561390917013"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter the corporation into contracts and cooperative agreements for the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86697A0950C344BC94E99E99DAE4BC32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sole-source contracts</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3105 of title 41, United States Code, a contract or cooperative agreement entered into under paragraph (1) may be a sole-source contract, subject to section 3304(a) of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3884BE18836A469EB500C25AD7BD2C74"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Acquisitions</header><text>Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, a cooperative agreement under this section may be used to acquire property, services, or travel for the direct benefit or use of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H456D218310944B5FBE9C21BF0CA200A6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Leases</header><text>For the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary may rent or lease to the corporation any real property located at the United States Merchant Marine Academy—</text><paragraph id="HA2D5CFBEFC8C4F2D9B64C5C904A80FD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under such terms and conditions as are deemed advisable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8857B752250461A83F04F0C276AA895"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for a period not exceeding 5 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E01151007D43B1A821A90533B7B5D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>so long as such real property is not required for immediate use by the United States Merchant Marine Academy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BD46933C3324EBA979134EE6E2051DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>so long as all proceeds from such rental or lease be retained and expended in accordance with subsection (j).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H174C4ABF59ED418E8FFC803EC21AC91A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Support services</header><paragraph id="H46E9EE034AC546DFBCD5DA844F3B4A11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>To the extent required by a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (d), the Secretary may provide support services to the corporation while the corporation conducts support activities at the United States Merchant Marine Academy only if the Secretary determines that the provision of such services is essential for the support of the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE1F699661384879BA9C9B5519A1A166"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No liability of the United States</header><text>The provision of support services under paragraph (1) may not result in any liability for the United States to the corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0147DF3516EB452491DF31AC2F77D850"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Support services defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>support services</term> includes utilities, office furnishings and equipment, communications services, records staging and archiving, audio and video support, and security systems, in conjunction with the leasing or licensing of property.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29F9252EAB9C4928A9C2E45237C20BAD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transfers from nonappropriated fund operation</header><paragraph id="HEAAA4C98D45C4091B8F6005DD4BAA4CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary may, subject to the acceptance of the corporation, transfer to the corporation all title to and ownership of the assets and liabilities of the Department of Transportation nonappropriated fund instrumentality, the function of which includes providing support for the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, including bank accounts and financial reserves in the accounts of such fund instrumentality, equipment, supplies, and other personal property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25AB070F47C04262A897B9D786D4D3AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In making a transfer under paragraph (1), the Secretary may not transfer any interest in real property.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA650A82571445BBBDCEE6BEB046CCA0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Acceptance of support</header><paragraph id="H5135112710614C7C97A5E5883F455A51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary may accept from the corporation funds, supplies, and services for the support of the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0759EF7EC5C4CCFB3D9658708C0DA99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employees of the corporation</header><text>For purposes of this section, employees or personnel of the corporation are not employees of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD2E264B794D43A9A140861BB88011BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funds received from other sources</header><text>To support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, the Secretary may accept funds from the National Collegiate Athletic Association, funds from athletic conferences, game guarantees from other educational institutions, fees for ticketing and licensing, and any other consideration provided incidental to the execution of the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2097B60668BE4D08AB8A7206C2751340"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that contributions under this subsection and expenditure of funds pursuant to subsection (j) do not—</text><subparagraph id="HC2B583A023B44E698A28403F27D06335"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of Transportation, or any employee of the Department of Transportation, to carry out any responsibility or duty of the Department in a fair and objective manner; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2A465597B074333B18ABAFC01D0AF2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of Transportation, or any individual involved in such a program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD6B252A629B487BA618EAF2DE04FE65"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Trademarks and service marks</header><paragraph id="HDF5F5C9A0A7548B399C9AC8C3F162973"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (d) may, consistent with section 109(h)(2) of title 49, United States Code, include an authorization for the corporation to enter into licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements (subject to the approval of the Secretary) relating to trademarks and service marks identifying the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCB07551CBBF4ADFBDBED1ACF0C30041"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The corporation may not enter into any licensing, marketing, or sponsorship agreement pursuant to authority provided under paragraph (1) that—</text><subparagraph id="H40D9459C4A5E43B88BAA56421C176C43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of Transportation, or any employee of the Department of Transportation, to carry out any responsibility or duty of the Department in a fair and objective manner; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5858E17F93AC4DF5A3137F023127C9F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines involves use of the trademark or service mark would compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of Transportation or any individual involved in such a program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED0DAE3B5E6E4350B3A9AB37C9701584"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Retention and use of funds</header><text>Funds received by the Secretary under this section may be retained for use to support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy and shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3974A5295E834C0FB9B963314DADDB63"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Licensing authority</header><text>Section 109(h) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HFAEFECFE0EBF4060A152C8D27177D331" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSCM00"><paragraph id="H60CB9FA13D1E4582997281FF3A12C4BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Licensing of intellectual property</header><subparagraph id="H8543451201484E5B8832FA3680A99F2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary may license trademarks and service marks owned or controlled by the Secretary with respect to the United States Merchant Marine Academy and may retain and expend fees received from such licensing in accordance with this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E6B3C7676D746B19ADB73F15D03274E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designated marks</header><text>The Secretary shall designate the trademarks and service marks with respect to which the Secretary will exercise the authority to retain licensing fees under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C34CB2D0BAF4FA385434B2B9DA87B8B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of fees</header><text>The Secretary shall use fees retained under this paragraph for the following purposes:</text><clause id="HF101823DA3A3484690B8D57935E7789C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For payment of costs incurred by the Secretary of securing trademark registrations and of operating the licensing program under this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="H1BB9149E65A047B2ADFAAEBE85499C52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For recruiting activities of the United States Merchant Marine Academy under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, to the extent that the total amount of the licensing fees available under this section for a fiscal year exceed the total amount needed for such fiscal year under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7B5FE09A088413ABB4F30B190903321"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Fees received in a fiscal year and retained under this paragraph shall be available until expended.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DF6BC6113D6400C8666A995DCC8B299"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph, the terms <term>trademark</term> and <term>service mark</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 45 of the Act of July 5, 1946 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1127">15 U.S.C. 1127</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section id="ideede1ee6-b3d8-4264-aea4-1373a0c927eb" section-type="section-one" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>USMMA Athletics Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ideb8f39e8-8267-4a43-8d89-99414305c335" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Support for athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id114c519602b84dd78cde7f078b087e2e"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">Chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52cbb7520b1f431aa70bf22adda5f942" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><section id="id032c296c547a447f967d549d8c960bd5"><enum>51329.</enum><header>Support for athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><subsection id="id7b53161f-ef2a-436e-b0fb-b82c35f15e46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Corporation for support authorized</header><paragraph id="id785a9d99-f081-4618-981b-456d9f046301"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation may establish, in accordance with the laws of the State of New York, a corporation (in this section referred to as the <quote>corporation</quote>) to support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id547a37f9-5a73-4390-80f0-2bf9b5cf1fd5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ownership</header><text>All stock of the corporation shall be owned by the United States and held in the name of, and subject to be voted by, the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76b47cd2-7d65-43e7-9961-681f985db632"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The corporation shall operate exclusively for charitable, educational, and civic purposes to support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1c32b1b7-2c81-43cf-a072-6d10a50739b5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Corporate organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The corporation shall be organized and operated—</text><paragraph id="id9e47d1e8-33fd-4b44-9082-d497c8395f6d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a nonprofit corporation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5903c914-47b7-496e-b480-1d1668e9475d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in accordance with this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31d3365c-db0d-47aa-b6be-4a99adf11b8f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pursuant to the laws of the State of New York, its articles of incorporation, and its bylaws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaa1b4217-aaa4-4239-afb0-124e642620e1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Corporate Board of Directors</header><paragraph id="idb8014ca6-3088-4d69-b833-5e5f85a3391e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation on compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the board of directors of the corporation shall serve without compensation as members of the board, except for reasonable travel and other related expenses for attendance at meetings of the board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id807cf893-9a6e-4c28-b0cc-ed2a3873e137"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Transportation employee membership</header><subparagraph id="id051de48f-5fbe-4656-9d7c-96e241f22b63"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize employees of the Department of Transportation to serve, in their official capacities, as members of the board of directors of the corporation—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2fc44441c784fe295c76c76a5543ec4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the sole purpose of providing oversight and advice to, and in coordination with, the corporation; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51262f55120345d998728363b6b52978"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who may not participate in the day-to-day operations of the corporation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf20339f-4bf5-4ae0-aa14-49973154e01f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employees serving as a member of the board of directors pursuant to an authorization under subparagraph (A) may not hold more than one-third of the directorships.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67a46a25-afe5-4368-a25d-1264b2ebfd8f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability of limitation on compensation</header><text>An employee serving as a member of the board of directors shall be subject to the limitation on compensation under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee24cc3c97914716b2b09996aa85c606"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Publication in federal register</header><text>The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register an authorization under subparagraph (A) of an employee of the Department of Transportation to participate as a member of the board of directors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id48675e9c-5e00-4134-9ef0-947cf1d990d2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contracts and cooperative agreements</header><paragraph id="id9b4f7b9e-bb5e-4b22-a0b0-8c597b1f8720"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter the corporation into contracts and cooperative agreements for the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e7b6fe6-b7b8-49dc-9844-b237adc43033"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sole-source contracts</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3105 of title 41, United States Code, a contract or cooperative agreement entered into under paragraph (1) may be a sole-source contract, subject to section 3304(a) of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id71507678-23c4-4725-9068-8171285793bc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Acquisitions</header><text>Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, a cooperative agreement under this section may be used to acquire property, services, or travel for the direct benefit or use of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6b8f407c-055a-4b67-a9a0-f13b32b88c81"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Leases</header><text>For the purpose of supporting the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary may rent or lease to the corporation any real property located at the United States Merchant Marine Academy—</text><paragraph id="id01447437-ca10-4005-acea-db6f31ee7293"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under such terms and conditions as are deemed advisable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97e14678-3d32-4199-80d9-2f8798b3ffb7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for a period not exceeding 5 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5bd1ad1a-5024-4e0e-99c2-99daf1eec3df"><enum>(3)</enum><text>so long as such real property is not required for immediate use by the United States Merchant Marine Academy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2e2c26c-983c-46e9-b31c-1ecb084d0a54"><enum>(4)</enum><text>so long as all proceeds from such rental or lease be retained and expended in accordance with subsection (j).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id19e4cd12-5650-47a1-832a-f19d5aa1f03a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Support services</header><paragraph id="id31697645-e2f2-44b8-ba49-549fedff5f77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>To the extent required by a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (d), the Secretary may provide support services to the corporation while the corporation conducts support activities at the United States Merchant Marine Academy only if the Secretary determines that the provision of such services is essential for the support of the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68ab3094-7430-4b1e-8b97-8b5617d3fce9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No liability of the United States</header><text>The provision of support services under paragraph (1) may not result in any liability for the United States to the corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b6ac845-3428-4622-9197-c7f1327a78a3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Support services defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>support services</term> includes utilities, office furnishings and equipment, communications services, records staging and archiving, audio and video support, and security systems, in conjunction with the leasing or licensing of property.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide8fd90fb-db31-498b-b2e4-9894cc0b5fbc"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transfers from nonappropriated fund operation</header><paragraph id="id0ae1d875-60bc-4713-8b95-e8b66fe4c0cd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary may, subject to the acceptance of the corporation, transfer to the corporation all title to and ownership of the assets and liabilities of the Department of Transportation nonappropriated fund instrumentality, the function of which includes providing support for the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, including bank accounts and financial reserves in the accounts of such fund instrumentality, equipment, supplies, and other personal property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b4c49a4-31c8-4799-874e-68f33c335abe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In making a transfer under paragraph (1), the Secretary may not transfer any interest in real property.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id31f04821-a5f7-4f65-bdf2-79d00dbf06a5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Acceptance of support</header><paragraph id="id3498db64-9a82-4778-a7cf-40e67129df9b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary may accept from the corporation funds, supplies, and services for the support of the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79cf1c3d-9f9e-4404-a6e4-eb5ac93dbb8e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employees of the corporation</header><text>For purposes of this section, employees or personnel of the corporation are not employees of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf448e39f-c4ce-48a6-8eda-f89a832597f5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funds received from other sources</header><text>The Secretary may charge fees for the support of athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy. To support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, the Secretary may accept funds from the National Collegiate Athletic Association, funds from athletic conferences, game guarantees from other educational institutions, fees for ticketing and licensing, and any other consideration provided incidental to the execution of the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea7b1d78-8e3e-49ce-8331-d8e62bc0263f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that contributions under this subsection and expenditure of funds pursuant to subsection (j) do not—</text><subparagraph id="idbcbe6040-5b81-465d-a1ab-034bf73fbc48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of Transportation, or any employee of the Department of Transportation, to carry out any responsibility or duty of the Department in a fair and objective manner; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0343a696-4a27-442b-b0c0-70117b627daf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of Transportation, or any individual involved in such a program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id428a49f5-4f36-41b3-b018-1265c8e3612c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Trademarks and service marks</header><paragraph id="ide2ce897d-a4be-4e37-b4a0-30625917c9a5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), a contract or cooperative agreement under subsection (d) may, consistent with section 109(h)(2) of title 49, United States Code, include an authorization for the corporation to enter into licensing, marketing, and sponsorship agreements (subject to the approval of the Secretary) relating to trademarks and service marks identifying the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1bc4fbb-f6f8-4e64-8786-ef74267599b7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The corporation may not enter into any licensing, marketing, or sponsorship agreement pursuant to authority provided under paragraph (1) that—</text><subparagraph id="id80277d1f-37f8-4625-9296-3c028abe6724"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may reflect unfavorably on the ability of the Department of Transportation, or any employee of the Department of Transportation, to carry out any responsibility or duty of the Department in a fair and objective manner; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8911063-9ed3-4ad2-a333-01f472935f5e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines involves the use of trademarks or service marks that would compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any program of the Department of Transportation or any individual involved in such a program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id774cc216-598a-4193-b8cc-55c37b564b19"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Retention and use of funds</header><text>Funds received by the Secretary under this section may be retained for use to support the athletic programs of the United States Merchant Marine Academy and shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c5e88a0b66645b693c3896e2533b951"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">Chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended </text><toc changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><toc-entry level="section" bold="off"><quote>51329. Support for athletic programs of United States Merchant Marine Academy.</quote>.</toc-entry></toc></subsection><subsection id="idc0bd6495-430e-495e-8a27-c1c7d9802e11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Licensing authority</header><text>Section 109(h) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id8f2d5bbe-f12e-46ae-99a3-89d48fa0bef1" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSCM00"><paragraph id="idf062d075-9261-436e-b3fc-39da9ab24f9d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Licensing of intellectual property</header><subparagraph id="id063c7ed1-04e5-489a-93f4-f782bf294419"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary may license trademarks and service marks owned or controlled by the Secretary with respect to the United States Merchant Marine Academy and may retain and expend fees received from such licensing in accordance with this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69bbeb94-ecbb-4210-9a61-d5ee51f87810"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designated marks</header><text>The Secretary shall designate the trademarks and service marks with respect to which the Secretary will exercise the authority to retain licensing fees under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ba96d81-ad57-4e03-8a09-757efd66f115"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of fees</header><text>The Secretary shall use fees retained under this paragraph for the following purposes:</text><clause id="id82117625-9f8f-49c6-bee2-e764cebbdef9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For payment of costs incurred by the Secretary of securing trademark registrations and of operating the licensing program under this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="idd312da8f-530d-4c14-8336-2d03e39a892e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For support of athletic programs and recruiting activities of the United States Merchant Marine Academy under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, to the extent (if any) that the total amount of the licensing fees available under this section for a fiscal year exceed the total amount needed for such fiscal year under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf6e7062-c5b8-4d30-a7b1-8b4445410116"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Fees received in a fiscal year and retained under this paragraph shall be available until expended.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id876d82b1-1f32-40c0-bb8c-e51c12bae92e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph, the terms <term>trademark</term> and <term>service mark</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 45 of the Act of July 5, 1946 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1127">15 U.S.C. 1127</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a2f6813f91644cfbdce24e7d576be6a"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>USMMA Athletics Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue guidance to implement a trademark and service mark licensing program under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

