<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM26892-VCG-53-9C5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 716 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate regarding critical elements of the United States policy towards the People's Republic of China.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 716</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate regarding critical elements of the United States policy towards the People's Republic of China.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China is the foremost rival and strategic competitor of the United States that has the intent and capacity to undermine the security, economic prosperity, and strategic interests of the United States and the allies and partners of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China has rapidly modernized and expanded its military in a manner that—</text><paragraph id="iddf3337261e1d4cad9616d8d259c70718"><enum>(1)</enum><text>poses direct threats to the security and economic prosperity of the United States, including by expanding its arsenal of nuclear, maritime, conventional long-range strike, cyber, space, and intelligence capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b22d58088a742d4933b83eba561be6a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aims to project power and deter the United States presence in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe92fef44c0e421c8b67d785a08f1bb3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitates intensified coercive military and illegal, coercive, aggressive, and deceptive activities (also known as <quote>gray zone activities</quote>) that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90d03f149a9748d3ae8d8128456344f9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">threaten the security and sovereignty of countries in the Indo-Pacific region; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62466db1f0ac439781fed4a890ced6c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compromise freedom of navigation in vital lanes of commerce, such as the South China Sea and the Taiwan Strait;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id28f3146d8c3a4200b98f69e6850a26f1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>aims to give the People's Republic of China the capability to carry out its threat to alter the status quo in the Taiwan Strait by coercion or force, including by delaying or denying third-party involvement in a Taiwan Strait contingency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40ae80b51c4f4776b1999de328b1f859"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports United States adversaries, such as the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, and the Russian Federation, including through the sharing of military technology and materiel;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China employs a wide range of state-directed economic and industrial policies designed to—</text><paragraph id="id87f2763e3a7144ae9e61f7e4a373f178"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disadvantage United States workers, firms, and long-term economic competitiveness;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida708dce4b1fc4c3090fe0c37619edf07"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">secure dominance in strategic industries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7e46d5a4b2c407dbb78b54e50832476"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">distort global markets, including by—</text><subparagraph id="id62d5d0016e6c438daaef5c5084d204c7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exploiting its position across global supply chains, such as critical minerals, advanced manufacturing inputs, and other strategic goods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ca573e728a745e59df07171b65bb4d2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>forcing technology transfers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf9b59e281ef43ab944175836136643e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engaging in intellectual property theft;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4b39a8ddfae40daa8da11cbb57f29c7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>creating market distortions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10f40b3e209f4c20af4d8b898aaf4237"><enum>(E)</enum><text>imposing expansive export controls; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43c6e9931ed24ef9a0bf9b1cb715b01f"><enum>(F)</enum><text>establishing barriers to market access;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China is working—</text><paragraph id="id0a17821a64a74b5f91e67695a3dfaad8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to surpass the United States in the development of critical emerging technologies, such as artificial intelligence and quantum computing, which will define twenty-first century economic and military power; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5aa7f43b749d49efb5d6bf8803aeefbf"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to use such technologies—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e30becbd5764500906eddd592d503a3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expand the reach and range of their offensive military capabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22b3769bd55e4d86aa3faeebf419608a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conduct widespread cyber operations, including operations targeting the United States and its partners;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China continues to be the primary source of precursor chemicals used by transnational criminal organizations to synthesize illicit substances (including illicit fentanyl and nitazenes) that harm communities in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China leverages international institutions and regional organizations, including standards-setting bodies and technical governance frameworks, in ways that—</text><paragraph id="id4b92c42509ca4c619f46fd59c84e87db"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give an unfair advantage to Chinese firms;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15f39708a6b742ccafd39216813410bf"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">embed technologies and rules preferred by the People's Republic of China in global markets to the disadvantage of companies in the United States and allied countries seeking to compete in strategic sectors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide80d61ca19ff44d485b3ded5da186bf2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>obstruct Taiwan's participation in global forums; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the People’s Republic of China is an authoritarian state that—</text><paragraph id="id6e62a5195d964b02a735574c28ce3b87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>restricts and suppresses human rights, religious and ethnic minority groups, civil society, and free speech and media; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id736e8c15602745cba0c0dce304381418"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engages in a sophisticated global campaign of transnational repression: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it is the sense of the Senate that the United States should—</text><paragraph id="ideca66c0003a14a81862b9e4d7e11a597"><enum>(1)</enum><text>address the security, economic, technological, diplomatic, and strategic threats posed by the People's Republic of China as the foremost priorities of United States foreign policy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida672a7e75ed34bab908503235531ba4f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sustain and strengthen deterrence against the People's Republic of China and enhance the capacity of the United States—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ca4a35c6d7b48ba9bd64b7959ec51e0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to defend its interests;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5d1d22c6d7b46e9bfdfa1b3c4ee6148"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support freedom of navigation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79ffb1607f2a46d1b74f50c2ad257436"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maintain peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region, including in the Taiwan Strait and the South China Sea;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d6898256ce94594b2b17482ced9bbf6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protect United States economic interests against the predatory economic and trade practices of the People's Republic of China, including by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ba130e3190e4ee58d867d2b386bbd7e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthening export controls and closing loopholes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ea138045ce849bbbbc7593393027b2b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restricting investments in strategic industries in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd74c32c2e5cf48678b4f1f88fd02e16b"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforcing forced labor restrictions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68bf08620a214f559dee5302cb4c88fc"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imposing costs to offset state-subsidized entities and goods;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fc24a60f6124d0e943adf8de448d08e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>dominate the artificial intelligence and other foundational technologies sectors compared to the People's Republic of China and other peer and near-peer competitors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11c0b9ea21714046bd06525d72070a60"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reaffirm the ironclad United States commitment to, and support for, United States treaty allies in the Indo-Pacific region, which stand at the frontlines of the People's Republic of China’s aggression, increased defense spending to deter such aggression, and provide vital basing for United States forces, including—</text><subparagraph id="id0838b836646a4cd5bb5c8440d56420e4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Japan, consistent with the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security Between the United States of America and Japan, signed at Washington, January 19, 1960;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6293f3cda3d84292991142e8b962bdbf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>South Korea, consistent with the Mutual Defense Treaty Between the United States and the Republic of Korea, signed at Washington, October 1, 1953;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaba2a74819c94994ba91a89e345953d4"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>Australia, consistent with the Security Treaty between Australia, New Zealand, and the United States of America, signed at San Francisco, September, 1951, and through the partnership among Australia, the United Kingdom, and United States (commonly known as <quote>AUKUS</quote>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59977742178a4ac29946ec5d9b129dd3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Philippines, consistent with the Mutual Defense Treaty between the United States and the Philippines, signed at Washington, August 30, 1951; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f387c49568949afaf42ff276d47cbda"><enum>(E)</enum><text>trilateral cooperation between United States allies in the Indo-Pacific region, including among—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58586e31fce240c1bbd493899937ceb5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States, Japan, and South Korea;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fb1be887af34a6f988e6380a9e9382b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States, Japan, and the Philippines; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4b8de6b81324b2bb0b02efef824bda9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States, Japan, and Australia;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id81daf80655324fa6b585bf2b536fe2c3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>preserve peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and maintain the longstanding United States policy on Taiwan, guided by the Taiwan Relations Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>), the Three Joint Communiqués between the United States and the People's Republic of China, and the Six Assurances between the United States and Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66d2fec5c4fe4a5395cc160843ede2b5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>strengthen support for United States partners in the Indo-Pacific region, including partners facing military, economic, and gray-zone coercion from the People’s Republic of China, including by—</text><subparagraph id="id9c73546d6da6427ba170d7287acb9009"><enum>(A)</enum><text>broadening United States engagement with India, including through the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21e6897a68754bc480dd1d491845dba3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advancing United States partnerships with countries comprising the Association of Southeast Asian Nations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ec0d7e541d64b31ba5446a2e7cfc365"><enum>(C)</enum><text>working with Pacific island countries to support their resilience and prosperity;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1085ce83cd40440ba18c4c982bc3177e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>mitigate the leadership and influence of the People's Republic of China in multilateral organizations, technical bodies, and international standards-setting institutions to prevent the adoption of rules or standards that disadvantage the interests of the United States or of its partners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86786655fad84649a1d90933dbe22f8d"><enum>(9)</enum><text>advance the democratic norms and values that promote human rights, openness, and the flourishing of civil society in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond, in accordance with United States laws, such as <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/78">Public Law 117–78</external-xref> (commonly referred to as the <quote>Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act</quote>) and the Asia Reassurance Initiative Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/409">Public Law 115–409</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

