<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25M99-LLJ-T4-6N5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 S3469 IS: BIOSECURE Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3469</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit contracting with certain biotechnology providers.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>BIOSECURE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida3d965d02f284b8e9e6ea86d92cc34d4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on contracting with certain biotechnology providers</header><subsection id="idc8336bb66ec142e09640c24f5a39aaf9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of an executive agency may not—</text><paragraph id="idc27817cf859b4ffd99112882b12bf67a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procure or obtain any biotechnology equipment or service produced or provided by a biotechnology company of concern; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf8d8688131e440adb8a075fcd44ed6ba"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enter into a contract, or extend or renew a contract, with any entity that—</text><subparagraph id="id325e12a715894e889dad676c53742631"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses biotechnology equipment or services produced or provided by a biotechnology company of concern and acquired after the applicable effective date in subsection (c) in performance of the contract with the executive agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8da783a478e840dfbd6dc355dde05120"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enters into any contract the performance of which such entity knows will require, in performance of the contract with the executive agency, the use of biotechnology equipment or services produced or provided by a biotechnology company of concern and acquired after the applicable effective date in subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3b2e6144e60f45e6b2552cd79a52ce2a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on loan and grant funds</header><text>The head of an executive agency may not obligate or expend loan or grant funds to, and a loan or grant recipient may not use loan or grant funds to—</text><paragraph id="id3b47ea091a17405fb27da0f125bd142b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procure, obtain, or use any biotechnology equipment or services produced or provided by a biotechnology company of concern; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id99cd356f6128470db4025344093fe181"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enter into a contract, or extend or renew a contract, with an entity described in subsection (a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbeeac292f0ef4b6c985c2ae9f9554b2f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><paragraph id="idba3527cf49d44db5891ae671e3d16c6e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain entities</header><text>With respect to the biotechnology companies of concern covered by subsection (f)(2)(A), the prohibitions under subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect 60 days after the Federal Acquisition Regulation is revised pursuant to subsection (h).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id474af39803f149a2994dbe96b22e6c93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other entities</header><text>With respect to the biotechnology companies of concern covered by subparagraphs (B) or (C) of subsection (f)(2), the prohibitions under subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect 90 days after the Federal Acquisition Regulation is revised pursuant to subsection (h).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8fc25cf7b3d48c7b32906cb32cd54aa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subparagraph id="id7bfd5c6e4f6a4a9fa92bb5e94fd12a36"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Prior to the date that is five years after a revision to the Federal Acquisition Regulation pursuant to subsection (h) that identifies a biotechnology company of concern covered by subsection (f)(2), subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2) shall not apply to biotechnology equipment or services produced or provided under a contract or agreement, including previously negotiated contract options, entered into before the applicable effective date under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf9e7ffe6853947d98fd8b92930664209"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text>The term <term>biotechnology equipment or services produced or provided by a biotechnology company of concern</term> shall not be construed to refer to any biotechnology equipment or services that were formerly, but are no longer, produced or provided by biotechnology companies of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb53f4d724bc844eabcf17db1bfaeb7cd"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver authorities</header><paragraph id="ideaf939b200874ad49dae97cac7ad2ee2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Specific biotechnology exception</header><subparagraph id="id24464d519de84ff6961e95ab521ac71c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The head of the applicable executive agency may waive the prohibition under subsections (a) and (b) on a case-by-case basis—</text><clause id="id37c336de12464d83849395dd7067ba7f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget; and</text></clause><clause id="idda51f27c1ce84e81bc77736d70b1d827"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such head submits a notification and justification to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 30 days after granting such waiver.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id141b7aeb56b74678a07e16d0210fd855"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><clause id="ideb125eaf36f34ef7bfdd55a3d0e672b0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), a waiver granted under subparagraph (A) shall last for a period of not more than 365 days.</text></clause><clause id="idd8721f4d6ebe448ca211c68e8555952d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The head of the applicable executive agency, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, may extend a waiver granted under subparagraph (A) one time, for a period up to 180 days after the date on which the waiver would otherwise expire, if such an extension is in the national security interests of the United States and if such head submits a notification and justification to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 10 days after granting such waiver extension.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ba7e7afed8248f690d244fa99e798bb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Overseas health care services</header><text>The head of an executive agency may waive the prohibitions under subsections (a) and (b) with respect to a contract, subcontract, or transaction for the acquisition or provision of health care services overseas on a case-by-case basis—</text><subparagraph id="id0bcee667e0bf4ce499bd7d0bd0954305"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the head of such executive agency determines that the waiver is—</text><clause id="ide3ce983b446549afb096180d9c3506d3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>necessary to support the mission or activities of the employees of such executive agency described in subsection (e)(2)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="id795fe8eac8d34085b2287d496ffd950d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the interest of the United States;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28f7258ad94c46acbf5abdb93411992a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided6c0f1a819949ccb5041daacb2634ab"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if such head submits a notification and justification to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 30 days after granting such waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddb0d5b3f438e4ca99afddc8559b301fc"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The prohibitions under subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to—</text><paragraph id="id113155f28aec41d391b4d1307aec1edd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc23fb2ad0d5042aeb3c4e584372ae9cd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the acquisition or provision of health care services overseas for—</text><subparagraph id="idb7f03643ec9f4025872d42242c85a47d"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc42ae0fdee32443caf6ddfa39aad999a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employees of the United States, including members of the uniformed services (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code), and dependents of such employees;</text></clause><clause id="id2959ff0a2d594cdea24c103a6ddcfbfe" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>covered beneficiaries (as defined in section 1072 of title 10, United States Code) not otherwise described in clause (i); or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4a8aae09b92481fbf7f3f6602e84c8a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other beneficiary if such acquisition or provision is carried out or administered by the head of a department or agency of the Federal Government; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f2a3d5bdebf44e49db74054c40d56e9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employees of contractors or subcontractors of the United States—</text><clause id="idf463e4c93d1e47d4937caa8ea27f58cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who are performing under a contract that directly supports the missions or activities of individuals described in subparagraph (A)(i); and</text></clause><clause id="id895c55c6e554484e92ec3d28d74b4e9b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whose primary duty stations are located overseas or are on permissive temporary duty travel overseas;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b62663af31e4f4ab048380f8175b80f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the acquisition, use, or distribution of human multiomic data, lawfully compiled, that is commercially or publicly available; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f95d3374fc342f89d2f0edc2b7b300a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the procurement of medical countermeasures, medical products, and related supplies, including ancillary medical supplies, in direct response to a public health emergency declared pursuant to section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf4e6cb7556ff4daf96885266a2ef10bd"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation of certain biotechnology entities</header><paragraph id="id38b25b7746474d2191ae8fd35f756d73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entity consideration</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall publish a list of the entities that constitute biotechnology companies of concern based on a list of suggested entities that shall be provided by the Secretary of Defense in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, and the National Cyber Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5bbcd3da9d484911a620e8edfb08f1b1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biotechnology companies of concern defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>biotechnology company of concern</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="ided7404c1d97b4d41b671b8636b9fb9dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An entity that—</text><clause id="id5e7e39fbbedc4069a5ac8f614f954583"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is to any extent involved in the manufacturing, distribution, provision, or procurement of any biotechnology equipment or service, as determined by the process established in paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="id8bfc3b006c994bd78c8fbc3479f96e60"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is identified in the annual list published in the Federal Register by the Department of Defense of Chinese military companies operating in the United States pursuant to section 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 3965; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b364d9201da4bc0973a21725b8302c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any entity that is determined by the process established in paragraph (1) to meet each of the following criteria:</text><clause id="idc8251fac5cc245289a6d36875c34c135"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Is subject to the administrative governance structure, direction, control, or operates on behalf of the government of a foreign adversary.</text></clause><clause id="id7fe3f87e2c2f455b917cbefb7200a565"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Is to any extent involved in the manufacturing, distribution, provision, or procurement of a biotechnology equipment or service.</text></clause><clause id="idb59466a4b13a4de59401d2bba902279e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Poses a risk to the national security of the United States based on—</text><subclause id="id54a267acf3d349bd80440713ca3ee4cc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>engaging in joint research with, being supported by, or being affiliated with a foreign adversary’s military, internal security forces, or intelligence agencies;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6a3e5a9c01eb4199a50fba687484fe98"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providing multiomic data obtained via biotechnology equipment or services to the government of a foreign adversary; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idf8768a228d9f438d99eed9ef66c39ff6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>obtaining human multiomic data via the biotechnology equipment or services without express and informed consent.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd528509c1c724696bb42dad9350486c9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any subsidiary, parent, or successor of an entity described in subparagraphs (A) or (B), provided it meets the criteria set forth in clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (B), as determined by the process established in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5a5a4f1bda8449982805e6d276cb5bd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after publication of the list pursuant to paragraph (1), and any update to the list pursuant to paragraph (4), the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, and the National Cyber Director, shall establish guidance as necessary to implement the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d7daef2eb0b4bec8a00a85841d4bf49"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in coordination with or based on a recommendation provided by the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, and the National Cyber Director, or upon receipt of a request pursuant to paragraph (7), shall periodically, though not less than annually, review and, as appropriate, add entities to or remove entities from the list of biotechnology companies of concern, and notify the appropriate congressional committees of any such modifications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ec128795e01492a92d759687de7a82c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notice of a designation and review</header><subparagraph id="idacad835d911c48bca8bba92cc605ac60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A notice of a designation as a biotechnology company of concern under paragraph (2)(B) shall be issued to any biotechnology company of concern named in the designation—</text><clause id="ida27fc52674b244d7800497e68371e894"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advising that a designation has been made;</text></clause><clause id="id7aad7f1f46ba45388fba469438135ef3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying the criteria relied upon under such subparagraph and, to the extent consistent with national security and law enforcement interests, the information that formed the basis for the designation;</text></clause><clause id="id67d748cdfa30473f944cd465303df2f3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>advising that, within 90 days after receipt of notice, the biotechnology company of concern may submit information and arguments in opposition to the designation;</text></clause><clause id="id69e2174f85424d938700f923f59a4eab"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>describing the procedures governing the review and possible issuance of a designation pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="id28fe0361aa9b41e1bd1bbf8704a40d3c"><enum>(v)</enum><text>where practicable, identifying mitigation steps that could be taken by the biotechnology company of concern that may result in the rescission of the designation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfd622304b7f4d21a6b167ca0b19c727"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Congressional notification requirements</header><clause id="id2df0a932bdfc4497b2094c983a7c397c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice of designation</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit the notice required under subparagraph (A) to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></clause><clause id="id45c8af1eeb2b437ca95ff6020555920a"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Information and argument in opposition to designations</header><text>Not later than 7 days after receiving any information and arguments in opposition to a designation pursuant to subparagraph (A)(iii), the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit such information to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a49e91785934843a8b3d8bb400129db"><enum>(6)</enum><header>No immediate public release</header><text>Any designation made under paragraph (1) or paragraph (4) shall not be made publicly available until the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in coordination with appropriate agencies, reviews all information submitted under paragraph (5)(A)(iii) and issues a final determination that a company shall remain listed as a biotechnology company of concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9c7cf1ff8944c80b41f999cce66895d"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Removal requests</header><text>If an entity on the list of biotechnology companies of concern believes it no longer meets the definition of a biotechnology company of concern as described in paragraph (2), then it may provide information and arguments to request removal from the list of biotechnology companies of concern to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget. The Director shall review such information and reply to the entity within 90 days.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida70097c750f84f6386bd282b42b94d0d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation of national security risks posed by foreign adversary acquisition of american multiomic data</header><paragraph id="iddcc675e2c94b46d2a29b43ccf4edd708"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General of the United States, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, and the National Cyber Director, shall complete an assessment of risks to national security posed by human multiomic data from United States citizens that is collected or stored by a foreign adversary from the provision of biotechnology equipment or services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc259ae0f5e82418885c332a6717ee2c3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report requirement</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the completion of the assessment developed under paragraph (1), the Director of National Intelligence shall submit a report with such assessment to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b97f815f8a44419ac52aa7ee5790973"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (2) shall be in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2462d60a487041ceb5a34efe05a23e4c"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of establishment of guidance required under subsection (f)(3), and as necessary for subsequent updates, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall revise the Federal Acquisition Regulation as necessary to implement the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcd5c4458608d4e87bf252d179d2900f1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reporting on intelligence on nefarious activities of biotechnology companies with human multiomic data</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the heads of executive agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on any intelligence in possession of such agencies related to nefarious activities conducted by biotechnology companies with human multiomic data. The report shall include information pertaining to potential threats to national security or public safety from the selling, reselling, licensing, trading, transferring, sharing, or otherwise providing or making available to any foreign country of any forms of multiomic data of a United States citizen.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd6387734e2784e93b45c65d7f8dec5ac"><enum>(j)</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id762db141cf5d4044ba46df6a4c5f0bf1"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id1d8824a518f4464dbea2a8bf363500d0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id8f3aed4bce9140bb9a81d7db4ad751d7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba78f16080704edeb71d9067d01c0fb0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Select Committee on Strategic Competition between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id09268d000ad74978a10e81c5dc949eed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biotechnology equipment or service</header><text>The term <term>biotechnology equipment or service</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idefdfb94a781e4e4e83854ef24156b785"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equipment, including genetic sequencers, or any other instrument, apparatus, machine, or device, including components and accessories thereof, that is designed for use in the research, development, production, or analysis of biological materials as well as any software, firmware, or other digital components that are specifically designed for use in, and necessary for the operation of, such equipment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id397a978a7f3e4478b5d25c581a16d640"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any service for the research, development, production, analysis, detection, or provision of information, including data storage and transmission related to biological materials, including—</text><clause id="id93aa4a616b544157bad5e9e630d75754"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advising, consulting, or support services with respect to the use or implementation of an instrument, apparatus, machine, or device described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id17d44976e374452a92b4282200778b32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disease detection, genealogical information, and related services; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0286b07e6d8a4cbb9403de91e4c69ebe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other service, instrument, apparatus, machine, component, accessory, device, software, or firmware that is designed for use in the research, development, production, or analysis of biological materials that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the heads of executive agencies, as determined appropriate by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, determines appropriate in the interest of national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb67f26ddcb1849ce8477eeeb3b4f3e4a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contract</header><text>Except as the term is used under subsection (b)(2) and subsection (c)(3), the term <term>contract</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idea8094f1244b44d884bba2dc1dbaf436"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any contract subject to the Federal Acquisition Regulation issued under section 1303(a)(1) of title 41, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d6807da1c9d439bba5943774a5cd09b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any transaction (other than a contract, a grant, or a cooperative agreement) entered into under section 4021 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id86b2c05e149449638a3b64b01382b208"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Control</header><text>The term <term>control</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 800.208 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74e9201eaa234edf867478e3b47e2840"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Executive agency</term> in section 105 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id703c01671cfd4f6ba37a18e46c7e2349"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign adversary</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee4cc87995244df38b48f42a42048322"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Multiomic</header><text>The term <term>multiomic</term> means data types that include genomics, epigenomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c4eb4f496864666b16ba77a76cd7fa7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Overseas</header><text>The term <term>overseas</term> means any area outside of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or a territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd2dc04b277eb4e5586856a490dbfd398"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Compliance with limitation on drug prices</header><text>For the purposes of section 1927(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(a)(1)</external-xref>), a manufacturer is deemed to meet the requirements of section 8126 of title 38, United States Code, including the requirement of entering into a master agreement with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under such section, if the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines that the manufacturer would comply (and has offered to comply) with the provisions of section 8126 of title 38, United States Code, and would have entered into a master agreement under such section, but for the prohibitions under subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

