<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC9114453A250479C95817AA7C32CDA9C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1410 IH: Congratulating the Carolina Hurricanes on winning the 2026 Stanley Cup Championship, the team’s first Stanley Cup win in 20 years.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1410</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Carolina Hurricanes on winning the 2026 Stanley Cup Championship, the team’s first Stanley Cup win in 20 years.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on June 14, 2026, the Carolina Hurricanes (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Hurricanes</quote>) defeated the Las Vegas Golden Knights 3 to 0 in game 6 of the National Hockey League’s Stanley Cup Final;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on their journey to win the 2026 Stanley Cup Final, the Hurricanes had the second-fewest losses by a Stanley Cup winner since 1987—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F6DF8E41E01436CB370CD6A8E83B43B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by sweeping the Ottawa Senators in 4 games in the first round;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE7E5578133D4B4D828911BC635C5144"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by sweeping the Philadelphia Flyers in 4 games in the second round;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86CD7F5652134A29BE955EC45C862EDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by beating the Montreal Canadiens in 5 games to become the Eastern Conference Champions and advance to the Stanley Cup Final series; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59EEA35991984DA2AFED1BCFA7E7D1CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by defeating the Las Vegas Golden Knights in 6 hard-fought games to ultimately win the Stanley Cup Championship;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Hurricanes have brought together fans from across North Carolina, overcoming significant college sports rivalries in unified support to rally around one team;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Hurricanes have shown up for the Raleigh, North Carolina, community through significant fundraising efforts with the Carolina Hurricanes Foundation and support for youth hockey programs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it has been estimated that the Hurricanes’ Stanley Cup Final home games generated $13,400,000 in total economic impact to Wake County, North Carolina, with 3 sold-out games and 3 Lenovo Center watch parties, and even more in revenue for local hotels, restaurants, bars, and retail stores;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Hurricanes have demonstrated a commitment to the Nation’s veterans and wounded warriors through their support of sled-hockey rehabilitation programs, including The North Carolina Warriors Ice Hockey Program, and other unique on-ice opportunities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Hurricanes and the entire Hurricanes community united to support Western North Carolina in its time of need following the devastation of Hurricane Helene in 2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Hurricanes, through their relentless offense, aggressive defense, and unparalleled goaltending, dominated the regular season and won 53 games and scored 291 goals against their opponents;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Lenovo Center is widely regarded as <quote>The Loudest House in the National Hockey League</quote> thanks to Caniacs’ dedicated, vocal passion;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Hurricanes’ victory parade through downtown Raleigh, North Carolina, was, in itself, a record-breaking celebration for the city with nearly 200,000 Caniacs gathered;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Captain Jordan Staal truly <quote>embodies what it means to be a Hurricane</quote> and became the oldest player to earn the Conn Smythe Trophy as the most valuable player in the playoffs, setting the tone from the first moments of the first playoff game;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Hurricanes’ Stanley Cup victory was the result of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4DF9CBFA4AFA40F09BA553763C01D1DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>dauntless goaltending from Frederik Andersen and Brandon Bussi;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16F736217483483780652FE96A478EAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>gutsy overtime-winning goals from Nikolaj Ehlers, Jackson Blake, Seth Jarvis, Taylor Hall, and Jordan Martinook;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE64C84BA56674ED481A0F7376A703817"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the suffocating defensive performances of Jaccob Slavin, K’Andre Miller, Jalen Chatfield, and Alexander Nikishin;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9593916DE6BF44689AD1D5FF57429211"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">valiant contributions from Logan Stankoven, Sebastian Aho, Andrei Svechnikov, Mark Jankowski, Shayne Gostisbehere, Eric Robinson, William Carrier, Sean Walker, Mike Reilly, Nicolas Deslauriers, Jesperi Kotkaniemi, and Pyotr Kochetkov; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H318812AB514D47E5AC87CB7F30449B03"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the unflinching grit and outstanding leadership of Captain Jordan Staal;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Head Coach Rod Brind’Amour has secured his place amongst North Carolina’s long legacy of legendary coaches and became the first person in 70 years to win the Stanley Cup as a player and coach for the same team;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas General Manager Eric Tulsky carefully crafted a winning team with savvy analytics and bold decision-making;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas owner Tom Dundon rejuvenated the Hurricanes’ franchise and invested significantly in hockey in North Carolina;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this Stanley Cup victory would not have been possible without the daily hard work and dedication of the Hurricanes’ and the Lenovo Center’s staff; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the innumerable contributions from every player, coach, and the entire Hurricanes family have brought immeasurable joy to their community and Lord Stanley’s Cup back to where it belongs, Raleigh, North Carolina: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3498B97E0F57497994AC634136F788E7"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H82672CDBE2CD47008E06FA3D08DF34B4"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H9A0D72A4C0F7417BBFDD6BCB5B04CC6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the Carolina Hurricanes for their historic playoffs run, countless contributions to sports, and their many successes as a franchise;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H290D3F4F07C64D6382815585D884756C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates the Carolina Hurricanes on an amazing season and for winning the 2026 Stanley Cup Championship;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H954E4EC4B40D44C08657753E87D2D892"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the players, coaches, staff, leadership, and fans of the Carolina Hurricanes organization;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8499AB6AD73F4D49A22743C3AE900938"><enum>(4)</enum><text>joins with all people in the United States and hockey fans all over the world in celebrating the return of the Stanley Cup to Raleigh, North Carolina;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4537F214DE0447BE9A66C679D05A6EE8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>respectfully directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37D40FAC756643A08107B24C15434285"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the owner and governor of the Carolina Hurricanes, Tom Dundon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC20B4472298B4F6A81EB98B7FC621FFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the general manager of the Carolina Hurricanes, Eric Tulsky; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H606B6C364A3640F4A48D6E399A79751B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the head coach of the Carolina Hurricanes, Rod Brind’Amour; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87AA9C94383F47858D5BC952106B27A2"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>recognizes Raleigh, North Carolina, as a hockey town and the State of North Carolina as a hockey State.</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

