<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF706B964866E4E3BA4D2279C057797DE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8366 IH: Pharmacists Ethical Autonomy and Religious Liberties Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8366</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the religious freedom of pharmacists choosing not to dispense or sell abortion-inducing drugs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C92EC24F8624A4FB0347DD733CDE69F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H035BEE2850114DD3B99FFEBA5E6100D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pharmacists Ethical Autonomy and Religious Liberties Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PEARL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H227614B81DB84A50899DEECC0F886886"><enum>2.</enum><header>Religious freedom protection for pharmacists choosing not to dispense or sell abortion-inducing drugs</header> <subsection id="H48D93B1A8B3044BAB1473F4667F89831"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other law, a pharmacist (including a pharmacist employed by a private business or government agency) shall not be required to dispense or sell, nor be subject to any punishment (including revocation of a license to practice pharmacy or the withdrawal of Federal funding) for choosing not to dispense or sell, the drugs mifepristone and misoprostol for abortion services, if such dispensing or sale would conflict with the sincerely held religious beliefs of the pharmacist.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H18E2F7BE770B45A08D03A1033D6B5731"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A pharmacist who is required to dispense or sell, or is punished for choosing not to dispense or sell, the drugs mifepristone and misoprostol for abortion services in violation of subsection (a) may bring a civil action in Federal district court for injunctive relief against the person imposing such requirement or punishment.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H09C1E7BCBCC24EA8A18EFF269F17EAD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pharmacist defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pharmacist</term> means a person licensed by a State to practice pharmacy, including the dispensing and selling of prescription drugs.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

