<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HFD05F34F0E3E404AAB9033380DA6C879" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5911 EH: Crystal Reservoir Conveyance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5911</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the City of Ouray, Colorado, certain land managed by the Forest Service, together with a reservoir.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H2980B96304694952BE7D07D68D80C9F7">
<section id="H3C9E1AC71E49445282702A1200D9584E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crystal Reservoir Conveyance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1959093D1D574C809053D7198CF60127"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of Federal land to Ouray, Colorado</header> <subsection id="HFEB8611BE7D44C51958417BCB4CFCDFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H6C78952412E4484B8ED9491F977D9CDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>City</header><text>The term <term>City</term> means the City of Ouray, Colorado.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5792B163816470FA823318E664913EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6186E246CD344C80BE6D13FF7FCDA437"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the site known as <quote>Crystal Reservoir</quote> in Ouray County, Colorado, including—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4230976CD076418E8CC54E6E46BFA778"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the lake associated with that reservoir;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2239B396F89A45369B1100DCC97874E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Full Moon Dam and associated facilities, including the spillway and outlet;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF719AF57A1641A1BDF4C66023DB3CAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Full Moon Ditch and Reservoir Number 10; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CB1D6E00BAE40C78AA544967E3EB960"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>all infrastructure associated with the reservoir; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H167318BC7AAD48AB9E7653790A5DA1F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the parcel comprising approximately 45 acres of land underlying and surrounding Crystal Reservoir, as depicted on the Map, managed by the Forest Service as necessary for access for repair, operation, and maintenance of Crystal Reservoir and the features described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB379D6FC60DC405BA432A72C871E6818" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map prepared by the Forest Service entitled <quote>Crystal Reservoir Conveyance</quote> and dated June 23, 2025.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB91A3C7D6668496EB1EC057AE4BDB080"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H32326EA723C547C98B6C01530BF601D6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convey to the City—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19F220C961924FEF8ED8DDA0B0D00F52"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as otherwise provided in this Act, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31B96703AAA543BBBEB70CFDE4571D31" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all right, title and interest of the United States in and to any water rights held for use on, appurtenant to, or otherwise associated with the Federal land, including the Full Moon Ditch and Reservoir Number 10 water rights described in the decree of the State of Colorado in Civil Action No. 1959, dated May 11, 1942.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC3AF2DBE9DB04B10B54A1DCB02AAE542"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The conveyance under subsection (b) shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HB29EA277201749DDBB5125FAA12DC3BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>convey fee simple title to the Federal land;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90C33BF98FC2425ABC9EC68E511D6C90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be subject to—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0046855348FB45EFBAA66268AB9AB8FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">valid existing rights;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5525A7489C5F4E0E9F049D83990CC487"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reservation to the United States, in the deed conveying the Federal land, of easements for each road, trail, and trailhead in existence on the date of the conveyance, together with such additional rights as are reasonably necessary for access, administration, operation, maintenance, repair, and replacement of those improvements; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E9EF4C650124D2BB3E4E9EE1AABB1AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the reversionary interest described in subsection (e)(3); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7744D86193D47EA8FC1C364E389313C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>except as provided in subsection (d)(2), be completed at no cost to the City.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB3BB635D152B4C8B9ADFA72DB574B0A3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs</header>
<paragraph id="H605E76B050784E7F96CFD5A682D8B085"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall pay all costs associated with the conveyance under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A15F51166674B44A07FF3D2C0138703"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>The City shall pay all costs associated with any surveys conducted for the purpose of accomplishing the conveyance under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB6D94F4030B4E0289B5AC2ECADF6444"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1C99E166E924DA7A13B699CE08C0D7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>As a condition of the conveyance of the Federal land under subsection (b), the City shall agree—</text> <subparagraph id="H457951DF6D9C478BBABF79FCD4D35A84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">effective beginning on the date of the conveyance, to assume responsibility for the costs of all repairs, operations, maintenance, replacement, rehabilitation, and regulatory compliance relating to Full Moon Dam and related infrastructure, including Full Moon Ditch and Reservoir Number 10;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H68856EEF5BC24CFFA6F3C15EECE3C760"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to maintain the Federal land in perpetuity as open space, to be held open—</text> <clause id="HA3C42E8A51444EE585933163C9CB4B20"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for public access for recreational activities, including fishing, except as reasonably necessary for public safety, resource protection, emergency response, or the operation, maintenance, repair, replacement, or rehabilitation of Full Moon Dam, Crystal Reservoir, or related infrastructure; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CCAD9D9BECB4973829CF3FD8C7768F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not subject to any fee for recreational access;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0ACDC7FAB09E4EF589393B9D721DC3F9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not to conduct on the Federal land any development, commercial operations, or construction, other than as needed for the operation, maintenance, repair, replacement, rehabilitation, public safety, and regulatory compliance for dam safety of Full Moon Dam, Crystal Reservoir, and related infrastructure, including Full Moon Ditch and Reservoir Number 10; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H285555A057264F25B535EEA0D1163CD6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not to expand the surface footprint of Crystal Reservoir at normal operating levels (as depicted on the Map) in a manner that would flood, impair, or harm any wetlands located upstream of the Federal land, subject to the condition that deepening Crystal Reservoir in a manner consistent with the water rights of the City shall otherwise be allowed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15200BDB716C419C8CBC94CBA2FF8A2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Necessary action agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conveyance under subsection (b) shall be made subject to terms agreed to by the Secretary and the City that authorize the City to take such action on the easements described in subsection (c)(2)(B) as the City determines is reasonable and necessary for—</text>
<subparagraph id="H611C66CA254A43AB8ACD718BEC68C8C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public safety;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA050009F4C234F8F97890226DCB312C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emergency response; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE9BE3D6E0D5C41BCB52260E359A820A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the operation, maintenance, repair, replacement, or rehabilitation by the City of Full Moon Dam, Crystal Reservoir, or related infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE48FF4A155CB4958954223CD5397E448" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other terms and conditions</header><text>The conveyance under subsection (b) shall be subject to such other terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H85C0C435B4D840BFBE4E33F8C964BF08"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reversionary interest</header>
<subparagraph id="H5DD452A7AF9B4279ABAF4DC5B4AF18F0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Written notice</header><text>If the Federal land conveyed under subsection (b) ceases to be used in accordance with the terms and conditions under this subsection the Secretary shall submit to the City written notice with respect to such use.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0170A5196D734AB997B2C9E2E0B9035E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>After the 90-day period beginning on the date written notice is submitted to the City under subparagraph (A), if the Federal land conveyed under subsection (b) continues to be used in a manner not in accordance with the terms and conditions under this subsection during such period, the Federal land shall revert to the United States, at the discretion of the Secretary, if the Secretary determines that reversion is in the best interest of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5C137B936E054F1397D9A16A3DD817A2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Easement</header>
<paragraph id="H605282A05B5B47EA8BD20BC62B799583"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the conveyance under subsection (b), the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="HB2EE235DA34E4B12A327D30E585E6329"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall recognize a perpetual easement for the Red Mountain Ditch for use by the City—</text>
<clause id="H449093C78D7E41458342CD8AA6657026"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the purposes relating to the Ditch specified in the decrees entitled <quote>Case No. 1751-B</quote> and <quote>Case No. 2013CW3040</quote> for the State of Colorado, including the diversion and delivery of water (not to exceed 6 cubic feet per second) for storage in Crystal Reservoir and subsequent beneficial use; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1EAF6328ABD348C89C7A8236AE31ACAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to access, operate, maintain, repair, replace, or improve the Ditch and its appurtenances for such purposes; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2C22EECFB136482FA55511D2E5AE3D21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may require special use authorizations for non-routine maintenance and repairs of Red Mountain Ditch or for the replacement or improvement of the Ditch. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8CF30E06FD64A8CBCC78ADE41BAEC4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Red Mountain Ditch defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>Red Mountain Ditch</quote> means the Ditch known as Red Mountain Ditch constructed in or about 1945 located, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, on lands administered by the San Juan National Forest and the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forest, in Section 14, Township 42 North, Range 8 West, New Mexico Principal Meridian. </text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC061635DBDFA404B92DD28D75C50501F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Water rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the conveyance under subsection (b), the City may use water in Crystal Reservoir for any beneficial use, subject to applicable water laws of the State of Colorado.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE87C6621590F44648077AE30DA6CCA7E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header> <paragraph id="H39D8CC4CA6FB4E4CA881DCC3B2877956"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize the Map and a legal description of the Federal land to be conveyed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2E431562CD9548158B2D5B9EA692016E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the City, by mutual agreement, may correct any clerical or typographical errors in the Map or legal description under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE046D55ECF6D423AB76AFE0C3B22756E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map on file</header><text>The Map and legal description under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in each appropriate office of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260602" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 2, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


