<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7FB16ACCD35E4BFEAA41AA50B6F338B5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8542 IH: Offshore Parity Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8542</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act and the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to provide for the delegation of authority to Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama to manage certain expanded submerged lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F3C8EBA6AD74BBEA404DD4D6DD589D4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF57CD030500D4145B6CFFC1B373B8DF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF174AFA0273B4237A292B9226ED4DD0A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE10BA12258994EBD9DEED890423F10B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide equity to the States of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama with respect to the seaward boundaries of the States in the Gulf of America by delegating management of the submerged lands from 3 geographical miles to 3 marine leagues if the States meet certain conditions not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H866AAD07AB5E4CC29BBB821A586ABBDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in delegating the authority to administer any leases, easements, rights-of-use, and rights-of-way, the States shall ensure that the rights of lessees, operators, and holders of leases, easements, rights-of-use, and rights-of-way on the submerged land are protected; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC3C5F7E58A042CEBAD8620A0A59AACE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to improve the management of fisheries by allowing the States of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama to oversee fisheries management in the expanded seaward boundaries.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF75AD8362B274DFBBF552598C9F787A3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Delegation of the management of oil, gas, and other energy activities on the expanded submerged land of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama</header> <subsection id="HA2E35B7F388C4F1E8AF9563D0D62133D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Delegation</header><text>The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6F751C2A977744CEA909CD9616D6A625" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2127F6D87B624CF79EFA6612510C2CAD"><enum>34.</enum><header>Delegation of the management of oil, gas, and other energy activities on the expanded submerged land of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama</header> 
<subsection id="H83E787780B2D49D5AAF9FC3A81D43BCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3E0748C264574DDDA9184A622245348F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coast line</header><text>The term <quote>coast line</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Submerged Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1301">43 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA97BF3D468B4FB382B02E22A0591822"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expanded submerged land</header><text>The term <quote>expanded submerged land</quote> means the area of the outer Continental Shelf that is located between 3 geographical miles and 3 marine leagues seaward of the coast line of the State as of the day before the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DDD9E29A38F4BDC944C739C368F6DE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H509D47A7A02248B1A9A5ADBFB48DF8F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means Louisiana, Mississippi, or Alabama.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5D96BA5B0A5C4585B28638F4E163EF4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delegation</header><text>Upon written request of a State before the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall, except as provided in subsection (c), delegate to the State the relevant authorities of the Secretary under this Act, except the authority under sections 14 and 20, to grant and manage leases of the expanded submerged land of the State if the Secretary finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB655C61BD33348BD9230A8EC8C0F5210"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it is likely the State will provide adequate resources to carry out such authorities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC47A3745A0FE4F3EA065AD1006F38F7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State has demonstrated that it will effectively and faithfully administer the applicable rules and regulations of the Secretary under this Act, including the requirements of subsection (c) of this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75270C79CB7A4AF09B5A807EF26C7EE7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such delegation will not create an unreasonable burden on any lessee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6CC69821F6544C4987C1829C874B5DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <paragraph id="H0FBE65F369E94760B57A643C6AE016D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No lease or tract divided</header><text>The Secretary may not delegate authority under this section with respect to any lease of an area that is not wholly located within the expanded submerged land of the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF31D5191C1B44238BEEACB42DF613393"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability to existing leases</header><text>The delegation of authority under this section shall apply to any lease of the expanded submerged land of the State granted by the Secretary before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE756F61238D0411D9F64B5385BDF4B4A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No 5 year plan required</header><text>A State to which authority is delegated under this section shall not be required to prepare, revise, or maintain an oil and gas leasing program under section 18.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6895FA64DBE14ABDA3609A7E7FB5B4A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revenue</header> 
<subparagraph id="H644F05B846434E51A80BED913EDFBBDF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Rentals, royalties, and other sums</header><text>A State to which authority is delegated under this section may collect rentals, royalties, and other sums, as determined by the State, from any lease granted after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title> by the State under such authority.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE76981462D75447FA3816C28562258A8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum bid and royalty amounts</header><text>The minimum bid and royalty amounts under section 8 shall not apply to any lease of the expanded submerged land of the State granted by the State after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D23CED2830C4AE191BE564409B46045"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disposition of revenue</header> 
<clause id="H4CCFA40396D64671B494CD50160D4EA3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Existing leases</header><text>The delegation of authority under this section shall not affect the disposition of revenue under any other provision of Federal law from any lease of the expanded submerged land of the State granted before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></clause> <clause id="H989C2270236E4B0C81B9C42ACE33C56A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>New leases</header><text>Section 9 of this Act and section 105 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 shall not apply with respect to a lease granted after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title> by a State under authority delegated under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F32E916D9EC4E248D9A405BFE9B81F1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Citizen suits, court jurisdiction, and judicial review</header><text>Section 23 shall not apply with respect to a lease granted after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title> by a State under authority delegated under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE51C74CA630A41A8A398B7B88452EBEF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Liability</header> <subparagraph id="H1A4A8679B84D4DF0AF258DA4EFC9AC04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State to which authority is delegated by the Secretary under this section shall indemnify the United States for any liability to any holder of an oil, gas, or other energy lease of the expanded submerged land of the State granted before such delegation of authority from the taking of any property interest or breach of contract as a result of—</text> 
<clause id="HE1F1443B4F1D49EBBFFAE47995BECB73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the delegation of such authority; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD49585A78914400BBBB1CF1C5130004E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the management of any such lease.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4D37FF614A640458B825FF2AB77AE11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deduction from oil and gas leasing revenues</header><text>The Secretary may deduct from the amounts otherwise payable to a State under section 8(g)(2) the amount of any final nonappealable judgment for a taking or breach of contract by such State described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D3ACD2EE74547E7A8A9A828FE778213"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Transfer of bonds</header> <subparagraph id="H008BD8DAF0DB40ADA4911F6A05FBD324"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after delegating authority under this section, the Secretary shall transfer any surety bonds for oil, gas, or other energy leases of the expanded submerged land of a State granted before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Offshore Parity Act of 2026</short-title> to the applicable State. The applicable State shall ensure that any decommissioning of a facility with respect to such leases is carried out in accordance with applicable Federal law, including regulations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE71CBE59DCED42F3A1F54DDC75EE46D1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to transfer bonds</header><text>If the Secretary does not transfer a surety bond for a lease under subparagraph (A) by the deadline described in such subparagraph, the Secretary shall ensure that any decommissioning of a facility with respect to such lease is carried out in accordance with applicable Federal law, including regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB82457D4BFD346999876B0E28B29A653"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Seaward boundary of louisiana, mississippi, and alabama</header><text>Section 8(g) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7AD55C8B1363499E950F66100B997201" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HFC41CC3A017E4C24A02122B86715F79B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definition of seaward boundary of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>seaward boundary</quote> means, with respect to each of the States of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama, 3 marine leagues seaward of the coast line (as that term is defined in section 2 of the Submerged Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1301">43 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>)) of each such State as each such coast line exists as of the day before the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H27CCB16E0B21430793093171FAC48614"><enum>4.</enum><header>State jurisdiction under Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act</header> <subsection id="H7F5CCA01D6A44E76B59F79B5AFBF5B2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 306(a)(2) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1856">16 U.S.C. 1856(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCC3E700698504C1683527229435DA796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10882A167CB24E24A81405602BAFD4BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H140B880E17064DF8A5DA0F16B79F87A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H657982ACDA9448FB9536394F4D3B02EA" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H32DD77F8ECD440E7A7232EC2525A43CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with respect to each of the States of Alabama, Louisiana, and Mississippi, to 3 marine leagues seaward of the coast line (as that term is defined in section 2 of the Submerged Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1301">43 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>)) of each such State as each such coast line exists as of the day before the date of the enactment of this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC145D74391024D00988683C35F722462"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> 
<paragraph id="HD320575060A7492F9DD986DA73B183D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Highly migratory species</header><text>The amendments made by this section may not be construed to limit or otherwise affect the authority of the Federal Government with respect to highly migratory species, species listed as a threatened species or an endangered species pursuant to the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), or fishery resources subject to international agreements as provided under Federal law, including the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>), the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), and relevant international treaties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC65132D8ABE4B1CA011F3F8A50FFF0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal jurisdiction</header><text>The amendments made by this section may not be construed to limit or otherwise affect the authority of the Federal Government under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H394858835D8A40F29C47D9C869D52273"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exclusive economic zone beyond the extended State waters of a covered State; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63A3ABBD07784E9BBB18E1DA4FBAD2C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>activities within the extended State waters of a covered State that relate to national security, international obligations, or other matters reserved for Federal authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEFEB07D5D4814A1185B69364B00ED61A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2128CD9A45EF4477B1A68CD7E0D04364"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coast line</header><text>The term <quote>coast line</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Submerged Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1301">43 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3FEC909FA8C46FAA874ADBD71857E73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered state</header><text>The term <quote>covered State</quote> means each of the States of Alabama, Louisiana, and Mississippi.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEDA87250C304FDCABD055BA275F1EBD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusive economic zone</header><text>The term <quote>exclusive economic zone</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5839743EE22E4AC1838AEDCD45E88812"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Extended state waters</header><text>The term <quote>extended State waters</quote> means 3 marine leagues seaward of the coast line of a covered State as each such coast line exists as of the day before the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA10F102F7F7B435495ED39EC33D64FEA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fishery resource</header><text>The term <quote>fishery resource</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55CB25C1AEDE47D6A2BF90C8D92E6BD9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Highly migratory species</header><text>The term <quote>highly migratory species</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

