<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H15DF2119DEE944AD9312C8C36A7B8074" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9230 IH: Statutory Term Limits on Congressional Pay and Power Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9230</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit a Member of Congress from serving as chair or ranking minority member of a committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate after 12 years of service in the House or the Senate, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF49810DAC94045A1A15881C1F6615085" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA4BB37B7BA2C4BB588B0897E8D545DB2" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Statutory Term Limits on Congressional Pay and Power Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H92CC4F65F15E4D69A787E2755725D92D" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restrictions on Members of Congress after certain period of service</header> <subsection id="H88876BB3BDC4465BA93F60517391557A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member of Congress (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) who has served 12 or more cumulative years in the House of Representatives or in the Senate, as the case may be, may not, on and after the date that the Member reaches 12 years of service in the Member’s respective House of Congress, be eligible for any covered benefit described in <internal-xref idref="H9C78812E437847DCB942C8C934AEB76A" legis-path="2.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C78812E437847DCB942C8C934AEB76A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered benefit described</header><text>A covered benefit described in this subsection is any of the following: </text> <paragraph id="HE93346D6C7DA42C0B9B4ED1D13EE082D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any payment otherwise required to be made with respect to a pay period for the compensation of the Member of Congress under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5723C5684BC4512B66390AC8DB8994A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Serving as the chair or ranking minority member of any standing or select committee in the House of Representatives or the Senate or in a House or Senate leadership position.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H06632D1BAB804CC1B02C8286CA9B8FA5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>House or Senate leadership position defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>House or Senate leadership position</term> means any of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7469A051F286427FBE25B8B79E6339B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of any office of the House of Representatives for which the appropriation for salaries and expenses of the office for a fiscal year is provided under the heading <quote>House Leadership Offices</quote> in the act making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year involved.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DF07085058C45EFA8407AC8CEDB162B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President pro Tempore, Majority or Minority Leader, Majority or Minority Whip, chair of the Majority or Minority Conference Committee, or chair of the Majority or Minority Policy Committee of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H36A682EA78EA478AAC826DA9D6268971" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of House of Representatives and Senate</header><text>This section is enacted by Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H5B462862A27945D3A4F198D59DF1F324" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and House of Representatives, respectively, and as such are deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution, and they supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1401324BC88438FB518A4870C5F26D9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBD1EE6D5D0F945FC98CA2F5D19263DFB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The prohibition under this section shall apply with respect to the One Hundred Twenty-First Congress and each succeeding Congress. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

