<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25015-FJR-XC-90C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3729 IS: PBM Reporting Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) submit to Congress two reports on agreements with pharmacy benefit managers with respect to prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PBM Reporting Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc157e724e70745489ecc6434be4a3efd"><enum>2.</enum><header>MedPAC reports on agreements with pharmacy benefit managers with respect to prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall submit to Congress the following reports:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01a6fe9d9fa3428fa5fdeeb0c1eeab06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than the first March 15 occurring after the date that is 2 years after the date on which the Secretary makes the data available to the Commission, a report regarding agreements with pharmacy benefit managers with respect to prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans. Such report shall include, to the extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="id92182fa64c774c29a6e38bc09356f0c7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of trends and patterns, including relevant averages, totals, and other figures for the types of information submitted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8df1b4e169b74e8a93a808b077ea176f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of any differences in agreements and their effects on plan enrollee out-of-pocket spending and average pharmacy reimbursement, and other impacts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef514e80897a4147be5cd672321a713e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any recommendations the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc365e050280746d28e6a8c38d4384109"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Commission submits the initial report under paragraph (1), a report describing any changes with respect to the information described in paragraph (1) over time, together with any recommendations the Commission determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

