<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT26125-C28-LP-JDL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4053 IS: To take certain land in the State of California into trust for the benefit of the Pechanga Band of Indians, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4053</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260311">March 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To take certain land in the State of California into trust for the benefit of the Pechanga Band of Indians, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="HB6E2BBBF67A04CDAADE2F68D1E9FD8F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Transfer of land into trust for the Pechanga Band of Indians</header><subsection id="HC1CF0FD4E6A144B1AC258B0E722FF07E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights and the conditions described in subsection (c), the covered land is hereby taken into trust for the benefit of the Tribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H968A475F9D5441E6AF10448A4054014D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall be—</text><paragraph id="HB5DE0F87AD594A94829A2699B5C184E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>part of the reservation of the Tribe; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0421C85CDBCF4BBC96992864E56ED575"><enum>(2)</enum><text>administered in accordance with the laws and regulations generally applicable to property held in trust by the United States for the benefit of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA302F6331964DF2AEA26F4B6C43F80A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions</header><paragraph id="H498F4744EBB547548E59201015935B0F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HF3E6469E2A9342E283699CB73B65612F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to all valid encumbrances, liens, rights-of-way, reciprocal road rights-of-way agreements, licenses, leases, permits, and easements existing on the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2501A749BE3F43749EDA8E1C02E033FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintained as open space; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC1D5C0D513E4A148A290878542111DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>used only for—</text><clause id="H458137251C5A49FB852B2DDB1A475055"><enum>(i)</enum><text>purposes consistent with the maintenance of the land as open space; and</text></clause><clause id="HB0E75C7A11B241849CBAD20B996D5436"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the protection, preservation, and maintenance of the archaeological, cultural, and wildlife resources on the land.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30819DD05D0448D8A8FA5AB0E4282CC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Construction and maintenance</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph prohibits the construction or maintenance of utilities or structures that are—</text><subparagraph id="HA62BAB0D0B184A5B91FA0FF6F2857A88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with the maintenance of the land taken into trust under subsection (a) as open space; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3626BB03AC464C179E1A76AB3F21BC86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>constructed for the protection, preservation, and maintenance of the archaeological, cultural, and wildlife resources on the land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5E38D76BF9C4F34BB388D4FC864FC6C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on gaming</header><text>The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall not be used for any class II gaming or class III gaming under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (as those terms are defined in section 4 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48850AB84A9B400DBBD960C2EF52DCFC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rights and agreements</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall alter, or require the alteration of, any existing water rights or service agreements.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB56CE6A1B7FD4D7086D5AD373CD7E042"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Map on file</header><text>The Map shall be kept on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subsection><subsection id="H327B9D131EDD46EB906538BBE8A3102A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6F230D240F0C4D4B9B706CC3F5B72860"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered land</header><text>The term <term>covered land</term> means all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the approximately 860 acres of land in Riverside County, California, administered by the Bureau of Land Management and generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Pechanga Land Conveyance Parcel</quote> on the Map.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DF88CD7B4724B6696D3A4B0C68F7EAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map titled <quote>BLM Lands into Trust for the Pechanga Band of Indians</quote>, and dated August 21, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6728019B0C354DA8A8ED35D4D2EBFEB7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEC518C3762E431E8D5C144C6D12E29D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Pechanga Band of Indians.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

