<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H76DA20A2C20F4A699DE8D8A915F6188E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8470 IH: Surveillance Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8470</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to ensure that all searches that significantly impinge on the privacy or security of a person require a warrant based on probable cause, to provide a right of action for violations of Fourth Amendment rights, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB1BB60CE6AB34636B5C7DB52EE777CED" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEC3C44CBCB9640D8B6597FCD7C81632A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Surveillance Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5EABBCFF3A22480CB3B98FEC9A3A307E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Warrant requirement for searches</header> <subsection id="H95B8F6BBD1654B78843134BDC67A288A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/205">Chapter 205</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HBDC01FC851A1471EBEE3BDE27009F659" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HDED5F86BDFE14B96BF6DA81DDE89F636"><enum>3119.</enum><header>Searches to accord with the Fourth Amendment</header> 
<subsection id="H431BDE5468EA435D9D2560F94B25A866"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Warrant requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="H54161371CB6B4D9A92F34379B7D72355"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), no search may be conducted without a warrant issued by a neutral and detached magistrate upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation, and particularly describing the place to be searched and the persons or things to be seized.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28757E6375CB44DDA7421A1B3ED9E65A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Third-Party Data</header> <subparagraph id="H99938AF3C9AF4AD190FC8E1FFC5A5E83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Presumption of privacy</header><text>The government shall not access any data, metadata, or personal information held by a third party, including financial services providers, telecommunication service providers, internet service providers, cloud storage companies, or data brokers, without a valid warrant, regardless of whether the third party consents or cooperates.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF940ED1F1DD6477DA424663EE16C3794"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception invalidated</header><text>No contractual agreement between a user and a third party may be interpreted as waiving the government’s warrant requirement for access to the data of that user, unless such waiver is knowing, voluntary, and explicit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC26F807954DE4C39B5B556C34297E7D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The following may be conducted without a warrant:</text> 
<paragraph id="H26FAE207B80C4DCC885BDEAEBD9E588E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Plain-view searches.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12DA426AD34C402C9E0EC4D21846B8BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The verification of government-issued primary photo identification documents during a stop of a motor vehicle, travel, or other interactions with law enforcement, including the verification of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F9BD0540B864E92A94C442948992EE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State identification card;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0C7261BA2164A38BDBBA447ECBC3F0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a driver’s license;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE114C47344D24B768A4270B89C8A688F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a passport;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC63965A6D6342208B2C70D720714C9C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a passport card;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H317781033B6D4FD8993D9F90B55379AA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a military identification; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB03DCE685464490794FA8D6AAA96E5FC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a permanent resident card.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H329A70FA4F0C4FD09C18D4CC5FE01882"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The collection or analysis of information that is lawfully published or voluntarily made available by a person or entity to a public audience, and which requires no circumvention of privacy settings, encryption, or other access controls.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC36A260669C415995DC6AECCE944A0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The use of lawful investigative techniques to collect data from publicly available sources such as new outlets, official government publications, public records, or user-posted content that is clearly accessible to the general public without special access or tools.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF419B5A2BDD449B4A187C0239E6D2276"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Searches conducted with consent.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2805031824F04EC8BD1F8BAB64430D0C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Searched conducted under exigent circumstances.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4CC54F3B7E17451E830469CF9E97022B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The exceptions described in subsection (b) shall not be construed to permit the warrantless collection, retention, querying, or analysis of data exposed to public view or accessible to a third party if the person associated with the collected identifiers did not express informed and voluntary consent to such collection with respect to data gathered by entering a public place, operating a motor vehicle on a public roadway, or patronizing a private establishment open to the public, including—</text> <paragraph id="HE39EF3EE062A4D779CCE1393ED2C8320"><enum>(1)</enum><text>biometric data, including facial images, faceprints, gait, voice recognition, or other unique physical identifiers, obtained through facial recognition systems or comparable surveillance technologies; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47EE9A07E1A34E1085074BBB3F2E0F1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>license plate images, vehicle metadata, or vehicle movement patterns obtained through automated license plate readers or similar systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2209F72688554985A304C972D1605C42"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitons</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H129224D4EB4F4F34B7A84F4174C76CE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Search</header><text>The term <quote>search</quote> means any government-initiated act that intrudes upon an individual’s reasonable expectation of privacy, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF3EFC16F88C7466A8F13FEF1F3D43104"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Investigatory acts</header><text>Any investigatory act purposefully directed at a specific person or entity, or the property of a specific person or entity, with the intent of obtaining information not otherwise available to the public.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48EA4437160D4DD89A507D092F8A8A16"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Government surveillance and monitoring</header><text>Any non-consensual surveillance, monitoring, or inquiry conducted by a government entity or its agents, whether through human, digital, or automated means, that collects information on a specific individual or entity, including information on that individual or entity’s—</text> <clause id="H2C9D43B333F3451FBF462F3BE1D2A947"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communications;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4D20A8ED0C2B4CADBDD1BE92AA17BA4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>associations;</text></clause> <clause id="H210DA63FD9D2452A9148FF0C8B711F3F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H74BCB80C163C4407A5815103BD1E772D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>social media usage;</text></clause> <clause id="HBF6FF32CB8014F31AD152343122184B7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>internet usage;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEC88FEDB15B741F38A70A782320D8564"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>financial transactions; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA5C04847F79D45BEA8642FEB19FF3715"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>travel.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD1A46D9AABB4500B85A72FBBE81E96B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Collection of personal data</header><text>The acquisition and analysis of any data, metadata, or information pertaining to a person’s digital or physical life, including—</text> <clause id="H5A6D9023057A449CA9EC5E22A2826E98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geolocation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC1E298E25EFD4C55B181E88DDD67AF12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communication records;</text></clause> <clause id="HE65CFF647BBF4402B5F927311C7435C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>personal device activity;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1AB600AC7403416C99D0054B258F1C1B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assets;</text></clause> <clause id="H77BD142A33B84C61AD48F2F9DA6541C6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>liabilities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H48D93F4B39A94D10BFA7C58CE68BB761"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>biometric identifiers;</text></clause> <clause id="HADAF5CB1875D4DBF9494F5825749E9BB"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>behavioral signals data; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H13E5ED9F6B5B40648E9D720F6AA34EB5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>financial transactions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA1C0EEA90FB43A88FB7D820F02F67C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plain-view searches defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>plain-view searches</quote> means the observation or seizure of evidence by a law enforcement officer who is lawfully present at a location, where the incriminating nature of the evidence is immediately apparent, and where such observation is incidental to the officer’s lawful presence and does not involve the use of enhanced surveillance technology or systematic monitoring.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB72CF82D49084A18990F33CCDC712258"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="HC115765B30164FDE823D76BA1304959A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modify, supersede, or limit any existing constitutional protection, or to authorize surveillance that would otherwise be unlawful;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81F56CE42C8A413DA128B35EB03263B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>eliminate or restrict constitutionally recognized exceptions permitting brief investigatory detentions or protective frisks based on reasonable suspicion; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E4DC89EEB5C4F71BBF0C6342B380977"><enum>(3)</enum><text>eliminate or restrict the authority of law enforcement officers to conduct brief investigatory detentions, protective frisks, arrests, or searches incident to ordinary criminal law enforcement encounters.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H981E620CE5004472A598FAC7301B9552"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/205">chapter 205</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAECB3842140A44E680B8B9AEC18FD26F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">3119. Searches to accord with the Fourth Amendment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H0F0F632487FF4644AE306B5FF0BC6846"><enum>3.</enum><header>Right of action for violations of Fourth Amendment rights</header> <subsection id="HB825D35F97664888A6555816EFD46536"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Revised Statutes are amended by inserting after section 1979 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6731214A94F34CB89A50E317B6170EBC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HEBE5EBDBA996438A894B54317BB3F4AF"><enum>1979A.</enum><header>Deprivation of Fourth Amendment rights</header> 
<subsection id="HBB904D00B18349DC85DF9CD0B9FFACDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Every person, including a Federal employee, who, under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage, of the United States, subjects, or causes to be subjected, any citizen of the United States or any person within the jurisdiction thereof to the deprivation of any rights, privileges, or immunities secured by the Fourth Amendment, shall be liable to the party injured in an action at law, suit in equity, or other proper proceeding for redress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE5495D6985B44526A2E1FF98D74107E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees</header><text>In any action, suit, or proceeding to enforce this Act, the court, in its discretion, may allow the prevailing party, other than the United States, a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H85EE0A7F31CE48B09F20D65E44EDAF16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal employee defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Federal employee</quote> means an individual other than the President or the Vice President, who occupies a position in any agency or instrumentality of the executive branch (including any independent agency).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8DFF64A32B894C058B4792421F484041"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize a Federal employee to bring a suit against their Federal employer or the Federal Government for conduct that is within the scope of the employment relationship.</text></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F02BBC524F84E84A09444D68591272C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of this Act, to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

