<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H508A374ABC0C4810911C9AEEAC981D71" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7108 IH: Improving Public Housing Agency Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7108</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve public housing agency accountability.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC88F6A6BA0354DD5AD4C8D77BAB8E632" style="OLC"><section id="H44502CB2744347E989A712A252244C4D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Public Housing Agency Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD643FD448EFD42D4B182BDFB022E98DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notice and review of receivers or Federal monitors of public housing agencies</header><subsection id="HE64656C3851D4929AD10156129FAA897"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall require each covered public housing agency to provide a notice each year to the Secretary that—</text><paragraph id="HFE3D038C3C1A4F1E98680C05A80256D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>indicates whether a receiver or Federal monitor remains appointed for the covered public housing agency as of October 1 of the calendar year to which such notice relates;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F1B29AC52CB448A8F5DD5F8F4831825"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides the date on which the receiver or Federal monitor was first appointed and the projected date, if known, the appointment of the receiver or Federal monitor will be terminated; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E124395EDF4EE7B53FA5F90F1205E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies the current receiver or Federal monitor appointed to oversee the public housing agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E685FE74C34455089A1C666E81A0DED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspector general review</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a written request from the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Inspector General shall provide to the requesting committee an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="H0B600020B566484BB7469A5C2C8A8956"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of any covered public housing agency’s compliance with any agreements entered into between the covered public housing agency and the Department of Housing and Urban Development, including specific areas of deficiency and progress toward compliance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98E51F99084745459176A3FF5E3385C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a review of actions taken by the receiver or Federal monitor appointed to oversee a covered public housing agency and any private sector housing development partners pursuant to such agreement, including any gaps in oversight by the receiver or Federal monitor;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DAF30C47ACB4515AF48CC3208C17B06"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the physical conditions of housing provided by the covered public housing agency, including the status of the covered public housing agency’s compliance with relevant health and safety requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H870206CC5F6141E7B1D701D7B29431BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an examination of any allegations of waste, fraud, abuse or violations of Federal law committed by employees or contractors of the covered public housing agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28AE734B96A94B3A88C972D7DC7BD2FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any additional pertinent information, as determined necessary and appropriate by the Inspector General; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F61C4E231C5490184D931D33141468F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Inspector General that relate to how to improve the compliance of the covered public housing agency with any agreements entered into with the Department of Housing and Urban Development or enhance the oversight of the receiver or Federal monitor over such covered public housing agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AF0828487C34C25AC8D0691DACF81C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEBEFA35433A14AAB91D9BB7AF4E629E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered public housing agency</header><text>The term <term>covered public housing agency</term> means a public housing agency (as such term is defined in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>)) for which an administrative or judicial receiver or Federal monitor was appointed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE231FE5C0BA49A98C2952403D50C2F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inspector General</header><text>The term <term>Inspector General</term> means the Inspector General of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB33E755A00C4E60A851E8468C7D9DB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

