<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25G95-WC1-MM-FL0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3377 IS: To delay the implementation of a rule relating to the importation of sheep and goats and products derived from sheep and goats, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3377</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To delay the implementation of a rule relating to the importation of sheep and goats and products derived from sheep and goats, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idb3a268b753444b4eabea8e33568489c8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Delayed implementation of rule relating to importation of sheep and goats and products derived from sheep and goats</header><subsection id="id23cfc878ad7a444f8464ae5bb4cd47c6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the date that is 1 year after the date on which the report is submitted under subsection (b), the Secretary of Agriculture, and any other Federal official, may not finalize, implement, administer, or enforce the proposed rule entitled <quote>Importation of Sheep, Goats, and Certain Other Ruminants</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 46619) and dated July 18, 2016.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide32ab6d185994e16a106a7565d69730f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report</header><paragraph id="id9e50d796b0c248a796e1d1c448de287d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><subparagraph id="idC1A782FF7099456490585F603CBC7BBA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study on the potential costs and benefits of the rule referred to in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73F0E5616057441EB16BB0B748FDFCF8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study required by subparagraph (A) shall assess—</text><clause id="id80cc13fa9b554265801f014df992af4a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the estimated amount of sheep and goat meat imported into the United States as a result of the implementation of the rule referred to in subsection (a);</text></clause><clause id="idfd53dfebca5248f38b1f097ce5e2330d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the estimated increase in the number of live sheep and goats imported into the United States as a result of the rule;</text></clause><clause id="ida4f346e3371d45daaa8b9a34a739753d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the estimated demand for sheep and goat meat in the United States during the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, disaggregated by region and State;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id0feb224adbe245e2aa4452991b0c9a8d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the impact of the COVID–19 pandemic on the economic data and market conditions for imports of sheep and goat meat and live sheep and goats;</text></clause><clause id="id469295468a2f450d8b679e8e98463a83"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the potential effects of the rule on—</text><subclause id="id46857CD1248E4CCB8670158CC0667F54"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the supply and prices of live sheep and goats in the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7601686341C243F3AAD311BD98417857"><enum>(II)</enum><text>producers of and markets for live sheep and goats in the United States, disaggregated by region and State;</text></subclause><subclause id="idb191e0690a7149b0887ad89ab6c0f2f2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>export opportunities for United States producers of sheep and goat meat;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0174BF1AA1E7437F90CE10AD5DB7CB89"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the competitiveness of the sheep and goat industries in the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0fc5db8e5ae24c54b54edf0ad78a2f9d"><enum>(V)</enum><text>consumer confidence in sheep and goat meat;</text></subclause><subclause id="idB0964DE81E534010BD274C88CEEF03C5"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the health of sheep and goat herds in the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id61262BE1E08B4DCC9204FBA63FAB8BF2"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>disease outbreaks across species of animals;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idd411b6cd0a634a849e574c5bf87786ed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the estimated amount of direct payments made by foreign countries to producers of live sheep and goats in such countries as a result of the implementation of the rule referred to in subsection (a); and</text></clause><clause id="idcd3d470a8a61475ea1b3b2bf9ca5e07b"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any negative impacts that could result from the implementation of the rule referred to in subsection (a) not covered by clauses (i) through (vi).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38db8ed87bfe497f94500e2023fdf8f0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="idCD6BCFF64A354535B0DF9E07F9DC4583"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the committees specified in subparagraph (B) a report that includes—</text><clause id="idc7123ddf592646499494e40dc9e16712"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an analysis of the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="id60e1ff1bec8d40e1ad9100ac218e5654"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations for changes to the rule referred to in subsection (a) to eliminate or mitigate any negative effects of the implementation of the rule.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id244E01965E0547DDAF8FF5984D06C446"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Committees specified</header><text>The committees specified in this subparagraph are—</text><clause id="id4fff3a69c8eb4d39a9e9d812a9a52111"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="idd42c206994f341a2bdbf4c722fb34147"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

