<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO26150-25Y-2J-TYD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3878 IS: To establish the Grand Village of the Natchez Indians and Jefferson College as affiliated areas of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3878</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Grand Village of the Natchez Indians and Jefferson College as affiliated areas of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id676cda34f236450f88d2dbe5acccdbdd" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of the Grand Village of the Natchez Indians and Jefferson College as affiliated areas of the National Park System</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dff4f3d5d424a18a8d06cc479adf38c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="id255f48484f664a64bc0b100ed71b984b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliated area</header><text>The term <term>affiliated area</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8c59dd1916e451dbfd22226e01be071"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Grand Village of the Natchez Indians in Natchez, Mississippi, established as an affiliated area of the National Park System by subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c118e2e71ec44b2ba6f4cdd086b1ba9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Historic Jefferson College in Natchez, Mississippi, established as an affiliated area of the National Park System under subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id618f1036b7df4ac199fbf852dd4bcc68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The term <term>management entity</term> means the management entity for the affiliated areas designated by subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1809e63b6fd4500acf3a0373845b68f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Affiliated Areas, Adams County, Mississippi Proposed Boundaries</quote>, numbered 964/194,653, and dated August 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id482db8d998ee4244b06d136d6e8d7901"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcd14198624f54363bea0ee49e53c148c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="idde2dd0eb31d7414c9a37587ce9f9096b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grand village of the natchez indians</header><text>To promote public appreciation of the significant historic contributions of the Natchez Indians, the Grand Village of the Natchez Indians in Natchez, Mississippi, as generally depicted on the Map, is established as an affiliated area of the National Park System.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7ea65a398e64cb782e1889aa4735395"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historic jefferson college</header><text>On the date on which the Secretary determines that Historic Jefferson College in Natchez, Mississippi, as generally depicted on the Map, meets National Park Service criteria for designation as an affiliated area, Historic Jefferson College, shall be established as an affiliated area of the National Park System.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb8ebf747f014e46b8a10e5df431bb72"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><subparagraph id="id3cd5e5a6bb6943a7a0fd35734678325c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the establishment of an affiliated area in accordance with this section, the Secretary shall prepare a map depicting the boundaries of the applicable affiliated area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7aea74bcf6154e1489cbec6a169c77f8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The map prepared under subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd9ad38b2a4ae420c90b37ce0e1a7934e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The affiliated areas shall be managed in a manner consistent with—</text><paragraph id="id3bca723edd4742eaaa07580fb7c8fa9c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2fae033a8b845c9ac26aed954d96fb1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3ca86f5286e44f8d9b2b97f811c89699"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The Mississippi Department of Archives and History shall be the management entity for the affiliated areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfa639f0ab99c497fac2b5b872a0c6846"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Secretary—</text><paragraph id="id1a64bc89f7ed46d5abc458f7df3a45c2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may provide technical assistance to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the management entity for the purpose of providing financial assistance for the marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the affiliated areas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfcc8b8c4418542ea8a11dfd994737c93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall enter into an agreement with the management entity that delineates the roles and responsibilities for the management of the affiliated areas consistent with the policies and standards that apply to units of the National Park System.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id348a7d2434b74933b7f2429c77b44549"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limited role of the secretary</header><text>Nothing in this section authorizes the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="id157054c3509a460aa8bcca154a35b935"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to acquire property at the affiliated areas; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ff8618ab5be47d2afecdd510f075b2c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assume financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the affiliated areas.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

