<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HC849119FA5EE40ECA4269412B9DC3EF2"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6735 IH: Connecting Caregivers to Medicare Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6735</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for outreach and education to Medicare beneficiaries to simplify access to information for family caregivers through 1–800–MEDICARE, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE4528E33D89D446283C5B288073470AF"> 
<section id="H3A39FCBDB716424DBE47769859795F4B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Connecting Caregivers to Medicare Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9BC1953B9B824F75B7D1C436661BBC55"><enum>2.</enum><header>Outreach and education to Medicare beneficiaries to simplify access to information for family caregivers through 1–800-MEDICARE</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1804 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395b-2">42 U.S.C. 1395b–2</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B9CE58A33F4483C9F5FE0C19DB268A8"> 
<subsection id="HE27AD99B568F40068CB19DDB4A9537E7"><enum>(e)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFD5BBE8D32EF4EDBA6704BAEAEB5658C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide for such outreach and education activities as are necessary, including as described in paragraph (2), to inform individuals entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B and individuals applying for benefits under part A or enrolling under part B about the option to authorize a family caregiver (as defined in paragraph (8)(A)) of such an individual to access the personal health information of such individual through the toll-free 1–800-MEDICARE telephone number maintained by the Secretary under subsection (b) if such individual completes and submits a specified family caregiver information access authorization form (as defined in paragraph (8)(B)) authorizing such access by such family caregiver to such information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEE2C3C938574FB6A261A02B72235975"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The outreach and education activities under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7F84248BD614D069E0E72C4054ACD69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Outreach and education efforts to provide information about the option described in paragraph (1) to individuals described in such paragraph, to providers of services and suppliers furnishing services to such individuals, to family caregivers, and to other appropriate entities specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2865014E90DC4B869AEDA898F972D27D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Outreach and education efforts to inform such individuals, providers of services and suppliers, family caregivers, and other appropriate entities of best practices identified pursuant to paragraph (4) to protect such individuals from fraudulent practices described in such paragraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25F44BE73A3240A5B9CF2F21EAF2B42C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Outreach and education efforts to individuals described in paragraph (1) to inform such individuals of all existing reporting mechanisms for suspected Medicare fraud.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89D84F4CCCED4F00B31EC7559C3075D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The inclusion of information about the option described in paragraph (1), and best practices identified pursuant to paragraph (4), in a manner that is prominent, easily accessible, and readily understandable—</text> 
<clause id="HD350B0CF69B0469EB18DD034C073AB1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the notice under subsection (a);</text></clause> <clause id="H82AB6D577E18411FAF7EA69EBFFF1AA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>through the Medicare.gov website or a successor website;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9BDBE40EE48D4763A30D92A26DDC565E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>through other efforts specifically conducted for individuals enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan under part C; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5D340FB5416F475599B2EDF571ACCB18"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>through other platforms or methods specified by the Secretary, such as social media.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA517A309099A4829B63DBA3F1020A576"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The inclusion, in a manner that is prominent, easily accessible, and readily understandable, of the specified family caregiver information access authorization form in the notice under subsection (a), through—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2157C58C3276474698CCCDCC0D575E0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the website described in subparagraph (D)(ii); and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FB7301A7CDF464F933B884591690628"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other efforts described in subparagraph (D)(iii).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0395986BE6204BE784AAE48FFD8C87A4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Education efforts to train operators of 1–800-MEDICARE on providing appropriate resources and information to family caregivers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD6C991EC8E649D4BFFC77A9F4553052" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Information about the option described in paragraph (1) provided through efforts described in paragraph (2) shall include a notification clarifying that such option is available to all individuals described in paragraph (1) regardless of whether such individuals are enrolled for the original Medicare fee-for-service option under part A or B or enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFA7CD012B3042CB8D17FFE21C8A0802" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary, acting through the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available best practices to protect individuals described in paragraph (1) against fraud relating to inappropriately accessing or using the personal health information of such individuals, including best practices for educating beneficiaries on fraud reporting mechanisms, and recommendations to improve timely agency investigation of beneficiary fraud reports. The Secretary shall provide for, as the Secretary determines appropriate, separate best practices for individuals described in paragraph (1), family caregivers, providers of services and suppliers, and other entities specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H712697E5FE314C509A7A7FA3080CE0B0" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide for opportunities (such as through surveys) for family caregivers to provide feedback to the Secretary on experiences accessing information through 1–800-MEDICARE and on the outreach and education activities conducted under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H579058EB7D4A48B082981685BDC34BF7" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The outreach and education activities conducted under this subsection, and the specified family caregiver information access authorization form, shall be made available in non-English languages, as specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H247E4F990E5848B08BFF21931B8CE190" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In conducting the outreach and education activities under this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the greatest extent practicable, coordinate such activities with activities carried out through State health insurance assistance programs or the Administration for Community Living.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF227F67EEE364E98AAB16F6ECB60543F" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H01123029508F4BA4A7C80B40C39800C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>family caregiver</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Recognize, Assist, Include, Support, and Engage Family Caregivers Act of 2017, and includes such other individuals as specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2158D4C4419C431A82895170D9EFF3FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>specified family caregiver information access authorization form</term> means the CMS–10106 form or any successor form.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


