<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ26288-WSJ-G2-9C2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4475 IS: Unlock American Energy and Jobs Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve Federal permitting, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unlock American Energy and Jobs Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3ca3cf9b3e0424eba61215e7b3371f1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Energy infrastructure under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act</header><subsection id="id2FCDF4795ED941E1A79A727EE7DD005B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State certification programs</header><text>Section 401 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1341">33 U.S.C. 1341</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idD2558D4ACA2B44AC9534C6FF78766968"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the heading and section designation and all that follows through <quote>may be.</quote> at the end of subsection (a)(1) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="idADAF68EBF53940249D926CBEAED239B7" style="OLC" act-name=""><section id="id666A9A25C3AE48C698EE4831945FE9E9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>401.</enum><header>Certification</header><subsection id="idE5048FC542B04DE390E02C527B50E7BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State certifications</header><paragraph id="id7BB03DB6C9B446E3BB12750AA5921AE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification required</header><subparagraph id="idE6B8297B1D464B2C94ADBDF16016A3AC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="id9F732F5D09424952A75B1E0E5F0DCDF3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Certification application</header><text>The term <term>certification application</term> means a request from an applicant for a certification described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause id="idDC281B31A1B74E2A833A49E358351B58"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certifying authority</header><text>The term <term>certifying authority</term>, with respect to a certification described in subparagraph (B), means the applicable entity described in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of subparagraph (B)(i).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf77d1b65f1634ad7af5c68cf99b18198"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Discharge</header><text>The term <term>discharge</term>, without any qualification, means the discharge of a pollutant from a point source.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id845A8143284E411A9152787CD38FB1DD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance with limitations</header><clause id="id37DB863399A643BFB44CD18789E3AC6E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any applicant for a Federal license or permit to conduct an activity, including the construction or operation of facilities, that may result in a discharge from a point source into the waters of the United States shall provide the Federal licensing or permitting agency a certification that the discharge will comply with applicable water quality requirements from—</text><subclause id="idEC4838A60FDF4ACD8D55A677C3BE1C5D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the State in which the discharge originates or will originate;</text></subclause><subclause id="id9B5090A1D4A544C59C4B1ADA9B6ED865"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if appropriate, the interstate water pollution control agency with jurisdiction over the waters of the United States at the point where the discharge originates or will originate; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id69CA94C8F7E246A59C3F3C6E88348856"><enum>(III)</enum><text>if no State or interstate water pollution control agency has the authority to give such a certification, the Administrator.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idBFB5AB1BB2EC4176922D5CBE5D1FC233"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certification of no limitation and standard</header><subclause id="id302EB9AB42C047CA86EDA6F5C4365191"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any activity described in clause (i) for which there is not an applicable effluent limitation or other limitation under sections 301(b) and 302 and for which there is not an applicable standard under sections 306 and 307, the certifying authority shall so certify.</text></subclause><subclause id="idD9F4650B7CE04017AD5C6C1F3D78EA0F"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>A certification under subclause (I) does not satisfy section 511(c).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id2E6B4471192B422ABE5EB3A6DF02DEA9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Certification required</header><subclause id="id781C151D67AA4E518E75FBA14A3A8CDF"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Construction prohibited until certification</header><text>Construction for which a certification is required under this subparagraph may not begin until the certification has been obtained, unless the requirement for the certification has been waived in accordance with this paragraph.</text></subclause><subclause id="id61A6CAB05671478FBE484BEB076DE45C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of denial</header><text>If a certifying authority denies a certification application, the Federal license or permit for which the certification application was made may not be granted.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7148F852E7FA4875AA1C239CFA9013C9"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Scope of certification</header><text>In determining whether to issue a certification under this subparagraph and in determining what conditions to impose on a certification under this subparagraph, a certifying authority may only consider whether the point source discharge for which the certification application was made complies with applicable water quality requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36680624BFF24961B0C2D5AD4AC80366"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Required procedures</header><clause id="idAF79E5D3BBF74FA3AE8BA54E5807550A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice and hearings</header><text>Each certifying authority shall establish procedures for—</text><subclause id="id18B762A480EF46FC8423F3F9B46A5437"><enum>(I)</enum><text>public notice in the case of all certification applications;</text></subclause><subclause id="id485DA1E0FD1F4D59ADC20FEAFBAE729B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to the extent the certifying authority determines to be appropriate, public hearings in connection with specific certification applications; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id230578643EE6484CB0DDB70A91A0A2F4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a prefiling meeting as described in clause (ii).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id9BDF6CA16E1F4853B092C8C70019D544"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prefiling meeting</header><subclause id="id84D9152F9F1F46E4B698981F05B75105"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Request</header><text>Before submitting a certification application, the prospective applicant may request a prefiling meeting with the certifying authority—</text><item id="id7B038C61895D44608FC29D3C1B4BDA50"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to ensure that the certifying authority receives early notification of projects for which a certification under subparagraph (B) is necessary; and</text></item><item id="id1B5F57C2A3F04BE08EE0780509685283"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to discuss informational needs with the certifying authority before submitting the application.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id5DB8FA2264504143821F2FF0BC2CB732"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Response required</header><text>If a prospective applicant requests a prefiling meeting with a certifying authority pursuant to subclause (I), the certifying authority shall—</text><item id="idE7CB1CB986904F88894DB0BC628E9FC0" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>respond to the request not later than 30 days after the date on which the request is received; and</text></item><item id="id1022BD74987242D6A6933D0DF13A833F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>hold the prefiling meeting with the prospective applicant by not later than 60 days after the date on which the request is received.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idFC5FACFFE56042589801F25B8340F436"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Denials of certification; conditions on certification</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idafb490f76dc347418eeb46741c471e84"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Denial requirement</header><text>A certifying authority may only deny a certification application if the certifying authority determines, based on clear and convincing evidence, that there is no modification to or reasonable condition on the activities of the applicant that could make it possible for the activity to avoid violating the applicable water quality requirements.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec390c0904f14651be5d22461c9b3fb8"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Requirements for conditions</header><text>A certifying authority may include a condition in a certification under this subparagraph that requires an applicant to modify the activity of the applicant only if the certifying authority determines, based on clear and convincing evidence, that the modification is—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e93e663387d4ebea63794105eaa76ff"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">necessary for the activity to avoid violating the applicable water quality requirements;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb426909769974d74981da7b85bd8e005"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the least burdensome of possible modifications for the applicant, taking into account—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadcde9b6c1da4601ba9c03bdb93b93e6"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">technical feasibility;</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97f078116bda4609aef2b4378a88a4c8"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>cost;</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fdf2667b01149ac8e4c1cfc870c543c"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the purpose of the applicant in proposing the activity;</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3c2b34c7353434f91c55d7e2b738701"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>impacts on the schedule for the activity; and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e67acf3b8e1437c86a0f003d2b2eded"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>commercial viability of the activity; and</text></subitem></item><item id="ida1019cf9159b4b418dea810083170e0d"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>consistent with the requirements of the Federal license or permit that is the subject of the certification.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id6ECB8283956E4AC7B296D5A37E7F9AA6"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Individual licenses and permits</header><text>If a certifying authority denies a certification application for an individual license or permit, the certifying authority shall provide to the applicable Federal licensing or permitting agency—</text><item id="idDEB9A915CB3B450EA6C0660D97BEDDE3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the specific applicable water quality requirements with which the discharge will not comply;</text></item><item id="idEB1CED14E2C542B08C1A14C13A825C96"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a statement explaining why the discharge will not comply with the identified applicable water quality requirements; and</text></item><item id="idAC2407FB091C4112BE0733CBAEBF013A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>if the denial is due to insufficient information, a description of the specific water quality data or information, if any, that would be needed to ensure that the discharge from the proposed project will comply with applicable water quality requirements.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idD666AD58841046948963DE1770B54FE2"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>General licenses or permits</header><text>If a certifying authority denies a certification application for a general license or permit, the certifying authority shall provide to the applicable Federal licensing or permitting agency—</text><item id="id9A5040C3DDA948A1ABFB1B0DC63DA4AC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the specific applicable water quality requirements with which discharges that could be authorized by the general license or permit will not comply;</text></item><item id="id23486D8DA19A41BB9B31268BB5911606"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a statement explaining why discharges that could be authorized by the general license or permit will not comply with the identified applicable water quality requirements; and</text></item><item id="idC3C7B2B048484034BAF5925E6ABF4168"> <enum>(cc)</enum> <text>if the denial is due to insufficient information, a description of the specific water quality data or information, if any, that would be needed to ensure that the range of discharges that could be authorized by the general license or permit from potential projects will comply with applicable water quality requirements.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="idAFE6B3D56AB345788ECFA38B67E90F13"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Review</header><subclause id="idD825854EEAF84645A72D5E2E505F1EA4"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which a Federal licensing or permitting agency receives a notice described in clause (iii) or a certification under subparagraph (B) that includes conditions to that certification, the Federal licensing or permitting agency shall complete a review of the process undertaken by the certifying authority in reviewing the applicable certification application to determine whether the certifying authority established a reasonable period of time within which to review that certification application in accordance with subparagraph (D)(ii).</text></subclause><subclause id="id6325DAA258D6494087A8407C28CB8898"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Denials</header><text>If, after carrying out a review under subclause (I) of the process undertaken by a certifying authority with respect to a denial of a certification application, a Federal licensing or permitting agency determines that the certifying authority did not, in determining the reasonable period of time within which to review the certification application, consider all of the factors described in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of subparagraph (D)(ii), the Federal licensing or permitting agency shall—</text><item id="idD78966E530D141528AF11154CAD25CE1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>deem the certifying authority to have failed to act on the certification application; and</text></item><item id="idFA5D8780103940EB9A42BA22A7C1DF0A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>pursuant to subparagraph (D)(iii), consider the requirement for a certification under subparagraph (B) waived.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idA5623E9334AE4E6EB914B36530213793"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>If, after carrying out a review under subclause (I) of the process undertaken by a certifying authority with respect to including conditions to a certification under subparagraph (B), a Federal licensing or permitting agency determines that the certifying authority did not, in determining the reasonable period of time within which to review the applicable certification application, consider all of the factors described in subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of subparagraph (D)(ii), the Federal licensing or permitting agency shall consider the certification conditions void.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55E0FDFCA54D40FCB5E4F62594826E8F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Review period</header><clause id="id8E220B742D614E7B9364831D1C704954"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A certifying authority shall, subject to this subparagraph, issue to the applicable Federal licensing or permitting authority a final action on a certification application within a reasonable period of time, which—</text><subclause id="idDE935D67905644309A54A61AEF944492"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be determined by the certifying authority by not later than 60 days after the date on which the certification application is received by the certifying authority; but</text></subclause><subclause id="id89676232A64044599F4C977D7AD5CFF3"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2E1174791A0D49BF89808C9BBAECBC41"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall begin on the date on which the certification application is received by the certifying authority; and</text></item><item id="idA79CEB56C9A34BE38181466BF04A2AB6" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall not exceed 1 year from the date on which the certifying authority receives the certification application.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id4187FFFFEC8440D09EF91540B33C6E38"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination of reasonable period</header><text>In determining the reasonable period of time under clause (i)(I), a certifying authority shall consider—</text><subclause id="id193751C823504908906898476635ABD7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the complexity of the project described in the certification application;</text></subclause><subclause id="idD286F1E2D1EB41FA81AB00A22877816E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the nature of any potential discharge from that project; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idAE4B0BC02F044C518F79755078C7A993"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the potential need for additional study or evaluation of water quality effects from the discharge.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id56B68201C82145D3B2617149CB197446"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Failure to act within period</header><text>If a certifying authority fails or refuses to issue a final action on a certification application by the end of the reasonable period of time established under this subparagraph, the requirement for a certification under subparagraph (B) shall be waived.</text></clause><clause id="id2800F443D1384A7587B2D06FEF394223"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>No pausing or tolling</header><text>The reasonable period of time established for a certification application under this subparagraph may not be paused or tolled for any reason.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89D2DAFB11A14D25805CF03B5EF7C362"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Final action</header><clause id="idD0B8C9ED26C74164A63EE95427008616"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After completion of the reasonable period of time established under subparagraph (D) and any review that may be required under subparagraph (C)(iv) for a certification application, the certifying authority or Federal licensing or permitting authority, as applicable, shall apply only 1 of the following final actions to the certification application:</text><subclause id="id745272E530544F55ACCE94E285A4ED96"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The certification application is granted.</text></subclause><subclause id="id19147823869D4DC59099C0455A0ED13B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The certification application is granted with conditions.</text></subclause><subclause id="idD90D75043ED1454FB85AF6F2D01B488E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The certification application is denied.</text></subclause><subclause id="id51FCA5A96D8E49F68E0372D16CFDC7F0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The certification requirements under subparagraph (B) have been waived in accordance with this paragraph with respect to the activity for which the certification application was submitted.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id99132D8765FD4115BFF30617AE0D2267"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No other final actions</header><text>No other final action may apply to a certification application except as described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53285654F0034452AC821002D04FD5AF"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Enforcement of conditions</header><text>The Federal licensing or permitting authority to which a certification under this subsection was issued shall be responsible for enforcing any conditions included with that certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id640AEFB3F28C4DF6BE97FDD38A882B67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a) (as so amended)—</text><subparagraph id="id317298575CE64A33A11A42B85140442F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>(2) Upon receipt</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="idD7FAC3F6AF7B4004B6B86F52F8E35B37" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="id73488C898335435EBC52B09BFDAD0852"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to Administrator; effect on other States</header><text>On receipt</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id301c1cbd821d4241961af7143bb7450f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>(3) The certification</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cdd5e5b87424e3d868a10861d00071a"><paragraph id="idc844942af73447d395e911aed68184c0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fulfillment of requirements</header><text>The certification</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id940eb55cdc224126a4d8222c0a928ba6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>(4) Prior to</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e61e75d6e5b412094cb745f2fa53083"><paragraph id="ide7fc85f69583488e9ecb6b20dbc54bc8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review for compliance</header><text>Prior to</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id387412c0bed64ceeb99650e949f823ff"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>(5) Any Federal</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a2ef66b0d4d49599f60733281da6ddc"><paragraph id="idd811e1b89f2d443f89ea39dbfa83a06e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Suspension and revocation</header><text>Any Federal</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf3df9ab0ab68434cb75e3e24cf340d2c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>(6) Except with</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba350fbf59d84efdb3bafc58161727f5"><paragraph id="id1b3bb4a4894d415ba7364fa610ac61ed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Applicability to certain facilities</header><text>Except with</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e69d8683beb4811a990270a19065c8e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>(b) Nothing</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ca0e2a9d4d642b6aaf320889635bce5"><subsection id="id298301ce9a58455ab8b7fa9b2948d7ce"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance with other provisions of law setting applicable water quality requirements</header><text>Nothing</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a2e961cd57a41819d6d4fe6f23ad1e3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>(c) In order</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cd981533d9c4fbf95f89dfde445086a"><subsection id="idb977a126518240e5b3bab7b3eebe0d0d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority of secretary of the army To permit use of spoil disposal areas by Federal licensees or permittees</header><text>In order</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id46B0BC477112494AACD95AB558F2C7C5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaedcd5cc631b42d4883d3c5ec1283614"><subsection id="id0c5931aff84f4644a055f9906cf8d196"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations and monitoring requirements of certification</header><text>Any certification provided under this section shall set forth any effluent limitations and other limitations and monitoring requirements necessary to ensure that any discharge into navigable waters will comply with applicable water quality requirements and shall become a condition on any Federal license or permit subject to the provisions of this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id1931EC742DB148C9A9661F94B7ED6B1E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id966187B22D0648A9A84E4818B4F50978" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="id10CB7374BC9C43B794B29BB0AEF966E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1994887f6c644de84b15126303eb2d3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Energy projects</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e1f131bc9b44c30904a0358f6df4cf1"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of affected certification action</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>affected certification action</term> means a civil action for the judicial review of a certification under subsection (a)(1) for a Federal license or permit—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09190c6845724560b96b99474f146d7a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the construction or operation of a facility for—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68321e50ff3344859624f2ac6b9a789d"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the transmission of electric energy or energy fuels in interstate or foreign commerce; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cfca16c3d164191a8567c819643c47e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the transportation of carbon dioxide (including pipelines or associated infrastructure) in interstate or foreign commerce; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbdb4acca6fc4451be375c11561d3a46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>from the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1efad2d4e2c1440795779d287e6a6d3e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34ab645e2bf24bafaf097a9fc6968318"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 19(d)(1) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717r">15 U.S.C. 717r(d)(1)</external-xref>), an affected certification action shall be filed in a court of appeals of the United States—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9e13fd9c8f34202ba98054060b64079"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the circuit in which the applicant for certification under subsection (a) is located or has its place of business;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb488aa40b0dd4dc1a524302f53386cb6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for the circuit for the State for which the affected certification action applies; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id546a8ee1bcac428091258cb88b70bc8e"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for the District of Columbia Circuit.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f61be92ae844a4e9f4f9999f415f414"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Original and exclusive jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court of appeals in which an affected certification action is filed pursuant to clause (i) shall have original and exclusive jurisdiction over the affected certification action.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d283899898c4363b5857133ab7bfb45"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Standing and filing deadline</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no court shall have jurisdiction over an affected certification action unless the affected certification action has been filed not later than 30 days after the date on which final action was taken on the certification under subsection (a) for which review was sought by—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id618c9c71bb1548eb931f9274b87a9242"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant for the underlying Federal license or permit; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1361994288fc4858bd5b23460faa5de0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a person who has suffered, or likely and imminently will suffer, direct and irreparable economic harm from the authorization, certification under subsection (a), Federal license or permit for which a certification under subsection (a) was sought, or activity for which that certification was sought.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc96ac16442f1494db6e771f6f2071bef"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Expedited consideration</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b1569a46a914b1fa42e0d398422a3bd"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an affected certification action, a court shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb58b1dbd1f0a4b65871c7731b70ee7ec"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set any petition for review for expedited consideration; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaef302efcd9e4eba8897aff3052d91ca"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subject to clause (ii), issue a final decision not later than 120 days after the date on which the affected certification action was filed.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa1efa00791c4f9fa6d675db02f56af9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>A court may extend the 120-day period under clause (i)(II) by not more than 60 days if the court determines that extraordinary circumstances exist that warrant the extended period.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30396316411e41a1b6ac62fa45f0f7a7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Failure to comply with deadline</header><text>With respect to an affected certification action seeking review of a certification under subsection (a)(1) the certification application (as defined in subsection (a)(1)) for which was granted, if a court fails to issue a final decision on the affected certification action by the end of the period described in clause (i)(II) and, if applicable, extended under clause (ii), the affected certification action shall be dismissed with prejudice.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadad57a9439b4981979750b49562618d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeline for action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Federal court remands a civil action for the judicial review of a certification under subsection (a)(1) for a Federal license or permit, the Federal court shall set and enforce a reasonable schedule and deadline, not to exceed 180 days from the date on which the Federal court remands the certification, for the certifying agency to act on the remand.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7313c6d71a1942fb8713ce6815f0eef0"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of applicable water quality requirements</header><text>In this section, the term <term>applicable water quality requirements</term> means the applicable provisions of sections 301, 302, 303, 306, and 307.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0191EE180AEF4B54BB1E1B2066E3B74E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permits for dredged or fill material</header><paragraph id="idCE88321A61FA463D958211A7DE9D98F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="idD3A957AB63C3462096F34F406D0184F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the heading and section designation and all that follows through <quote>(a) The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="idA13D37C2808143F39A68ACAC40DB2C91" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC" act-name=""><section id="id112CC3B8B85E4B7E9E2C30748FD9C8FD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>404.</enum><header>Permits for dredged or fill material</header><subsection id="id47CAE35C9C8C469BB3BB6A8FD02D6697"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Discharge into navigable waters at specified disposal sites</header><paragraph id="id7DB40379EE3A4F4BB72D0294A16B9272" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB34CD3B60909471F98D47BE79D9D719A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1) (as so designated), in the second sentence—</text><clause id="id8623296A2F3B4707A288F74C9B2DBE69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this subsection</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="idB0869F6272B544F4AECC93B1C9E97043"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Not later than the fifteenth day</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="id9B1789ADE45E44C4924EFD0BF0578EEA" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="idF79223E1766D4E8E8FB632CCD71824E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than the 15th day</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9CC1AA2A7CEA44FFA93CEC3930048DE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="idF82DA56AAE2F4EE9807BDFFB3E9711FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the third sentence—</text><subclause id="id15C750DDF7C844A7B6527246129010B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his finding and his reasons</quote> and inserting <quote>the findings and reasons of the Administrator</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id2CED1F3AAB9444E7B889030E7A6C7157"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Administrator</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="idA020A0EE0C76486F9CF429FECBC97034" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="id614079D27CA644DFA2E694875675F202"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Findings and reasoning</header><text>The Administrator</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="id12EA0568AC5A4F37A4F9491BE49D41B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Before making such determination</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="id73D2113C0F254DCEBF990622D0AEFE94" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="id99AEA6BF151043E491F69283359484A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Before making a determination under paragraph (1)</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="id2B9065BB889F4F00A12C0AABE42D9F68"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(c) The Administrator</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="id4A6C9DDC7EAC4E59B731DE22883685B8" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="id3FFA041D65FF47D0A132FD2E5B681AF1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition of specification of areas as disposal sites</header><paragraph id="id02782CF59BF241A5B6DC90BCFCDC8DCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Administrator</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="idA06C5A0BC83343F897B0E0316DA84046"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) (as so designated) the following:</text><quoted-block id="id7C99A1FF4A714D0CA2F028CF69F96BCF" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="idF2C1BC80C1F84422832FEBFCFFD376F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Administrator may not prohibit the specification of a defined area as a disposal site, or otherwise deny or restrict the use of a defined area as a disposal site after a permit under this section for the area has been issued by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3E5CC8CFE0944D1F85723181853AAD92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><clause id="id5D8C84F4E00E4134B90DF92650B60BCB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the second sentence—</text><subclause id="id6D79A45158994A68A741D850040A7263"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (b)(1) of this section, and (B) set forth</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="idC9B3AF006EF3468DBF6761AD1AC705AC" style="OLC" act-name="" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>subsection (b)(1); and</text><clause id="idC530DC35D03E4A2FB91E31AF40D8C91D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>set forth</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="id73C7DB53C9D04596A62B734D6054A103"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall (A) be based</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="id43423B1E0C4F4131A738399CE250DA65" style="OLC" act-name="" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>shall—</text><clause id="idAECD495804454AD2BBD205984831DAC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be based</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="idE892B802F90C444B85E86C4314ACF5C0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Any general</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="idBF1BDDC9E8FB4ADD9826358DEF14E931" style="OLC" act-name=""><subparagraph id="id974AD473E5A745F28E9DDBFDCB571224"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for issuance</header><text>Any general</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="id2DC40BFA11984E9CA6F213F465AEBC8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(e)(1) In carrying</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="id526F9FC72EF54D4A86B5EED1F4360600" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="id99CD1BB6FC904E48A78F242FA8220EBE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>General permits on State, regional, or nationwide basis</header><paragraph id="id9610E05608C1493484F7E15F75A8FB16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permits authorized</header><subparagraph id="idF21E6C46295348ADBF33FFE358F7B005"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="idC520BAF71EE6454A85FEF2FAFE3C87FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8540e0a95554049ae003492b0277923"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(2) No general</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="id6ADA962633E14AD192C77D258D845E16" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="id9618C84E471A4328B8B8B875FEF93412"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term</header><text>No general</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id283406ab2e584c1aa7974cb4d44b5c65"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>five years</quote> and inserting <quote>10 years</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idEC50E97443214C5DB9779292B9D4B00E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id7B2D86B21D68446391807FAF8506140D" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="HED7B4F730C194F7EA5E8F3A96139AAF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the environmental effects of an activity under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="HA6C165208D334E95A1F81D6A013D063E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consider only the effects of any discharge of dredged or fill material resulting from the activity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5032570BADB84DF8B18925834FAFA25F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall consider any effects of a discharge of dredged or fill material into fewer than 3 acres of navigable waters to be a minimal adverse environmental effect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B4F454773AC4258A4407EAE2DEE7E20" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may consider any effects of a discharge of dredged or fill material into 3 acres or more of navigable waters to be a minimal adverse environmental effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95291ddd400b4f728273d333f91d29c1"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Single and complete projects</header><subparagraph id="id90331DE9DA164B0180C8770B34187CC6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of single and complete project</header><clause id="idA51AF4599E29409A887A1F401F6C55AF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>single and complete project</term>, with respect to a project for which the Secretary is determining whether a general permit issued under this subsection applies, means that portion of the total project proposed or accomplished by—</text><subclause id="id7DD16BF538D043F09F4126290A56B78F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a single owner or developer;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2006CC9F571B4342AC47674F0DFCD0B0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a partnership of 1 or more owners or developers; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idA527703E90AA483FB6865BAC631882B9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an association of owners or developers.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idC53FD11DB6C64D4596367B3835821689"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Linear projects</header><subclause id="id20FB0503425345BA8365EDD3F54A3770"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this clause, the term <term>linear project</term> means a project constructed for the purpose of getting people, goods, energy, or services from a point of origin to a terminal point, which may involve multiple crossings of 1 or more waters of the United States at separate and distant locations.</text></subclause><subclause id="idF1D3CA3032BA4255872B3CCF24A9FC25"><enum>(II)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, with respect to projects described in clause (i) that are linear projects—</text><item id="id6B77047E0B1F4AB4B44AAAC637880411"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the crossings of separate waters of the United States at a specific location shall be considered 1 single and complete project; but</text></item><item id="idFDDD557E136542B9AB30DE9D439AD48C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>each crossing of a single water of the United States shall be considered a separate single and complete project if those crossings are at separate and distant locations.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idF7E5A564E757433AA590819AFD576B35"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Additional exclusions</header><text>For purposes of subclause (II), individual channels in a braided stream or river, individual arms of a large, irregularly-shaped wetland or lake, and other, similar bodies of water shall not be considered to be separate waters of the United States.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8B9BF428435B415BBCC88BE49960952F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In determining whether a general permit issued under this subsection applies to an activity, the Secretary shall consider the estimated total of all losses of waters of the United States expected to result from the single and complete project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id788050C2E364440CB7DC9AE973E041C7" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of multiple permits</header><text>The Secretary may combine 2 or more general permits issued under this subsection to authorize a single and complete project, but the same general permit issued under this subsection may not be used more than once for a single and complete project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id54948918B72B4D80A37D1F241B2A6B7E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reissuance of nationwide permits</header><text>In determining whether to reissue a general permit issued under this subsection on a nationwide basis—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idF8A53AD22D9241709827D63A13189793"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no consultation with an applicable State pursuant to section 6(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1535">16 U.S.C. 1535(a)</external-xref>) is required; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idA0F93BD2B2A14D69A93C2C4AA7672FAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no consultation with a Federal agency pursuant to section 7(a)(2) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(a)(2)</external-xref>) is required; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id85D78778E3224847833BF6DBA78A0B41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for purposes of carrying out the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to that reissuance, conducting an environmental assessment on a nationwide basis is sufficient for purposes of compliance with that Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id94639C9AAFC849F78E4CFDD7919FDD29"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nationwide permit for oil and natural gas pipelines</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary shall maintain a nationwide permit for the activities required for the construction, maintenance, repair, operation, and removal of oil and natural gas pipelines and associated facilities that result in the loss of, with respect to waters of the United States, an area of fewer than 3 acres for each single and complete project (as defined in paragraph (4)(A)), which shall be known as <quote>nationwide permit 12</quote>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8E4E549504A3422D9B6D02D224F47062"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text><clause id="id58130FC7EA344CDF8F184B20183CCAA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idAE1702B2EA5A4491863287B4925B8E25" style="OLC" act-name=""><subparagraph id="id508DE69CCCAC4CEC8EF2D4DDE089D74F" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>To issue permits not later than the date that is 1 year after the date on which the State receives an application for the permit, which may not be paused or tolled for any reason.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C0827035DBB419AB539FF35C1F5B12B" indent="up1"><enum>(J)</enum><text>To ensure that, if the State does not issue a final action with respect to an application for a permit within the 1-year period described in subparagraph (I), the application is considered to be approved.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9769E97C309B4CD59BD755FA395F8CE5" indent="up1"><enum>(K)</enum><text>To carry out a programmatic review of the program annually to ensure that the program does not exceed the authority granted to the State under this section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="idA1EC5F9396D943509250EA3B8FAD0E36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idADBF60EDA6054DAA958CC719B73EC9A6" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph id="id8A03B2C84DFE45F5B06464BF9371D858" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Action required</header><subparagraph id="id950FE924E00F4F24B1700D2E041BE935"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State with a permit program approved under this subsection shall issue a final action with respect to an application for a permit described in subsection (g)(1) not later than 1 year after the date of receipt of the application.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6F6383C208A4C1A97F9172A0E43534C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to act</header><text>An application for a permit described in subsection (g)(1) submitted to a State with a permit program approved under this subsection shall be considered to be approved if the State fails to issue a final action with respect to the application by the end of the 1-year period described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1C75BB51214C40CD9E279D4BD1CC4578"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No pausing or tolling</header><text>The 1-year period described in subparagraph (A) may not be paused or tolled for any reason.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6F39A29CF7D649A89945A71A3E7E55F3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subsection (s)(3), in the third sentence, by striking <quote>acton</quote> and inserting <quote>action</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA7011B73D45D425399D99B7ED0019242"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in subsection (t), by striking <quote>(t) Nothing</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="idE18F3286C4CE4D908D8347FDAA6A7139" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="id5ED4F2B87DBA4FB2AC87DB59E14DECDC"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id345802538C244594A04B601716965F0D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (s) the following:</text><quoted-block id="idF9F5B92A63E446068CC946D908BBEC9E" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="id1BBA0A46E0A54A639EBFD17107D59997"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><paragraph id="id9DF1DD1AD3F24250910F031AA7E8A5FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><subparagraph id="id4E794B0DA2044659B00BBA9A58BE665C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an action seeking judicial review of an individual or general permit issued under this section shall be filed not later than the date that is 60 days after the date on which the permit was issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id244F2049B54D41AE846F5CCA0B1F15C0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) authorizes an action seeking judicial review of the structure of or authorization for a State permit program approved pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2EECA3996F514AF785E869C21BE89BE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeline to act on remand</header><text>If a Federal court remands a permit under this section, the Federal court shall set and enforce a reasonable schedule and deadline, which may not exceed 180 days from the date on which the Federal court remands the permit, for the issuer of the permit to act on that remand.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id15FD14F1AA744E78A0AF634083118EF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ratification of current permits</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, each category of activities authorized by a general permit issued under section 404(e) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(e)</external-xref>) (including nationwide permit 12) or under section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1899 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/403">33 U.S.C. 403</external-xref>), that is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act shall, consistent with subparagraph (A) of section 404(e)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(e)(1)</external-xref>), be considered to cause—</text><subparagraph id="idD799A4B8031D41998ACCF8B2077E2A5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than minimal adverse environmental effects when actions authorized under those permits are carried out separately; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFC5439072ED7432898B90A79E0F22BC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than minimal cumulative adverse effects on the environment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id43483840963441CAB5630A6F502E337E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection or the amendments made by this subsection requires a State (including an Indian tribe that is treated as a State pursuant to section 518(e) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1377">33 U.S.C. 1377(e)</external-xref>)) for which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency has approved a permit program pursuant to subsections (g) and (h) of section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) to seek reapproval of the permit program in accordance with those subsections.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide6bf1d11801b43f085520c79c807f6f5"><enum>3.</enum><header>LNG terminals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id456ca6031b554636b5edd860960fb40e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(3)—</text><subparagraph id="idefa3bf1d79c54b1fadfb1e14571ff5e0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>find</quote> and inserting <quote>finds</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d5b333e1cf44457a1df5475be3e47e9"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>Before January 1, 2015, the</quote> and inserting <quote>The</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfbadd0f387c74c95b066256fd2456ee9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7eb9412ca464877b3ebaaa5028ae002"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4c7371c381246c29db8670452327236"><subsection id="id78f9e8603de245ab9e78a25eb3c635dc"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public interest finding</header><text>In carrying out a finding of public interest under subsection (a), the Commission may not consider any environmental factors pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id8fe286299f184219877d20beddec9c0d"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nuclear energy licensing</header><subsection id="id2ad4e526c0e6419696514fc18caf721a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of license terms for commercial reactors</header><text>Section 103 c. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2133">42 U.S.C. 2133(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21a7329947644df08591728bc5723cd1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>c. Each such license</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="id2D96E7C6D41647B7A23269DC2A0407B5" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="id2863720CA0494DA3A079F062C4028714"><enum>c.</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idbf705303e49445f18f4b2b263187e080"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), each such license</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7921a4d8f0774137b3ebf93f9c898314"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idB289D79EEFF5494EB50078FB5EDFB7EB" style="OLC" act-name=""><paragraph indent="up1" id="idBB6BBF564EB7446592CB8B3ABE8AECE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of a license issued under this section for a utilization facility for the generation of electrical or thermal energy, the period of the license shall not exceed 60 years from the authorization to commence operations, and may be renewed on expiration of that period.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62e95a955b694025bcd057bc7a88cd44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Early site permits</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall finalize a rulemaking amending section 52.26 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc001b9715d3f435e8790e53bd3a219b7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an early site permit issued after the date of enactment of this Act does not expire;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd501fdd83f634e00924da72f44ca92ab"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an early site permit issued before the date of enactment of this Act shall, without further review or approval by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, remain in effect indefinitely on the request of the permit holder or any other entity that references the early site permit in an application for a construction permit or combined license; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7eb601bee1345ff83f23271b2deb8e3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an early site permit, regardless of when the permit is issued, may be revoked only on a finding by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, supported by clear and convincing evidence, that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27210a7702514c7382b26d8d6203d9cf"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">significant new information has arisen since the issuance of the early site permit with respect to the radiological, seismic, meteorological, hydrologic, geologic, or demographic characteristics of the site that was not considered during the original permitting proceeding and that renders the site unsuitable for the construction and operation of a nuclear power facility; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id515f5a4b7e1e41c38b9bbebd0d902b52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>revocation is necessary to ensure adequate protection of public health and safety or the common defense and security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d12f078b15c4c0bbdbee75aea11444d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Categorical exclusion</header><text>The construction and operation of a new nuclear reactor at a site for which the Nuclear Regulatory Commission has previously issued, or is currently reviewing an application for, a construction permit, operating license, or combined license under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2011">42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be categorically excluded from the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HA0D8FF7E773C450391C674078F0CED2A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Judicial review under NEPA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 is amended—</text><paragraph id="H474C8677FEF34CF4B14A15B1AF887442"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 112 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4336f">42 U.S.C. 4336f</external-xref>) as section 110A, and moving the section so as to appear after section 110; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A253953189C4B1994188000B0213444"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 110A (as so redesignated) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H723893D66F38474F8DD34538D96EC432" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><section id="H3A257FF4D8894320A05C9936D6C2D600" commented="no"><enum>110B.</enum><header>Judicial review</header><subsection id="HCEA1BFB0E9C74E1995063A6A684BADC1" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Remand</header><paragraph id="H7FBE0FEEABA449D1BD675A670B1B9B53" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a court holds, under section 706(2)(A) of title 5, United States Code, that a final agency action does not comply with the requirements of this Act, the only remedy the court may order, notwithstanding chapter 7 of that title, is to remand, without vacatur or injunction, the final agency action to the Federal agency with—</text><subparagraph id="H3A0B05E608E1420086BA06B8DB646E44" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specific instruction to correct the errors or deficiencies found by the court; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H610C595F6E9B4C22992156DD21615279" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a reasonable schedule and deadline to correct such errors or deficiencies, which may not exceed—</text><clause id="HF028CC2DFE5F4947A6214461E8433597" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an order entered before the date of enactment of this section, the date that is 180 days after that date of enactment; and</text></clause><clause id="HC3BC9AACDBCD4BB9A05246FA425853D6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an order entered on or after the date of enactment of this section, the date that is 180 days after the date on which the order was entered.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87924EF14D7B4286B318FC31ACF9D708" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continued effect of final agency action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A final agency action remanded under paragraph (1) shall remain in effect while the Federal agency corrects any errors or deficiencies found by the court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H078E2529EDF24661881C69451CB2CA29" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations on claims</header><paragraph id="H3C37B65F5D11481C998B58CFF3D1472E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a claim relating to whether a final agency action complies with the requirements of this Act shall be barred unless—</text><subparagraph id="HA2DA08213CA547299360DCC2936CF2C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the claim is filed not later than 150 days after the final agency action is made public, unless a shorter deadline is specified under Federal law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB0B419A86C24419A4E4E4C591B6DCAD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a final agency action for which there was a public comment period on an environmental document, the claim—</text><clause id="HDCF9399652FA4C3188A89F028410E42F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is filed by a party that submitted a substantive and unique comment during that public comment period by the noticed comment deadline for the environmental document and the comment was sufficiently detailed to put the applicable Federal agency on notice of the issue on which the party seeks review; and</text></clause><clause id="H0D1A9CB196554C9189904B5D756A5941" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">concerns the same subject matter raised in the comment submitted during the public comment period;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F820213800F4DBC979D395FBE55453C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the claim is filed by a party that has suffered or imminently will suffer direct harm from the final agency action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8A2812CCCBE4DB09922A4F762011B0F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the claim does not challenge the establishment of a categorical exclusion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0412889657B7428AB6ED8254107BCCB8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplemental environmental documents</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a40dc8e34724d879740c59e1f1578b6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Federal agency issues a supplemental environmental document in response to a court order remanding a final agency action, the deadline described in paragraph (1)(A) shall be the date on which the Federal agency makes public the agency action for which the supplemental environmental document is prepared.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e19eace4ac145ce89dfb182fddeedd4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claim for review of a final agency action described in subparagraph (A) shall be limited to information contained in the final supplemental environmental document that was not contained in a previous environmental document for the final agency action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88C50CF1BD574EE9850C26E606BEA857" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Actions for use of tribal trust resources</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc492c22e67a944c7873f2f9abba8ef85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), for any final agency action that authorizes or affects the use of land, minerals, or other resources held in trust at the time of the final agency action by the United States for the benefit of a federally recognized Indian Tribe, there shall be no administrative or judicial review of the final agency action based on a claim of failure to comply with the requirements of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H500E1CA3228E466C9A3FFC8694270D19" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to actions for administrative or judicial review—</text><clause id="HA199712F1A9C407781A7160D7A8A4A6E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>brought by the federally recognized Indian Tribe for which the United States holds the land, minerals, or other resources in trust; or</text></clause><clause id="HF452B41D0A5A4A9E8F788C6B9488AACE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that involve reasonably foreseeable effects of the final agency action that occur outside the land, minerals, or other resources held in trust by the United States for the benefit of a federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B285249201249638EF13A70B82B853F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline for resolution</header><paragraph id="H3EE8C9EBE9D3488C874B38FD0A47801A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A court shall issue a final judgment on a claim relating to whether a final agency action complies with the requirements of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="HB745C295172049B8A497BDA1D07E86CE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as expeditiously as practicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8993824FF4134BEFA247F04B418931D8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unless a shorter deadline is specified under Federal law, not later than the date that is 180 days after the date on which the agency record for the review is filed with the reviewing court, which shall be not more than 60 days after the filing of the claim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE56405E1BED1497292A7E896335712DB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accelerated deadlines</header><text>Nothing in this subsection prevents a court from further expediting review of a claim relating to whether a final agency action complies with the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE9CA70944FC49A396D3AF200E6A04A3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appeals</header><subparagraph id="H43B3E53E63FD456883EEBA9AA3DF3119" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Filing</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id520a741aaded4542b999b695dd5bbfc4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notice of appeal of a final judgment described in this subsection shall be filed not later than 60 days after the final judgment is issued.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47fc0222c52a45d393210c08b934fd17"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Remanded actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a final agency action remanded under subsection (a)(1), the Federal agency and, if applicable, the applicant shall have the right to appeal during the pendency of the remand.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF09BDDAA23B4F808DD6D829F9447B23" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline for review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A court shall issue a final decision on an appeal filed under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H3384FBB2791D4E5F9F83EE3E3E14C0A1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as expeditiously as practicable; and</text></clause><clause id="H5AF341F3D062409792BA62504ADF20F8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than the date that is 180 days after the date on which the notice of the appeal is filed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68ED6A43AD2F423EA268F6EBCBB66E25" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No effect on review of compliance with other deadlines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section affects the right to obtain review under section 107(g)(3).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

