<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H55C3A41F37AA4E1D9BDBF4AF7FF6AB4A"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7601 IH: No Immunity for Glyphosate Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7601</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funds to implement the Executive order entitled <quote>Promoting the National Defense by Ensuring an Adequate Supply of Elemental Phosphorus and Glyphosate-Based Herbicides</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F829BFF0D454EF2AA269A3C507754A3"><section id="HD0B5E3E76007440E8EEA25D6245DBC81" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Immunity for Glyphosate Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H72BCC62C3F6944A0AC276463914011A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>No federal funds for executive order relating to phosphorus and glyphosate-based herbicides</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used to implement, administer, or enforce the Executive order entitled <quote>Promoting the National Defense by Ensuring an Adequate Supply of Elemental Phosphorus and Glyphosate-Based Herbicides</quote>, issued on February 18, 2026.</text></section><section id="H4388C1E4224A49CFBA678DD164450005"><enum>3.</enum><header>No immunities for glyphosate manufacturers</header><subsection id="H4FEF2AE8F5234E4580242CC66FE610EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>Any person, or the estate, survivors, or legal representative of such person, who suffers or has suffered physical injury, illness, disease, or death caused, in whole or in part, by exposure to elemental phosphorus or a glyphosate-based herbicide manufactured, distributed, sold, or supplied within the United States, may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States against any covered entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1C7F3856DC54B37B4E6093CF10F9EA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered entities</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>covered entity</quote> means any person, corporation, partnership, association, contractor, subcontractor, or other entity that manufactures, distributes, formulates, supplies, or sells elemental phosphorus or glyphosate-based herbicides.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD58E5980B2E84E1CAFCD9071A698CAB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over any civil action arising under this section without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6FAD1B9B725A40E5A788582B06610A64"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action under this section, the court may award—</text><paragraph id="HE0FBA26E01BF44058C870958A846C353"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compensatory damages, including damages for medical expenses, lost income, pain and suffering, and wrongful death;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAFC44A2525E4BB88B5D1CF57EF95D5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>punitive damages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04D32BB925DB4E2AA82B336882609D73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>equitable relief, including declaratory and injunctive relief; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE2F16F081C445C8AC7F53711C08F54"><enum>(4)</enum><text>attorney’s fees and costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41A6B4B53E3747CCB6CA04455B92DD96"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver and nullification of immunity</header><text>Notwithstanding section 707 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4557">50 U.S.C. 4557</external-xref>), or any other provision of law, no covered entity shall be immune from civil liability under Federal or State law for injury, illness, disease, or death caused by exposure to elemental phosphorus or glyphosate-based herbicides.</text></subsection><subsection id="H15C6E64D50D54C84AE829379CE3AEE45"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No federal contractor defense</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, including any doctrine of Federal contractor immunity or preemption, no covered entity may assert as a defense to liability in any action brought under this section, or under any other Federal or State law, that the manufacture, formulation, distribution, sale, or supply of elemental phosphorus or a glyphosate-based herbicide was conducted in compliance with, or pursuant to, an Executive order, regulation, directive, contract, or other authorization issued under the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4501">50 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law, regulation, or authority.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB4AC6F8D26F448C3B4CD37295AB176BD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preservation of existing and pending claims</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H46C9972BE5244236A96F62E0CDF19106"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preempt, displace, or otherwise limit any civil action authorized under Federal or State law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BA32D11973645779B2FC7DD6312CFED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require dismissal of, or otherwise adversely affect, any civil action pending on or before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H669862B93D8E4E16926145D9A39DA01D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to any claim arising before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H04DDDB5ACBD1478FACAF0FE8D93F3640"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Non-Preemption of state law</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt, displace, or limit any right or remedy available under State law.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

