<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07FDBB779C6A4DFAA9374C1D5294C414" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9127 IH: Sergeant Dave Crete Fighting for the Overlooked Recognition of Groups Operating in Toxic Test Environments in Nevada Veterans Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve benefits for veterans who may have been exposed to toxic substances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE6632B38017947418CA5AB001C4EE5AF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAFA5BB7F64CC4F54ACFFA5236FB1E2CE" section-type="section-one" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sergeant Dave Crete Fighting for the Overlooked Recognition of Groups Operating in Toxic Test Environments in Nevada Veterans Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Sergeant Dave Crete FORGOTTEN Veterans Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H707473DEF04B4210BCF669FBFB1169B9"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HA85F81A402B04F50ABFFEE3B61B984FD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active military, naval, air, or space service</header><text>The term <term>active military, naval, air, or space service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(24) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E4C4E837B034CF887034261D2C59774" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered location</header><text>The term <term>covered location</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEA6408D144824896B64B5C66DED29868" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any facility on the most recent list of facilities covered under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7384">42 U.S.C. 7384 et seq.</external-xref>) published in the Federal Register by the Department of Energy; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F9EF61D2614494084C38B86CA42CC87" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to service on or after January 27, 1951, any location within the Nevada Test and Training Range or the Nevada National Security Site (as defined on May 19, 2026).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65DD6C5EDEC1424EAFEDEA50E0495BBE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Toxic exposure</header><text>The term <term>toxic exposure</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(37) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC29B3C82409C4E99A498CCCCD58572E7" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coordination with Department of Defense to identify veterans who performed military service at covered locations</header> <subsection id="H30D4E95B987D46BB8C30ED1D64CFBCE7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish and carry out a process to identify veterans who served at a covered location and may have encountered toxic exposure during active military, naval, air, or space service.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF83E9B05DA814F83A690B3878C0D38FA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of available information</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall use—</text> <paragraph id="H012B096C8743428C85BCEA01C376B151" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>military personnel and deployment records maintained by the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H44EE67725AB6405B8DF2F47A3A9AE57B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information provided by veterans through the registry established under section 7.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H84E57EF68B3148CC96C37985CA407D28" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No affirmative evidence required</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may not require a veteran to provide affirmative evidence of exposure to a specific toxic substance if service at a covered location is established.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H549A2992835E47EC8FF9B9FD7B840492" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment as radiation-risk activities by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1112(c)(3)(B) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A4ADA74401A4C12BE006FEAA027D5F1" changed="not-changed"> <clause id="H68AFF0EE4C9B4CE7B11176CE1729A147" commented="no" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Active military, naval, air, or space service, or onsite participation in any aspect of the development, construction, operation, or maintenance of a military installation (as defined in section 2801 of title 10), within the area that comprises the Nevada Test and Training Range and the Nevada National Security Site, as defined on May 19, 2026, during the period beginning on January 27, 1951, and ending on the date which the Secretary of Defense, with independent verification, certifies that the area that comprises the Nevada Test and Training Range and the Nevada National Security Site no longer pose radiation risk to personnel present, or enactment of the <short-title>Sergeant Dave Crete Fighting for the Overlooked Recognition of Groups Operating in Toxic Test Environments in Nevada Veterans Act of 2026</short-title>, whichever is later.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H244A4579EE094FB5B04B14751DB4F0A9" changed="not-changed"><enum>5.</enum><header>Presumption of toxic exposure for veterans who served at covered locations and presumption of service connection for certain diseases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1119(c)(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H536530A8345A403B9B0228E822EFB268" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A)(viii), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F27A7069A6E47019F9C58288260B4A8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ix), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1618D4DBD9248CBB7131256C99DF322" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text>
<quoted-block id="HC653D58C690F475B84C593C9EC964144" changed="not-changed" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC">
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F998B35ED7941B69E75E36D10A11C6B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at any time, performed active military, naval, air, or space service while assigned to a duty station in, including airspace above, any facility on the most recent list of facilities covered under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7384">42 U.S.C. 7384 et seq.</external-xref>) published in the Federal Register by the Department of Energy; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FB1F8A0C4314DC0A581565AD77DD490" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>on or after January 27, 1951, performed active military, naval, air, or space service while assigned to a duty station in, including airspace above, any location within the area that comprises the Nevada Test and Training Range and the Nevada National Security Site, as defined on May 19, 2026.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="H7558613A038B4AE7AF7679FA81E8F8C4" changed="not-changed"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study on toxic exposures at covered locations</header>
<subsection id="H24C0BAF2B7364FB8A73B44A84C12E2D1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall seek to enter into an agreement with the Department of Health and Human Services or another appropriate scientific organization to study potential toxic exposures and environmental hazards at covered locations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6EB5D53AB45246688BD32B90F0556D2C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HB35F7C79A9534383BA4C9A4106A8D77D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify exposures associated with military occupations of veterans who served at covered locations, including exposures relating to chemicals, compounds, agents, and other phenomena; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47AD2A5B172F4B43B3E4055283584710" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review the literature to determine associations between such exposures and the incidence or prevalence of overall cancer morbidity and overall cancer mortality, and determine, to the extent possible, the prevalence and mortality of cancers among such veterans by using available sources of data, which may include—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE2880664D0014031977BECCFEB5CBE6C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health care and other administrative databases of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and the military departments, respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB0601F5119D4E1CAF60AB8C2D657730" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the national death index maintained by the National Center for Health Statistics of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDC594C30D2F84D2BA62D8E669D3013EF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer authority</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense to carry out the study required under subsection (a) may be transferred without regard to section 2215 of title 10, United States Code, to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to pay for the study.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB261C2FA19324EBB8762A0CC14B695E6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>At the conclusion of the study required under subsection (a), the Department of Health and Human Services or other appropriate scientific organization, as the case may be, shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives, the President of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, and the Chair of the National Research Council a report containing the results of the study.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H45A92CC6E8EA44DE9F0FDD0549BD4DBD" changed="not-changed"><enum>7.</enum><header>Establishment of covered location veteran registry</header>
<subsection id="HDFC195DC9178462099E45BEA8F115D36" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish and maintain a registry of veterans who served at covered locations who may have encountered toxic exposure during active military, naval, air, or space service (in this section referred to as the <quote>registry</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5A92348C758F47D7A6C1D19B112705BD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The registry shall be used to—</text>
<paragraph id="H17A1CD3E314248CA8D79EAE3AEA7DBF3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect, process, maintain, and consolidate epidemiological information required to analyze incidence of adverse health effects among veterans who served in covered locations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5D5D845CC71498BAA0761CAA3519283" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate coordination between the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense to verify service;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDDE8D6287D5047F183E15D4E8187496A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inform veterans of available health care, benefits, and screenings; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB2783CF01CC4DDFB39ED57574AC7ED7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support outreach, research, and claims adjudication related to toxic exposure.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1B8FD6E3CACF460CB1018678802B316D" changed="not-changed">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Opt-Out and recruitment</header>
        <paragraph id="H97DC789AFF784550AA4573EC933F746F" commented="no" changed="not-changed">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Opt-out</header>
 <text>Participants must have the opportunity to opt-out of inclusion in the registry.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDF6F43396E134A9FB33FBDA212775119" commented="no" changed="not-changed">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Recruitment</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall recruit veterans described in subsection (a) who are not represented in data sources of the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HF1A6D94590F84AE4BCEF979C31E2E8BA" changed="not-changed" commented="no"
        display-inline="no-display-inline">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Data-Sharing</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall share information collected through the registry with the Secretary of Defense, consistent with applicable privacy and security laws, for purposes of identifying affected veterans and improving care and benefits delivery.</text>
      </subsection></section>
<section id="HE47C0F72CCD246C7A508E40CDF29DB93" changed="not-changed"><enum>8.</enum><header>Classification of certain facilities as locations where contamination occurred and members of the Armed Forces were exposed to toxic substances</header>
<subsection id="HB07F36755E7C4FB783BE181763157B7C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall classify the following locations as a location where contamination occurred:</text> <paragraph id="HDE29EDC413B24558A696C0CDAEEACB83" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On and after January 27, 1951, the Nevada Test and Training Range, including the Nevada National Security Site (as such site is defined on May 19, 2026).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9727A05FF2254D86BCC421044E245AB4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any facility on the most recent list of facilities covered under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7384">42 U.S.C. 7384 et seq.</external-xref>) published in the Federal Register by the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E7FCDE35D2C46F9A569C565CA457362" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification process</header> <paragraph id="HE90426F9E3D649308C70F9EE8655E8B0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a process to identify members of the Armed Forces and former members of the Armed Forces that were stationed at a facility specified in subsection (a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71661DCE8D684B95AD8B613469A997A0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a process to permit members of the Armed Forces and former members of the Armed Forces to provide documentation or evidence of their assignment at a facility specified in subsection (a) to assist the Secretary in identifying those members and former members under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F13877BE30D42A5ADB4B7801BFE4A85" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Efforts</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall make all efforts to identify individuals described in paragraph (1) and shall not require members of the Armed Forces or former members of the Armed Forces to submit evidence of their stationing.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF982654737974FA1B6E66A509801C096" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sharing of information</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall share with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs all information and documentation gathered under subsection (b) in order to provide the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with adequate documentation of the service of members of the Armed Forces and former members of the Armed Forces at facilities specified in subsection (a) and any injuries, exposures, or illnesses related to such service, for the purpose of establishing any claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to which such members and former members are legally entitled.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

