<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H790E0E1178E14376BD0E6F6E41E6D90D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1166 IH: Providing for the expulsion of Representative Eric Swalwell from the United States House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1166</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260413">April 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for the expulsion of Representative Eric Swalwell from the United States House of Representatives.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Eric Swalwell is a Member of the United States House of Representatives;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, on April 10, 2026, investigative reporting publicly revealed allegations from a former congressional staffer that she had engaged in a sexual relationship with Representative Eric Swalwell;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas that same former congressional staffer stated that, on at least one occasion, Representative Eric Swalwell engaged in sexual activity with her while she was too intoxicated to consent;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the allegation involving sexual activity with an intoxicated congressional staffer has been referred to and is under investigation by the Manhattan District Attorney’s Office;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Members of Congress hold positions of authority over staff and individuals working within the congressional environment and must never exploit that authority for personal advantage;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, on April 12, 2026, Representative Eric Swalwell suspended his campaign for Governor of California following the public reporting of these incidents, reflecting the seriousness of the misconduct;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Representative Eric Swalwell all but admitted to engaging in a sexual relationship with a subordinate congressional staffer through his own public statements acknowledging <quote>mistakes in judgment</quote> following investigative reporting on the relationship;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives (Code of Official Conduct) provides that a Member <quote>shall behave at all times in a manner that shall reflect creditably on the House</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, as a Member of the United States House of Representatives, Representative Swalwell must be held accountable to the highest standards of conduct in order to safeguard the public’s faith in this institution;</text>
                </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Constitution of the United States charges the House with policing the behavior of its own Members, and the House should take action against Representative Swalwell commensurate with his violations of the Rules of the House;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the continued service of Representative Eric Swalwell brings discredit upon the House of Representatives; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, given his egregious violations, Representative Eric Swawell is not fit to serve as a Member of the United States House of Representatives: Now, therefore, be it</text>
                </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC92F633FD94C4F56BD36F701FDEBDE0B"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD0F1CD144C9C47C4AF9C7BB80966D608"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That pursuant to article I, section 5, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States, Representative Eric Swalwell, be, and he hereby is, expelled from the United States House of Representatives.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

