<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6BCA944E80FA4BC185091DC5B3F9A035" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9520 IH: War Hazards Compensation Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the War Hazards Compensation Act and the Longshore and Harbor
            Workers’ Compensation Act to require that the Federal Government pay interest on late
            reimbursements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H969FBF66AAA14160A527024896C18112" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC187319656BD4BE6A6D9AF35C23E9876" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>War Hazards Compensation Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H885D141FC35C4BFEA50C830CBBA08990"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interest on late reimbursement of War Hazards Compensation Act claims</header> 
<subsection id="HB31C7496F00644F6BE7201E339762010"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9A2D1F121C0443189D7D1FC3396D6580"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The War Hazards Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1701">42 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) (in this Act referred to as the <quote>WHCA</quote>) relies on private insurance carriers to advance payment of compensation to covered employees, often for extended periods, before reimbursement by the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CAEB6E2D811450C861A104562ECAF82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Delayed reimbursement imposes substantial carrying costs on insurance carriers and insured employers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63EF22E04A344F85998C168C555B55CD" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Persistent delays in reimbursement discourage insurer participation under the WHCA and threaten the availability and affordability of insurance coverage for employers engaged in overseas and national defense related activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC59BECA5F4E444BBB3646F2C274CF7ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Under the WHCA, there is no provision for the accrual of interest on late WHCA reimbursements, which effectively shifts the cost of Federal delay onto insurance carriers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H15ECFADB606A47A1AB8BF70B7052C696"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the War Hazards Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1701">42 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H67A5E6D3AF8A4CF3BF536AC7773D0BE2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HC0E86027F4F249F18DB0D1786D1BC709"><enum>108.</enum><header>Interest on late reimbursement</header> 
<subsection id="HCE6F02D863B94A93B5D08024EC0F6B55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of completion of reimbursement submission</header> 
<paragraph id="H61D9E65D6E6E439C98FCA3385D6AFB57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Complete reimbursement submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claim for reimbursement made pursuant to section 104(a) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H8A4C9D18873F443491DFA2DDDCE285E8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>All forms prescribed by the Secretary for reimbursement under this title, including Form CA–278 (Claim for Reimbursement of Benefit Payments and Claims Expense Under the War Hazards Compensation Act) as provided by the Office of Workers’ Compensation Programs of the Department of Labor or any successor or substantially similar form.</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46E5A8FC09964548A572FAF386D4325F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Documentation relating to the payment of benefits for which reimbursement is sought.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85C7366EE6B149278D32C5BBFCA5E867"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any additional information specifically requested by the Division of Federal Employees’ Compensation of the Department of Labor (in this section referred to as <quote>DFEC</quote>).</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93D13F5EFC0B4F609AC68934C0BB691D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acknowledgment requirement</header><text>Not later than 14 days after receipt of a claim for reimbursement as described under paragraph (1), DFEC shall issue a written or electronic—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD11A17FD0D647129B8930F96CFEF9AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acknowledgment that such claim for reimbursement is accepted; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D72C9C862244D2DBD28570B8A4AC1CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notice of any specific deficiency of such claim for reimbursement preventing such acknowledgment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEBFCB82926BB46D889BD6E6D2BBA8492" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deemed complete designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If DFEC does not issue an acknowledgment or deficiency notice as required under subsection (a)(2), such claim shall be deemed to have been acknowledged under subsection (a)(2)(A) on the date on which DFEC received such claim.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE43BFA53510B4F17959060F936CC7ECB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Commencement of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interest shall accrue at the overpayment rate established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6621">section 6621</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 on the amount owed with respect to a claim for reimbursement under section 104(a) beginning on the date that is 60 days after the date on which an acknowledgment is issued under subsection (a)(2)(A).</text> </subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H44B7EA105A6B4970B91100C4BC9F3AB0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of outstanding claims for reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of section 108(a)(2)(A) of the WHCA, as added by the amendments made by this section, any insurance claim for reimbursement made pursuant to section 104(a) of the WHCA that is outstanding on the date of enactment of this Act shall be deemed to have been acknowledged on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5FBCEF526F94CC3BCAF1AF211D09EE9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementing regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Labor shall promulgate regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDDBE27E2A56A4872A1AC6B973680416D" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization for hiring minimum number of examiners</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Division of Federal Employees’ Compensation of the Department of Labor shall hire not less than 15 full-time employees for the purpose of reviewing and processing WHCA claims.</text> </section> 
<section id="H211E46E3499741A4B78997B97A2E069A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modification of collateral requirements for War Hazards Compensation Act claims</header> 
<subsection id="HA812AAC8527440ACBBA189891F78B80F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5CE3BFC0B0AC4F888DD4196D4EC0EDA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Under the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/901">33 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) (in this Act referred to as the <quote>LHWCA</quote>), employers and insurance carriers are required to secure the payment of compensation to covered employees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA09E3381A9AC465C9C5DB8ACB0E0D7F4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 104 of the WHCA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1704">42 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>) provides for the reimbursement by the United States of benefits paid under the LHWCA for injuries or deaths resulting from a war-risk hazard.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H849DCD2445D7475CAD7CCF05FD8F82CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Labor, under section 703.204 of title 20, Code of Federal Regulations, requires insurance carriers to post collateral to secure reimbursement obligations, including for WHCA claims.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31F4EA5296C24FD49B58DE11B6A2DB1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For WHCA claims, the United States Government bears the ultimate financial responsibility for benefit payments, subject to statutory reimbursement procedures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7790EFD3894649319EA2BCC2FB503408"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Requiring full or substantial collateral for WHCA claims imposes unnecessary financial and administrative burdens on LHWCA insurance carriers, increases costs for government contractors, and may discourage carrier participation in markets supporting national defense.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H84A297A5552B44F4999F8FD618B9108D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 32 of the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/932">33 U.S.C. 932</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA239FC9555AE443A8D943FF80A11D613" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H23C290EF27A946589C01F838EDD2E94E"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary may not require an insurance carrier to post collateral, security, or other financial assurance for liabilities arising from claims reimbursable under the War Hazards Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1701">42 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2213E3FDDA2D4B4B9668F29C7FC993AB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming regulatory amendments</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall revise section 703.204 of title 20, Code of Federal Regulations, and any related regulations to conform with the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6B004DEFE9154793B7D4EB8CB00F39B2" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>No effect on benefit entitlements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB0289F329D0B4CC8A57809634CFE1E27" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce or delay benefits payable to an injured employee or surviving beneficiary under the LHWCA or WHCA; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1080AA6F4DA140E3BC788571C7C426CD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>alter the obligation of the United States for timely reimbursement of eligible WHCA claims in accordance with existing law.</text> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

