<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H84F1178A2D7341FB9024EE6DBAC55238" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6832 IH: Packaging and Claims Knowledge Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6832</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to include requirements for recyclable, compostable, and reusable claims for packaging for a consumer product, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF10101175B864E62BCBD80E17E0D40E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB6D214A39C8C438D98CAE084E6D8502C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Packaging and Claims Knowledge Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PACK Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H96E6CF11D87349EFB8909A26A54E375F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements for recyclable, compostable, and reusable claims for packaging for a consumer product</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 26 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD7A18473E3DE46D191A52F2E6B556B09" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H0AF93923D65E415F929DDB5EAFA92B45"><enum>27.</enum><header>Recyclable, compostable, and reusable claims for packaging for a consumer product</header> 
<subsection id="HE7DF183FB2A3420BBEF0421C889BD43F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compostable, Recyclable, and Reusable Claims</header> 
<paragraph id="H1B2E8719506544D2BDDE6CC69A9220F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recyclable Claims</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA5BD84929BF0469DA7CD93B1890ADE81"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deceptive claims prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person may not claim that packaging for a consumer product is recyclable if the packaging is not recyclable.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D770C7A4F2449EFAACEA5537F236DDD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualifying claims of recycling required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), a person shall clearly and prominently qualify the description of a recyclable claim by informing consumers about the availability of recycling programs and collection sites where the item is sold—</text> 
<clause id="H6F64D8C5F0634B71BB3E7B490F81F6A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by including the percentage of consumers or communities that have access to recycle the packaging for the consumer product; or</text></clause> <clause id="H50B48465BFF74949BA0CE405B80BBD4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by including qualifications that vary in strength depending on availability.</text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1B804CD12D049469E5006EB364844D9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exemption from qualified claims for availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person is exempt from the requirement of subparagraph (B) if—</text> <clause id="H459D3A38641C4160BCFB89CA1D8CD2C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a recycling program or facility is available to a substantial majority of consumers or communities in which the consumer product is sold; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB9A1A548C2C24F2FB3951C772366BC2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the entire consumer product package, excluding any minor incidental component, is recyclable.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3C8DC10E4A54187B8B1147E304AF2FA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Not recyclable</header><text>The following circumstances are not considered recyclable for purposes of this paragraph:</text> 
<clause id="HA2FFF03064214502A68C9EB586B21E4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A case in which any component of the consumer product packaging significantly limits the ability to recycle the packaging of the consumer product.</text></clause> <clause id="H152B60350D9F468D87D02BC5F23A3A45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A case in which packaging for a consumer product that is made from recyclable material, but, because of the shape, size, or some other attribute of the consumer product packaging, is not accepted in recycling programs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF17E4EBF6E3D465EA6D16C8C13692821"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compostable Claims for Consumer Product Packaging</header> 
<subparagraph id="H43367502CF234608AE413B0247D7804C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deceptive claims prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person may not make a claim that packaging for a consumer product is compostable if the packaging is not compostable.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13E6DC3F1A224D22A21ACB9481B92CCD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Evidence required</header><text>A person that claims packaging for a consumer product is compostable shall have competent and reliable scientific evidence that the packaging is compostable.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96609EFB8B0746FA9DE4D0276ED5BE56"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualifying claim of compostability required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person shall clearly and prominently include a qualifying description on any claim that the packaging for a consumer product is compostable to the extent necessary to inform consumers about the ability of the packaging to be composted if—</text> <clause id="H2071331DE40A4ABF81898D4D360A84C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the consumer product packaging cannot be composted safely or in a timely manner in a home compost pile or device;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8A13FC6AD7714822AC0A809587B27DAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the claim misleads reasonable consumers about the environmental benefit provided when the consumer product packaging is disposed of in a landfill; or</text></clause> <clause id="H78E434ED26D249BDA27A38B00CE385D0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">municipal or institutional composting facilities are not available where the item is sold to a substantial majority of consumers or communities.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0271841BF548495DB312DBBD66137CC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reusable Claims for Consumer Product Packaging</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8C47D50EF5C04F7DBACD66BBB3540906"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deceptive claims prohibited</header><text>A person may not claim that packaging for a consumer product is reusable if the packaging is not reusable.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD98D150F9BD44F0D87E71EDB2877FE99"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Means for reuse required</header><text>A person may not make an unqualified reusable claim for consumer product packaging unless the person provides the means for reusing the packaging through—</text> 
<clause id="H464DF02FA45042BB978215319F16B2D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing a system for the collection and reuse of the packaging; or</text></clause> <clause id="H794487173F1A48918FBA909A988AADA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>offering for sale a product that consumers can purchase to reuse the original packaging.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCB9E1852FF8426FAE0B017CE9B354E2" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of Resin Identification Codes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consumer product packaging that is not eligible to bear a compostable, recyclable, or reusable claim shall not bear a resin identification code that is surrounded by three chasing, triangulated arrows, except that such packaging may bear a resin identification code that is surrounded by an equilateral triangle, consistent with ASTM International Standard D7611/D7611M–19.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD343667A25B948C6BF32BF72EF2C1984"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Third-party Certification</header><text>A person may not make a claim that packaging for a consumer product is compostable, recyclable, or reusable unless an accredited third-party certification body has certified such claim.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F2AD0FC2D6E419CA98BF6D6DA6912EB" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section may not be construed to apply to packaging that is not for a consumer product.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7CEF5B6D7C434D1F9776FA51CA5686CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission Guidance</header> <paragraph id="HCB2F3E88BA124FCD9027483600E5DDAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall issue guidance for a person to be in compliance with subsection (a) that includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDDE3DF823DA94BC5A00695CEF5141947"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Criteria for accreditation bodies to consider in accrediting third party certification bodies, including whether—</text> <clause id="HB622017491564BFB9DA0C17A64A04F35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a third party certification body meets the requirements of ISO/IEC 17065:2012, including any amendment; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H73EE7FEE2D214F8982801B695D3BB2DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such body is qualified to certify compostable, recyclable, and reusable claims for consumer product packaging consistent with the requirements described in this section.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE54ABE45CEE94577B5A8352BF95756A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A consideration of different types of consumer product packaging materials, including paper, plastic, glass, metal, or a combination thereof.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H871182F755E74FBE942E96D18DD0306B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A consideration of different colors, shapes, and sizes of consumer product packaging materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45EF390C458B425998F15B1EAC3A026C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules and regulations prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 6(g), the Commission may not issue any binding rule or regulation under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA7B883542604F7D9ADC9C4B7E84346B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personnel and Formation of Advisory Council</header><text>In issuing guidance and in administering the provisions of this section the Commission shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8E4CA656F0F446587C059A908F73BD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>work with and consider input from the Administrator to leverage the knowledge of the Environmental Protection Agency on issues related to waste and product lifecycle management, including on issues relating to the use and management of compostable, recyclable, and reusable consumer product packaging; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78A1232DADB948CFA30F08E24E8E919E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall establish an advisory council that meets at least annually and is comprised of subject matter and technical experts representing industry stakeholders, including packaging material suppliers, manufacturers of consumer products, and entities involved in the collection and management of discarded consumer product packaging.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H83B536E4C3664F54B14414E5161D8DE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <paragraph id="HAB82F7F72EB945D19409FDFF689AD950"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair and Deceptive Acts or Practices</header><text>A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BD6689A4EAA41A4B0FED13FCA1F5904"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5FC2D8B6618C4CFD964344BEE9BCA760"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of this section were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06BB7CBF49354CBDAC55ABB38D5214ED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and Immunities</header><text>Any person that violates this section shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0DA112AEC53F4921BC6ECB836E75B06F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Compelled Claims</header><text>The Commission may not compel, require, or otherwise mandate a person to make a claim that consumer product packaging is compostable, recyclable, or reusable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E12C507A074420DAB4ADE3530A394D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text>A State and political subdivision of a State may not establish, enforce, or continue in effect any provision of law or a legal requirement that is not identical with any requirement under this section.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF1B82E772D7419083F23DDF33C70C67"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H663CF23F55294B79A801ADD71362722B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accreditation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>accreditation</term> means a determination by an accreditation body that a third-party certification body meets the applicable requirements of ISO/IEC 17065:2012, including any amendment, and is qualified to certify compostable, recyclable, and reusable claims for consumer product packaging.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FAE00464B9F44DDB613204EF56DC011"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accreditation Body</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>accreditation body</term> means a person that performs accreditation of third-party certification bodies and is in compliance with ISO/IEC 17011:2017, including any amendment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA9CBC6EB53047428ADC26C4188BFD14"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Accredited third-party certification body</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>accredited third-party certification body</term> means a third-party certification body that an accreditation body has determined meets the requirements of ISO/IEC 17065:2012, including any amendment, and is qualified to certify and is certifying compostable, recyclable, and reusable claims for consumer product packaging.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF0E87B347634619800A5D831EADEE4E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADC43AEE5A254A2F9BD4CC16717F246C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Claim</header><text>The term <term>claim</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H04F8783E105E4640875FE739D084CBD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any statement or representation that is conveyed through any means, including through writing, symbols, marks, graphics, or electronic or digital links; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2157A12FC0F24CD483A6E2B7C59141DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any instruction regarding how to recycle, compost, or reuse packaging.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41AACC21F8A047D6B2C1E321016F17E5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20CA55B2099B42CC9A386463BEA59130"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Compostable</header><text>The term <term>compostable</term> means the packaging is designed to be associated with materials collected for composting that meets ASTM or equivalent industrial compostability standards, and similarly appropriate standards for the case of home compostability, and is capable of breaking down into, or otherwise becoming part of, stable and mature compost at an appropriate industrial composting facility, or in a home compost pile or device.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07F6BB2970BA4F63A717BC768616D61D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Consumer Product</header><text>The term <term>consumer product</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H6DDA8BE7B6C549B6BE96FCBD80489766"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any tangible product;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0579AC48459E42F2AA76EB01B69E60A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is—</text> <clause id="HB6881A65F83E4F0096E14519753497C9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sold, offered for sale, or distributed in the United States, or intended to be sold, offered for sale, or distributed in the United States; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4254A6CBCCB04ECC8EE9F28396AF2BA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to a person that is an individual consumer and not a trust, firm, joint stock company, corporation (including a government corporation), partnership, association, State, municipality, commission, political subdivision of a State, or any interstate body, including any department, agency, and instrumentality of the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DDF830B5E5B49C4916439C96BBA1F4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which is normally used or consumed by an individual consumer, including for personal, recreational, educational, family, household, or personal property maintenance or care purposes, including any product that is ordinarily available for purchase by an individual consumer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B0DAE67BD00484EA6641A20530FCB43"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Packaging</header><text>The term <term>packaging</term> means any material that is used for the containment, protection, handling, delivery, and presentation of a tangible product that is sold, offered for sale, or distributed in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8296807CCAD474FA00B75AEF92D4AAD" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means any individual, partnership, corporation, trust, estate, cooperative, association, or other entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2701E1A94A114B149B1AB09E8E3D4DA0"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Recyclable</header><text>The term <term>recyclable</term> means that packaging can be collected, sorted, reprocessed, and ultimately reused in manufacturing or to make another item.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7988648A01A4CB3B5FF6533344DACC8" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Reusable</header><text>The term <term>reusable</term> means the packaging is designed to accomplish within the life cycle of the packaging more than one trip, rotation, or use for the same purpose for which the packaging was primarily designed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC953C0309E684DEB8687508FC0D04867"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Substantial majority</header><text>The term <term>substantial majority</term> means 60 percent or more.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF4F117E3B324AD0A14FF527AEAD1A2F"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Third-party Certification Body</header><text>The term <term>third-party certification body</term> means a person that is eligible to be considered for accreditation to evaluate, develop, and certify compostable, recyclable, and reusable claims for consumer product packaging.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

