<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H165D75A7116941CFA43269090291EAD5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9299 IH: Advancing Next-Generation Genetic Learning for Effective Resource Strategy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9299</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a grant program to award amounts to eligible entities to develop and carry out programs to incorporate eDNA monitoring techniques into and use eDNA monitoring techniques in carrying out sport fish surveys, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H039BF359C62749EBBF538E16DDBF0A69"><section id="HA44FA9FF5C58489BAA8EA1CDABD91747" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Next-Generation Genetic Learning for Effective Resource Strategy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H263F8B4DEDC74FA2978665FB2E6B13F6"> <enum>2.</enum> <header><enum-in-header>e</enum-in-header>DNA sport fish survey grant program</header> <subsection id="H2FC570D0523F4ADB8E369881F76589FD"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and Sport Fishing and Boating Partnership Council, shall establish a grant program to award amounts to eligible entities to develop and carry out programs to incorporate eDNA monitoring techniques into and use eDNA monitoring techniques in carrying out sport fish surveys, to be known as the <quote>eDNA Sport Fish Survey grant program</quote>.</text>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                  <subsection id="H25CE6A6F5032475A8C618BA33F145459">
                                                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                                                  <header>Applications</header>
 <text>To be eligible for a grant under the grant program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                  <subsection id="HB4AB0CD748924D6A9FF4D24B249FD20C">
                                                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                                                  <header>State and tribal fish and wildlife
                                                  agencies</header>
 <text>In carrying out the grant program, the Secretary shall encourage each eligible entity that is awarded a grant under the grant program to collaborate and work in coordination with relevant State and Tribal fish and wildlife agencies.</text>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                  <subsection id="HC7E0209E88374716B6627B7FDD4413EE">
                                                  <enum>(d)</enum>
                                                  <header>Eligible uses</header>
 <text>An eligible entity that is awarded a grant under the grant program shall use such grant to develop and carry out a program to incorporate eDNA monitoring techniques into and use eDNA monitoring techniques in carrying out sport fish surveys in order to—</text>
                                                  <paragraph id="HA0C3D03B6978475F98B95AF11306C0BA">
                                                  <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>increase the spatial scale of the sampling of sport fish surveys across broader geographic areas, including under surveyed or remote regions;</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  <paragraph id="HFC36292B501247DB870C192219AD366F">
                                                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>increase the frequency of sport fish surveys for improved accuracy of population count and species distribution for management;</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  <paragraph id="HBC2EB37017394CE88EC89E9E985343D3">
                                                  <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>enhance the accuracy of species identification and population estimates of sport fish;</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  <paragraph id="H8B0F6E7C59EC43BA82688E182A53364E">
                                                  <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>improve the availability of data for sport fish populations to inform fisheries management and conservation practices;</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  <paragraph id="HB765F3E21A2B4D26A1CF0924A9B61D1E">
                                                  <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>detect invasive species; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7A466822D654986A9A71047CAFD0DE9"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>monitor species listed as endangered species under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>).</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                  <subsection id="H448A7F1A493C42E085F09F3903C51857">
                                                  <enum>(e)</enum>
                                                  <header>Priority</header>
 <text>In awarding grants under the grant program, the Secretary shall give priority to applications from eligible entities that demonstrate the intent of the eligible entity to collaborate with other eligible entities in using any awarded amounts.</text>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                  <subsection id="H550C0E19B2E54DD48BEBDC010A0357DE">
                                                  <enum>(f)</enum>
                                                  <header>Data collection</header>
 <text>In carrying out the grant program, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, identify and collect data that informs objective metrics of the efficacy of each program carried out by each eligible entity that is awarded a grant under the grant program.</text>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                  <subsection id="H065CC536837B42129A8476FFF2E9416F">
                                                  <enum>(g)</enum>
                                                  <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2033.</text>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                  <subsection id="HEED805E1C4A94A38BFCB3197D1379FA0">
                                                  <enum>(h)</enum>
                                                  <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6BF9DC1A2E5844A6B2246083C20FD47B"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header><enum-in-header>e</enum-in-header>DNA</header> <text>The term <quote>eDNA</quote> means genetic material, such as DNA or RNA, that is collected from an environmental sample of water or sediment.</text>
        </paragraph>
                                                  <paragraph id="H6CCB0798F6DB4CA59829307F7142F916">
                                                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                                                  <header>Eligible entity</header>
 <text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text>
                                                  <subparagraph id="H023F0AFDAD594553B637A0B71BE6D2FA">
                                                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a State, local, or Tribal government;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF49E8BFFEB94C0EA917CEA67A99A742"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>an institution of higher education; and</text>
                                                  </subparagraph>
                                                  <subparagraph id="HF75DB36B3B5E414F98AE340BFAD18439">
                                                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>a nonprofit organization.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D4FF41991C04713A506D7D619C01C6F"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Grant program</header> <text>The term <quote>grant program</quote> means the eDNA Sport Fish Survey grant program established under subsection (a).</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  <paragraph id="H8E807E652C6B4393ADB1EC48D9277730">
                                                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                                                  <header>Institution of higher education</header>
 <text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  <paragraph id="HB177C2A82C674FD28062A12374EEE76D">
                                                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                                                  <header>Secretary</header>
 <text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey.</text>
                                                  </paragraph>
                                                  </subsection>
                                                </section></legis-body></bill>

