<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC40AA7BF9FDC42EFAD9684CB4E4E0BD9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9240 IH: Tax Dollar Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide the Comptroller General of the United States access to State records and documents for the purposes of certain audits, investigations, and evaluations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDA938340A663431E9CD42EDB35BCFF92" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0248ECA07152460E932C5D6C9C4821D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tax Dollar Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0D9CE761F1324C9FB1916CF7515701B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Comptroller General access to State records and documents for the purposes of certain audits, investigations, and evaluations</header> <subsection id="HC494FFA451D54B79926B445687182561"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access upon request</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any State, local government or municipality receiving Federal funds, directly or indirectly, shall provide the Comptroller General of the United States, upon request, access to the State budget, financial records, expenditure reports, contracts, grants, subgrants, and other documents necessary to audit, investigate, or evaluate the receipt, expenditure, administration, and fiscal controls of Federal funds.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8A33518085B4BD7A70A113C37FC1DF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Access to records for the proceeding fiscal year</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the end of each fiscal year, and annually thereafter, each State receiving Federal funds shall provide the Comptroller General of the United States access to the records described in subsection (a) for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBAF8AD88021946F6876A7E3774C5907D"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Failure To provide access</header> <text>If a State fails to provide such access, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget may withhold, suspend, or condition Federal funds provided to such State until the State provides such access.</text>
      </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

