<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26220-KNG-CS-FMG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 701 ATS: Designating the week of April 20 through 26, 2026, as “National Dark Sky Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 701</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of April 20 through 26, 2026, as <quote>National Dark Sky Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States are increasingly seeking opportunities for outdoor recreation, stargazing, and unique nighttime experiences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas national parks, rural communities, and protected landscapes with dark skies attract visitors interested in stargazing, recreation, and nature tourism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the night sky has significantly impacted cultural traditions and human history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ability to observe the stars, planets, and other celestial bodies is an important part of the shared natural heritage of all people and should be preserved for future generations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas dark sky tourism provides economic opportunities for communities located near parks, observatories, and open landscapes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preserving dark skies supports scientific discovery, astronomic research, and educational opportunities for students and communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas astronomy education and public stargazing programs inspire interest in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas artificial lighting can obscure visibility of the night sky and may limit opportunities for the people of the United States to observe stars, planets, and other celestial phenomena;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas excessive artificial light can disrupt wildlife behavior and ecosystems;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many species rely on natural cycles of light and darkness to regulate biological process and ecosystem balance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reducing brightness at night can save energy, reduce consumption, and lower costs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas artificial lighting has increased significantly in recent decades, contributing to light pollution across the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas efforts to reduce light pollution can be achieved through simple measures such as shielding lights, directing lighting downward, and limiting unnecessary illumination: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idab7269e2213b4822914caa4de2166f25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of April 20 through 26, 2026, as <quote>National Dark Sky Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7e316402dff412cb76162eec61dfbe4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages Federal agencies to coordinate among themselves to expand safe and informative dark skies opportunities to support local communities and all people of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ee39b1246144c6c8ddeabc296a4aa51"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages communities, educators, scientists, and local governments to raise awareness of the value of preserving dark skies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4bf597f75544491d87f8ca3207dd73a1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages individuals and organizations to adopt responsible outdoor lighting practices that protect the natural night sky.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

