<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77B8C148A08144F6BE9D1CE8B63AAE7D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8914 IH: No Taxpayer-Funded Settlement Slush Funds Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8914</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 1304 of title 31, United States Code to restrict payments for compromise settlements or awards.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H319437C7312840A58A28DC5BA3E7D875" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB3434B206FDD4DB8A512405E95667649" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Taxpayer-Funded Settlement Slush Funds Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H381A394BE0F04FD3ABDEE31D1581986F"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Restriction on Federal funds in connection with Trump, et al. v. IRS, et al</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used to create or make payments to fund the compensation fund created by the settlement agreement entered into on May 18, 2026, in connection with the disposition of Trump, et al. v. IRS, et al., Civil Action No. 1:26-cv-20609–KMW, before the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of Florida.</text>
        </section> 
<section id="H13467E0C0A774F3C885BFFD910A6B1F8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restriction on certain payments for compromise settlements or awards</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H78797C1B09F243EB848310D4AB3053BE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HC14044E355BF426A93CC32DB9CDA6600"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A compromise settlement or award may not be paid to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7F50A553DD184208BD20A00FC7DA04E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President or Vice President;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7C0B72F736A405285540CB1B48755CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the parent, spouse, child, or spouse of a child of the President or Vice President;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB13D03C829143BD9EB1D2479E6A6B75">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>a presidentially-owned entity;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB8CF52A440C4BCD8B378D0482D32F3C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any member of the cabinet;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4019AABD6A5C473EBAB6AF837A83FC39" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any individual who is employed by the Executive Office of the President who is paid at a rate of basic pay equivalent to or exceeding the GS–15 level;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30B57A575FA94D6FAAA2AC1B901E46B1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a political appointee; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B60E52AC71543CABB2842E893B5CD2D" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who served in a position described under paragraph (4), (5), or (6) during the period for which the President who appointed such individual is in Office, including any period after such individual leaves such a position.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H4CCACE75BA5D4D638E32690A9C8610A1"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A compromise settlement or award may not be paid with respect to a claim alleging harm resulting from an investigation, prosecution, or conviction for an offense related to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2DB8DD6075874289AA728083BBF8E187"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the January 6, 2021, attack on the United States Capitol;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF65E2781C5C4F75B06333C57A3C9446"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interference in the 2016 presidential election by a foreign government; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44B4713C277A47CD91C3C3499E86250E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the same facts or circumstances as a civil action filed against the United States that was dismissed with prejudice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD9E6D4BF76FB4E95B56CB350AAE2FE67"><enum>(g)</enum> <paragraph id="H7306476AE08144FB880625046B1E0E70" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a payment of more than $100,000 is made for a compromise settlement or award in accordance with this section, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall report to the Chair and Ranking Members of the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBB427A1357964E0D8444730F8D9E1801"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of the plaintiff or awardee of such settlement or award.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E42C4E0AF4C4BA4AC849C47E5E0EA59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The type of judgment for which the settlement or award was made.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H206E7E2DB5DA4FD894567150871FDD8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name of each attorney representing the plaintiff or awardee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18692E56F8F541FBA5604F35D5210788"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The name of each agency involved in the claim and the name of each official approving such settlement or award.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD2AAE63D37041FAA5767452AB0E5A0B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A brief description of the facts and circumstances that gave rise to the settlement or award and the authority authorizing such settlement or award.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H250DD8D31B2B47849E6BEF6CAF9DAABD" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide notice to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate prior to authorizing a payment for a compromise settlement or award in accordance with this section if that payment—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H724E6D3F4C3C4EAC95DA3F3FBF58DAC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is of more than $250,000 to be made for a compromise settlement or award in accordance with this section; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED9DCE82DDB349488B9BBA98A3522E95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is to be made on the basis of imminent litigation or suit against the United States, or against its agencies or officials upon obligations or liabilities of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBCF427499B440EDB92C975F0E936A37" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A payment for which a notice is required to be submitted under paragraph (2) may not be made for a period of 120 days after the date on which such notice is received.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H4451655F086C449BA8074CDBEB47055F"><enum>(h)</enum><text>In the case that a compromise settlement or award is made in violation of subsection (e) or (f), the Attorney General may bring a civil action against a plaintiff or awardee who received a settlement or award in violation of subsection (e) or (f) in an appropriate district court for injunctive relief and repayment of such settlement or award.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE61B2829196C4835A34A1DC2A097AB6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Nothing in this section, or an amendment made by this section, shall be construed to prohibit Congress from appropriating funds for a payment prohibited by this section on an individual per claim basis.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3A5A7480A1294A0791D8C70BEBD5D7AA" commented="no"> <enum>(j)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A settlement or award made on or after January 20, 2025, (including any settlement or award entered into prior to the date of the enactment of this subsection) shall be subject to the requirements of subsections (e) through (h).</text>
                </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D1DF029CE6D41B8BA05A35B2B38EE91" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury may not establish a compensation fund, or approve a payment to such a fund, and no Federal funds may be used by the Secretary to so establish such a fund or approve such a payment—</text> <paragraph id="HA8AA0419C1354D269F86296A3B27FB97" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pursuant to a compromise settlement with the President; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF552218514F4259A5471C4D00B6D0B9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if such payment would be in violation of subsection (e) or (f) if made from the Judgment Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27BA58155B7D4C079456DD680E92521C"><enum>(l)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD135E383718B4984964F3A9375966D9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>presidentially-owned entity</term> means a corporation, association, partnership, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, other legal entity, or sole proprietorship in which the President or Vice President has an ownership stake, except that such term does not include an entity in which more than 100 people have an ownership stake and the President or Vice President, as applicable, holds no more than five percent in a beneficial ownership stake and that—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E2E117F6CF54C48B3C0B6A653FF0C1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issues securities registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission pursuant to section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78l">15 U.S.C. 78l</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H280208C7A7C84EE1BD409D798078BDB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an investment company registered pursuant to section 8 of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-8">15 U.S.C. 80a–8</external-xref>) that does not have a stated policy of concentrating the investments of the investment company in any industry, business, single country other than the United States, or bonds of a single State within the United States; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B00784A16B241E49DD9842BF943C5ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a unit investment trust, as defined in section 4 of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-4">15 U.S.C. 80a–4</external-xref>) that—</text> 
<clause id="HE427446FBBB94FBE937789DB70939DCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a regulated investment company, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/851">section 851</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8CE847CDEF7E44B1B1BCDC076D5D62FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not have a stated policy of concentrating the investments of the investment company in any industry, business, single country other than the United States, or bonds of a single State within the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77FF7190D66B46C9A4055E668A27B059"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>political appointee</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 9803 of title 5.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

