<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25908-R37-RR-94X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 SRES 431 ATS: Supporting the goals and objectives of Choose Respect Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 431</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251003">October 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and objectives of Choose Respect Day.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Intimate Partner and Sexual Violence Survey—</text><paragraph id="idc64732fe7b8a4534bf87d81db597bd40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>up to 12,000,000 individuals in the United States report experiencing intimate partner violence annually, including physical violence, rape, or stalking; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21d82e1f28e7431da7a488c967270716"><enum>(2)</enum><text>approximately 1 in 5 women and up to 1 in 7 men in the United States have experienced severe physical violence by an intimate partner at some point in their lifetimes;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Bureau of Justice Statistics, 3 women in the United States on average are killed each day by a current or former intimate partner;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas domestic violence can affect anyone, but women who are 18 to 34 years of age typically experience the highest rates of domestic violence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas survivors of domestic violence are strong, courageous, and resilient;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas most female survivors of intimate partner violence have been previously victimized by the same offender;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas domestic violence is cited as a significant factor in homelessness among families;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas millions of children are exposed to domestic violence each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a study found that children who were exposed to domestic violence in their households were 15 times more likely to be physically or sexually assaulted in their lifetime than other children who were not exposed to domestic violence in their households;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas survivors of domestic violence experience immediate and long-term negative outcomes, including detrimental effects on mental and physical health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research consistently shows that being abused by an intimate partner increases the likelihood of substance use by that individual, as well as associated harmful consequences;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 85 percent of American Indian and Alaska Native women have experienced some form of intimate partner violence in their lifetimes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers in the United States put their lives at risk each day by responding to incidents of domestic violence, which can be among the most volatile and deadly calls;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Congress passed the Choose Respect Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 931) to encourage safety and respect in relationships, especially among adolescents and young adults;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Congress designated October 1 of each year as Choose Respect Day to increase awareness of domestic violence and to encourage those in relationships to choose respect; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas October is Domestic Violence Awareness Month: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ida58898d818294118bde9cefdc396f8af"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and objectives of Choose Respect Day; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1c977bd568547f186a058d3ca466ad6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all private citizens, organizations, and Federal, State, and local governmental and legislative entities to recognize Choose Respect Day through proclamations, activities, and educational efforts in furtherance of changing the culture around the tolerance of domestic violence.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

