<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7F095FF36144146AD50E1AD6F150FF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8463 IH: Pre-Payment Fraud Prevention and Treasury Data Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8463</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish governmentwide requirements for pre-payment fraud prevention actions, to provide the U.S. Treasury appropriate data resources, to facilitate participation in governmentwide anti-fraud data sharing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H76D8CC80478345CDA0B30220EF6E93F4" style="OLC"><section id="HCA1D789863594781930EFDAA95EA8945" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pre-Payment Fraud Prevention and Treasury Data Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFB16EB5300E84FAC86AFEB13F375F632"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pre-payment fraud prevention requirements for agencies</header><subsection id="H1CD9943EF5C846558FA630AB59041A76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of pre-Payment agency responsibilities</header><paragraph id="H75BE9F36BFA24D6E81ADFAFA32CC8EE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">Chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3325">section 3325</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7D0F6BB4E6C643B8BA93101B692E9B50" style="USC"><section id="HC03882B5AD244BC094CB2F5FBFAEDF73"><enum>3325a.</enum><header>Agency duties for fraud and improper payment prevention before
 the issuance of a payment voucher request</header><subsection id="HCA37049C181B4DC5A6D1246BF231A070"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory actions before issuing a payment voucher</header><text>The head of an agency, or an officer or employee described in section 3325(a)(1)(B), may not certify a voucher under section 3325 until the following requirements are met:</text><paragraph id="HD52D3772E9894FF8A250B5A776126EDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each pre-certification requirement described in subsection (b) for such payment request.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H064B2D74FDF4435CAC7133B0889206A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Confirmation is provided that the payment complies with any disbursement requirement and instruction, including any pre-certification requirement, published by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB51EA5406733431F93CB06ADB51B1405"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Confirmation is provided that any other appropriate payment, account, and payee validation program or service that the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Director, requires to reduce fraud and an improper payment resulting in financial loss to the Government, including any agency evaluation of the fraud-risk indicator of a program required under section 3352 and agency procedures required under section 3554(b)(1), have been conducted, in accordance with necessary exceptions for statutory, policy, or operational reasons.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AEB9962881344A78E564EBA73B74A2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment verification pre-Certification requirements</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and as needed thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, issue regulations, and guidance as necessary, for the pre-certification requirements of this section, for vouchers certified under section 3325, including any deadline for pre-certification information and related records to be submitted to the requisite Treasury official and disbursing official under subchapter IV of this chapter, before the date of disbursement in order to allow for sufficient time to meet the requirements of this section, including the following:</text><paragraph id="HD8717EB787ED47D3B5026A2BD468D286"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Funds are available at the time the obligation is incurred and if an obligation is incurred when funds are not available, then the agency may not certify the payment voucher.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A0AEFEEA23A4AA1846B86E9796484D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The amount of the payment and the name of the payee on the payment voucher are correct, in conformance with the prescribed standard format.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H181DAF4042424F239098174F6097734B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A valid social security number, taxpayer identification number, employer identification number, individual taxpayer identification number, or payee ID number is provided for each payee on the voucher, if applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A3AE08A3C24877A6A13667AE28B4A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The appropriation or fund from which the payment will be made is available for the purpose described in the voucher and indicated with the appropriate Treasury Account Symbol or Business Event Type Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B7A9A926BFD4979BDACC59319B786CF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A payee is not deceased, if the payment would be improperly made to a deceased payee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H065D78B12914400DAEFE0A2515AA95C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The account number, if any, provided on the payment voucher is held at a financial institution and is open, valid, and belongs to the payee or a valid designee of the payee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E17FFA886574BE18AB04A329E6BBED7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other identifier in conformance with the payment verification pre-certification requirements established by the Secretary of the Treasury, which may include the Procurement Instrument Identified and the Federal Award Identification Number.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E0E7015533F4CF18EC32E92FC937A00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Return of payment voucher</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Director, shall issue guidance and establish procedures to authorize the Chief Disbursing Officer of the Department of the Treasury, or an agency disbursing official, to return to the relevant agency certifying official, including a notification to the agency, any payment or payment voucher issued under section 3325 which does not comply with pre-certification verification requirements established under this section as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDB939D49C4874DE7894FB77A24A2D4D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agency requests for exemptions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall include in the guidance issued under subsection (b), or in other regulations or guidance issued under this chapter, a process for agencies to request exemptions from some or all of the payment verification requirements for specific payments or categories of payments under this section. Any approved exemption shall be documented in any related payment voucher certified under section 3325 for the duration of the exemption.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H884B091D7D124950A8E7279427704BD5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Codes, is amended by inserting after the item for section 3325 the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9D6231A2C6504F46BC86D0EAFA1944C3" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">3325a. Agency duties for fraud and improper
                                payment prevention prior to issuing a payment voucher
 request.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9501448771C24139A54952F29A386287"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to responsibilities of agency certifying official for payment vouchers</header><text>Section 3528(a) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H71DC1C808C6F45A2B6F97A20AD6DABDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting after <quote>of this title</quote> the following: <quote>, including pre-certification requirement described in section 3325a</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H543A0C693F534B2C83BF04435276FB8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H286DD0933FC04985A912D9D6D3AEBF35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HABCDCCB5FDA8458EAE1F85C034FCD321" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H167CA05B62AF47E08E6DB80613991865"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ensuring that—</text><subparagraph id="HD9DFFAB315324927988D36E4487551E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agency has complied with the requirements of section 3325a and subchapter IV of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BF2AF3C16984359A7BF66F30D1DA3B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a covered recipient is in compliance with the reporting requirements under section 6107.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8CFA5B501C4443DA151AC2C3EC4807F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prepayment requirements of payment disbursing officials</header><text>Section 3325 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H04F5DC8896874432953D27876C5F5B11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d) by striking <quote>taxpayer identifying number of each person</quote> and inserting <quote>information required to be submitted under section 3325a(b) of each payee</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF9E36A2A935481A9A62DBAD4A8EA41C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9A202EF2EA1F497C9BC9CFA6BC0638F7" style="OLC"><subsection id="H853C73A2FDE04E8E8415C93CA5D3B4E1"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H554932D6A44E45978678DF9292162F35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Before certifying a voucher to a disbursing official, the head of an agency or an officer or employee of an agency described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1), as applicable, shall take necessary actions to accurately disburse payments to the recipients of those payments, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H09B2842B17DA416C96C4C6C7052F1EA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>verifying the accuracy of the bank account information to which a payment is to be disbursed, to the extent practicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E848DC8BFC74BD09BA4771F1A416C88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comparing the bank account information of the proposed recipient to other payment records available to the agency, to the extent practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2564A08EA9E6425CA5F86050E8350AF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall issue guidance to carry out this subsection, which may be carried out through any guidance issued for section 3325a(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB21BF14A636D4B98890E3B07A6059667"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements and authorities of payment disbursing officials</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 3325(a) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H08948F6F7614405D8EFB7B20F86AC89C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, compliance with an order to pause a payment pursuant to section 3337(b),</quote> after <quote>except for the correctness of computations on a voucher</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A25E9F0DAEF403FABC388702C8FA50C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>,,</quote> and inserting a comma.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CA8D997AC9A44A48D7AADB89D4DC999"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Addition of fraud prevention indicators to agency improper payment risk assessments</header><paragraph id="H8F162DC4A86045F2BEA0B01BBC152064"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions amendments</header><text>Section 3351 of title 31, United States Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA5109163485C4DFDA351736EF6B1CEA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><clause id="H20E9D4AFAEE74B4181BD29D046D8AFAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Initiative</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">System</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HE870AF940AC74EBAA02BD7167CC6CFBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Initiative</quote> and inserting <quote>System</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H8510E6FC2CBF41A3A1A16FEEEF625788"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>initiative</quote> and inserting <quote>system</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AEB536FA7BC4749A24BDE78C044EA15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding the following in the appropriate alphabetical order and redesignating the paragraphs accordingly:</text><quoted-block id="H7112D062F9E94215BC33E2D23D5BB49C" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H5002824E93FE47B181156658BD233205"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Appropriate authorizing and appropriations committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate authorizing and appropriations committees of Congress</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB85D152F7562494CB52F2E1FDABF3192"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EFBFDF4C5D944A2A27E274B0C4FBC91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44512C2285584BE5A8628FCB08DFF063"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7154B87D8606441AAC5F78A14DE7C831"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Budget Committee of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Budget of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31FF5B0CCEC6473FB0989A3FDA44E4A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other relevant congressional committee of jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H61BE74EBBDD94C97B57244B4C17DA4BB"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE85F95884E14287A41FB67AA456AE3A"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Fraud-risk indicator</header><text>The term <term>fraud-risk indicator</term> means an objective data point or analytic signal that indicates an anomalous payment pattern or increase in the volume of a payment amount, a verified data mismatch, network or behavioral anomaly, or match identified by the Do Not Pay system and any other payment, account, and payee validation program or service provided by the Department of the Treasury that would result in financial loss to the Government.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C54BB81EB7D44178F6F9741F8745310"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 3352(a)(1) of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HD132AE50283C4206BE96A1541D1D45B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H855D276D7AB94E1ABA96E5827FED80A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA5772C4015E4847BD9E9E974D2E408E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HDE8707F9E1F44171B9EBABDEB9D0AA7B" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H6AFCAC47359A4938BEA4717FE2A9BD1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>design and apply fraud-risk indicators to the programs identified under paragraph (A).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4932AE6F6D1149439C07C576A486B285"><enum>3.</enum><header>Treasury do not pay system</header><subsection id="H0C48F4628A1A4C6F94E8C5FDEB6C94EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 3354 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H53A83906DFB04726B7974F9C7C36F6BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Initiative</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">System</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H887180AF6B754B5795C66CF0EF06A638"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H9D6BDD958AD94F04865C77DBACB07943"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H09BBAF4ECBBD490692A50B2E5EA08AD3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H20F3C1E58BA34D85A3E45276FC925FDE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of each executive agency shall establish and maintain appropriate preaward and prepayment procedures to prevent and recover improper payments, including payments resulting in financial loss to the Government, and to prevent financial fraud. Such procedures shall include, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="HDC63A8C186D644958C122FDBE01CDFD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>screening all persons or entities that receive, or seek to receive, Federal awards or payments against all appropriate Do Not Pay system data assets, including data assets described in paragraph (2)(a), and risk tools before an award is made or a payment request is submitted to the disbursing officer in accordance with section 3325a; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AD41729080A46F8B876894315E45233"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a periodic review of available data assets and notification to the Secretary of any data asset that the agency requires access to, either directly or through the Do Not Pay system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1046C9538E4496487EC05F15E5076E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H6E8BF87DB1184980B1C942E177F1D052"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>At a minimum and before issuing any payment or award, each executive agency shall review as appropriate the following databases to verify eligibility of the payment and award:</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the Social Security Act, and the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act, the Secretary shall have access to the following data assets and incorporate them in the Do Not Pay system, without the need to pursue designation under paragraph (3), for the sole purposes of improper payment prevention and detection:</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H47C9B9F5DB0D4A57B9EB499BA7BF4E77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H41AEC31E123B4745949A0B4E92B16AC2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HFE7BC9C3AB05494B9736F3474D593A69"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Directory of New Hires pursuant to section 453(j) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/653">42 U.S.C. 653(j)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32A05DBF5B0743B89C6AAC94BFAB8CF8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Information made available to such head pursuant to a request made under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103(i)(9)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77060E2AFF8F4598A1B2CAF13F6E81C4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Information made available to the Secretary of Treasury by the Commissioner of Social Security pursuant to section 235 of the Social Security Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A23C508B93D4DDF8D310759A020BA3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HFA01FEDC115E4682AC3699A2EFF9CFB6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H72C79F7BF25144E19996BD073F94F1EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional data assets</header><subparagraph id="H2CEF1437047D40328621706B9F72945B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Secretary may designate additional categories of data assets for inclusion in the Do Not Pay system to address risks of fraud and improper payments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17DD5619736243B5818D4518A008FF3E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privacy and notice</header><text>In designating data assets that include personally identifiable information, law enforcement sensitive information, or information subject to section 552a of title 5, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H38F0E4B14E3B420F9AB9C38824EBD81E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>act in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget; and</text></clause><clause id="H94F9975750CE439794682FCD32917EA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide public notice and an opportunity for comment for not less than 30 days prior to designation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBEC5583521849EAA83C29E8643CB96B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Database inclusion</header><text>Following designation of a category of data assets under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide public notice and an opportunity for comment for not less than 30 days before adding any specific data asset within such category.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DF725F578614B0D8BE9FA3DEEA05C77"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Non-sensitive data</header><text>Data assets that do not include personally identifiable or law enforcement sensitive information may be added at the discretion of the Secretary without designation if a list of such data sets is disclosed to the public on a public website maintained by the Department of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10E1AD8481BB4A4B98C70B44A5EAEE83"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of data matching for purposes of agency use of do not pay system</header><text>For purposes of section 552a of title 5, or any other provision of law, a computerized comparison of two or more automated Federal systems of records, or a computerized comparison of a Federal system of records with other records or non-Federal records, carried out by the Secretary to verify payments or identify or recover improper payments under this section shall not be considered a matching program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91969D3802AD41E786AE56C540A2F84E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on use</header><text>Information obtained through the Do Not Pay system may be used solely for the purposes described in paragraph (1), or for Federal or State law enforcement or investigative purposes. Any officer, employee, contractor, subcontractor, or agent of a Federal or State entity may not publish, examine for a purpose not explicitly authorized under this section, or communicate such information furnished in such data assets other than in fulfillment of the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99C1EA9800444EFC896816DECF663F78"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Penalty for unlawful disclosure</header><text>Any person described in paragraph (5) who knowingly and willfully discloses information in violation of that paragraph shall be fined not more than $5,000, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B9FCA3554A4B2090E4357A25FEDE65"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Exception when payment otherwise required under law</header><text>The head of an executive agency may be exempt from the requirements of paragraph (1) if a Federal statute expressly requires that a payment or award be made notwithstanding potential ineligibility, and the agency head notifies the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget prior to certification of the payment under section 3325.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20EC1C70E6214C6BBB74E165CA36B8F4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>data asset</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3502(17) of title 44.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14C76BD0344D4AED978E4EB4FC17E8B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) through (e) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2F76FC0D995B421BBDA2095506CD5E30" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H1218F976CFA0411DA23691A1C4659D94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of system</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish and maintain a Do Not Pay system, which shall be administered and operated by the Fiscal Service of the Department of the Treasury. The Do Not Pay system shall include—</text><paragraph id="H28739EC2BD7D4BBC8CDF75D43C6379B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the data assets described in subsection (a)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34C57698EDD545AE8F7387E950144B2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such other data assets as the Secretary of the Treasury may designate, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to assist agencies in carrying out subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED11C3939EA24F36B9BE7F131555887C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State and other governmental use</header><paragraph id="H76FE41C684C64DBA999B9405A72B7C63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State and local government administering a federally funded program, and any contractor, subcontractor, or agent thereof, including State and local government auditors, shall establish and maintain appropriate preaward and prepayment procedures to prevent and recover improper payments, including payments resulting in financial loss to the Government, and to prevent financial fraud. Such procedures shall include, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="H0D246D946B67468691D79EC1DCDA1EE9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>screening all persons or entities that receive, or seek to receive, Federal awards or payments against all appropriate Do Not Pay system data assets, including data assets described in subsection (a)(2), and risk tools before an award is made or a payment request is submitted to the disbursing officer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02E1F7A77BF349459E94B943AE0E0AD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>periodic review of available data assets and notification to the Secretary of any data asset that the agency requires access to, either directly or through the Do Not Pay system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A1B51A8723440DF8DE1B5FD9C26436E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other governmental use</header><text>The judicial and legislative branches of the United States (as defined in section 202(e) of title 18) shall have access to the Do Not Pay system for purposes of verifying eligibility for payments and preventing fraud and improper payments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2763BE1127784607AB7FA31180E00F7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall issue guidance establishing privacy and other requirements applicable to such access, consistent with section 552a of title 5.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H857B246505184D258CE59D230C414863"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the appropriate authorizing and appropriations committees of Congress an annual report on the operation of the Do Not Pay system, which may be included as part of another report submitted to Congress by the Secretary, and which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H9C9407FCE04B465ABEB1DE8DFA9DCE08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An evaluation of the effectiveness of the system in reducing improper payments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6903C4A05B274A2E9FCEB7DCEA476FF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information on the frequency of corrections and identification of erroneous data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H313110C571C14F6CA818CDE3AB556F75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations for legislative or administrative action to enhance the operations of the system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7ACB11648C3403FBBE4BA7912A068E4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of agency compliance with the requirements of this section, including a listing of all memorandums established with the head of an agency under subsection (a)(4) that documents agency use of the Do Not Pay system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD08927E74F754B4E89C0FFEEF913D87F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuity and transition</header><paragraph id="H6DCB3F98A1BE4FC8AC95D803CE2B0655"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Continuation of previous system if necessary</header><text>The Do Not Pay initiative in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this section shall continue as necessary to support implementation of the Do Not Pay system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13673ACC3AC847638B8BCE567B493637"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance, rules, and procedures</header><text>Guidance, rules, and procedures in effect before the date of the enactment of this section shall remain in effect until modified by the Secretary or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC71D72866F774970AE068A0B206A68FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed—</text><subparagraph id="H8BBE8F39A2744CAA9FC4E92FFA832F5F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as specifically provided in subsection (a)(4), to modify or supersede the requirements of section 552a of title 5, including the requirements for notice in section 552a(e)(12) and for due process rights of an individual under section 552a(p); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22308741B77641DA860D74AB592AF3B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to limit any authority of an Inspector General under applicable law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5D990DE9E5841289C134F780F044F57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The item relating to section 3354 in the table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended, by striking <quote>Initiative</quote> and inserting <quote>Program</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H10E26422DD404D5E9E83DE1AC3F6E4C9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Single report on first time use of funds by recipient</header><subsection id="HC4CF4E8E36C34DCCA66378EB4DF83CD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of post-Award single report requirement on first-Time use of funds by recipient of Federal award</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/61">Chapter 61</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HCA54FE0B63BF44CAA8206A6A3C2C0EED" style="OLC"><section id="H41B54CCD7D0A4CFCAFFB26382376C41E"><enum>6107.</enum><header>Single report on first time use of funds by recipient</header><subsection id="HADB46F0CF70745D9AF8A15DB8E89D48D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal award reporting requirement</header><text>The head of each agency that administers a covered award shall require each covered recipient to, as a condition of receiving amounts under such award, submit to the head of the agency, not later than 180 days after the receipt of such award unless a deadline exception may be applied pursuant to pursuant to regulations promulgated under subsection (b), a one-time report on the use of such amounts that—</text><paragraph id="H8168E63D15A34DA083F107E81690490E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes any content required to be included in such report pursuant to subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19A56D6366BC47EF962BDBAC5A96696D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is in the format required under such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H139BBF35199546B286710DD4E3F9DAC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Governmentwide report regulations and guidance</header><paragraph id="HDDFAB82E069C46CBBEBD4C0B68D959DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contents and format of report</header><subparagraph id="H7A304DA93251434E987F99FC39276F84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Promulgation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury and the standard-setting agency designated under section 6402(a)(1), shall promulgate regulations, and any clarifying guidance as may be necessary, to establish governmentwide requirements for the content and format of the report described under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D92110B6C7942BE8F7F2CBCC7970825"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Any guidance or regulation promulgated under subparagraph (A) shall be updated as necessary, but in any case, shall be updated not less often than once every 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB10B84C8D9FE4530B7A26A7D20546C2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report minimum requirements</header><text>The regulations and any clarifying guidance promulgated under paragraph (1), shall at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="HF2EEDE59F7CB463CAED93D11D1504DD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enable the head of an awarding agency to determine whether amounts provided under a covered award are being used by the recipient required to submit the report, and any sub-recipient or sub-grantee thereof, for the intended purpose of the program, as set forth in statute, regulation, or policies and procedures of the agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7119CE302B9147A89B4A28039A62469E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enable fraud prevention, detection, investigation, and mitigation, in future awards of Federal funds to the recipient required to submit the report by identifying relevant fraud-risk indicators that would require a referral for investigation and criminal referral to the appropriate entity of the Federal Government, including any identified effort by a recipient to defraud the Federal Government or violate sections 3729 through 3731 of title 31, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>False Claims Act</quote>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H525EF77C258145C4B19BB6AFA1089066"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that any sub-recipient or sub-grantee, at any level, of the recipient required to submit the report provide to such recipient such information as may be necessary to enable aggregate reporting on the covered award by the recipient;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD183D4784B34BC287A3C2B6B274CE45"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require the heads of agencies to apply the governmentwide data standards established under chapter 64 with respect to the format and content of the report required to be submitted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9576AE4486FF49B3B2E0B75EF8AA6011"><enum>(E)</enum><text>align with the Federal award reporting requirements and data standards under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/282">Public Law 109–282</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6101">31 U.S.C. 6101</external-xref> note), to the maximum extent practicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD70B8975DABF4981ADB25EE5316E2348"><enum>(F)</enum><text>reduce recipient and agency reporting burdens by avoiding duplication in recipient reporting obligations, to the extent practicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF195B67565440C4BEBA1E04D4AA5580"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provide clarification for agencies to apply a reporting deadline exception under subsection (a)(1), which may be made for an entire program or type of covered award, beyond 180 days when the use of the covered funds by the covered recipient takes place more than 180 days after a receipt of such covered award.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E9E13F3EF8A4BD0BC488E1ECFE65D4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency requirements</header><text>In accordance with the regulations and any clarifying guidance promulgated under subsection (b), the head of an agency that administers a covered award shall—</text><paragraph id="HA8BAF21B5FFF4F89A4CE1BD0D8AB6210"><enum>(1)</enum><text>update the terms and conditions of Federal awards in the agency programs to implement subsection (a) for covered recipients;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D785190C2B5499EB43931D0426D380B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a summary of the post-award reporting requirements established under subsection (a), including the required content and reporting format, in the Notice of Funding Opportunity (which has the meaning given the term in section 200.1 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations) for Federal financial assistance (as defined under section 7501 of this title) in order to assist applicants for such assistance in understanding post-award reporting obligations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB239A8E6DD044D0DA78E6DD4923D685B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="H5D59F3F286FB4799A133CEB95CD30E35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide user-friendly and plain language directives for covered recipients to fulfill their reporting obligation under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H867A6FA777214994A9AF2492F505C801"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use existing post-award reporting requirements to reduce the burden of cumulative post-award reporting; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD257ADDC70454AF5A8418EEAFB19AD77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish procedures within the agency to identify covered recipients that are not in compliance with the reporting requirement under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9821501D47FA47A69038EFF12E5DCA11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>For a case in which a covered recipient does not submit the report required by subsection (a), the awarding agency shall—</text><paragraph id="HC4AAF1600D9B4386926C70D98E59C09F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide a timely written notice of noncompliance to the recipient that—</text><subparagraph id="HFDDADAFD893F4251944A9034AE21AB8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>clearly states the reason for noncompliance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81ACBAE5C73C4BE38C428A84F5035F42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notifies the recipient of the obligation of the agency to cease further disbursements to the entity until the covered recipient is in compliance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9814F66829C4798929509A9C47507AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides clear instructions to the covered recipient on how to come back into compliance; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73C68ACED2094F3DA737D1EBB3DFB3E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent a payment voucher from being issued under section 3325 for a payment to such recipient, for any program funds, until such report is submitted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BAA9AF95BFA49C18141C8553AEE73A6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability of report</header><text>Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall be—</text><paragraph id="H1F169588A92A424AB139FD6D4F47AE47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>kept on file by the agency for a period of not less than 5 years after the date on the conclusion of the duration of the award; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A67C9F2C12247ECAAC6AEDD7D531284"><enum>(2)</enum><text>made available upon request to—</text><subparagraph id="HF171193101FC4F2FB083D029FD730399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4622DD42AD7848E5A3334C963572FFED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCAB929EB8944187A042D0C0C9D65D7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Attorney General;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE400FE206DC34F089B80032C28A660E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Inspector General of the agency concerned; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H129EA806463546B0A7256DC819A4A40E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0726159F60E40B6B855019D5E1FB761"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of information included in report</header><text>Information included in the report required by subsection (a) shall be used by the agency in support of improper payment activities of the agency under section 3352 as appropriate and applicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2537AB09BB94900AB4F3D3DC3C66994"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H783937B2D845462C821254F22F971577"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB0E5E800F08345D1921669FD72E2257C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC1697799EC747579FC667AE55F6F4A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C01505520874FFA8A01DD9F33248F7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF770A45A15C04675B6002C81656659B7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other relevant congressional committee of jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91394BA020AC4E709378771FA1E08AF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered award</header><text>The term <term>covered award</term> means a Federal award (as defined under section 7501) in an amount not less than $50,000 (based on fiscal year 2027 constant dollars).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C8DB984C6A7449FA34502A02C2D08C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered recipient</header><text>The term <term>covered recipient</term> means any entity, including any State, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States, including a pass-through entity (as defined under section 7501), that receives the covered award from a particular agency program for the first time in that program’s existence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A7FD2FD839C42619C6EE8EAFE370443"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fraud-risk indicator</header><text>The term <term>fraud-risk indicator</term> means an objective data point or analytic signal that indicates an anomalous payment pattern or increase in the volume of a payment amount, a verified data mismatch, network or behavioral anomaly, or match identified by the Do Not Pay system and any other payment, account, and payee validation program or service provided by the Department of the Treasury that would result in financial loss to the government.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1EF79CF6EE814B459E7928066AE51CC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of application of first reporting deadline</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) of section 6107 of title 31, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply to a covered award made during the fiscal year following the promulgation of regulations or guidance by the Director under subsection (b)(1)(A) of such section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF633AFF934A64AF38433751C5CB0AA2D"><enum>5.</enum><header>U.S. treasury data access for purposes of program integrity</header><subsection id="H460705363F924502946C20CEC5E46AFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to the national directory of new hires</header><text>Section 453(j) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/653">42 U.S.C. 653(j)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFB97BDB37F414551B85A9571BE6C818B" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H0268ADC4CC9B40CBB58011D1B33BD776"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Information to assist in the prevention of improper payments</header><subparagraph id="HD28D5AE647B24EEC9DE4CD54F9F2FCE4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall have access to the information in the National Directory of New Hires for the sole purpose of detecting, preventing, and recovering improper payments (as defined under section 3351 of title 31, United States Code), including for use in the Do Not Pay system established under section 3354 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE7AD6174848423C89DC310BBCB959F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>For the sole purpose of detecting, preventing, and recovering improper payments, the Secretary of the Treasury may disclose information in the National Directory of New Hires to—</text><clause id="HF7008FBE260541FFA0297717AB74D023"><enum>(i)</enum><text>agents and contractors of the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></clause><clause id="HD93905E1454F463EB4977BC02A7D6885"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Federal and non-Federal individuals and entities authorized to receive information in the National Directory of New Hires directly from the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="H28D85ADD5F7E4024879A274003CA7232"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>entities with access to the Do Not Pay system; and</text></clause><clause id="HA6AC2754FA104645AC335E1B511C9B17"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such additional individuals and entities as agreed to by the Secretary and the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2B932C869A8348DDB4F6008B24F5CC3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Privacy-Preserving validation of select tax information</header><paragraph id="H01700096F36042BC951B61DAEF3BCEE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H7EBD967092A046739798A588FB29647F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HD711E18D035F480EA39F364A7E805FE2"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Disclosure of certain return information for use in the do not
 pay working system</header><subparagraph id="H12F629462A354D08A9A35B35B5015E64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon execution of a written intra agency agreement between the Internal Revenue Service and the office of the Department of the Treasury that operates the Do Not Pay system described in section 3354(c) of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary may disclose to any authorized person described in subparagraph (B) return information described in subparagraph (C) with respect to an individual taxpayer for the applicable period described in subparagraph (D) for the limited purpose described in subparagraph (E). The Secretary may further authorize the redisclosure of such return information by an authorized person described in subparagraph (B), subject to such terms, conditions, and safeguards as the Secretary determines appropriate, to other authorized persons described in subparagraph (B) solely for the limited purpose described in subparagraph (E). The Secretary shall disclose or permit the redisclosure of such return information only to the extent necessary and for the purpose of the Do Not Pay system assisting an authorized person to identify, prevent, and recover improper payments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BD438F4DB714C9AA8CB36184E5142F2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized person</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>authorized person</term> means—</text><clause id="HDDD517A6E0FA489A80C294260B531F32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an officer, employee, agent, or contractor of the Department of Treasury, whose official duties require access to the Do Not Pay system for the purpose of facilitating the identification, prevention, or recovery of improper payments, or</text></clause><clause id="H6CB77A98216248999C71BEBF08E03542"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an officer, employee, or contractor of an entity authorized to access the Do Not Pay system for the purposes described in subparagraph (E).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA40D6B63990741C18B743BF429B4B22E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Return information</header><text>The return information that may be disclosed under this paragraph is limited to—</text><clause id="HB74A132310D240CFA38AF33D072C287B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>taxpayer identity information,</text></clause><clause id="H19C71F6A54654654859ACF71FAA5D5BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>filing status,</text></clause><clause id="HF9955A0606964F6EA9467D5AEACCFCEC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>adjusted gross income,</text></clause><clause id="H519228532C5C4153A637EFE5E6ACCB65"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>net profit or loss, as reported on Schedule C of Form 1040 (or successor form),</text></clause><clause id="H464174B2280641E6ACA72F18F81987C9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>bank account and routing information,</text></clause><clause id="HEB165D7D62C24369B5FD57124AE8D2A6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>if applicable, the fact that there was no return filed,</text></clause><clause id="H7C1E4DA377014AA3A80F3B62C88877DC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the taxable year with respect to which the preceding information relates, and</text></clause><clause id="H19022186B9AA444EA523714F42ABCA2F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any reported identity theft related to the taxpayer identification number.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H255D4E3D38BD4F3B8CFE3EF146B6962D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Applicable period</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable period</term> means, with respect to any individual taxpayer, the period—</text><clause id="H71AA49469696429EB90FB52F0ED00ACA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consisting of the number of taxable years specified in the agreement entered under subparagraph (A), except that such period shall not be fewer than 3 taxable years, and</text></clause><clause id="HC504906BE8754B74B8713D8C62D59230"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ending with the most recent taxable year for which the information described in subparagraph (C) is available.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2B3DCDEEC954AB7AF5F9F087CF56DEC"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation on use of information</header><text>Information disclosed under this subparagraph shall be solely for the use of the authorized persons to whom such information is disclosed and solely for the purpose of detecting, preventing, and recovering improper payments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H43DB304226F94A5AA77B6ECECBF83130"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph id="H4B554DBA09B242E884CDD86932F26357"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(a)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>subsection (i)(9),</quote> after <quote>subsection (e)(1)(D)(iii),</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DD2D4329AAC4E328088D0EEF94927D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 6103(p)(4) of such Code is amended—</text><clause id="HFF3A07E1A29E40C0BFCC992909911284"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="H6B59AEB2AFC540F3B99039939A9D594D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (7),</quote> and inserting <quote>(7), or (9),</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA55127ECF2084C348E0774CACF64E297"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (7)(A)(ii),</quote> and inserting <quote>(7)(A)(ii), or (9),</quote>;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA007010D53E140909C9A71A4B33EC65B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)(i), by inserting <quote>or (9)</quote> after <quote>(i)(3)(B)(i)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H021BDAC5875E4A44A0502D0CED3DD8EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I) of subparagraph (F)(ii), by striking <quote>(5) or (7),</quote> and inserting <quote>(5), (7), or (9),</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F0F7B5DF93B4A4EA6889AC18DC4626C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 7213(a)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or (7)(A)(ii),</quote> and inserting <quote>(7)(A)(ii), or (9),</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07870625694D47D0A58BCE84600B335B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to any disclosure made after the effective date of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H576FD6C27466460FBF42A75F64C72C4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access to social security information</header><text>Title II of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HF2EA1487659745A8A1A46D037E4E12A1" style="OLC"><section id="H731EBA0D032A42AB9889198A30FA9BC3"><enum>235.</enum><header>Disclosure of information for do not pay system</header><subsection id="HD54A2C85CBBB4682B44373B23749D95B"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of the Treasury (or his designee) under which—</text><paragraph id="H5B88C122775E431196049B248F0E6257"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Commissioner establishes a reliable, secure method, which compares the name and social security account number provided in an inquiry against such information maintained by the Commissioner in order to confirm (or not confirm, including the reason for the nonconfirmation) the validity of the information provided;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52D6663814C4487F8B5CDF83452A650E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>appropriate safeguards are included to assure that the confirmation (or nonconfirmation) is used solely for the use of the authorized persons to whom such information is disclosed and solely for the purpose of using the Do No Pay system to identify, prevent, and recover improper payments, and any redisclosure shall be subject to the provisions of section 3354 of title 31, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B992B7D273941AD8540095059A56743"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary shall pay the Commissioner of Social Security the full costs (including systems and administrative costs) of providing the confirmation described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C03BC0ACD4F4A7F949E71C7C616D95C"><enum>(b)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph the term <term>authorized person</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H92EE88A9EF5547598A92C6918B9F6DB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an officer, employee, contractor, or agent of the Department of Treasury, whose official duties require access to the Do Not Pay system, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BC9A15952604B91A01A62A2380EA049"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an officer, employee, or contractor of another Federal agency, or a State agency that manages Federally funded State-administered programs, whose official duties require access to the Do Not Pay system.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HA636BF09743F465AA995E29CA8D74D32"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

