<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3A333C1C1344F4E99F73938DEE27F2D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8575 IH: Enhancing Mobilization of Public-Private Organizations for Women’s Economic Rights Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen the public-private partnerships and policy efforts of the Department of State to advance women’s economic security in South and Central Asia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1DC801BD81C645AE914A3ADE156AD699" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC7106BD69D9749D58135B6EE32682D49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Mobilization of Public-Private Organizations for Women’s Economic Rights Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EMPOWER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H093046FA9E0D41758317A6A06EF7DDE3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB363C046A89C4F8C8CCB7B34C9632109"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Women’s full and unfettered political, economic, and social participation is vital to realizing universal human rights, global prosperity, peace, and security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23D3B41D15FF412795CD96917C20A38B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Women’s labor force participation, asset ownership, and economic security are development multipliers, promoting family financial resilience, community health and development, children’s educational attainment, and poverty reduction, among other development gains across South and Central Asia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9F3667A1ADB4E088964700A6B8C45B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Women’s economic participation and opportunity, educational attainment, health and survival, and political empowerment are directly proportional to countries’ economic competitiveness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF926A1B049A24D5BB9ED530D8148FBEA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Women make up about 33 percent of South Asia’s labor force, among the lowest female labor force participation rates in the world, yet gender parity in employment could increase South Asia’s Gross Domestic Product by between 19 to 58 percent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7893F97550A04F47873B04DDA36610E8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While the percentage varies across the five Central Asian states, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan also have some of the lowest female labor force participation rates in the world, at 29.6 percent and 35.9 percent, respectively.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76F534ED88974D9A915C475AC76B8120"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Women’s Councils are consortia of public-private partnerships between the Department of State and United States and South Asian businesses, civil society, and universities, to matchmake technology, networks, expertise, and resources of our corporate and civil society members to create more impact together than any entity could alone.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A967798225E4018B9B692125AD07DF5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Women’s Councils implement President Trump’s Presidential Memorandum on Promoting Women’s Global Development and Prosperity and the bipartisan Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7C9D8CB29074B0EB2FED9ECCA560C33"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Women’s Councils accelerate women’s economic empowerment in South and Central Asian countries, growing economies and advancing stability and prosperity for all, at no cost to American taxpayers.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H976480B298474C91A53823C7A921712C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to promote women’s economic security and advancement, including in South and Central Asia, as an integral part of the broader conduct of United States foreign policy in the region.</text></section> <section id="H0952EEB0B9B64FB3A584B3AC02D4DDEA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Women’s councils and public-private partnerships advancing women’s economic security in South and Central Asia</header> <subsection id="H74F16E7B4ACC4AA2AF88592E49321F81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall maintain and seek to expand existing women’s councils and other public-private partnerships that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4BBCEA44CF1145959D68EB15669A892F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>forge ties between the United States and countries in South and Central Asia, by catalyzing commitments from the private sector, civil society, and academia; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD9724C2267D479B9AA56D6BB7779663"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advance women’s employment, entrepreneurship and access to education, such as the United States-Pakistan Women’s Council, the United States-India Alliance for Women’s Economic Empowerment, and the Alliance for Afghan Women’s Economic Resilience.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F49EAC1089B4A4B980B44A1499F43D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the activities authorized under subsection (a) should support—</text> <paragraph id="H1DF06E0C91B9489FA823292190BDF3F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>women’s financial inclusion and access;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED974A0DC0B0497FA13DE17442EBECFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>women’s access to mentorship;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA679D03B3DBE4822966D529AB8150E10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>women’s asset ownership;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA52CDE2B45BD4B1E90002A27BCF154BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>incubation and scaling of women-owned startups and small and medium enterprises;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB07A482807C4919AD1E26BE0511C3A8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>access to procurement opportunities by women entrepreneurs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7180B8598634207A6CEA0D26217CF52"><enum>(6)</enum><text>career-enhancing educational opportunities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D0B64F1610D40B3AC6FB84E7703F70C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>women in science, technology, engineering, the arts and mathematics;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FDDB07CA2F148B5A7D2DE9B87E89E13"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the care economy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2F22726F09D45EA8DABE611F74BAA0E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>addressing legal and social barriers to women’s economic empowerment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82C941B29AF74F5882AF4CD3997F571F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities authorized under this section may be conducted in the United States, in countries in South and Central Asia, or in third countries.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H508D1F9DC87443E6BF6A03DA7A3612C6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Establishment of Unit</header> <subsection id="H4A0DCFDA07CF47DFB5245C09FD2DDBF5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish within the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs a Unit responsible for overseeing the public-private partnerships described in section 4(a). Such Unit shall be led by a Special Advisor for Women’s Economic Security, who shall report to the Assistant Secretary of State for South and Central Asia.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6854C568B81D4234B149E78DFD6F1814"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special advisor</header><text>The Special Advisor for Women’s Economic Security shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEEDAF8387E1B403AABC5623E7D278AC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be appointed by the Secretary of State, including from among existing officials or employees of the Department of State to serve as the Special Advisor in addition to that official or employee’s existing role; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FA83FECFBCB4996AF681D0A70D1048F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have the rank and status of Ambassador.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC7F8E4B6594B4AECA6D5280D22544335"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designated point of contact</header><text>Each United States diplomatic and consular post the Special Advisor determines relevant shall designate a point of contact from among the personnel of such post, whose duties shall include identifying and tracking relevant private sector commitments with respect to the public-private partnerships overseen by the Unit established under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCBD35FF5F8A24D159D7CE8D6B8E18A01"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header> 
<subsection id="H7164ABA481C04F839610B8E2F15AFDD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H69A0B8B2F71542D29E9D3F127EA32C57"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the steps taken to implement this Act, including allocated personnel and funding;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9D3D62950C04292B1CAFA5BF6BC3C46">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the status of the commitments and partnerships described in section 4(a); and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95EA8D410EBD404FBA9155C19E570603"><enum>(3)</enum><text>economic data on the impact of work of the Unit authorized by section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBC1063603EE64983BFCE69F067409ECF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0218D310FF9E47B9A638E52469ED6B2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C6436D4582148A9B9ACF693CD86F2F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

