<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E18E11BF94E40658D155D43CC2A243F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1026 IH: Condemning the violent disruption of a religious worship service at Cities Church in St. Paul, Minnesota, reaffirming the constitutional right to religious freedom, and commending the Department of Justice for its prompt investigation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1026</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260130">January 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the violent disruption of a religious worship service at Cities Church in St. Paul, Minnesota, reaffirming the constitutional right to religious freedom, and commending the Department of Justice for its prompt investigation.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 18th, 2026, a group of protesters forcibly disrupted a religious worship service at Cities Church in St. Paul, Minnesota, interfering with congregants’ ability to peacefully assemble and freely exercise their faith;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reports and video evidence indicate that individuals entered the sanctuary during an active church service, shouted over clergy, physically obstructed the service, intimidated worshipers, and created a threatening environment for families and children in attendance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States guarantees the free exercise of religion, including the right to worship without intimidation, coercion, or violence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas places of religious worship occupy a uniquely protected position under Federal law due to their constitutional significance and their role in American civic life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Freedom of Access to Clinic Entrances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/248">18 U.S.C. 248</external-xref>) makes it unlawful to use or attempt to use force, threat of force, or physical obstruction to intentionally intimidate or interfere with any person lawfully exercising their religious beliefs at a place of religious worship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the FACE Act provides criminal penalties and civil remedies for violations involving interference with religious worship, recognizing such conduct as a serious civil rights offense;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to publicly available reports, media coverage, and video documentation, Don Lemon was present during the disruption of the worship service at Cities Church and actively joined individuals participating in the disturbance of the service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas participation by a nationally recognized media figure in the disruption of a religious worship service represents a profound abuse of public influence and lends legitimacy to unlawful conduct targeting people of faith;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public figures who physically join or amplify disruptive acts against houses of worship contribute to intimidation, escalate tensions, and undermine constitutional protections for religious exercise;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas while peaceful protest is protected under the First Amendment, entering a church during a worship service to disrupt, intimidate, or obstruct religious exercise is not protected speech and is inconsistent with Federal law and American values; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas failure to clearly condemn such conduct, especially when committed or endorsed by influential individuals, risks normalizing religious intimidation and emboldening future attacks on Americans exercising their faith: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE91284443F40489097EF5A383B4EE1B3"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB75AD3ABC9934915A0A332B93187EB7D"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HAD33B29351B844DFA39AC1B22EE1BE87"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strongly condemns the protest and riot that disrupted a religious worship service at Cities Church in St. Paul, Minnesota;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA2139A52120483E9F05923717E64A93"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that the free exercise of religion is a fundamental constitutional right that must be protected from intimidation, obstruction, and violence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96FB9F5C4FF6499F8E70C6BCABC78174"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">declares that targeting houses of worship for disruption or harassment constitutes an attack on religious liberty and the rule of law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47ED6F3B7CEA4849B8E76D5E123090B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that the actions taken during this incident may constitute violations of the Freedom of Access to Clinic Entrances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/248">18 U.S.C. 248</external-xref>) and other applicable Federal civil rights laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB390B29DF94440A686CA7495AA0040B2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns Don Lemon for joining and participating in the disruption of a religious worship service, thereby lending credibility and encouragement to conduct that interferes with the constitutional rights of worshipers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FBDB49DB4F04FBAA9C762D13BCFCB60"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the Department of Justice for its prompt investigation into the events surrounding this incident, including the conduct of all individuals involved, and to fully enforce the FACE Act and other relevant Federal statutes of the law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49464493025548C88BD49D5CFA38352D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges Federal, State, and local authorities to ensure that Americans may worship freely and safely without fear of intimidation, disruption, or violence.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

