<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE37549B622A24ED8A09DB0390A73F4FC" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1046 IH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3310) to designate Venezuela under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit nationals of Venezuela to be eligible for temporary protected status under such section, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3310) to designate Venezuela under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit nationals of Venezuela to be eligible for temporary protected status under such section, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDCC7E746E90744A68DC69CDACD32E3BC">
    <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"
      id="H09493ACDEC414456AA48EDE2A1489F1B">
      <enum/>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 3310) to designate Venezuela under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit nationals of Venezuela to be eligible for temporary protected status under such section, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, and on any amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the majority leader and minority leader or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H3EC9D0E4EF98443E8E07D93CC44FD2EB">
      <enum>2.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 3310.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H0F00847F459645ADB13785DFEBE7B6DC">
      <enum>3.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.R. 3310 no later than one week after passage.</text>
    </section>
  </resolution-body></resolution>

