<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN26126-87P-R6-661"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4130 IS: Cost Openness and Spending Transparency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4130</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To put a public price tag on all projects supported with taxpayer dollars.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idBF5F663D3EA5417FB6DFEC39C483F5CA"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cost Openness and Spending Transparency Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COST Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id018C5334FFD748DBB9FE56FCD584C888"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure requirements for Federal funds</header><subsection id="id89CEEA24CC9946669B8087A60FA839CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id655ECC754D3D45BCBA17018CFDF14D96"><section id="idAD0AC2B3BFD14A398573697884A23A5B"><enum>1356.</enum><header>Disclosure requirements for Federal funds</header><subsection id="id1E73E72C7B3D42AEAEEEAEEA0B7BEC05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>agency</term> means—</text><paragraph id="iddaa86485b2c9409c8ae7db5ad6ffe973"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an Executive agency, as defined in section 105 of title 5; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida02d3d4129284c39b47af8d86d8b8f95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an independent regulatory agency, as defined in section 3502 of title 44.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id769524f0b00442afb0a0cad94ebccb59"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disclosure requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency and an individual or entity (including a State or local government and a recipient of a Federal research grant) carrying out a program, project, or activity that is, in whole or in part, carried out using Federal funds shall clearly state in any statement, press release, request for proposals, bid solicitation, or other document describing the program, project, or activity, other than a communication containing not more than 280 characters—</text><paragraph id="id53eec6e5b31e47e29361eb5ab5087ccb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the percentage of the total costs of the program, project, or activity which will be financed with Federal funds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00c14cc8b71049d7adf07ecb989cd4b4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the dollar amount of the Federal funds made available for the program, project, or activity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb850d60056014c1694b71c6eeb9e1b5a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the percentage of the total costs of, and dollar amount for, the program, project, or activity that will be financed by nongovernmental sources.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaeb918a416de46eea500f3276ec32508"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>An individual or entity carrying out a program, project, or activity that is, in whole or in part, carried out using Federal funds shall, as part of the performance progress reporting regarding the program, project, or activity, include a certification indicating whether the individual or entity complied with the disclosure requirements under subsection (b) with respect to communications containing not more than 280 characters relating to the program, project, or activity.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcb4aec8d13b348719c0e675491277d2d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance review</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall annually—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ef3d63caa294c78937580249bdfc642"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review a random sampling of public communications issued by agencies and recipients of Federal funds for compliance with the disclosure requirements under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id602d1fe462674573971b2edbd8c4957f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make publicly available the findings of the review under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13f07f26487541488d3f8f0aaf9b98b1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public reporting</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall make available to the public a mechanism to anonymously report communications that do not comply with the disclosure requirements under subsection (b), which shall require that such a report include—</text><paragraph id="id986526308bcd4a63b41efd8cd30fa105"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the noncompliant communication or, if publicly available, the location of the noncompliant communication; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida15a580babc7474cba0aabe11b7b3026"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying information regarding the program, project, or activity that is, in whole or in part, carried out using Federal funds.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id43B711BAF7EF4162981C6D08BD8AE59C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id511e03a8-a0bf-4711-8ded-690480cb95b4"><toc><toc-entry idref="idAD0AC2B3BFD14A398573697884A23A5B" level="section">1356. Disclosure requirements for Federal funds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

