<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFE599CCEA9C248C4BF15129AF9B84545" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>106 HR 7673 IH: To amend the Organic Act of Guam to provide an exception to the “public purpose” requirement for certain land transfers in the case of a transfer restoring such land to the original landowner or heirs, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7673</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Organic Act of Guam to provide an exception to the <quote>public purpose</quote> requirement for certain land transfers in the case of a transfer restoring such land to the original landowner or heirs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H668407FBD45F4A689ADBB729A6871782" style="OLC"><section id="H08D98C39EFC24F3394330D4C69BD92F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Restoring private land ownership</header><subsection id="H90393A1C82C04B9DB7358B2B9C938851"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of land ownership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1 of the Act of November 13, 2000, entitled <quote>An Act to amend the Organic Act of Guam, and for other purposes</quote> (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/504">Public Law 106–504</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/521">40 U.S.C. 521</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H78C249EBE8E64D51B122FA98642D9919" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H623D517C00284B58A5F102E5D221F89C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transfer for restoration of ownership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <quote>public purpose</quote> requirement under subsection (b) shall not apply with respect to any transfer of excess real property that the Government of Guam shall subsequently transfer to the original landowner or to the heirs of such person.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDB4056AFBB5848E7BA574B096C9BB740"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Government of Guam shall—</text><paragraph id="H3991B6C42AB1429DB8585461CFB738EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a process to transfer excess real property described in subsection (g) of section 1 of the Act of November 13, 2000, as added by subsection (a) of this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F2F43C0901F4AEFB32A01BD4C5F0695"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing such process.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A042D089FD140CE863428FFC75B8193"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National security review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any excess real property received by an individual under subsection (g) of section 1 of the Act of November 13, 2000, as added by subsection (a) of this section—</text><paragraph id="HF25941EACC7F4130A49AE1F0661F00BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any sale of such property by that individual to a foreign person, other than such a person that is an heir of such original landowner, is a covered transaction for purposes of section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C30FC8D42824687B4749F80040E34E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States shall initiate a review of such transaction under section 721(b)(1)(A) of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

