<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA26124-0XT-52-69R" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 602 ATS: Supporting the United States Olympic and Paralympic Teams in the 2026 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 602</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee discharged; considered and agreed to with an amended preamble</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the United States Olympic and Paralympic Teams in the 2026 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games.</official-title></form><preamble commented="no"><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, for more than 100 years, the Olympic and Paralympic Movements have—</text><paragraph id="id42eb6dcad6d7477f8daf0f6d92c889ae" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educated young people through amateur athletics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22f66d9a6c74491faef7d9376b095131" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">brought together athletes from many countries in friendly competition; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88b0ac46cb5d4988ad8d7721d3600ca1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">forged new relationships among athletes bound by friendship, solidarity, and fair play;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Milano Cortina 2026 Olympic Games will take place in Italy from February 6, 2026, to February 22, 2026, and the Milano Cortina 2026 Paralympic Games will take place in Italy from March 6, 2026, to March 15, 2026;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Olympic and Paralympic Teams (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Team USA</quote>) have won, between 2000 and 2026, 622 gold medals, 622 silver medals, and 559 bronze medals, totaling 1,803 medals, during the past Summer and Winter Olympic and Paralympic Games;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, at the 2026 Olympic Games, over 2,900 athletes from 93 countries will compete in 16 sports disciplines and 116 medal events, and at the 2026 Paralympic Games, 665 athletes from more than 50 countries will compete in 16 sports disciplines and 79 events;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, at the 2026 Olympic Games, Team USA will compete in 16 sports disciplines and 111 contested events;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States plans to send 232 athletes to participate in the 2026 Olympic Games, including 115 women and 117 men;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States has already qualified at least 36 athletes to participate in the 2026 Paralympic Games, with many more expected to qualify;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the people of the United States stand united in respect, admiration, and pride for the athletes of Team USA and their athletic accomplishments, sportsmanship, grace under pressure, goodwill toward other competitors, and commitment to excellence;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the many accomplishments of Team USA would not have been possible without the hard work and dedication of the many sports organizations, administrators, coaches, and family members who have provided critical support to the athletes;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States maintains a commitment to the safety and security of Team USA;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Government is grateful to Italy for hosting the 2026 Olympic and Paralympic Games;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, upon the conclusion of the 2026 Milano Cortina Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games, the United States will assume the role of host-country of the next Summer Games and stands ready to support the athletes and organizers of the 2028 Los Angeles Olympic and Paralympic Summer Games and those of the 2034 Utah Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Team USA exemplifies rigorous competition, fair play, and the pursuit of dreams: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1" commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ida8eb97e3f4034d3298fa61d96224e222" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applauds the athletes and coaches of the United States Olympic and Paralympic Teams (referred to in this resolution as <quote>Team USA</quote>) and the families who support them;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5ba8501061b46e2b6028e3a6d0493e3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the Government of Italy and the regional and local governments of Italy, including the governments of Milan and Cortina d’Ampezzo, for their efforts to commit tremendous resources to provide a safe and secure environment for the 2026 Olympic and Paralympic Games;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e4e8b25c2174a37a125954e99b464c2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the athletes of Team USA in competing at the 2026 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc617fa9cd674a88b86cb13f1f48d054" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commits to ensuring a safe and secure environment for the fans attending and athletes competing in the 2028 Los Angeles Olympic and Paralympic Summer Games, at events in both Los Angeles and Oklahoma City, and in the 2034 Utah Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

