<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26474-CHJ-3P-8YN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4178 IS: National Transit Frontline Workforce Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4178</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a transit workforce center, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HBA69E098DC994FFBB3C8DB3C256C0C5A"><section section-type="section-one" id="HDB3279070F974136A02D09AA8462BC71"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56605b94507c48408929afd7e8c508c3"><enum/><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Transit Frontline Workforce Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id786dae5aa06945c58d44a620f89164aa" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transit Workforce Center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5314 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFED147915E794AC486C6DA45778A5DA1"><subsection id="H165B872F1D044B99B12D4C43F63D2710"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transit Workforce Center</header><paragraph id="HFC966062F6E5489DB810C9E137D3F49F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph id="H9EBF6FE8B6284B9D892B6043FB2917C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a transit workforce center (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Center</quote>) and award grants to a qualified nonprofit organization to carry out the mission and duties of the Center pursuant to this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H035A01B54C4F4B26ADB54A5758B8A0FC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified nonprofit organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), a qualified nonprofit organization is an entity that—</text><clause commented="no" id="H4AE07036B6FA4231A2556862E3D6DA77"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a nonprofit organization;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H7B8B22DC624C473FB55986634ADDC386"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>operates nationally;</text></clause><clause id="H82AA57DEC4F744899165D36F4BC1E5D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has demonstrative experience in, and abilities regarding—</text><subclause id="HCC49731D8BCC426D994E9500DD2833B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provision of technical assistance to address issues in public transportation workforce development; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC563B55D754D4682AFD8AA654D6F3F55"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outreach and marketing activities that focus on current and emerging public transportation workforce development needs;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAA0151A838D44F2181FA7DB366018E07"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undertakes activities to support standards-based training for the public transportation maintenance and operations workforce through collaborative approaches, including labor-management partnerships;</text></clause><clause id="HCCE36C2431C94928A8D6E141BA055667"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undertakes activities to support public transportation workforce development with respect to emerging technology areas; and</text></clause><clause id="H2642AE9D2FF7477282230FE0D50BB2FE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the project management, organizational, fiscal, and administrative capacity necessary to effectively staff any proposed initiatives and deliver proposed outcomes, including implementation of any key components of such initiatives and outcomes, such as technical assistance, outreach, and marketing.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA3F5477FC8846B29F0E0A8BF64296C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mission of the Center is to assist the public transportation industry by supporting the recruitment, hiring, training, and retention of skilled frontline public transportation workers, which in turn may enable public transportation providers to operate transit more efficiently, safely, and reliably, to better serve communities, and to increase transit customer satisfaction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8427974E868A4A879C6C8514591D0B2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Center include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA6B7E2F13774449F8BDC3167D22FFADA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing, and providing directly through the Center, training programs to support the workforce development needs of public transportation providers, including training addressing the workforce development needs specific to public transportation providers delineated by service to each of urbanized areas, suburban areas, rural areas, and Tribal populations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16AE4DC112644FA199AC1E76B60654A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing and disseminating educational materials and other resources related to public transportation workforce development, including materials and resources designed to support training programs of the Center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0245CA2C7D8444CAE076241D141C5C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing, leading, and contributing to presentations, dialogues, learning sessions, and strategic planning sessions—</text><clause id="H80145095E64D4B679C26E8EB9BDD6252"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in partnership, collaboration, or consultation with entities in the public transportation industry, including entities that provide public transportation workforce development, career support for public transportation workers, or transit-related technical education; and</text></clause><clause id="H434C5ABFF254469187B20CC970BA6E4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regarding any topic that supports the needs and priorities of the Federal Transportation Administration or the public transportation industry, especially topics related to the recruitment, retention, job readiness, and preparation of a skilled frontline public transportation workforce capable of working with new and emerging technologies.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H504B82D12A414295ACD6F27857CBD56E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance regarding workforce development to public transportation providers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB00097F92C7B4DD29BD784798F8B9680"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting data analytics and providing analyses regarding public transportation workforce trends to public transportation providers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE76F3893F15847E389C3E57529E4683C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Leveraging transit-related workforce data to support efforts of public transportation providers to ensure the recruitment, retention, and advancement of a skilled workforce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE74BEC4D42F4E45B08FB3FC426BDB90"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting outreach, marketing, and other similar activities to increase engagement by, and awareness within, the public transportation industry with respect to the research, resources, trainings, projects, services, and initiatives of the Center that support frontline public transportation workers, including workforce-related research and information regarding changes to applicable policies of the Federal Transportation Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8B1BAAECC784E8FAC3541495C56DB8D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties of the Center, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H02B33121C5C74D5084CE797E1E295903"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit the qualified nonprofit organization selected under paragraph (1) to collaborate or consult with the Administrator of the Federal Transit Administration, the heads of public transportation providers, relevant national professional membership associations, and representatives of frontline public transportation employees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11E34B3423C84408819FBDC9E9412626"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require the qualified nonprofit organization to consider requests and feedback from public transportation providers when developing and providing training programs of the Center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

