<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25J98-K61-PT-S9L"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3454 IS: Growing University Artificial Intelligence Research for Defense Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Defense to establish one or more National Security and Defense Artificial Intelligence Institutes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id50f54368a51a4ad9ba31aa98cb519283" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Growing University Artificial Intelligence Research for Defense Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GUARD Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="S1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Security and Defense Artificial Intelligence Institute</header><subsection id="HDB5F4D3B535B480B86BB9F53012D6EA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may establish one or more National Security and Defense Artificial Intelligence Institutes (referred to in this section as <quote>Institutes</quote>) at eligible host institutions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H222DE829A2CD4D718AD2A83ABBD4A0DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Institute described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A National Security and Defense Artificial Intelligence Institute referred to in subsection (a) is an artificial intelligence research institute that—</text><paragraph id="H82E60AC226044AB983BDA269D2C5CEB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is focused on a cross-cutting challenge or foundational science for artificial intelligence systems in the national security and defense sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA87D0819B4524430997149BBF0916905"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishes partnerships among public and private organizations, including, as appropriate, Federal agencies, institutions of higher education, including community colleges, nonprofit research organizations, Federal laboratories, State, local, and Tribal governments, and industry, including the Defense Industrial Base and startup companies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE83ED324D2A45EF9133C12F33617625"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has the potential to create an innovation ecosystem, or enhance existing ecosystems, to translate Institute research into applications and products used to enhance national security and defense capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AB25D3AF5DA47918B252D5F91ECAF56"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports interdisciplinary research and development across multiple institutions of higher education and organizations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H276BEAB5B0B54E239D08FF8213EEE70E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports workforce development in artificial intelligence related disciplines in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AA1DAA0D0FD47AAA08EFF7EFB6DE27B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financial assistance authorized</header><paragraph id="HD9817059085F46A29EE923F2A3D1F3A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may award financial assistance to an eligible host institution, or consortia thereof, to establish and support one or more Institutes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7FA58B06977420CBC466848479AFA58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Financial assistance awarded under paragraph (1) may be used by an Institute for—</text><subparagraph id="H305BC939937D474A8E9563EB86E315D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>managing and making available to researchers accessible, curated, standardized, secure, and privacy protected data sets from the public and private sectors for the purposes of training and testing artificial intelligence systems and for research using artificial intelligence systems with regard to national security and defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AE74B8344254E648DD4188CF6F24676"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing and managing testbeds for artificial intelligence systems, including sector-specific test beds, designed to enable users to evaluate artificial intelligence systems prior to deployment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF493615F1DF04E279734DC55D173F6CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducting research and education activities involving artificial intelligence systems to solve challenges with national security implications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF50C79D4B6C84F5583D550D9266BBC91"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing or brokering access to computing resources, networking, and data facilities for artificial intelligence research and development relevant to the Institute’s research goals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H259EAEE46CC74CE4B83E1F0BB5698B83"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to users, including software engineering support, for artificial intelligence research and development relevant to the Institute’s research goals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H668578727C9A4473B33488CE613CA5C8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>engaging in outreach and engagement to broaden participation in artificial intelligence research and the artificial intelligence workforce; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE52872B374441838D6B0676F63BE745"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other activities as may determined by the Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EBF40D27A9349DDA6D2B62E46DF2914"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Financial assistance under paragraph (1) shall be awarded for a five-year period, and may be renewed for not more than one additional five-year period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6040ABE73A79450585DC65C8E3DB1F6E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application for financial assistance</header><text>An eligible host institution or consortia thereof seeking financial assistance under paragraph (1) shall submit to the Secretary of Defense an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F32CA7E13D946AD83859C44FE39049B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Competitive, merit review</header><text>In awarding financial assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall use a competitive, merit-based review process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E8885EB2532482CA7C7C09CDA26EA93"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In awarding financial assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may collaborate with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government with missions that relate to or have the potential to be affected by the national security implications of artificial intelligence systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF5A5EBC14D74BF385752CB3E0DC05A1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No financial assistance authorized in this section shall be awarded to an entity outside of the United States. All recipients of financial assistance under this section, including subgrantees, shall be based in the United States and shall meet such other eligibility criteria as may be established by the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE78E6F7F038F46CFACDDEADC902A7AE8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible host institution</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HEBC0A29BC9354175A17430744D8F27B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) in the United States that conducts research sponsored by the Department of Defense; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19367FCC17F04E4C992B6817CAECBB1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a senior military college (as defined in section 2111a(f) of title 10, United States Code).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

