<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEC1AC43E75764885B2FA7FAEEDB86A2D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5998 IH: To provide for the continued operation of the Hatch Act Unit of the Office of Special Counsel during a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5998</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the continued operation of the Hatch Act Unit of the Office of Special Counsel during a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEFACE5FC53E3406A881BF414F769A17D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCBFA4525BA1F4D7A92AF7BAB0D970C26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Office of Special Counsel Hatch Act Unit operations during shutdown</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During a lapse in appropriations, any services by an officer or employee of the Office of Special Counsel related to carrying out the duties of the Office of Special Counsel with respect to alleged violations of sections 7323 and 7324 of title 5, United States Code, shall be deemed, for purposes of section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, services for emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

