<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA26647-0D2-VM-X50"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S4683 IS: Warfighter Artificial Intelligence Readiness and Preparedness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4683</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to assess the effects of artificial intelligence integration on warfighter effectiveness, skill retention, and operational readiness, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="idcca32d67d0bb460da630aa6a33c581d3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Warfighter Artificial Intelligence Readiness and Preparedness Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WARP Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id50ab7b6691294c268c7d26ae2efc77a1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessment of artificial intelligence effects on warfighter skill retention and operational readiness</header><subsection id="id3ccca7eb32ad4e5292d95c8e87158637"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment required</header><text>Commencing not later than August 1, 2027, the Secretary of Defense shall conduct a comprehensive assessment of the effects on human performance of the adoption of artificial intelligence systems by personnel of the Department of Defense on the maintenance and retention of essential warfighter skills.</text></subsection><subsection id="idff4af8bbff2e4280812c19c36dd5698c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination and lead official</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior official—</text><paragraph id="id5414e1a464324bef8af181a783bce65b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to coordinate the assessment and research activities required by this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e83bfbea6ab4578b2c97220a5d96dba"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to oversee the integration of findings under this section into the policies of the Department, with the objective of maximizing both artificial intelligence-enabled performance and proficiency in critical, hard-to-recover skills; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf47d263c843b48a796473ffaa95642ee"><enum>(3)</enum><text>who is authorized to coordinate among the military departments and relevant defense agencies for purposes of carrying out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id70fc1459d0e541328a4b288ac669a6c3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of assessment</header><text>The assessment required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id1f3bc861c6114a1986b6da59e7b7e00d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identification of military occupational specialties and operational roles where structured proficiency management will be most critical to sustaining readiness alongside artificial intelligence adoption based on the susceptibility to skill atrophy resulting from reliance on artificial intelligence-enabled systems as well as speed and investments to recover such skill.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a113a44b57f4b869bcf9e1cbce54ada"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Evaluation of the conditions under which artificial intelligence-enabled systems augment warfighter capability and the conditions that call for deliberate proficiency sustainment measures to preserve independent judgment and awareness based on the cognitive, operational, and manual skills decline among personnel who regularly use artificial intelligence-enabled systems compared to personnel performing equivalent tasks without such systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf82d1b6366a04ac78a79bf7677441dc1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of measurable indicators that distinguish beneficial skill augmentation from conditions requiring proficiency intervention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c2bdd2cf4234fd28ac7169a6fa19abe"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Assessment of how current training and certification programs can be structured to build and sustain critical, hard-to-recover proficiency based on a review of the conditions under which reliance on artificial intelligence systems may contribute to overreliance, miscalibrated confidence in system outputs, diminished trust in independent human judgment, or reduced situation awareness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf85aea8673a5441b927070c003b1e939"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Evaluation of whether current training programs and certification standards adequately preserve critical warfighter proficiency for degraded-mode, denied, or contested operational environments, including the adequacy of primary, alternate, contingency, and emergency planning frameworks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3f3f3293eb4443a92168a039ef031bb"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recommendations for policies, training protocols, doctrine, acquisition requirements, talent management strategies, or readiness metrics to ensure that artificial intelligence adoption strengthens operational readiness.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2955a58751d942a595f8c98373454e10"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research activities</header><paragraph id="id2e6bc7da9a2d4d9290010713e4b52c38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The official designated under subsection (b) shall carry out research activities to support the assessment required under subsection (a), which may include controlled experiments or high-fidelity simulations comparing performance with and without artificial intelligence-enabled systems, longitudinal studies measuring skill retention trajectories, full-spectrum performance, and recovery timelines, assessment of operator confidence and decisionmaking accuracy under simulated contested conditions, and development of standardized skill sustainment metrics applicable across the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e5095b55c7749efa663224dc40391eb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out the research activities under paragraph (1), the official designated under subsection (b) shall coordinate with the following entities, as appropriate:</text><subparagraph id="id12bf4286f3a54974a893298bb85b62ea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Army Research Institute for Behavioral and Social Sciences.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a7f009713e94054b5abdad872fd33cc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Office of Naval Research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id883ce57793444a919bfe5b768c3c068e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Air Force Research Laboratory Human Effectiveness Directorate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49542cb4cc164537ac3b9ce4ce35066a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Chief Digital and Artificial Intelligence Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ea0d7bd58c64ccabe04de8918dc2c06"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The military departments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96c40f3082cb4500bac1c0267bb97e01"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Assistant Secretary of Defense for Readiness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide10c08ca66e94e09a45339881e572c61"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Such other research entities and operational commands as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1dba1fac379a4eddae6f36754fdea5c6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Research methodology</header><text>Research conducted under this subsection shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d44ecfa9e484187a19c02d970771d36"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish baseline measurements of task performance and cognitive capabilities prior to artificial intelligence system use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id059dcde6b1f94f66ba0342444df9d009"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess performance changes during routine artificial intelligence-assisted operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a405de85b8443878da4dbf011940ab8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate skill sustainment when artificial intelligence systems are removed or unavailable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b9a1c654e7e4d4b8e5ae15ffc54e80e"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measure recovery timelines to baseline proficiency after extended artificial intelligence-assisted operations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc34ee10054f84bd38e1ff560d0a40720"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify factors that accelerate or support skill sustainment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida84f5b08cbcb4ad38cd033863398a7c5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="idbdb55921183f4848a8f7667df1189084"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><subparagraph id="id42de1c8e7f41460a9ae3723f76b7d299"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the assessment required under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id174e7f88f12945bd936a7fe3ae6307c2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text><clause id="idfa95f0da01a3442e96def4e3e33aaa32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An identification of military occupational specialties and operational roles where proficiency sustainment will be most critical based on which are most vulnerable to hard-to-recover skill atrophy.</text></clause><clause id="id220bc4b6bd3346499a91b89ff352cf3c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Preliminary findings from controlled operational experiments and the design of longitudinal studies under subsection (d)(1).</text></clause><clause id="id346cd8ff217f4aa0bf6f2c6e852946a5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An assessment of opportunities to strengthen readiness based on identification of high-level risks to proficiency based on current or planned artificial intelligence deployment practices.</text></clause><clause id="id69e32a9e7a8c424a9a6afcbf6e2702e9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Recommended changes to policies, training, doctrine, or acquisition requirements to optimize human and artificial intelligence integration.</text></clause><clause id="id02774f9ce54d41f48009a3409268dd6c"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Recommendations for updates, identified as near- or long-term in nature, to existing training programs, certification standards, and operational doctrine to build and sustain critical and hard-to-recover proficiencies and identification of the Department of Defense component or office best positioned to implement each such recommendation.</text></clause><clause id="iddfbdaab50b8e433e86ce7826e8d1afd7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>An identification of any additional authorities, resources, research partnerships with academic institutions or federally funded research and development centers, or technical expertise needed to conduct the research activities described in subsection (d).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idad58377e637a4df6ad595d7262f87462"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Longitudinal study report</header><subparagraph id="id2cbd46e3d1674fafa82c113d3385c875"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report containing the findings of the longitudinal studies conducted under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa9935ca4d0249b79ba18635f730cf90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text><clause id="id7fd2c16d04da4e1d97b863985233c580"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An identification of measured rates of retention and atrophy of hard-to-recover skills across different military occupational specialties and operational contexts.</text></clause><clause id="id0ff93e74a3f44f9ca0f1b36e16051b26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An assessment of skill recovery trajectories and the time required to restore baseline proficiency.</text></clause><clause id="iddb6ddb3d5dd84107bc03a735fb355e10"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An evaluation of degraded-mode performance outcomes under simulated contested conditions.</text></clause><clause id="id6d5817bb87a74475b84bcf38344fbe37"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Updated recommendations for policies, training protocols, doctrine, acquisition requirements, or readiness metrics based on research findings.</text></clause><clause id="id09c9c33b17004876b613d204a8faee04"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any update to the recommendations made under paragraph (1)(B)(v).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id44683039e3f94783881ba3a2e5e4de59"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Briefings</header><paragraph id="id5b4578ce29864760a408cf6aa2dec4e1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the submittal of the initial report under subsection (e)(1), the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the findings and recommendations contained in such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca4eacf0ca0248e58149929cab9ec9d0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Longitudinal study briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the submittal of the longitudinal study report under subsection (e)(2), the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the findings and recommendations contained in such report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7497bcfb49984179999ebceaa781a8ba"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Review of training and doctrine</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall assess whether existing training programs, certification standards, and operational doctrine adequately account for the effects of artificial intelligence-enabled systems on skill retention and degraded-mode performance and shall include in the reports required under subsection (e)—</text><paragraph id="idb5abde12e114442da983c102063278e8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations for updates, as appropriate, identified as near-term or longer-term in nature; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2406bc27953455791366a0248723d05" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identification of the Department of Defense component or office best positioned to consider implementation of each such recommendation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide60a8ed200204132b6f342d57ded250a"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="iddd1f4845a00b4bf3ba6b4b5161f3df4a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence system</term> has the meaning given the term <term>artificial intelligence</term> in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4061">10 U.S.C. 4061</external-xref> note prec.).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2472b35e63fd46ffbcc51fdd781d7bc7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence-enabled system</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence-enabled system</term> means any weapons system, decision support tool, or operational capability that incorporates or relies on an artificial intelligence system.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21b2e5d873bb47f7adb423b28c4c4c10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida44f2ef772d04892a27760de4bac8b1c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Degraded-mode operations</header><text>The term <term>degraded-mode operations</term> means military operations conducted when artificial intelligence systems or supporting infrastructure are unavailable, partially functional, compromised, or under adversarial attack.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id910a9f235ffa4f3fac6dcea4b068b6db"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Primary, alternate, contingency, and emergency planning</header><text>The term <term>primary, alternate, contingency, and emergency planning</term> means a framework for ensuring continuity of operations when primary systems become unavailable, requiring personnel to employ alternate approaches, contingency plans, or emergency procedures.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

