<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAE0B3E98818442A0A35AB07D23ACA6A7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1276 IH: Recognizing the 100th anniversary of the Bend Chamber of Commerce.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1276</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 100th anniversary of the Bend Chamber of Commerce.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Bend Chamber of Commerce traces its origins to 1926, when local business leaders formed the Bend Commercial Club to promote economic opportunity and civic development in the growing community of Bend, Oregon, and unanimously voted on May 26, 1926, to rename the organization the Bend Chamber of Commerce;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, during the early decades of the 20th century, Bend emerged as a major timber center supported by large lumber operations such as the Shevlin-Hixon and Brooks-Scanlon mills, and the Bend Chamber of Commerce helped local businesses coordinate economic development and community growth during this period of rapid expansion;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, throughout the 1930s and beyond, the Bend Chamber of Commerce served as a forum for business collaboration and civic leadership, advocating for policies and infrastructure that strengthened Bend’s economy and supported its residents and workforce;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1937, the Bend Chamber of Commerce warned of the need for sustainable forestry practices as Central Oregon’s timber economy expanded, demonstrating early leadership in long-term economic planning for the region;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Bend Chamber of Commerce has grown alongside the city itself, expanding from a small business alliance into one of the largest chambers of commerce in Oregon, representing nearly 1,650 member businesses and serving as a leading voice for economic vitality in Central Oregon;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Bend Chamber of Commerce has played a critical role in helping the community navigate economic transitions, including the shift from a timber-based economy to a diverse regional economy that includes tourism, outdoor recreation, advanced manufacturing, health care, and technology;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Bend Chamber of Commerce has developed programs and initiatives that cultivate leadership, workforce development, and civic engagement in Central Oregon, including Leadership Bend, Bend Emerging Talent, Youth Career Connect, Bend 101, and NEXTUp Leaders;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Bend Chamber of Commerce advocates for business and community priorities at the local, State, and Federal levels, addressing issues such as workforce housing, childcare availability, economic competitiveness, and infrastructure needed to sustain a growing regional economy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Bend Chamber of Commerce is predominantly supported by its members and remains an independent voice for the business community, helping convene employers, civic leaders, and policymakers to address shared challenges and opportunities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Bend Chamber of Commerce has fostered collaboration among businesses, nonprofits, educational institutions, and government partners, strengthening Bend’s reputation as one of the most vibrant and innovative communities in the Pacific Northwest; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the year 2026 marks the 100th anniversary of the Bend Chamber of Commerce, commemorating a century of leadership, advocacy, and service to the Bend and Central Oregon community: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF1C2CF1F56D24E3297525113464308E1"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD2A451BDF070453BA52397AEBAE5AEBE"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HE8F26E86980C42298BD91F9D5AF038FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and celebrates the 100th anniversary of the Bend Chamber of Commerce and its century of contributions to the economic vitality and civic life of Bend, Oregon, and the Central Oregon region;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39CC2B79A9AB4B5689932971D48A6830"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the Bend Chamber of Commerce for its enduring commitment to supporting entrepreneurs, strengthening businesses, and fostering collaboration across the community;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B9083DFB48942DFB0E5FFE5AD2F4A48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the generations of leaders, members, staff, and volunteers whose vision and service have shaped the Bend Chamber of Commerce over the past 100 years; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H409112C896424BB4A9A46B3E66E3908F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages continued partnership among businesses, civic organizations, and public institutions to ensure a thriving and prosperous future for Bend and Central Oregon.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

