<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF0DEA6693E0C41E6BE3E5C29374CAE76" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6707 IH: Consistency in Foreign Investment in the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251215">December 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the United States Trade Representative to prioritize North American alignment on foreign investment review during the next joint review conducted under the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H80A9C001775E4592908D3BDFE0A8C3DB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H148C24C5CF7C44A19EDF8015BDB56377" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consistency in Foreign Investment in the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CFIUSMCA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H61C50E6C6C0F440EA69FF9231550701C"><enum>2.</enum><header>North American alignment on foreign investment review</header> 
<subsection id="H5BB94F76B9134BFA91FE992563E76B31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HAE5EFF3284E446E69266FF2785D9427F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Canada and Mexico are the two largest trading partners of the United States, with bilateral goods and services trade between the United States and each such country reaching approximately $1,000,000,000,000 in 2024;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA17BB25E18144343AD363B97F1B3331A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA) underpins much of the trade referred to in paragraph (1) and promotes a strong North American supply chain that supports millions of good-paying jobs in the United States;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28465A72C4AA4B69B1A7F5332FE8DD52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>given the close economic relationship between the United States, Mexico, and Canada under the USMCA, ensuring that each party has robust investment review mechanisms in place is important towards strengthening the collective national security interests of those countries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H454E3C1C5D114DA0816A5F344F3CE117"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States plays a critical role in protecting the national security of the United States by reviewing foreign investments for national security risks; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55D7F55A56E949C687F82E55625C0BDE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the establishment or modification by Mexico and Canada of legislative and regulatory frameworks to review foreign investments for national security risks that are similar to the framework established under section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565</external-xref>) would—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23E246B6005E43FEBE700DAE1C988503"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advance the national security interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD213F7F07588493889FEB381B0105BD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow for closer coordination between the USMCA countries with respect to shared threats from investments in strategically important economic sectors and critical infrastructure in North America.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HACB7481CEDA241729E1F14569241EC9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint review negotiation objective</header><text>Subject to the requirements of section 611 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4611">19 U.S.C. 4611</external-xref>), during the first joint review conducted after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Trade Representative shall advocate for—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H359F6EB8FECE4775ACFA72575B8033D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each USMCA country to implement a legislative and regulatory framework for reviewing foreign investment for national security risks that is similar to the framework established under section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4565">50 U.S.C. 4565</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E3E83C354B44E71AF25F951021B548F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the establishment of a mechanism for USMCA countries to coordinate to address shared threats from investments in strategically important economic sectors and critical infrastructure in North America that is overseen by the Trade Representative, Secretary of State, and Secretary of the Treasury and provides a forum for each USMCA country to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDAFB1D441D8941F9A104C4C20CC70407" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement this mechanism;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0EA0A9B14344DC3A4FDAE26A69DCFEC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhance communication and cooperation among the USMCA countries related to shared threats from foreign investment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4ACB2277EBAB4304B1813FD76655CBD0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitate the development of consistent foreign investment screening practices and standards among the USMCA countries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2421C474A474D1EADF21AC076B0D96D" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>exchange information on shared threats from investments in strategically important economic sectors and critical infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H147EF26FD43449549CF1639B97FB4391" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>notify the other USMCA countries of investments in strategically important economic sectors and critical infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85263BFF91134C04BD06830D66AFDD51" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identify, consult, manage, and resolve existing or proposed foreign investments in one USMCA country determined to pose a national security risk to another USMCA country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B4765E85AC146699F5AA9368F779E3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (b)(1), the Trade Representative shall coordinate with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State with respect to the provision of technical assistance to USMCA countries to support the establishment or modification of frameworks for reviewing foreign investments for national security risks. With respect to the provision of technical assistance to USMCA countries to support the establishment or modification of frameworks for reviewing foreign investment for national security risks, the Trade Representative shall also consult closely and on a timely basis with appropriate Congressional committees, including the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2918E075DD0B4081BE2B16D432497904"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA4039D16F1F84AD889858461C8372FEC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>critical infrastructure</term> means, in the context of a particular covered control transaction, systems and assets, whether physical or virtual, so vital to the United States that the incapacity or destruction of such systems or assets would have a debilitating impact on national security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CD9EF59C0D44F9183DA09ECA8D8AC66" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign investment</term> has the meaning given the terms <term>covered investment</term>, <term>covered investment critical infrastructure</term>, and <term>covered transaction</term> in sections 800.211 through 800.213 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8810FD56655423496D0E84F0960F3DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Joint review</header><text>The term <term>joint review</term> has the meaning given that term in section 611 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4611">19 U.S.C. 4611</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D74E5896D244637BB95DAACB94B5303"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Trade Representative</header><text>The term <term>Trade Representative</term> means the United States Trade Representative.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0CED2B7B12B4BF9939948D9E304B2C0" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National security risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national security risk</term> has the meaning given that term for purposes of any determination under section 721 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, including as provided in Executive Order 14083 (87 Fed. Reg. 57369; relating to ensuring robust consideration of evolving national security risks by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFBEEB67414441A394652005F478A10B" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Strategically important economic sectors</header><text>The term <term>strategically important economic sectors</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFBF328FF2154496EACE447A8867A6DA3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advanced computing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H756EC2EEEABF45A5B7FA97825DF2E2DA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advanced engineering materials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F9B07F07BE548729AB691D64887A548" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advanced gas turbine engine technologies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B66B7D55E334929BD39CE6478211CD7" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>advanced and networked sensing and signature management;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H638C2E1D4C68427BA5EFB84C97A569FB" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>advanced manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CD39AA517844213A57FAC214BAD14AD" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>artificial intelligence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE20BEBE2496C4B9198D3EE675FD1E714" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>biotechnologies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H079332EB53A6473E9C7D80DACCFA7F3B" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>critical technologies, as such term is defined in section 800.215 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53CEEC27E15341379ACA5C7823CADBB9" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>data privacy, data security, and cybersecurity technologies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFEBEF1939EB4C4F8255F6C9521974D2" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>directed energy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9523A1EEB4A8410A89DFB99BDB033D69" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text>highly automated, autonomous, and uncrewed systems, and robotics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB90BF90E7E049868D56AE2F342535AD" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><text>human-machine interfaces;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA94672C8D76455E8781B9A702CC0853" commented="no"><enum>(M)</enum><text>hypersonics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CC42ECF19F84076824DA4962A221B39" commented="no"><enum>(N)</enum><text>integrated communication and networking technologies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B690635EBA3496681FFBBF56AA1883A" commented="no"><enum>(O)</enum><text>positioning, navigation, and timing technologies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD5BC603619C465391700566077B1CA9" commented="no"><enum>(P)</enum><text>quantum information and enabling technologies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FFD31BF58AD4FF087589B1401FD4858" commented="no"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>semiconductors and microelectronics; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E08CAAF39B44F85868C0825F9FDA278" commented="no"><enum>(R)</enum><text>space technologies and systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6FDC46E390F4BE1AC793EC568505B25"><enum>(7)</enum><header>USMCA</header><text>The term <term>USMCA</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4502">19 U.S.C. 4502</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC31BA8B1CCB14136A1BB5F7D401129BC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>USMCA country</header><text>The term <term>USMCA country</term> has the meaning given that term in section 202(a) of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4531">19 U.S.C. 4531(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

