<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HC739286F795E4CB5B7681A7C0D71E32B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2137 RH: Review Every Veterans Claim Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 549</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2137</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–633]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 14, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to limit the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to deny the claim of a veteran for benefits under the laws administered by such Secretary on the sole basis that such veteran failed to appear for a medical examination associated with such claim.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HVR00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HC8C6714751C34414B780D446AC2A22F5"><section id="HF79BFC78A47A4A02A3E83C375A9D849F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Review Every Veterans Claim Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HE66A5DA0413E4BB5A5B58731D6566E40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on denial of claims for benefits under laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs on sole basis that veteran failed to appear for certain medical examination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 5103A of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H15AA3FEF1325476D81CE1A9444B420DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">compensation claims</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">claims for benefits</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B90E36F0AF84830AB510074F2F81147"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>treat an examination or opinion as being necessary to make a decision on a claim for purposes of </quote> and inserting <quote>provide for a medical examination or obtain a medical opinion under</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50D626E551AB4928947939268881E843"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H186FF22E87484DCFB162F85683E0CF0A" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><paragraph id="H48789C190D674D59BC97C70957C414CE" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a veteran fails to appear for a medical examination provided by the Secretary in conjunction with a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary, the Secretary may not deny such claim on the sole basis that such veteran failed to appear for such medical examination.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H0F26B897CFEA4E3D98DF9C214C118FC2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvements to efficiency of adjudications and appeals of claims for benefits under laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="HA81BE7D8813A47F2823DF559C0A37D10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report on length of adjudications</header><paragraph id="H95D6027A2ACA4886AEBBB932CCF53671"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5109B of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H946BBB506B334A75A792531CDB002B42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">In general.—</header-in-text>The Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8D04D7383964C4C9F85B5AF733F16FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H85EECA5BF2374705B665911177DC7D9E" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><subsection id="H110053645BDF4F338DEA66DF496669B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text><paragraph id="H3F5C3E9631BB4E94AD2DA6185C00C1EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the average length of time a claim (or an issue within a claim) that was remanded by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals was or has been pending before the Secretary after such remand;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2863F66AB11D438B977C58F20D08A5D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of cases that advanced on the docket by reason of a motion that was filed under section 7107(b) of this title and on which the Board ruled, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="H824850051E5B40A8B8D1A03B890E18F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether a motion was granted or denied; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E98DAE80AA1416CB837B0F661809A5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reason provided for the motion; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2056B8B8B47748928C2AA8F2A150C8B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of appeals dismissed by the Board, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="H80B38D345DBC4351887A6C284402ED52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether or not the dismissal was by reason of the death of the appellant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E41ACE057F34A59BF04FE99F2EAF57B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a dismissal by reason of the death of the appellant, whether or not such death was a result of suicide. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H565A914487464B96B9CDD0243DBE93F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit the first report required by subsection (b) of section 5109B of such title (as added by paragraph (1)) by not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FE18DC03B144D61A6DB4DA4D97FA770"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines for advancement of cases on docket of Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Board of Veterans’ Appeals and the General Counsel of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall prescribe guidelines for the advancement of a case on the docket of the Board on a motion for earlier consideration and determination under section 7107(b)(3) of title 38, United States Code. Such guidelines shall include the type of evidence that may be submitted with the motion for the advancement of the case to show grounds for such a motion.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1DCA400B604741078C87DBE27C476969"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement To track certain claims for benefits</header><paragraph id="H9DD7710CFE964C0380D708DCCB25DB85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/51">Chapter 51</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5109B">section 5109B</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H142702AF88304C83827C73323B1ECFE5" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><section id="H34B68D12B9AA4312BB7337C20B975C8F"><enum>5109C.</enum><header>Requirement to track and maintain information on certain claims for benefits; notice of certain assignments</header><subsection id="H3CFB6C75BD5F490E99903EAFBD4A7F2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use technology to track and maintain information (including information with respect to timeliness) on—</text><paragraph id="H401896F7B2BC4842A495EAD9AD053ADF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary (including issues within such claims) that are—</text><subparagraph id="HDD05B677023E4A3798CD4631A86B7E1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>continuously pursued in accordance with—</text><clause id="H695B67E7E4E54A8D98CADF18308309B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sections 5104C(a) and 5110(a)(2) of this title; or</text></clause><clause id="H097DE159CFFD4BB4ADF1C028F3EA6404"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other policy established by the Secretary;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FADEAF18AB74BC3B73D98998885A436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>filed in the National Work Queue (or any successor system) but have not been assigned to an office of the Veterans Benefits Administration for adjudication;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB60D2DC1A1074FE6B3FCB7F8EA914D30"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">afforded expeditious treatment by the Veterans Benefits Administration pursuant to section 5109B of this title or any other policy established by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H232CAB1754564449A10D972A3A92B64E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remanded by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals to the Secretary pursuant to section 7104 of this title; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB798E9CC7218453C84E3F82599435778"><enum>(E)</enum><text>pending a hearing by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals under section 7107 of this title;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08EBE03B516A4002B70C2CB3C0DAD6C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>instances in which an adjudicator of the Veterans Benefits Administration does not comply with a relevant decision of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals to remand a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary (or an issue within such a claim), including any such instance in which the relevant decision concerned a failure on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy the duty of the Secretary to assist under section 5103A of this title;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7F025A61267473BAC44EA9EFDEA1323"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supplemental claims under section 5108 of this title that are filed—</text><subparagraph id="HAC0B98BD7DF3458582C298EFD9311E08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with section 5104C(a) and section 5110(a)(2) of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DB91E51039043C19094353CB4363B76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the date of the applicable final decision of the Secretary with respect to a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary (or an issue within such a claim); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83D28F72BEDE4535AF2A1CF173348BC6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>first notices submitted to the Secretary of the death of individuals in receipt of benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary, disaggregated by such individuals who were—</text><subparagraph id="H14ED91A117BB4348B6E3B16AA216796F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assigned a fiduciary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E56191225D54C069AC7BE25B6D756E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not assigned a fiduciary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DCCA714907F456F9892B093A3E498CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA3D2127FD07C47BD985C60471DA59417"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report that includes all information maintained and tracked pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A32A8942B84A418FBA78AC65B837B4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted by not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Veterans Appeals Efficiency Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B78398EA2A54C349D4912FB10B18CAB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5109B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HFD5CDE786A0643E4A95A59EEC1E12644" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc-entry level="section">5109C. Requirement to track and maintain information on certain claims for benefits; notice of certain assignments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BDAC26A69CB437CA60D9037C30DE9A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Improvements to Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header><paragraph id="H58E73A02B2A54B3C80299B85B1A5525E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to aggregate certain claims</header><subparagraph id="H603C49C61DD74103919E75A829E18FCE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7104(a) of such title is amended by inserting after the second sentence the following new sentence: <quote>If the Chairman of the Board determines that more than one appeal involves common questions of law or fact, the Chairman may aggregate such appeals to decide such questions of law or fact.</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C97941E253A457F9C44E783B0367B05" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subparagraph (A) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs completes the development of the policies and procedures required under subsection (g)(4)(A)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEDEE03C355B4A1F9C7474AC1F071589"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement to ensure substantial compliance with certain decisions</header><text>Such section is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="H400AE819CD82493CB008DF85C769A2D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (g); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B94BF74F25D4A4BA7E76614A0FB39D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following new subsection (f):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HEF08C14473AA45519A38ED8E054BC9D5" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><subsection id="H0CABA0B1645D4BACBFAA6E59185E7DBD"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H09F0D652EFBE4FBCB7924FE91D9D2732"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary, acting through a member of the Board, shall ensure substantial compliance with any decision of the Board to remand a claim.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6FA9679C4E24CB897142D7C672C114F" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The agency of original adjudication may waive the requirement under paragraph (1) with respect to a decision of the Board to remand a claim to the Secretary, if a member of the Board determines—</text><subparagraph id="HD7FD97F9B874414D8C41A5C1694B3D42" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence added to the evidentiary record after the date of such decision is sufficient to resolve the issues underlying such decision; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF06D5627B3DF42BF862E90537C64133A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such decision was unnecessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63CF55B070464B1286764BC64F501E0E" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the Secretary waives such requirement, the applicable member of the Board shall include, pursuant to subsection (d), a determination of such waiver in the decision of the Board. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H574B29CDBEE0452489F6AF01BBC50897"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of aggregate; report</header><text>Such section is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7395E02E6F3B42F28F371F9E1F86927A" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><subsection id="HC2703A3EC3E14F4FB91FD8E04552F3B9"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than five years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Veterans Appeals Efficiency Act of 2025</short-title>, and every five years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the aggregation of claims by the Board under subsection (a). Each such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HEA944E7CAC05480E80AEA69174A93485"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an identification of each instance in which the Board aggregated appeals during the period covered by the report, including, for each such instance, the number of appeals that were aggregated;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3112B4DC1C346AE9CCA1A8FC6108858"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the aggregation of appeals has contributed to improved efficiency at the Board with issuing decisions on appeals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0770156EE774DB480961A590F292BD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other matters as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE1DAC2CEE3A4F95BFC2EE2FFB688418"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In this section, the term <quote>aggregate</quote>—</text><paragraph id="H4546477853EE4BA1B048B3534EEE536D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means any practice or procedure to collect common issues, claims, or appeals by multiple parties for the purposes of resolving such issues, claims, or appeals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AEB39967D514D0F8D4C53BEFBC4471D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes the use of joinder, consolidation, intervention, class actions, and any other multiparty proceedings.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE53B74FE6B0D4B8C84573B917D40FAF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expansion of jurisdiction of Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7252 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2F5F672F527F44DA8605470932D6EE74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBA5068BF2AE482D935409F1729866B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H82FF29B4FB5E48AAAF6398F6BE75AEAD" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><subsection id="HBF5FEE51F5B54FD5B5D006F6D87B35D9" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H32B6D1EEC4004B6590435A7486F88402"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB7F064B382E74C8696C0712C85554377"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In a covered proceeding in which the appellant or petitioner files a request for class certification pursuant to the rules prescribed by the Court pursuant to section 7264 of this title, the Court shall have supplemental jurisdiction over any claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary—</text><clause id="H729B09D13740431997FCD2755C05F3E6" indent="up2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that satisfies the definition of the class contained in the request for class certification; and</text></clause><clause id="H67D55329DE4F4035B5AC6C20F432416E" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which the agency of original jurisdiction has issued a nonfinal decision and the claimant has filed a notice of disagreement under section 5104C(a) or section 7105 of this title, including any case in which a claimant has filed a supplemental claim within one year of a Board decision under section 5110(a)(2)(D) and 5108 of this title following a notice of disagreement and decision of the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8953115F47441119D845F38DDD42561" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H8EA032777D0B42A4AF152632F530032A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a covered proceeding means an appeal over which the Court has jurisdiction pursuant to section 7266 of this title; and</text></clause><clause id="HF8B901F3162A4AD48C4FF10DB69B8208"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the definition of the class contained in the request for class certification includes claimants who have filed or will file a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary specified in such request for class certification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A83221D86D44D519BBFBA4A274B3BDD" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A claimant may submit a request for administrative review of such a claim under section 5104C(a) of this title during the period beginning on the date on which the named claimant of the motion for class action review submits to the Court a motion for class action review and ending on the date that is 60 days after the later of the following dates:</text><subparagraph id="H3CFAD56DD4AD4E0195730787971F0A12" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date on which the Court issues a final decision with respect to such claim.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF80141F57EC148A984F316D1CBE194D4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The date on which the Court issues a final decision with respect to such motion for class action review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53FC5A9B05AD469F895AAE6D61A97AD6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a claimant whose claim is decided by the Board during the period when the Court is reviewing the motion for class action review the deadline for such claimant to file an appeal to the Court with respect to the decision of the Board shall be tolled if the Court denies the motion for class action review. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D2B53E62E024D12AE22E4A958A36239" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H08E7098FC37C4737B5DAFA2EF733FACB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary, the Court may remand a matter to the Board of Veterans’ Appeals for the limited purpose of ordering the Board to address a question of law or fact if the Court determines the Board failed to—</text><subparagraph id="HB819D2A127454239A11E96A3A400E916" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address, in the relevant decision of the Board, an issue that—</text><clause id="H823D0B61A1984F8E80CA8E1136FD96AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the claimant or the representative of the claimant raised; or</text></clause><clause id="H7874230954134022B1694F8587E79725"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was reasonably raised by the evidentiary record of the claim; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B62DCDE5E054B17B670FC9105E932E4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide adequate reasons or bases for the decision of the Board with respect to such question.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4DA244F08FC4B40A2DA8F6A35F8B3F9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Court shall issue Rules that provide for each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H666250BC6AD044CDB8F35C943B42FD51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>When and how a party to an appeal (either the appellant or the Secretary) may request that the Court issue a limited remand.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9A49F0161C04264AF828E1DE9994581"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The period of time within which the Board is required issue a decision on the relevant question identified in a limited remand.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C900094792E4B7AA1871A60B019D13E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Guidelines for when the Court may grant a request for a limited remand.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63CDD688CD0D4F3C8EFD96FC5EC2D119"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guidelines for when the Court may decide sua sponte to issue a limited remand without a request from any party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E1B52CA6AEB433E9726A36077B40891"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A requirement that the parties to an appeal for which a limited remand is issued provide notice to the Court when the Board issues its decision on the relevant question identified in the limited remand.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE03664CFFED4A7391B0706EF2E9F2CE" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>With respect to any matter remanded to the Board pursuant to paragraph (1), the Court shall—</text><subparagraph id="H42DA0BBC99BE43BAA74C18F21E1D0C93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>retain jurisdiction over such matter; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ECC5BB8BE504B21A424A3B355F84AB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stay the proceedings of the Court on such matter until the date on which the Board issues the decision required by such remand.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA6E38799B6840ABA1523A922AFBD505"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Study and report on common questions of law or fact before Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header><paragraph id="H75C5DA570EB84819A425DF76EAD0CCC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals shall carry out a study to identify questions of law or fact the Board commonly considers when reviewing appeals pursuant to section 7104 of title 38, United States Code, for which precedential guidance would assist the Board in issuing final decisions on such appeals. The Chairman may use artificial intelligence and other technology in carrying out such study.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA8B8DC058804E16973BF6639E7DEBE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chairman of the Board of Veterans Appeals shall submit to the Committees on Veterans Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes the findings of the study required by paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H813C700239664BC084C2842FEBB92CC3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Independent assessment of potential modifications to authority of Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header><paragraph id="HD09BD0ED381F4ECD9AE7FF467BD7AAB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall seek to enter into an agreement with an FFRDC under which the FFRDC shall conduct an assessment of the feasibility of modifying the authority of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, to permit the Board to issue precedential decisions with respect to questions of law or fact arising in matters before the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA8DA8DE133F4C8ABCD02D03D9A8D6BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report; briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary fails to finalize an agreement with an FFRDC under paragraph (1) before the date that is 180 days after the date on which the Secretary enters negotiations with respect to such agreement, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3302EE5544374ED7B1F148333ABDC8B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes—</text><clause id="HA99E86F4731F4BA99E8EE28498036805"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an explanation of the reasons the Secretary failed to satisfy such requirement; and</text></clause><clause id="HCFC7ACE7C979425782317FB334A593D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an estimate of the date on which the Secretary will finalize the agreement under paragraph (1); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C1C99BAFF14416188F18AC275601090"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 60 days after the date on which the Secretary failed to satisfy such requirement, provide to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing on the progress of the Secretary toward finalizing such agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF28451ED60AD4DE7B6DEDA1A2170B634"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An FFRDC that enters into an agreement under subsection (a) shall, in consultation with veterans service organizations, veterans’ and survivors’ advocate groups, relevant legal experts, and the Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States (or the designee or designees of such Chair) submit to the Secretary a written assessment that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBE3397B3B21D481D9954879DAC79F984"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination of the FFRDC of whether modifying the authority of the Board to permit the Board to issue precedential decisions with respect to questions of law or fact arising in matters before the Board is feasible.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCB8DFF41ED64305B4FFB57944B4AC1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the authority of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals to aggregate, for review, more than one appeal under chapter 71 of such title that involves common questions of law or fact pursuant to section 7104 of such title, as amended by subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DBAF0C52DF54F67B43D7F6C1185F51C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recommendations of the FFRDC with respect to rules or principles to which the Board should adhere when aggregating appeals for review pursuant to section 7104(a) of title 38, United States Code, as so amended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D880C50BE4C4C80B4D19CCF319D06BA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report; implementation</header><subparagraph id="H24F8AFCA54F846DDA65B337FEA59DAA9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the Secretary receives the assessment under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H1A8BEA19B718469DB945DAF326B19618"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a copy of such assessment; and</text></clause><clause id="HE91398F18C504372BF7FF7623DFD036E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begin developing policies and procedures to implement the recommendations in the assessment with respect to the authority of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals referred to in paragraph (2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94F1C05D017C49D3BED880457F0F5905"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall complete the development of the policies and procedures required under subparagraph (A)(ii) by not later than six months after the date on which the Secretary begins developing such policies and procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7FCFC1F63944D4084721CBAFA7A3C39"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HB1ABDA2E47B745859904DE8BF3F0E4B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>FFRDC</quote> means a federally funded research and development center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E3D9917BCA24B589EB296C7BB099D16"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>veterans service organization</quote> means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H93C3E6FD78D4435098F39D934A3B8A0E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improvements to system for adjudication of claims for benefits under laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H7662B09E49DC4371A9C0F92E0C288799"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program for quality assurance in decisions of Board of Veterans’ Appeals; performance reviews</header><paragraph id="HA6350193922E4EA4A573ADB35E5DA3ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7101 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9EF477BC417A46CAA8299C2B6DD8B9FF" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><subsection id="HAB1CDEDDBC5048BCA698D023D10B840E"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H70F38452C4A04B4C88734DDBA1CB66CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Chairman shall carry out a program to ensure quality in the decisions of the Board. Under such program, the Chairman shall—</text><subparagraph id="H85193F22A8CE48F59DC094EE3DAA5996" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop policies and procedures for—</text><clause id="HE395C3CF953E419E889996DD9323B87C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measuring quality in such decisions;</text></clause><clause id="H02D11EBA33E44A7DB983C57177CC55F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintaining data and identifying trends with respect to—</text><subclause id="H2AB67CE6FC744BC08FE10592B0483467"><enum>(I)</enum><text>errors in such decisions;</text></subclause><subclause id="H191263EE3FBF4F079820ABBCF1FC9494" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>errors in decisions remanded or returned to the Board by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H854E8CF98D2A444A8AAEB61AEF87FCCF" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>specific members of the Board that issued decisions that were subsequently vacated by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H54276BED101E4B8C9BE5827F033AB572" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensuring any such decision of the Board to remand a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary is necessary under any applicable law or regulation;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBE43C12F13D43C5BF7DDF4A1320E505" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a claim for such a benefit that is remanded to the Board by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims—</text><clause id="H13760E8113BF4FC9A5370268493984CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inform any employee of the Board responsible for drafting the decision of the Board with respect to such claim that such decision was remanded;</text></clause><clause id="H7A812D622259418D8C5042FE54609A6E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide any such employee with a copy of the relevant order of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims (including a copy of any accompanying joint motion for remand); and</text></clause><clause id="HD856ADCD7D9F4FCF81C89F92421CA2EC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide incentives to such employees to review such relevant orders and joint motions for remand; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC693FF45F3144E7E8E535D6E2544661B" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that any error identified by the Board under such program is corrected before the date on which the Board issues the final decision associated with such error.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0829AF86756C487B851C6BDE751448BD" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In developing policies and procedures to measure quality in decisions of the Board pursuant to clause (i) of subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), the Chairman shall consider the data and trends maintained and identified pursuant to clause (ii) of such subparagraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9AB93C3CD394FF8A017D492AED75ED4" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Chairman may use technology, including artificial intelligence, to maintain such data and identify such trends.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF4A0CFAC7C421587294FC42CFA2A94" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report on the program required by this subsection that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report, an identification of—</text><subparagraph id="H8EE327E819EE41438BE8597D868E6A1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>elements, if any of the process of the Board for reviewing an appeal under this chapter that lead to errors in decisions of the Board; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CB97E16B04E4B46A4404B33028728BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the most common reasons that a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary was remanded to such Board by the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F2EBAE8E4A444ED90EF83C43E0CF1E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall submit the first report required by paragraph (2) of such section (as added by paragraph (1)) by not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD7CF04EBEA842C08BC4F2A892BA88FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training program for certain employees of Board of Veterans’ Appeals; performance reviews</header><paragraph id="HED9675CCEDA44C60AA126BD8D2D24681"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training program</header><subparagraph id="H97A300F37D9647D794F0982FD6ECEAF4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 71 of such title (as amended by subsection (a)) is further amended by inserting after section 7101A the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H42284BA81A6B4EB58A6C4416AC6FED46" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><section id="H17E8FE70E2AB42E39093CF8DB522F523"><enum>7101B.</enum><header>Training program for Members of Board on timely and correct adjudication of appeals</header><subsection id="H300E708597E047A1A4C6D0FAF9EF9CE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in conjunction with the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, shall develop and carry out a program to provide Members of the Board training on timely and correct adjudication of appeals under this chapter.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9A3DFD3EE7F4856892F9F4EBDA721E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required considerations</header><text>In carrying out the program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><paragraph id="H3903E57981594A94A314C88BF9D68526"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Feedback, if any, from members of the Board and covered employees with respect to such program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4683BE3AD35B4B6691349E95AAE97B29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Data on errors in decisions of the Board maintained pursuant to the program for quality assurance required by subsection (f) of section 7101 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5A4F02FF8D54893BF12D020D300617A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any decision of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to remand a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary to the Board for further action, including a joint motion to remand such claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54901601CBBA4DDCB480B31ABA932953" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessments of effectiveness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in conjunction with the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, shall develop a method to assess, on an annual basis, the effectiveness of the training program under this section. In developing such method, the Secretary shall consider best practices for assessing the effectiveness of training programs, including the Kirkpatrick evaluation model.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8256707851DD421D8B6E37A8FEBC366D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report on the program required by subsection (a) that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text><paragraph id="HB99B97CD4F32436F825B05DCDF26D9CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of the topics of the training provided pursuant to this section, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="HA0A6A2BDC4974857AAB98295AD5A39CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mandatory training; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9884F9DA1F7C429A8BD5DC06DEC5BB94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>non-mandatory training; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01455CBD53C74766B9998F676AEA6177"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the results of the assessment of the effectiveness of such program required under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H032B2EE0D9EC47468130E40BAD0D787A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered employee defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered employee</quote> means an employee of the Board who is—</text><paragraph id="HBEE22926F4A54A95BC1BE88A44C3918A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not a member of the Board; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37BA65C2BB9049579B9285DB94389254"><enum>(2)</enum><text>responsible for drafting decisions of the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DE1BFAA6DE447779853A910B680CC21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7101A the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H9DED3E37160445BA9EA7224230E6B8C7" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc-entry level="item">7101B. Training program for Members of Board on timely and correct adjudication of appeals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17E17E23F3C44030BD1BA12389D6F1A3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Performance reviews of Members of the Board</header><text>Section 7101A of such title (as amended by paragraph (1)) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H5FBE7F2E45C141EBA8507F24890FE01D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) of subsection (c)(1) by striking <quote>not less often than once every three years</quote> and inserting <quote>not less often than annually</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15559E167D7249B6B0ACE8142198D879" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H879733E9F63D48FD94AF63F1C64D193B" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><subsection id="HEE4107F4EE7040E0A89A538A5B97A695" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7D2B3CCD0EA042FAA3F0469CC77D6210"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to any performance review of a covered employee, the Secretary may not consider the timeliness or quality of work of any Member of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AE62A7A6E8D4D68AF0872F27C2F0DF0" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 7101B of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26D5798E9EB04BAD859D01F0488401DB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Decisions of Board to remand</header><paragraph id="H09F78FD4F19D4D65A0A76F4C019A459B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information relating to decisions to remand</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7104 of such title is amended in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="H11AA440C972F42319D617CAD23389DC2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as paragraphs (2) through (4), respsectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F755C9D788F4EC1ACABE886828075B8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) (as so redesignated), the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H796E8B3E67CD4C25A8B9D9D3870A3161" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><paragraph id="HE712A5BFA6E443899A9FC313331E9AB1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a claim that the Board remands for further action, a statement of the specific reasons such claim was remanded, including any failure on the part of the Secretary to comply with—</text><subparagraph id="H8B63A1F634EC4E8E86AC83549F564F85" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary’s duty to assist under section 5103A of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF21FE3F8FDE949FC958D9BA1345EC4C6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary’s duty to notify under section 5103 of this title;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0CB257C3CC84B279653E738F15DA932" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of remanded decision for certain employees</header><text>Such section is further amended in—</text><subparagraph id="HFB4CDC4A6A7440AB9C65B52570E5B80A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subsection (e)—</text><clause id="HD703D42DA979491EB32C58A7B74EC4DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as subparagraphs (A) through (C), respectively;</text></clause><clause id="HC73F9EC9BD474A02B91AC86328C300DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>After</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) After</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H3E4CDADFE3A845A0BBE24D57E6074C05"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HA8F47DC51E3E48D68E6356F9E65D4B33" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><paragraph id="HC6C5EF0ED9A3464C91358790A77633FB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, pursuant to a decision on an appeal, the Board remands a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary for further action, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, issue a copy of such decision to each employee of the Veterans Benefits Administration who committed the error resulting in the decision of the Board to remand, when applicable.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6149F6593AF8437BB9B070339BA407ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (g), as redesignated by section 3(d)(2)(A), by striking <quote>under subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>under paragraph (1) of subsection (e)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEA367DB941D4345987CF77507471594"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports for Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header><paragraph id="H31FA34E340004F03974478B4DC6EE619"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">Chapter 71</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7114">section 7114</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H543DDEF84EF84D55A3D98C5A796A8E0C" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><section id="HD944C441B54E486AA20BBCEEB80C178F"><enum>7115.</enum><header>Annual report on Board of Veterans’ Appeals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Chairman of the Board shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an annual report that includes, for each decision of the Board to remand a claim for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary to the Secretary for further adjudication during the period covered by the report, a statement of the reasons for such decision of the Board, disaggregated by decisions on—</text><paragraph id="HAEE3C54EF08C4B4F835E38CD901FCE49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>claims with a rating decision dated on or after February 19, 2019; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90F95AA3BBE04BEDA5BB7AC427FA74EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>claims with a rating decision dated before such date.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FA8E6CCF7944ED5A31A1CBDF447330D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>The Secretary shall submit the first reports required by subsections (a) and (b) of section 7115 of such title (as added by paragraph (1)) by not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E39627840D24A729C9008CC0DD1662D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7114 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0809DBFE8F074E08870CBC768120F8B2" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00"><toc-entry level="section">7115. Annual report on Board of Veterans’ Appeals</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C9C8A5043C04C98AB1FD93383368271"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Plan for improvements to quality in decisions of Board</header><paragraph id="HC47ADE450ACC4D6A8BD80379CC5678D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals and the head of the Office of Administrative Review of the Veterans Benefits Administration, shall develop a plan to—</text><subparagraph id="HC7EFDC0F1718436D8A1ED47C353371BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the quality of decisions of the Board to remand, pursuant to section 7104 of title 38, United States Code, claims for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary to the Secretary for further action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01A6BF241B5C45F685EDEA7E7A478DE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mitigate the number of such decisions that are unnecessary under any applicable law or regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBD1A00450944350800E1F64B3A00759" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on such plan by not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF0D5D5385D6749D89AFF64B4D0866008"><enum>5.</enum><header>Notice of avoidable deferrals of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; study and report on certain opinions of Department of Veterans Affairs Office of General Counsel</header><subsection id="HBC4C8882312A4E7EA34CD21F36E23190" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice of avoidable deferrals</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop policies, procedures, and technological capabilities to ensure that each employee of the Veterans Benefits Administration that commits an avoidable deferral with respect to a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in the National Work Queue is notified of any avoidable deferrals that such employee commits with respect to the same claim.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8633CAA4B9E540D497B3201A581AA6C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report on certain OGC opinions</header><paragraph id="HA94DA628D6D048B3B3A1C2FE8C964FDD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Office of the General Counsel of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Chairman of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, shall complete a study to identify—</text><subparagraph id="HC3D9656586834E29A81688DA623C58AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issues about which an opinion from the Office of the General Counsel of the Department would foster consistency in the decisions of the Secretary with respect to claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E133B00DFAF4566A82875B016F32AB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issues raised in appeals of such decisions to the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims before the date of the enactment of this Act about which the Office of the General Counsel has had inconsistent opinions in matters involving substantially similar questions of law or fact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8244142B5ADF488A97786A5F9F97E7DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HB6EFCAA789984C498B6778FEEABF1DD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings of the study required by paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0F1E55C6B8A4E6980D6802FFDBBEE26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement of which issues identified pursuant to such study about which the Office of the General Counsel of the Department intends to publish an opinion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B96E38F66AB426B90DC394B1A8F33E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a timeline for the publication of any such opinion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3D0A2D0435884E1181AE6B9FA38C5EDC" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Extension of certain limits on payments of pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5503(d)(7) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>November 30, 2031</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2034</quote>.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

