<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDE372CDDC33740D190ED51ED0E5AC438" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3497 RH: Medal of Sacrifice Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 399</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3497</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–466]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250519">May 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 19, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a medal of service for law enforcement officers and first responders.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HCF56E13364B8434E992D00B25720420F"><section id="H5C2072D06AA4423BBECB4851DEF7FE00" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medal of Sacrifice Act</short-title> of 2025</quote>.</text></section><section id="HB1E6AAF657EB41AFA357AD3DBA6EDDF6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders</header><subsection id="HA599195DD3544690960FDDCE2F15720B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall issue a medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders who were killed in the line of duty.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC9706E28A62740E88A79D488A9F62A22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><paragraph id="HBD2F01BA1F2F46F785FC799538F4662C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local, State, Tribal, territorial, or Federal law enforcement officer or first responder who was killed in the line of duty shall be eligible for the medal of sacrifice established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F28BF2052F54C2DAB9181EE05064BBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><subparagraph id="HB50FD8C27DA04F9EB10902CC45802A83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local, State, Tribal, territorial, or Federal law enforcement officer or first responder who is killed in the line of duty, but who is subject to an official finding of wrongdoing, shall not be eligible for the medal of sacrifice established under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H980740B0B80D4BB5AC12AB71CC55753D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an official finding of wrongdoing, the Commission established under subsection (c) shall investigate the circumstances surrounding the law enforcement officer’s or first responder’s cause of death, including considering any findings by the local, State, Tribal, territorial, or Federal agency with respect to the officer’s or responder’s death. The Commission established under subsection (c) shall make a final determination as to the officer’s eligibility for the medal established under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA978A60CE5E49F5BB37515C2F641B24"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Official finding of wrongdoing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>official finding of wrongdoing</term> means a determination by the law enforcement officer’s or first responders’ superior officer or employing law agency that the officer acted outside of the scope of their duties or not in accordance with the agency’s official policies or procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6884B4845AA5417AB5E7E8323810CA67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Commission on medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders</header><paragraph id="H03DAFC3E32BC42E0BB6C2FB4B02F7822"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish a Commission on the medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders (hereinafter known as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA605F12438EE41469D6CBC674467D7AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall appoint 12 members of the Commission. Such members shall be law enforcement officers, first responders, and representatives of organizations knowledgeable about law enforcement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AF03A2A36B945FE86B21F6DE18869A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Members of the Commission shall be appointed for a term of 5 years and shall be eligible to serve up to two terms, either consecutively or non-consecutively. The President shall make appointments to fill such vacancies as may occur on the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H545A9A1693E14196A6B46450395B034A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members shall not be paid for serving on the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9DF5C46E9F84BEBB97D257A61D35498"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="H06AE5FBFEBEE4A308C30061597DCFDE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the Commission on the design of the medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6772FCC8985647FF934F6A5FE8FD76CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote the establishment of the medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9AD53E3685A4E5FBDEDA433D1363769"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine how the medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders shall be presented; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ED4FBC329914B568204CAEB1E402D96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>make any final determination necessary pursuant to subsection (b)(2)(B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A05E92F96F4410C91C31D27E3AE492A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the President regarding criteria for assessing eligibility pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB7DF9F948DB47FCBF9749CCB520E30C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Initial award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall award the following law enforcement officers the medal of sacrifice:</text><subparagraph id="H27FD41F9F0D544B8A74301FF676083A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Deputy Ralph <quote>Butch</quote> Waller (Badge #8434);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B7205CB42C54FAB96B35F77CD632F29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Deputy Ignacio <quote>Dan</quote> Diaz (Badge #7637); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H064A48A64FE549438A37431BED293777"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Deputy Luis Paez (Badge #3882).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FD9C10673814B5C9E1156E373C01D36"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Commission shall cease to exist on the date on which the President determines that the Commission has completed each responsibility under paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H099C64EC0A4C474DA1313D31BE59D067"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Description</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The medal of sacrifice for law enforcement officers and first responders shall be a modified quatrefoil, with rounded lobes extending from a central octagon. The field incorporates features of the Great Seal of the United States, redesigned by Tiffany &amp; Co in 1885. The American eagle is charged with a coat of arms as a shield, argent, on a chevron gules between three lions rampant azure, as many chevronels argent; the crest, out of a coronet or, a double-tailed lion rampant azure, holding in its dexter paw a torch or enflamed proper; and <quote>Integritas</quote> included as a motto. Surrounding the seal are mullets, 47 in number, alternating with three rampant lions and incorporating four chevrons. In base, the word <quote>SACRIFICE</quote> is inscribed. In dexter base, three oak leaves are placed, symbolizing the national tree of the U.S., representing strength, resilience, and honoring the families and widows of the fallen. The reverse of the medal is sandblasted and bears an engraving of the names of the fallen heroes. The medal is suspended from a ribbon, either Azure or Gules depending on the fallen hero being honored. The ribbon bail is prepared and attached by hand soldering to the back of the medal. The medal is crafted from Silver Ag925 with 24k Gold Vermeil, with a weight of approximately 63 grams. It has a diameter of 2.25 inches. The Vermeil plating has a thickness of 2.5 microns. The medal combines national symbols with heraldic elements to represent the sacrifice of the fallen deputies. The use of Silver and Gold signifies the value and honor associated with their service.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

