<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55E14A52576C495C83877831F36B9C2D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 907 IH: Honoring the victims of the devastating attack that took place at the Waukesha, Wisconsin, Christmas parade on November 21, 2021.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 907</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the victims of the devastating attack that took place at the Waukesha, Wisconsin, Christmas parade on November 21, 2021.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on November 21, 2021, in Waukesha, Wisconsin, an individual committed intentional homicide on parade participants and attendees, killing 6 people and leaving 62 others with injuries;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the attack occurred during the 58th annual Waukesha Christmas parade, a tradition that featured over 60 local civic groups, businesses, schools, public services, and entertainers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Virginia Sorenson was a cherished long-time member of Milwaukee’s Dancing Grannies and longtime choreographer for the group;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Tamara Durand was a new member of Milwaukee’s Dancing Grannies who volunteered for local hospitals and the Red Cross while caring for her grandson;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas LeAnna Owen was a committed member of Milwaukee’s Dancing Grannies who managed an apartment building and rescued bulldogs;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Jane Kulich was a loving wife, mother, grandmother, and friend, and was dedicated to her co-workers at Citizens Bank, with whom she was marching in the parade;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Wilhelm Hospel volunteered for Milwaukee’s Dancing Grannies to support his wife, Lola, and was an avid outdoorsman;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Jackson Sparks was a loving child who enjoyed playing baseball for the Waukesha Blazers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in response to the tragedy, the community continues to stand <quote>Waukesha Strong</quote> in efforts to honor the victims and heal together;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, two weeks after the attack, homes and businesses were decorated in blue lights to honor the victims;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on September 24, 2022, a mural that serves as a beacon for the community was dedicated to the lives lost in the attack;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on November 21, 2023, a parade memorial on Main Street honoring the victims was unveiled;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on November 21, 2024, a parade memorial statue at Grede Park honoring the victims was dedicated;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on November 21, 2025, a parade memorial sculpture at Grede Park honoring the victims was dedicated; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, 4 years later, the Waukesha community continues to overcome this tragedy: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAF64B016E74B41FA8B76946DD4A89416"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD58EA92260F047FB8EEBF85511DDF8A1"><text>That House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HEB861D9FC4B74206A3D44489173EF887"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the memories of Wilhelm Hospel, Virginia Sorenson, LeAnna Owen, Tamara Durand, Jane Kulich, and Jackson Sparks who died in the attack;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04DA42AB5ECD490C92235756F7B3CD50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offers its heartfelt condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of those who died in the attack;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5A25EFFAC62C45D9985854EE861B9755"><enum>(3)</enum><text>applauds the life-saving efforts of first responders and health professionals in their efforts to provide care for the victims; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CE2DCF19B3D4BB1AD65B298348675F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the Waukesha community for showing unparalleled resilience, courage, and strength.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

