<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL26184-HF4-PY-G3F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4037 IS: Diabetes Interventions Addressing Barriers to Enrollment, Technology, and Education Services (DIABETES) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4037</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260310">March 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure continued access to diabetes technology upon Medicare enrollment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Diabetes Interventions Addressing Barriers to Enrollment, Technology, and Education Services (DIABETES) Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Diabetes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd21b02756b3c405db03a68a4ac9372f7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; Sense of Congress</header><subsection id="idab8f5209dc874727b22697de12a8775c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id7beec8962e754e60a29c75b4e0d6b9b8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in 2021, an estimated 38,400,000 Americans, or 11.6 percent of the entire United States population, have diabetes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb41b14fbdf29415caddc23c700703938"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number of individuals with diabetes is projected to increase to an estimated 54,900,000 individuals by 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddfc8f3bc95ee46cb97486cf34fad2494"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Diabetes disproportionately impacts the Medicare population, as the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services found in 2022, and 26 percent of Medicare beneficiaries have diabetes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25319e223731483cb061be247d0ac4a5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Both type 1 and 2 diabetes can significantly harm long-term health and is associated with numerous comorbidities such as cancer, heart disease, chronic kidney disease, blindness, and amputations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd23f413c794444d3904aa2d1b42c7ba4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The direct and indirect cost of diabetes is significant as the American Diabetes Association found that the total annual cost of diabetes in 2022 was $412,900,000,000, $306,600,000,000 of which is attributable to direct medical costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87b30b0f73ec49a2b1789ba7f86fe7f3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The American Diabetes Association and the American Association of Clinical Endocrinology have set forth clinical guidelines that include the use of continuous glucose monitors, insulin pumps, automated insulin delivery systems, and diabetes self-management training for individuals with diabetes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7de33177917f47658df0ffc1b782ffb6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An automated insulin delivery system consists of a continuous glucose monitor, an insulin pump, and an algorithm or software.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b32c88780c340a88f830ef262d0cc78"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The algorithm or software is a critical component of an automated insulin delivery system as it continuously learns the user’s behavior and physiological responses and automatically administers the appropriate amount of insulin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf8ecedf80d85497cb147deb90ddbefc1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Medicare currently fails to separately reimburse for the essential algorithms and software that drive automated insulin delivery (AID) systems, which may stifle future innovation and maintenance, and impede beneficiary access.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd595916bd29480b842d047cff0574e2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Medicare has an existing pathway to separately reimburse for the algorithm or software in an automated insulin delivery system, the Medicare durable medical equipment benefit.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf36e1cc86ed6402aa048c189e540f4a7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Including continuous glucose monitors, durable insulin pumps, and related supplies into the competitive bidding program further limits innovation and access to diabetes technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd754b54f1ee847119456cb2f28ee9390"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services’ final rule entitled <quote>Medicare and Medicaid Programs; Calendar Year 2026 Home Health Prospective Payment System (HH PPS) Rate Update; Requirements for the HH Quality Reporting Program and the HH Value-Based Purchasing Expanded Model; Durable Medical Equipment, Prosthetics, Orthotics, and Supplies (DMEPOS) Competitive Bidding Program Updates; DMEPOS Accreditation Requirements; Provider Enrollment; and Other Medicare and Medicaid Policies</quote> (90 Fed. Reg. 55342 (December 2, 2025)), which reclassifies continuous glucose monitors and durable insulin pumps as items requiring frequent and substantial servicing when they are phased into the competitive bidding program, will have numerous unintended consequences that may prevent Medicare beneficiaries from accessing the continuous glucose monitor or durable insulin pump they need to survive.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idecf6bdf903004dad8b15cfb1554a4f32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding automated insulin delivery systems</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Health and Human Services should commit to take administrative action to—</text><paragraph id="id18f1d439e6fc4abfa5d0db6509770018"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognize that the algorithm or software in an automated insulin delivery system is a <quote>reasonable and necessary</quote> item <quote>for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury or to improve the functioning of a malformed body member</quote> consistent with Medicare coverage requirements under section 1862(a)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb821b3f7e6e4ec5b967d08adca5d48c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure the algorithm or software in an automated insulin delivery system is treated as a separately payable supply to durable medical equipment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e3bfff5d3484d3498334a37b8fe1931"><enum>(3)</enum><text>when applicable, recognize the algorithm or software in an automated insulin delivery system as <quote>medical supplies associated with the injection of insulin</quote> consistent with section 1860D–2(e)(1) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id54a1b3284ac94a56a04ba031c65f5559"><enum>3.</enum><header>Continued access to diabetes related technologies</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4de00687f9b14c0fbb8425ef55ef402c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(ww) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ww)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id2ee26bcc8b7f4faaac53e300dfe2e193"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefcc1a51b5f54ee79803d804ecb39b00"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and</quote> after <quote>upon the agreement with the individual,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb0fb1b594b14faeb066a5b30ae69973"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>and ensuring care continuity for individuals using diabetes technology covered under part B as described in paragraph (5),</quote> after <quote>(as defined in paragraph (4)),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf8fdca41468246868179214ef4777e0b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2278689608d4471eab1ded66bc00f907"><paragraph id="id3960bcabd4cc4b8b92703479e3c05c15" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id84a12dce074642a5922f347ba4af7ef4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C) of this paragraph, during the first 12 months of an individual’s enrollment for benefits under part B, a provider (as defined in subparagraph (E)) may certify to the Secretary that an individual is using 1 or multiple diabetes technologies covered under part B (as defined in subparagraph (D)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idb0f3de6517d94521894fdde2318b24d9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the initial preventive physical examination or other covered service as determined appropriate by the Secretary during the period described in subparagraph (A), the provider may make a determination of the individual’s use of diabetes technology covered under part B. In the case where the provider makes such determination, the provider shall submit a certification to the Secretary as required under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idd39f9459e4d842c49176bd9526c4e2d1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebdbd5db6af84670aa4306435b2e44d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a finalized certification form, developed pursuant to public notice and opportunity for comment, for use under this paragraph;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e3ef42c11364f76bf2aedffee03fcd7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue guidance and instructions to medicare administrative contractors (as defined in section 1874A(a)(3)), that require the relevant medicare administrative contractors to only assess whether the certification form is included in the individual’s medical records when making a determination of whether coverage of the diabetes technology covered under part B is reasonable and necessary as described in section 1862(a)(1)(A);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a548a415be74c6585a6fca6ea9d33f9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a process through notice and comment rulemaking for considering whether an individual’s diabetes technology that is not covered under part B at the time of the certification described in subparagraph (A) should be a covered benefit under existing statutory authority; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa502c9ffd6642a99e27cddab538a41d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue appropriate guidance to relevant audit and oversight entities to ensure those entities do not inappropriately cause disruptions in access to diabetes technology covered under part B.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idc047c93601de4153a33bee14c2df2cb5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>diabetes technology covered under part B</term> means, with respect to an individual, any device, related supplies, and software or algorithm that, at the time the certification described in subparagraph (C) is made with respect to the individual, is covered under part B for an individual that has diabetes under the applicable ICD–10 code list, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id7c5184a0f7ee4edf9ca974ae710e77bb"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>provider</term> means a physician (as defined in section 1861(r)), nurse practitioner, clinical nurse specialist, physician assistant, (as those terms are defined in section 1861(aa)(5)), or certified nurse-midwife (as defined in section 1861(gg)(2)), or other provider of services or supplier as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ee72db8387b400180311c2c0a374f48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="idae553b32594f4c779cdeece86e51f397"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving access to diabetes outpatient self-management training services</header><subsection id="id29898b8bd4e44cc190ff7958a98e551b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861(qq) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(qq)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id2a5176b3e2e345e6a0aad1a35852c0d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="idb7ca0cfdd5df4829b564054d66e08d50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Secretary determines appropriate</quote> and inserting <quote>specified in paragraph (3)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95a9bff32e7d4b8c9c7d57b39cba51c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the physician who is managing the individual's diabetic condition</quote> and inserting <quote>a physician or qualified nonphysician practitioner</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb0b72ce9ca44433867555676842b9c3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0bf9b3e643b1461e993e2d3e346f425f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1d4a43c081d4cba9cdac272a15b80b3"><paragraph id="id2032b2df281744b0845cd50985839b34" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of paragraph (1) and subject to subparagraph (B), the times specified in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="idd7cd948e486840f3800e9a8f132d8e97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An initial 10 hours of individual or group educational and training services to remain available until used.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8acec0bf77e14b2294c0fdecbdefa61d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An additional 2 hours of individual or group educational and training services each year, beginning with the year in which the initial 10 hours described in subparagraph (A) are completed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c1a4bacf14c46d1a31b91cd11bf5c12"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not limit the quantity or duration of educational and training services furnished by a certified provider to an individual with diabetes if such services are deemed medically necessary by a physician or qualified non-physician practitioner.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0d10fd86f45c439e841d0a900eb6e50e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medical nutrition therapy services</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2)(V) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)(V)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id724da1f997fa4eeba0461f183a0466ed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking clause (i);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8e726ba094d4ab08216cc0dae9683b7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (ii) and (iii) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddcec3b15013f43d49bfd107b84fb5036"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>after consideration of</quote> and inserting <quote>consistent with</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idea498748e6174e1c8552a3ab23376d74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing</header><text>Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id1ea133181b7446c79e41b1563a98f923"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="idff71fe419d8d4c4da98aab2fdd721020"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (HH)</quote> and inserting <quote>(HH)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7dd272ce842e46f28eb4ef6e8744d8c9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting the following before the semicolon at the end: <quote>and (II) with respect to diabetes outpatient self-management training services (as defined in section 1861(qq)), the amount paid shall be 100 percent of the lesser of the actual charge for the services or the amount determined under the fee schedule that applies to such services under this part;</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0571dcdb1b1c48c0ae0d4cf236d9cf9e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the first sentence—</text><subparagraph id="id2675036805a14a74924159d71acf89b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, and (13)</quote> and inserting <quote>(13)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12890283a2754b08894e7557aaca9fde"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1861(n)..</quote> and inserting <quote>1861(n), and (14) such deductible shall not apply with respect to diabetes outpatient self-management training services (as defined in section 1861(qq))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id439d6ae0a4ed48f4aff4794d05537e40"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="id963b2d6487304b62a307fcd7c3b0fd81"><enum>5.</enum><header>CMI testing of providing virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1115A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id3850987BB4864FD8A586839B6F656CB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(A), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The models selected under this subparagraph shall include the testing of the model described in subsection (h).</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1F5C38D06B86424188F187FFCB8843BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="id843AED657EF145C499B61FA21B69BEB1" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="id57836F70CBAF482F81938E73F29954A0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Testing of providing virtual diabetes outpatient self-Management training services</header><paragraph id="idBE516D83167D4FFA9FE14AB0CB551737"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall implement a model to test the impact of providing coverage under title XVIII for virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services furnished to applicable beneficiaries with respect to improved health outcomes for such applicable beneficiaries and reduced expenditures under such title XVIII.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec8b02313c7b4e62b71985131ef5c321"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Model design</header><subparagraph id="id74084d28ce654cc5b0eabe13b464891e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall design the model under this subsection in such a manner to allow for the evaluation of demographic characteristics of applicable beneficiaries participating in such model and the extent to which such model accomplishes the following purposes:</text><clause id="id3ac5d95d5c4144b084defe1aad83e8b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Improvement in health outcomes with respect to the diabetic conditions, including by reducing A1c levels.</text></clause><clause id="id76cf9f4ae8bb42698851340af2df1840"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Reduced hospitalizations due to diabetic-related complications.</text></clause><clause id="ida1661977be9a459e9f4fc1af210bf60b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Increased utilization of diabetes outpatient self-management training services as evidenced by, for example, Medicare beneficiary participation and utilization of covered hours during the first year and subsequent years or use of diabetes outpatient self-management training services in rural and underserved communities.</text></clause><clause id="id70ce65f120494685aed529b608815919"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Improved medication adherence.</text></clause><clause id="idf31d5d0f749645dfb86724bbcda6f8e2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Reduced expenditures under this title attributable to the model.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69c4ee29c2f0415ead9d8aab2f583977"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In designing the model under this subsection, the Secretary shall, not later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of this subsection, consult with stakeholders in the field of diabetes care and education, clinicians in the primary care community, experts in digital health, and beneficiary groups.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id65b4144b1bdc4d0fa71169319133d957"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="ide064e4ed969e4f4dbab626a8f8098141"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>applicable beneficiary</term> means an individual with diabetes as described in section 1861(qq).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74c3240e9df54e3dbff0aef99f40d041"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified web-based program</header><text>The term <term>qualified web-based program</term> means a web-based program—</text><clause id="id934bd67ba8314ab9aa6563dec535908f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designed to furnish educational and training services to an individual with diabetes to ensure therapy compliance with respect to the individual’s diabetic condition or to provide the individual with necessary skills and knowledge (including skills related to the self-administration of injectable drugs) to participate in the individual’s management of such condition; and</text></clause><clause id="id206e9def84114e6ca0c0bb75774b8cf9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that meets the quality standards described in section 1861(qq)(2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C01C17F07604FE5BE09E615D56A15E4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services</header><text>The term <term>virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services</term> means any diabetes outpatient self-management training services (as defined in section 1861(qq)) furnished by a qualified web-based program for synchronous or asynchronous diabetes outpatient self-management training services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id148d40f798374596b86739ca07d00c13"><enum>6.</enum><header>Providing insulin pump training and education</header><subsection id="idbbc762c5d6cc4bf0a1f8f770e21ab331"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish new Healthcare Common Procedure Coding System codes under the fee schedule established under section 1848(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(b)</external-xref>) that describe hook-up, calibration, and patient training with respect to an insulin pump similar to Current Procedural Terminology codes 95249 and 95250 (and any succeeding codes). The Secretary shall ensure the newly established codes sufficiently describe patient education and training as well as insulin pump placement services for technologies covered under section 1834 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>) and part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-101">42 U.S.C. 1395w–101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id8eb29c40fa8443509f3ad35b3f36a6df"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education and outreach</header><text>The Secretary shall use existing communications and mechanisms to provide education and outreach to stakeholders with respect to the ability of health professionals to bill the newly established codes described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="id200896ad84a94143babe6152c805ddcd"><enum>7.</enum><header>National coverage determination on insulin pumps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue a proposed national coverage determination (as defined in section 1869(f)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff(f)(1)(B)</external-xref>)) for infusion pumps, continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII), number 280.14 pursuant to section 1862(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(l)</external-xref>).</text></section><section id="id0fc8723b1412435e9dd9be6d00da1168"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report on enrollee access to diabetes-related services and technologies in Federal health care programs</header><subsection id="idf50cdac1747346f8a3236c11fd2ac08e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall submit to the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, a report that assesses the barriers individuals face in accessing diabetes technologies and diabetes self-management education and support services across Federal health care programs. The report shall specifically review barriers, which include prior authorization practices, the use of preferred formularies, coverage intensity limitations, and other utilization management techniques, to accessing diabetes technologies and diabetes self-management education and support services faced by individuals enrolled in a Federal health care program, and whether any Federal law, regulation, or policy adversely affects access to those covered services or limits the ability of individuals with diabetes to receive services that align with standards of care.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0582f76658e040c3a773d8fe7c5a3037"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id0ae3adf887d048379ff3707cf5a2c5b4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Diabetes technologies</header><text>The term <term>diabetes technologies</term> means items described in section 1861(ww)(5)(D) of the Social Security Act, as added by section 3, and any device, related supplies, and software or algorithm that monitors or manages an individual’s diabetes that is medically necessary for the individual’s diagnosis of diabetes, regardless of whether the device, related supplies, and software or algorithm is covered under part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act. Such term includes glucose monitors, insulin delivery technologies, related supplies, and software or algorithms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id84ac3769936d4b3db95b5410ae015e8c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diabetes self-management education and support services</header><text>The term <term>diabetes self-management education and support services</term> means services described in section 1861(qq) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(qq)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ab96065f433453c94f7987ce177abff"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal health care program</header><text>The term <term>Federal health care program</term> means any plan or program that provides health benefits, whether through insurance or otherwise, that is directly funded in whole or in part, by the United States Government, including a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B(f) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b(f))) and a health benefits plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idaf3d28a2d4c645f397fd35fe61a1d995"><enum>9.</enum><header>Ensuring access to diabetes-related technologies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1847(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (42 1395w–3(a)(2)) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd819c937f0142beb147e7d69571e940"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5077d0daed7144f5a932f3ae1552c62a"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Certain diabetic-related items</header><text>Continuous glucose monitors and insulin pumps that are covered as durable medical equipment under section 1861(n) furnished on or after January 1, 2031.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

