<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9661C9E7FA8F410FB9A5158CD4A9E055" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1160 IH: Praising the efforts of United States Combat Search and Rescue teams in the recovery of two United States Air Force Airmen who ejected over Iran.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1160</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Praising the efforts of United States Combat Search and Rescue teams in the recovery of two United States Air Force Airmen who ejected over Iran.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since February 28, 2026, the United States and allied partners have conducted daring operations, known as Operation Epic Fury, to disable the oppressive Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps regime;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas United States and allied intelligence has credibly assessed the IRGC nuclear program poses immediate threats to United States interests and Eurasia;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas United States Central Command has reported that American forces have successfully conducted more than 13,000 combat missions in Iranian airspace, striking more than 12,300 targets;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas United States aerial dominance in the United States Central Command area of responsibility has resulted in over 20 years without a combat loss of United States aircraft;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on April 3, 2026, a United States F–15E Strike Eagle was interdicted over Iranian airspace, requiring the ejection of the pilot and Weapons Systems Officer into enemy territory;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the actions of both aviators give credit to their resolve, training, and equipment, allowing them to successfully evade the enemy while signaling their location information to American forces;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the immediate rescue effort reflects a whole-of-government approach to blend the United States military and intelligence apparatuses in order to ensure the safe and swift rescue of both downed Airmen;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the pilot was successfully rescued shortly after the crash, and the Weapons Systems Officer was rescued after nearly 48 hours of evasion in the early hours of Easter Sunday, April 5, 2026;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Weapons Systems Officer affirmed his safety in an encrypted radio transmission that read <quote>God is Good</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the rescue operations involved thousands of United States personnel, to include special operators, intelligence specialists, planners, pilots, logisticians, and countless others whose individual heroism personified the values of <quote>No Man Left Behind</quote>; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives praises the United States aviators for their courage and the United States personnel involved in the recovery of our downed aviators: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H14CDD2E76C44449DA3579BF776506D2C"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H555A1217DD4B4092874229DDFD21FEA6"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE24F452CD57E4C9B9B4DF64A63558F4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the heroic actions of the United States Armed Forces and intelligence personnel who executed the high-risk recovery of downed American aviators in hostile territory;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11848FEC032B44BE89F2F867D3974353"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the extreme physical and mental endurance of the aviators, who successfully evaded Iranian-backed forces for over 24 hours in rugged mountainous terrain;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD7D2ACCE6BD4114948A89B33272B76B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the tactical proficiency of the rescue teams, who braved adverse weather and active enemy pursuit to ensure that no service member was left behind; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82E167B8FFC24F28A05364478BCCD92F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applauds the seamless coordination between joint force components that enabled the rapid localization and extraction of an isolated personnel member;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5837E6F8F6B46A3972BECF70649456A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>affirms that the daring rescue reinforces the United States unwavering commitment to the recovery of its personnel, regardless of the complexity or danger of the environment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H175E5477142B45CAB5DA04D2CE0FAF6F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>highlights the superior training and technological edge of the United States military that allowed for a successful extraction under the nose of aggressive foreign actors; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4921255C7D4B4B5D8B58A7954635F6AA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>expresses the profound gratitude of the American people to the pilots, maintainers, and Special Operations forces involved in this mission; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CE74D41F96B424DB6BCFD7ACE05E00D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>declares that the success of this mission stands as a testament to the courage and readiness of the American warfighter.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

