<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25657-4RG-C6-X1V">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3073 IS: Pay Our Capitol Police Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3073</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251029">October 29, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms.
                    Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr.
                Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of
                    Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>)
                introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the
                    <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on
                    Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>Making continuing appropriations for the United States Capitol Police with
            respect to a Government shutdown.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="H546A6FCDC057486295CB97EF9FECF09A">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pay Our Capitol Police Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HB2F1921626CB40B49A7A9B61B8B2DD03">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Continuing appropriations for the United States Capitol Police</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa11d878c6b44b968ecc581e64118a94">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for fiscal year 2026 are not in effect—</text>
                <paragraph id="H17EAB2B609B84E069990BA168B2DAD13">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as are necessary to provide salaries, including overtime, hazardous duty pay, and Government contributions for health, retirement, social security, professional liability insurance, tuition reimbursement, recruitment and retention bonuses, and other applicable employee benefits, to—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c89ee5998964605a3c35deee1e7f599">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">members of the Capitol Police whom the Chief of the Capitol Police determines are excepted employees or employees performing emergency work, as those terms are defined by the Office of Personnel Management, during such period; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HC90D276E6DB343F8A18961251756672E">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">civilian employees of the Capitol Police whom the Chief of the Capitol Police determines are providing support to the members of the Capitol Police described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA2B6735660EB4DEBB8D8BD6C31483B9C">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as are necessary to provide payment to contractors of the Capitol Police whom the Chief of the Capitol Police determines are providing support to members of the Capitol Police described in paragraph (1)(A).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id5546f9d489b64923ba7afaee409cc768">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Interim continuing appropriations</header>
 <text>Appropriations made available under subsection (a) may not be obligated or expended for the Capitol Police during any period during which continuing appropriations for the purposes for which amounts are made available under subsection (a) are in effect for the Capitol Police.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id7e02f82c164e449baf46cc107cea2f29">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Charge to future appropriations</header>
 <text>Expenditures made pursuant to subsection (a) shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever an Act in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is included is enacted into law.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="HADC5B6EF16594233923560D2CB333E63">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Termination</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall be available until whichever of the following first occurs:</text>
            <paragraph id="idA9F7E15B83E64A6C9AB2E95BBF1E0A3B">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enactment into law of appropriations for the Capitol Police through September 30, 2026 (including a continuing appropriation) for any purpose for which amounts are made available in section 2.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idF3E75B246FC6488EB17324C4894C5E78">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enactment into law of appropriations for the legislative branch through September 30, 2026 (including a continuing appropriation) without any appropriation for such purpose.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida111e81d3a7e42d7ad9ea00dc81e209a">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>September 30, 2026.</text> </paragraph> </section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id350c8db737fd4925bc847ff2710c6885"> <enum>4.</enum> <header>Effective date; special rule</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad5b5d8d1b8f4287a02e3af6afd59603"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Effective date</header> <text>This Act shall take effect as if enacted on October 1, 2025.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id742dde9724fe48838cd6a2451f86f1f4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Special rule</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payments of pay and allowances from amounts appropriated under section 2 for any portion of the period beginning on October 1, 2025, and ending on the day before the date of enactment of this Act shall be provided as soon as practicable after such date of enactment.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

