<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KIN26015-8Y4-G5-991"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4030 IS: Supporting After-School STEM Educators Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4030</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide out-of-school time educators with professional development in STEM subjects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting After-School STEM Educators Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida3d2d71faa5a44f791927815819cddec"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id10daf2b843ce4948be72430a85fd95ab"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is growing recognition, as evidenced through program provider surveys conducted by the Afterschool Alliance, that the workforce for after-school, summer, and other out-of-school time programs is facing staffing crises, which are even more apparent for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics educators in that workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3068e3d9e5c472ca1199ed5ac444bdd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>STEM proficiency will have a major impact on the Nation’s future economic competitiveness and on the preeminence of the United States in scientific inquiry, technological innovation, and maintaining a scientifically literate public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c2bffe2cf134460b98d94266c2bb3d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Results from the National Assessment of Educational Progress, the Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study, the Programme for International Student Assessment, and other sources show that students in the United States are not demonstrating sufficient achievement in the STEM subjects, particularly in the years following the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d529eba26994f9d9cba2eb7ccf6c6bd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Research demonstrates the importance of after-school, summer, and other out-of-school time programs in engaging students in STEM fields and building STEM-relevant skills and proficiencies, especially for girls, students from populations traditionally underrepresented in STEM fields, and students from low socioeconomic circumstances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1289a3e984fa48fb86ceaf6a96b8e903"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Research also demonstrates the importance of having high-quality, well-prepared educators to support those programs, helping to inspire and motivate students to be interested in STEM.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e9f1d8fdba9488ab8521ab0ee3f499f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The investments by the Federal Government in STEM education require a capable and supported educator workforce in order for educators to provide quality opportunities for students to be engaged in STEM subjects outside of the school day and to build a balanced pre-kindergarten through 12th grade STEM education portfolio that fosters learning in school as well as in out-of-school time programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb27f40941cf3437c91c1aeab5a95ceef"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In order to sufficiently build up the Nation’s future STEM workforce, the Federal Government needs to bolster and enhance structural support for today’s STEM educators and ensure a robust network of future STEM educators. Developing the systems of support to help program providers access high-quality STEM curricula, resources, peer support, and professional development, is warranted.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idd51ecb4ecb6d4e5fa050f16f45c90894"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="idd5b2b33a44054296b25ef4e56154a066"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to recognize the important role that after-school, summer, and other out-of-school time educators, in STEM subjects, play in facilitating STEM education and development of the STEM workforce; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8215f1ee0c08448290d814ef18eb0d74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support STEM educators in after-school, summer, and other out-of-school time programs, including supporting their professional development and well-being through Federal funding.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idb51783e5ac6e48c5831b1ae0d0ebb606"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe482552bf824b4b8e0d14f0c17e1aec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intermediary</header><text>The term <term>intermediary</term> means an entity, public or private, that works to support quality after-school, summer, and other out-of-school time programs for student development through—</text><subparagraph id="id5c8de922aa454696b7da612d4d0fa3d5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>technical assistance and professional development for program educators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cf3d06319fa4e58bff6e944c8d9a6ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>program quality improvement initiatives, including assessment, evaluation, data analysis, and data dashboards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04fb0446372b4c9c84608519bc5f16c1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>resource development and coordination, including development and coordination through fundraising, grant writing, partnership building, and support with braiding funding and pass-through funding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46a9ccb1d1244fb9b1d67fedb3630c56"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public awareness efforts to promote the importance of out-of-school time programs and build partnerships to help programs secure funding and support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf5a63dea8bf4900a4786857a066054e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text>quick and fluid action to be able to respond to needs and opportunities, partnering with State and local government agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ca522b2ec6d47eebd6ae04c4c2b6680"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Out-of-school time</header><text>The term <term>out-of-school time</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8215a68bbab41998c1c2736987aa312"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used with respect to a program, means any organized educational, enrichment, or child care program (including a service) that is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id209f110e09314c268f740cb6afc92ae0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designed to engage pre-kindergarten through 12th grade students during a time when the students are not participating in a formal school program; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id446820548efe4892b965f8a4064eab74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offered during after-school, summer, or another out-of-school time by an entity such as a community-based organization, educational institution, school system, museum, library, student organization, community center organization, park organization, religious institution, or other nonprofit or commercial organization; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68f14787a10a4a91a7771dd727d7faaa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used with respect to an educator, means an educator in a program described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4323e39a7324998be6c0d1de969e93f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program provider</term> means a nonprofit provider of an out-of-school time program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf179fb11d7f45e78c5969dcd59cf686"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb603d1478b1a4429a18c7ba9e2d4638e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31f5f5680d544739a4c14a448b81d556"><enum>5.</enum><header>Out-of-school time STEM educator professional development scholarship program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida147c1f0697a40d8a725d9d5b03c9c38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31bdf498d7ba4ca6b59e2ec20ba9bffb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program through which the Secretary shall award grants to intermediaries (including consortia of intermediaries) to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29be9b37ee444cfab01fcb2c5ba4913b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support program providers of after-school, summer, and other out-of-school time programs by assisting the program providers to allocate professional development scholarship funds to educators, and otherwise to enable the educators to participate in the professional development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8874b443c08a4162aee30391e3184ed9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide support for the programs through centralized databases and peer networks (which may be used by the program providers funded under this section and other program providers); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc33c27b1e1874360b9c7b2441b29ef05"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">streamline accountability for the programs funded under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86deddc5da0b49ebad1713ce8de87827"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periods</header><text>The Secretary shall award the grants for periods of 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18d9b2a812c241fa8edaef64c1b5ba80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Number of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award not more than 1 grant per State, unless sufficient funds are made available for this section to enable the Secretary to award an additional grant for a State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd62387cceb9e4210921c02bf5528254a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an intermediary shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1de155aff03f442abe5720e223fe87a2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding the grants, the Secretary may give preference to intermediaries that identify a partner (including a consortium of such partners), such as a private or for-profit company, foundation, institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)), local workforce development board, local government agency, or another local industry partner, or a State educational agency (as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) or State workforce development board, that has committed to providing, each year, non-Federal matching funds equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of the grant payment for that year.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fd1ed579e694c2388be97065dd9cc4a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An intermediary that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18929e3d37f54c92ab6370a9d41429b9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to make subgrants under subsection (e), on a competitive basis, to program providers—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97eaf4f152b64d6085e6f9f325753a42"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enable STEM educators to participate in professional development (including coaching); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcad258d7f45746f3b327cceccb2904b9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to meet program provider reporting requirements established under this section;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a40b212432b446abe183633e2c3ea57"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop a statewide peer support structure by establishing a centralized database and facilitating peer networks under subsection (f) for out-of-school time educators; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf12d54f71b1c41cf99af7e8dc5ab2694"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to meet intermediary reporting requirements established under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id166e5314e5b64318bf873d59b50fb2d1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subgrants to program providers</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58354cb3eebd4cbba766835518847261"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0a60ece33224604af49130af5b474fc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Periods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An intermediary shall make a subgrant under this subsection for a period of not more than 5 years, and make payments under such subgrant annually.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd5f0a0e09f94223ad2a82dbff57b371"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The intermediary shall make such a subgrant in an amount determined on the basis of the need of the program provider applying, taking into account both the professional development needs of the provider's educators and the needs of the community served by the program provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79418467f8394616b587055200fcf950"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Number of subgrants</header><text>An intermediary that receives a grant under this section may use the grant funds to make subgrants to not more than 25 program providers to fund professional development (including coaching) in STEM subjects, and carry out other activities described in subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idafe0af5ffa2d411aac08b5e879f1f360"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Solicitations</header><text>When soliciting applications for subgrants under this subsection, each intermediary shall intentionally publicize the subgrant opportunity to all program providers of out-of-school time programs in the State, especially smaller organizations that may take more effort to reach.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id076f8867e3c5414f92324b19227406b6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a subgrant under this subsection, a program provider shall submit an application to an intermediary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the intermediary may require, including a program proposal for activities to be carried out under the subgrant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idafe81c4a841d4e9b84786adbb84e4eec"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluation of applications</header><text>In determining which program providers will receive subgrants under this subsection, an intermediary shall evaluate the program proposal in the application on the degree to which such a proposal—</text><subparagraph id="id812c1db8be53495c878806c147a8781b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensures educators are able to implement what the educators learn from professional development opportunities, using methods that resonate with their student populations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id90efad04c7374bafb68e872f9be5d780"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensures educators are supported in—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id139e47d8af9a424bbae7cb1220ce124f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtaining professional development (including training) opportunities that lead to STEM credentials or certifications that hold local or national labor market value (according to the National AfterSchool Association (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>NAA</quote>)) under the thriving workforce recommendations (defined, for purposes of this Act, as the Out-of-School Time Job Quality Standards issued by the NAA on June 27, 2024), such as acquiring the NAA Professional Credentialing System’s STEM microcredentials; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2eff369413947ac95d4265022f2e425"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using the professional development to increase their wages and follow pathways for professional growth; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7703cb623331468daf8a14b64c372962" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides that the program provider will—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ccc1109d49e4035bb5c9cd49bce2163"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less often than annually, evaluate and appropriately reward the educators receiving the professional development for their professional growth; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida64bb9a99688442486d1015466ab2cec"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase recognition titles for educators who acquire new skills, experience, and responsibilities in alignment with the NAA thriving workforce recommendations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab6b26f7b807409fa4256f83d07b2022"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In determining which program providers will receive subgrants under this subsection, an intermediary shall give priority to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide57b0fce39a042d2b7cae3e0ccb48b5d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a program provider with a selection of professional development opportunities that encourage peer-to-peer networking and support during and after the training portion of the professional development takes place;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66d5d6697d0a4df9baad870597f4c778"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a program provider with a program—</text><clause id="idd786ff3040b14ecc8711da61959ed3ad"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a community with historical underinvestment in access to STEM learning opportunities for students both in and out of school;</text></clause><clause id="idb743988760ca48748c09358b64722565"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with a high percentage of students who are underrepresented in STEM fields; or</text></clause><clause id="id4a5ac3cdbb324b04bd95f4d404163ccc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in a rural area where learning programs for students are more remote from typical professional learning and industry hubs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17f2029bccb84afcbbc4fd471a752f89" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a program provider that seeks—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b1dd4d9d2c64030b8d573c50123311b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support educators, including seasonal educators; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78f8df05e753443f97114700eadb3e76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide train-the-trainer and coach development trainings for more long-term educators.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4e3c0de8ddd47238ed66914e027fd1b"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide42835cee84b49d89739267a1aaa4fc5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Professional development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program provider that receives a subgrant under this subsection may use the subgrant funds (by providing scholarship funds or through other means) to pay for the professional development (on-site or off-site) for educators who are or seek to become STEM educators, and otherwise to enable the educators to participate in the professional development by paying for the staff time of educators to participate in the professional development, paying to hire substitute staffers for the time the educators are at the professional development, paying for the time and resources needed for the educators to share and implement the professional development (in appropriate cases) with program colleagues, and paying for any travel costs associated with the professional development.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e54ca438bd7498fb6420e6265bba4dc"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Professional development content</header><text>The content for the professional development for out-of-school time educators who are or seek to become STEM educators may include any professional development tailored to the out-of-school time educator and STEM facilitation that the program and educator identify as necessary and relevant to the educator's professional growth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6bf87ab98ab44c9a09242e7c43e1729"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>A recipient of a grant or subgrant under this section may use not more than 15 percent of the grant funds or subgrant funds, respectively, for administrative costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b2cd1ccd6b94f99a10837d1b4a4fcbb"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Reporting</header><subparagraph id="id4f2a70c4b9054fa2b2db5c712e0ab5d3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id771dfc892adb487d985f3af5573e0a84"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Program providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of each year throughout the period of the grant, each program provider that receives a subgrant under this Act—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0bb715d732d94368869decfd97aed29e"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall evaluate the professional development activities carried out through the subgrant on—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id834a9cd1195f4926991bdb8c4eccb756"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree of change in educator confidence in implementing or facilitating the implementation of STEM programs;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8588c285b5f248e4ba2a863989ac3a2c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the degree of integration of the knowledge received by the educators through those activities into their out-of-school time programs; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e9eac694f1043c388eded421563336a"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>student and parent satisfaction with the STEM component of the resulting programs;</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ed58efad71d44f88786682621681d1b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may evaluate the professional development activities on additional indicators to measure the effectiveness of the professional development in the context of the provider's out-of-school time program, such as indicators relating to—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e90222754464ddc90194a5c27fe7a15"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the relevancy of that STEM component to skills that prepare students for the workforce and improve their everyday life;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1b22d6c9d4f46c3a0131e4963413f76"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree of integration of the STEM knowledge received by students with content knowledge received by students during the school day; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida17a1b97edec4378b2eba8848d24ea68"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree to which the knowledge is enabling students to become aware of STEM occupations and the relevance of STEM content in nontraditional STEM occupations; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b539595d8314749ba91963fef797473"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall prepare a report containing the results of the evaluation under this clause, and submit the report to the intermediary that made the subgrant.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida974dc9b0541407c90e1b0302ff45b4a"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Intermediaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The intermediary shall prepare and submit to the Secretary a report summarizing the program provider reports received under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b4782e758ed4fb0967230dbf3e40b5f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final reports</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcab4bbef54aa4f3fa15fb1487d7e947b"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program providers</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81ba9949fd314031a7f368420ccf1c1e"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Indicators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of the 5-year grant period, each program provider that receives a subgrant under this Act shall evaluate the professional development activities carried out through the subgrant on—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4530d4e8770747468584032f33dc294f"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage change in the number of students (disaggregated by age level) attending the provider's program;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9c2e4b1dcc146be90dd0a2f2d609c5a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the percentage, of the educators who were beneficiaries of funds for professional development under this subsection, who were retained by the provider;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf27a4fbb369f4342b4046386f69ff532"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the percentage, of all educators, who were retained by the provider;</text></item><item id="ida57d4ead7ab14945a78c13d2953f25ce"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the percentage, of the educators who were beneficiaries of funds for professional development under this subsection, who obtained additional STEM credentials or certifications described in paragraph (4)(B); and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3c17b8d7eb24c13801d8b553bd0414e"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the percentage of students of such educators who leave the provider’s out-of-school time program with an increased engagement in a STEM subject or desire to pursue a career in a STEM subject.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id416b92849fec4a0cb05296cd41404c74"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Measurement</header><text>In measuring the indicators described in subclause (I), the program provider shall use methods that may include student, parent, and educator surveys, Youth Program Quality Assessments, and longitudinal tracking.</text></subclause><subclause id="id248d632a48e34ab298d3472732979127"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The program provider shall prepare a report containing the results of the evaluation under this clause and submit the report to the intermediary that made the subgrant.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida352e41fd55d41e6817da5a598022e8a"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Intermediaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The intermediary shall prepare and submit to the Secretary a report summarizing the program provider reports received under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide5bd6d63df32453fb55173f0a389991e"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Centralized statewide support structures</header><text>Each intermediary that receives a grant under this Act shall use the grant funds to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fafe258b94749798af18977d024ab94"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a centralized database of professional development opportunities for out-of-school time educators (including virtual opportunities, opportunities to bring professional development onsite, and national opportunities, as appropriate); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda1d620fa57a49aeba0bbfa2cf68a2f9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate peer-to-peer networks between out-of-school time educators who are or seek to become STEM educators, and STEM education experts through the establishment of an electronic portal, community events, and other means.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b234316287c42a1a87754769529411a"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="idbd7cbf7b434641c994e9250612f8e1cb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of each year throughout the period of the 5-year grant, each intermediary that receives a grant under this section shall submit a report to the Secretary regarding the progress achieved through the activities carried out under the grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1a7485dcb3644869475f2efb84b98f6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final reports</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9de6e383d3fb4f7a936f3aa4cf771173"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Preparation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the end of the 5-year grant period, each intermediary that receives a grant under this Act shall prepare a report that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59e0d96ccdd84c39b946709e30e56501"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">summarizes the evaluations submitted to the intermediary under subsection (e)(8);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc94bd374810642809fa929fbf55f64ad"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes best practices for accessing professional development in STEM education for program provider educators;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95d68ebe096842288315071546b2f8bf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the use of funds under the grant; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb49a88857c324a8780f20ab959bd990a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the short-term and long-term impact, of providing professional development opportunities, on the program provider educators that received the professional development, on the students in the programs of the program providers, and on the programs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4fa0e56e3a6436ea8ff79a3fb3e63ab"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The intermediary shall submit the report to the Secretary, who shall make the report publicly available.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd768cd241e264c259c1539b21faad70a"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

