<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9ED143D026514CA7A953F4D314378D3C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6704 IH: Drunk Driving Prevention and Enforcement Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6704</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251215">December 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a competition to accelerate vehicle integration of passive, anti-drunk driving technology, with a cash prize awarded to an entity that demonstrates technology that is ready for integration into passenger motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA6BC3A10358E4A849F3B5DB1099A1C67" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9E96FF93CEFE4DB49644D2307B15B365" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drunk Driving Prevention and Enforcement Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H43BF52BB111448468FE75F188E520FE5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H67BDAAA9251B4534B59D850B61336655"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB5501262B6DA4181B7BFBB949F874C10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Alcohol-impaired driving is a leading cause of death and injury on our nation's roadways, with more than 12,000 people killed every year and hundreds of thousands seriously injured in drunk driving crashes annually. These deaths and injuries are 100 percent preventable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7415A6AF8D2C4CF288E7E589DD507980"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress has directed the integration of passive, advanced anti-drunk driving in-vehicle technology into all new passenger motor vehicles under Section 24220 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB741A3252DB64639886B38593A27B2B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accelerated deployment are needed to bring forward passive, consumer-ready vehicle-integrated technologies designed to prevent drunk driving.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5802198CDDCA4F24853BA90EBC957425"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Public-private innovation prize competitions have proven effective in spurring rapid advancements and breakthroughs in science, engineering, safety and technology.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H01FD94988481434B9623652B38D89876"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to establish a competitive prize award program to incentivize deployment of effective, passive, anti-drunk driving technology that is consumer-ready for integration into passenger motor vehicles.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HEBCA4CA744DC4EF0AA4316C1A4626F2C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of prize competition</header> <subsection id="HFCC11A5D3FA8491C81E50F7C14658B52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall carry out a program on a competitive basis to award a cash prize that the Secretary determines is appropriate to recognize outstanding achievement in the development of passive, advanced anti-drunk driving technology to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7AA5E2E15E744D26A14C20C1F9C14E15"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement the adoption of breath-based, touch-based, or other sensor technology to prevent drivers with a blood alcohol concentration at or above the legal limit from operating a vehicle; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47C5DC053CE946548CF281612DBFC540"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>install consumer-ready, passive, advanced anti-drunk driving technologies in vehicles to eliminate drunk driving.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFBFC15AA8E1C48E1BDB3D6B379D61E70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Competition requirements</header><text>The program established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0C2D86FCB84A455DA738D6C8BF77BE69"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use a competitive process for the selection of a recipient of a cash prize;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC8080FA15B24BD68111ED932971585A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>include the widely advertised solicitation of submissions;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H609214361FA140AB886AC28A5EE2F9A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make available a prize purse of not less than $45,000,000 to be awarded to the winner of the competition who is able to demonstrate consumer-ready, passive, advanced anti-drunk driving technology for vehicle integration; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDBFE2B962244C7194FC361D4D56FBBF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be open to individuals, private sector entities, nonprofit organizations, academic institutions, and consortia thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H83266F43BBF24CB2AC1021F52FA354B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to other authority</header><text>The program established under subsection (a) may be carried out in conjunction with, or in addition to, the exercise of any other authority of the Department of Transportation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC247F68C48849BE87238322FE6E45CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of carrying out this Act, including the prize purse, administration, evaluation, and outreach, there is authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) $50,000,000 to remain available until expended, except that such amount may not be expended after the last day of fiscal year 2028.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBA68DF9AFAC046C9827A0C7AE85A4B87"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Congressional notice</header> <paragraph id="HCC5890AB224748CCBEAF468D089C263E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after a cash prize has been awarded under this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee of Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate written notice of such award.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5267A85B05D942FDA0124EDEACD81992"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each notice submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA6CD07CFFA54BBBA99B511F54357711"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the technology development for which the cash prize was awarded;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75B21FCDF90443419D9DA2FFDDD2092F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the outcomes and benefits that the competition winner anticipates generating; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2C1B3B379654B02B05D4940AE18474E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for further accelerating deployment of anti-drunk driving technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C7CC940C24F4A17A806D60303F5AE9B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee of Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that contains—</text> <paragraph id="H6C363F4A1B264671BDB53A4977FF87A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>details on the results of the program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6795D07331B74378A9D1317975A5B808"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional steps the Department can take to ensure vehicle integration continues at a rapid pace, including through implementation of section 24220 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC50EFA6963F14948A68B5DCF3EF92332"><enum>4.</enum><header>NHTSA Traffic Safety Enforcement Center of Excellence</header> <subsection id="HF87D085C8D91482BB325B5C051E59D6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a Traffic Safety Enforcement Center of Excellence within the Department of Transportation, to provide leadership and technical assistance to States and law enforcement agencies to maximize efficient and effective ways to conduct traffic safety enforcement of hazardous driving behaviors with the goal to reduce fatalities and injuries on the roads of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5C1CFE400D94612B3E681CF11F6A836"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Traffic Safety Enforcement Center of Excellence established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H62913807B74E4CC4B47C709EF69FD9EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve as a central location within the Department of Transportation for expertise in traffic safety enforcement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1283CCEA138E4DE08D8F2CC6E3FDB1F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide State highway safety offices and law enforcement agencies across the country with centralized expertise, tools, and support;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC900FA7BA9024CAFBF1A0FBBD4AFD5C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote evidence-based strategies on what works in hazardous driving behavior enforcement, including targeted, cost-effective drunk-driving patrols, speed enforcement best practices, and coordinated traffic safety campaigns proven to reduce roadway fatalities and injuries;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H398A93A31C7F46B2ADA3B598281BEC7D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish best-practice protocols for enforcement operations, with the goal of improving outcomes based on data and research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67E01F5B37DE48A8B6773619B351403E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop and deliver standardized training on the use of data for hot spot detection, drug-impaired driving enforcement strategies, speed management, and other risk mitigation of death and injury on public roads;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4209CB9524942EA8377300CE59E8875"><enum>(6)</enum><text>assist States and agencies in using real-time data systems to identify high-crash corridors and target enforcement resources in the most efficient ways;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAF9F86E247F4D06B02572CEC30FF154"><enum>(7)</enum><text>help agencies assess current enforcement practices and identify gaps;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7927B9CB8674E86B3E5837271DE9573"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide recommendations for hazardous driving behavior enforcement plans based on crash data and local context;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C9D37AFAC934DB9826FB4BC7C344D01"><enum>(9)</enum><text>assist agencies in using limited resources more efficiently through data-driven deployment and risk-based enforcement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6A9D134DC7B3404FA098A3CE18BF83A5"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help States fully leverage programs under sections 402 and 405 of title 23, United States Code, by providing technical assistance on program development and design and outcome measurement tools;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9774AC432C4A467587E3E4E48D5B4A78"><enum>(11)</enum><text>launch model demonstration projects in States or cities to test new roadside technologies, data-driven deployment models, new enforcement strategies (such as those targeting drug-impaired driving), and share results nationally to help with the adoption of effective tools;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF6D33E84DDB4F4E93A9DEDDB52689AC"><enum>(12)</enum><text>serve as a national convener for State highway safety offices, law enforcement agencies, traffic safety researchers, victims and survivors, and public health and traffic safety leaders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFEDB7C759A0430FAFE79BB1C2311473"><enum>(13)</enum><text>collaborate with, and provide support on, traffic safety enforcement to all operating administrations of the Department of Transportation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE06D308BFBF3433492656EDD7FCF5433"><enum>(14)</enum><text>have a workforce composed of Department of Transportation employees, including direct hires or detailees from o<!---->perating administrations of the Department of Transportation, Department of Justice, and other Federal agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H063AA1EFF0784C9884A400E7F848D906"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The Traffic Safety Enforcement Center of Excellence shall not supersede laws or regulations granting certification authorities to Operating Administrations of the Department of Transportation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50797FFDDE8A499ABB5EF351526DAB9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on staffing needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall report to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee of Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on staffing needs and the staffing plan for the Traffic Safety Enforcement Center of Excellence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6164F4597C224B1CB02165D7094C3D06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD48E610408D64CE5A8CF7142E4337223"><enum>5.</enum><header>National drug involved crash data collection system</header> 
<subsection id="H98F290E56EFE4918ABD1D93ABE75A1A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to track and analyze the role of drugs in serious injury and fatal traffic crashes, supporting enforcement, prevention, and research.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H00CFF5AA29A84F849AD226DE08FF4F82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC44E284FE13A41418DB573172F6CF78B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Drug involved crash</header><text>The term <quote>drug involved crash</quote> means a crash causing serious injury or death in which 1 or more drivers test positive for impairing substances other than alcohol.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H998C9CDFD06649E5AFC5D3F4FE34DE19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Impairing substance</header><text>The term <quote>impairing substance</quote> means prescription, over-the-counter, controlled, or illicit psychoactive drugs affecting driving.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE30843C050546CA9C790F39775F708D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7F52252D82BA4FB8AA83B773EBE5DB52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall establish a national drug involved crash data collection system to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8141593C748C486A8A45352435D216C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect standardized toxicology data from States for fatal and serious injury crashes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA761DF24C6E945A287EDBC83DBD783BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">link crash data with medical, coroner, hospital, and emergency medical services records;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E108C72E2104B37932A9FCA5C8EC990"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide model protocols for specimen collection, testing, and reporting;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H778A7E0CA403490E82CB63587ECB74F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>operate sentinel sites in multiple States to pilot enhanced data collection; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46A5D2EDAD064F1383EDB21AABCB787C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>report annually to Congress and the public on trends, substance types, and geographic patterns.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF692976B259441EDA767EFF815860733"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State grants</header> <paragraph id="HA79D75E6AEE342678B24B23FD8EBF99A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may award grants to States for toxicology labs, specimen collection, training, data systems, and data linkage.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46D380809D974DC192A74525D6FD84BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall prioritize States that contain high-fatality, rural, or underserved areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59726106DC494FFAB8E3CACCD28F1CBB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-Federal funds</header><text>The Administrator may require a non-Federal match from a State to be eligible for a grant under this subsection unless the State demonstrates hardship.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3609E8CD92C943BF9E9917F967168EB8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation timeline</header> 
<paragraph id="HA1A37ED7C45D48B488836DB2FF60D049"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Model protocols</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall publish the model protocols required under subsection (c)(3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B90D19276FB4B9F88DF8F7DA6A6B997"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sentinel sites</header><text>The Administrator shall ensure that the sentinel sites required under subsection (c)(3) are operational not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46BBD3C966FD4E9DBCDE7A5529047F62"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that the system established under this section has begun collecting standardized toxicology data from States for fatal and serious injury crashes beginning not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8647531AFE7B48B0AAAED8B5D65F785F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Privacy protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any data made available to the public pursuant to this section shall be deidentified before and used in compliance with Federal and State privacy laws, including the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/191">Public Law 104–191</external-xref>), as applicable.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0EDF5384CE2A4DE1A4EB126D7AEAB2D8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

