<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB3A58D881BD5457C8F40B46BDB6AC5A5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1079 IH: Recognizing the significance of Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease and the need for robust funding of the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke at the National Institutes of Health.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1079</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the significance of Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease and the need for robust funding of the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke at the National Institutes of Health.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease (CMT) causes damage to the peripheral nerves, which transmit information and signals from the brain and spinal cord to the rest of the body, and can also directly affect the nerves that control the muscles;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that 126,000 individuals in the United States have CMT and 2,600,000 people worldwide;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas nearly all cases of CMT are inherited;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the specific gene that causes CMT has not yet been identified;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are many different types of CMT, including CMT4B3; and</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, despite its impact, Federal funding for CMT research was actually less in 2022 than in 2021: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5E78956EEDB34102A5DB1D70DCDD3984"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H19F7B8E561A34A1B924DA35A91F82446"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H5043B4BD8F15432297E2051FD6130264"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes that Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease is a significant disease impacting thousands of Americans and millions around the world;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4BE77B395D8497EBF753C9CDEE08F5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses that Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease should receive robust funding for research to ensure all is being done to study this disease at the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke within the National Institutes of Health; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD1FD15304A047DC812CC091553B68A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses the need to continue to invest in research efforts to tackle Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease and other rare diseases that currently have no cure.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

