<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H878A098485FF41FDABDE9F66EA323F48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7252 IH: Restoring Community Trust Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7252</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H56486B17EBAF4805A13ECBC85AF6C6BB" style="OLC"><section id="H81C0133F11EA4FE29760B3CE37BC8A72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Community Trust Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC5AC330BB0A94CC2B1BC385D2450BF6D"><enum/><header>Repeal of communication between government agencies and the immigration and naturalization service<editorial/></header><subsection id="H1295C55BB01C47EEA3EAB487595AA816"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H13C2E76669BC4A0F8A58035C77F38F3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Constitution clearly establishes a system of dual sovereignty in which the Federal Government and the States retain distinct and independent spheres of authority, including primary responsibility for the organization, administration, and supervision of State and local government employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA112A6C6EF904FEBAD9A14FDCE208966"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>Under Supreme Court precedent, including New York v. United States (1992), Printz v. United States (1997), and Murphy v. NCAA (2018), the Federal Government may not compel States or political subdivisions to administer or enforce Federal regulatory programs. It also may not prohibit States from controlling their internal governmental operations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC73F861B985541AA89890471C264154F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>) threatens the ability of State and local governments to establish policies governing the receipt, use, and disclosure of information by their own public institutions, intruding into areas of traditional State and local authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95887426BD29474C98C7599700F4BCE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State and local governments have a substantial interest in fostering trust between residents and public institutions, including law enforcement, to promote public safety, emergency response, and community engagement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6211EBFFAA74802A5D503E119F742C1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Many interactions between individuals and State or local agencies occur for purposes completely unrelated to Federal immigration enforcement, and information sharing in such contexts may undermine the effectiveness of those governmental functions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H488CD9AA0BDA4B2F8542A113076612D6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Federal Government retains exclusive authority over civil immigration enforcement and possesses independent tools and resources to enforce Federal immigration law without trying to regulate State or local governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88B9194D034B4860AFDCC649CBBBA3B8"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A repeal of section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>) would not limit the Federal Government’s authority to enforce Federal immigration law or to obtain information through means otherwise authorized by law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE105EE4A7DD46758AD9F3A3B5CF4A4E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>) has generated legal uncertainty and litigation concerning its constitutionality and its interaction with Federal grant programs, imposing administrative and financial burdens on State and local governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B531DE32C8242A0A4873301C8DB1CF9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Effective governance is best achieved when responsibility for Federal law enforcement remains with Federal authorities and responsibility for State and local government remains with State and local officials accountable to their residents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE18501ABBE54D3DB3C10E855DDEEA3F"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of repealing section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>) is to restore constitutional balance, reduce legal ambiguity, and respect State and local control over internal governmental operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E12F2326257439D91AC646FF46A61EF"> <enum>(11)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit or restrict any State or unit of local government from communicating, cooperating, or sharing information with a Federal immigration authority, consistent with applicable State or local law or otherwise limit the authority of the Federal Government to enforce the immigration laws (as such term is defined under section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5AC4D7F397FD439394544B4934F2DA0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

