<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL26113-D3H-7D-8V8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3829 IS: Corporate Crimes Against Health Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3829</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prevent exploitative private equity practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corporate Crimes Against Health Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc1a0119d1274e6cb0f818483325579b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unjust enrichment clawback authority and criminal penalty</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e6ecc8fee8c4c5aa69dda3e7ed789ea"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unjust enrichment clawback</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/31">Chapter 31</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4A841A696ACC4E9EA4ED72A4FD4B6C33"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf478f9d6f8c4491eb5a027b14c7f30a7"><enum>671.</enum><header>Unjust enrichment clawback and criminal penalty</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde39f44e744543af894aae3b6ed87343"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>covered party</quote>, <quote>target firm,</quote> and <quote>triggering event</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 674(b).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11c16a5c1a1e4ed58dd1dd3829bb8698"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibited conduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered party whose actions contributed to a triggering event that results in the death or injury of a patient or patients under the care of the target firm, shall be punished in accordance with sections 672 and 673.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2050ba0ff91146bd9cf4812b2fdd30c8"><enum>672.</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Whoever violates section 671(b) shall be imprisoned for not less than 1 year or greater than 6 years.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12cbbeff19274ddbba7297e4c6700e5e"><enum>673.</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5096f10d9ed4dedbdc48ae03413f747"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amount of penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever violates section 671(b) shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount of not more than 5 times the amount of any clawback authorized under section 674.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16d2553f71e742c9bad96c46b4f01d27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text>Any amount of civil penalty collected under this section shall be deposited as miscellaneous receipts in the Treasury of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68bc28daafd549668a945bd0863747d3"><enum>674.</enum><header>Clawback</header><subsection id="id6f0aebd6735d4195a4b60ba0ca84f243"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id208f252d51d94ca3a368fab333a4e8cd"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any covered party to acquire from a target firm covered compensation by unjust enrichment, and any such covered party shall be subject to the penalties described in sections 672 and 673 in addition to the required clawbacks under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac5f7faf16f94339a55b3e6114107e01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><subparagraph id="id39026eaef1364889b21429d52e43e88c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required clawbacks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a target firm experiences a triggering event, the Attorney General or a State attorney general may claw back all or part of the covered compensation received by the covered party that is obtained from the target firm during the preceding or succeeding 10 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb95e73aebe64f2aa0377f661e50e76f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Actions to recover required clawbacks</header><clause id="idc7f51ea67b694abb9d0033c09f9337c2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Powers of the Attorney General</header><subclause id="idd93ce3a7e0624191a38ff8907d9e927f"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the Attorney General may enforce this section.</text></subclause><subclause id="idadf0e6cceb2e4ea5afc892bb421e7792"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Attorney General under any provision of law.</text></subclause><subclause id="id27e0487d15a14043baeafb26f0824c30"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>In an action brought by the Attorney General to enforce this section and the regulations promulgated under this section, a covered party shall be liable for all or part of the covered compensation received by the covered party that is obtained from the target firm during the preceding or succeeding 10 years.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id8dc306998529456081eb9ca45aeea3a7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Enforcement by State attorneys general</header><subclause id="id13889ba65cf04ae1b90cf7aa72caa341"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>If an attorney general of a State has reason to believe that a triggering event has harmed the residents of that State, the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to recover all or part of the covered compensation received by the covered party that is obtained from the target firm during the preceding or succeeding 10 years.</text></subclause><subclause id="id4999dbdd118e4999ba9065c6f4b4ff12"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Rights of the Attorney General</header><item id="id163e220c335f486fb94cd419f2616430"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Notice to Attorney General</header><subitem id="id1ad1cc99fc064ee8aa5884ee8c166e18"><enum>(AA)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subitem (CC), the attorney general of a State shall notify the Attorney General in writing that the attorney general of the State intends to bring a civil action under subclause (I) not later than 10 days before initiating the civil action.</text></subitem><subitem id="id39d587c0a2334e3aadafda1b18dcbb4b"><enum>(BB)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required under subitem (AA) with respect to a civil action shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></subitem><subitem id="id1527b00cc9404eb89c1b05ab3517cb4c"><enum>(CC)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required by subitem (AA) before initiating an action under subclause (I), the attorney general of the State shall notify the Attorney General immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></subitem></item><item id="id5d27b8718b364109a2f16b5bb3623b16"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Intervention by the Attorney General</header><text>The Attorney General may—</text><subitem id="id9593681d3c86448bb3ea6fd9af1f491b"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>intervene in any action brought by the attorney general of a State under subclause (I); and</text></subitem><subitem id="idfb44b602571943d2b82fd57df12c01cb"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>upon intervening under subitem (AA), be heard on all matters arising in the civil action and file petitions for appeal of a decision in the action.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idb2b48297cb994abca86d57791d83195d"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text>If the Attorney General institutes an action under clause (i) with respect to a triggering event, a State may not, during the pendency of that action, institute an action under clause (ii) against any defendant named in the complaint in the action instituted by the Attorney General based on the same set of facts giving rise to the triggering event with respect to which the Attorney General instituted the action.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07c34332063c4982b4ba9cd7db2ea601"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text>It shall be an affirmative defense in an action under this section if the applicable covered party shows by clear and convincing evidence that the covered party could not prevent the triggering event.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa2fa397e83b4e99b3efa58fdd7b3054"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deposit</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f5fc6f85e364717aef65413dfb965ca"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), any covered compensation clawed back in an action under this section shall be deposited in a fund created by the Attorney General and distributed by the Attorney General, in the interests of justice—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd6f5aa7dae74118b69f4ed84897ea0e"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to cover shortfalls in the salaries, employee benefit plans, or other benefits owed to current or past employees of the target firm negatively affected by the behavior that is the basis of the action; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf22edc93bd1f40dbba8082f53e975a6d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to be put to use in the interest of serving the health care needs of the harmed community.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id487c386c7bbf4b749ca5103915fb52a5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Bankruptcy as a triggering event</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the entry of an order for relief under title 11 or the commencement of any other insolvency proceeding is the triggering event that a target firm experiences, the Attorney General shall prioritize covering funding shortfalls in any pension funds benefitting harmed current or past employees of the target firm.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d1ed2c7b4e646e4ad7e11bc6f18e403"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="ida5efed11e88748618b17f8d225a189e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text>The term <term>affiliate</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id06a5d4c6381f4de0a3b9027156a92ea6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a person that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with power to vote, 5 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities of another entity, other than a person that holds such securities—</text><clause id="id562e6460c1d74f54b85e30c44b823a33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a fiduciary or agency capacity without sole discretionary power to vote such securities; or</text></clause><clause id="idaa5298bf67bc4cc19662bbac70a57840"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>solely to secure a debt, if such entity has not in fact exercised such power to vote;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18c2bfd53f984ca2ab0ea79831be217f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a corporation 10 percent or more of whose outstanding voting securities are directly or indirectly owned, controlled, or held with power to vote, by another entity (referred to in this subparagraph as a <quote>covered entity</quote>), or by an entity that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with power to vote, 10 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities of the covered entity, other than an entity that holds such securities—</text><clause id="id8274c161ced34d18b6584440a3bfee4b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a fiduciary or agency capacity without sole discretionary power to vote such securities; or</text></clause><clause id="idc14a9bfe59ba47d98396aaa9415fbed2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>solely to secure a debt, if such entity has not in fact exercised such power to vote;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided5dd0dec2f04131b8c09ebd84dcfb2f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a person whose business is operated under a lease or operating agreement by another entity, or person substantially all of whose property is operated under an operating agreement with that other entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95a99cf5b78443aaafd4d7932ae66a8c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity that operates the business or substantially all of the property of another entity under a lease or operating agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide9db789e4f2e49c7afa0d044a7c474c3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Change in control</header><text>The term <term>change in control</term> means a change in a legal right with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="id011e00d572e7489ea5a93e4ae8661b3c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the power to vote more than 50 per centum of any class of voting securities of a corporation that engages in interstate commerce; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf119236ff93540579d51403635463a89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any lesser per centum of any class of voting securities of a corporation that engages in interstate commerce that is sufficient to make the acquirer of such an interest a person that has the ability to direct the actions of that corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id71df990937f54a3897a864e5cfc23173"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Control person</header><text>The term <term>control person</term>—</text><subparagraph id="idacd7f00592d54e109be7edf1cc8a58c4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text><clause id="id5cc351ea769944e3882c3b9ab23e20cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a person—</text><subclause id="id0c632d5e6c70400c802c0cc951901c99"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with power to vote, including through coordination with other persons, 10 percent or more of the outstanding voting interests of a corporation; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idefb01909dbc04a019710473fc5ae710b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that operates the business or substantially all of the property of a corporation under a lease or an operating or management agreement;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf333ed10c256480a90e024f1b5197d01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a corporation, other than a target firm, that has 10 percent or more of its outstanding voting interests directly or indirectly owned, controlled, or held with power to vote by a person that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with power to vote, including through coordination with other persons, 10 percent or more of the outstanding voting interests of another corporation; or</text></clause><clause id="id63ea0d685cc5456c86a2884d34525683"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a person that otherwise has the ability to direct the actions of a corporation; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7f4e739290e4ffa89baa80b1c6ba5cc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a person that—</text><clause id="idad1a2b9c255743fabd128228a19349ef"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4bf9413554ba47a698a679bdce676a01"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is a limited partner with respect to a controlling private fund that is a partnership;</text></subclause><subclause id="idb5ab4467d2fd43b6bb909d145ad46e31" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not participate in the direction of the management or policy of a corporation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7f5f5bb7a857466cb5958d0b2f10db50" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is not an insider with respect to the controlling private fund described in subclause (I);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id9eadc3c4aa2a470999dfa4a240fd9207"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a pension fund or employee welfare benefit plan, if neither the fund nor plan (as applicable), nor any beneficiary or affiliate of the benefit or plan, is an insider with respect to a controlling private fund; or</text></clause><clause id="id0db2c4e952a9474683feab303915799b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>holds the voting interests of a corporation solely—</text><subclause id="idb7831b1598554725889b1ad4085259c2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in a fiduciary or agency capacity without sole discretionary power to vote the securities; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id74d3390a9b94476385529cae40383ee0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to secure a debt, if the person has not—</text><item id="id8831a5fe5e6d400bbe43f50b95dd1297"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>exercised the power to vote; or</text></item><item id="idb7f36bd042b84eacb816d23215f229ec"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>exercised any other governance rights with respect to the corporation.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida703deec41804162917d798cd949f81b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Controlling private fund</header><text>The term <term>controlling private fund</term> means a private fund that, directly or through an affiliate, becomes a control person with respect to a target firm through the change in control transaction with respect to the target firm.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id219535bb23e24522931a6585e9d47c00"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Corporation</header><text>The term <term>corporation</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id595efbc324dd408b9d08c9c3eb133db1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a joint-stock company;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fb98d7d6f5f453596c4836bc71db54b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a company or partnership association organized under a law that makes only the capital subscribed or callable up to a specified amount responsible for the debts of the association, including a limited partnership and a limited liability company;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bb8bcbf79f943c6821cf531ed19836b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a trust; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddce4704a6563450eab4b9366d536e42d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an association having a power or privilege that a private corporation, but not an individual or a partnership, possesses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idae9b1d4ff38f4ae3bbf1c035ae5cf0ac"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered compensation</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb568d8a9e26403caf25c3875982575d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">salary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id980507f9fb4a446fa4a8f08f8c45912a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any bonus;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id159b07ed442a4a5ba6f356abf005f40f"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any compensation that is granted, earned, or vested based wholly or in part upon the attainment of any financial reporting measure or other performance metric;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36b09fcb54fd4b24b65fc832eb650367"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">equity-based compensation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30d58ec84a0c4666a9c6c73807051a5d"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">time- or service-based awards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc96bfaa3c8a4002ba4d49689e59febd"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">awards based on nonfinancial metrics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe79ae953b2b44dc924b1309cebf67fe"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any monitoring fees, management fees, advisory fees, accelerated monitoring fees, transaction fees, or fees for services not rendered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida253be6875484add9a8148e6c36a9cbb"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any profits realized from the buying or selling of securities or assets, including any real property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id850df78c6b224383a8ac8fcc5e6ebe97"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any severance pay;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b7bca04c15e4fc9b7860c9f9b8925b9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any golden parachute benefit; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb193a88cf2724b23a2ae01307b28157c"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other transaction similar to a transaction described in subparagraph (H) or (I).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6715035fbca64b5098325ab3fdd4d8c8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Covered party</header><text>The term <term>covered party</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0f4f951b1f44802a70bc7b412f76253"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any current or former director, officer, or control person of, or agent for, a private equity firm or target firm;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8bfe58b65a448e883246d9f77a1934f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any current or former shareholder or joint venture partner that participates in the conduct of the affairs of a target firm; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1b87a959a5340dd82481af06dc7928f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any private fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6603a3a83cd84ebbb5ca5d8f505cffe1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Employee welfare benefit plan</header><text>The term <term>employee welfare benefit plan</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4bc62d5b055241bbbcd516b9706345fc"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Insider</header><text>The term <term>insider</term> means any—</text><subparagraph id="id0f73aed3bd5c4d58a17e13655d2d625e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>director of a corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6f9ce34807245c59795ea9350b8fc4a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>officer of a corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9d79f5a1bde45cc8a0c5baa8f535f36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>managing agent of a corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba51c86101314c2881cee7bc59b46c2f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>control person with respect to a corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3a2242dce354cbfbe76782e3777acb7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>affiliate of a corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f6e773a7a6d45e4b02bfb8dea404d50"><enum>(F)</enum><text>general partner of a corporation that is a partnership;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54bc6d9b977d4d769679a47e4d6895f3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>consultant or contractor retained by a corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86a198e1af134b63b2fdc57ddd808343"><enum>(H)</enum><text>affiliate, relative, or agent of a person described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (F); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id517d60da3a774b02b02e6a0d8ea32adf"><enum>(I)</enum><text>affiliate, relative, or agent of a person described in subparagraph (H).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id60fea63bb7944530ab936d3f23e8d9a9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Interest coverage</header><text>The term <quote>interest coverage</quote> means the revenue of the target firm less the expenses of the target firm, excluding tax and interest, during the most recent fiscal year of the target firm.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc575d08901a447a2b11ddcdd615690f1"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Pension fund</header><text>The term <term>pension fund</term> has the meaning given the term <term>pension plan</term> in section 3 of the Employee Retirement Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93948fc792774be49a8673ef301d78d8"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Private fund</header><text>The term <term>private fund</term> means a corporation that—</text><subparagraph id="id9f81e46ce80f4693b354fcde47aa961e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would be considered an investment company under section 3 of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-3">15 U.S.C. 80a–3</external-xref>) but for the application of paragraph (1) or (7) of subsection (c) of that section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8650efe3303c4684a076c785c546e33d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a venture capital fund, as defined in section 275.203(l)–1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddbb285e7139d42cb840102bdbd11e0b8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not an institution selected under section 107 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4706">12 U.S.C. 4706</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ede6793c088482ca52e2038af85b252"><enum>(13)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relative</header><text>The term <term>relative</term> means an individual related by affinity or consanguinity within the third degree as determined by the common law, or individual in a step or adoptive relationship within such third degree.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda451355dc99473ba5441ddf4d05798a"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Security</header><text>The term <term>security</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2(a) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95df33fcaf654570b69a98c1ccb5b786"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Target firm</header><text>The term <term>target firm</term> means a health care corporation that is acquired in a change in control transaction.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b2def0631444ae29b9ff64a2ac62c57"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Triggering event</header><text>The term <quote>triggering event</quote> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22fd994fb7024c729e026d21f1c1d9b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any time at which a target firm is behind on salary payments greater than 25 percent of the total workforce of the target firm for a period of more than 90 days;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84ad3444f82c46cf9ffbfb3c7bb11199"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">closure of the target firm;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb49fcb312bf14566b6d430c48a1b4a6a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the target firm is behind on rent payments for a period of more than 90 days;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc040ba799c44b16824ff1693e76387a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if the target firm defaults on a loan for a period of more than 90 days; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d7639779d80481eb9910380e052cad4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the entry of an order for relief under title 11 on behalf of the target firm or the commencement of any other insolvency proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15274e19029b493db58461aec431fc02"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Unjust enrichment</header><text>The term <quote>unjust enrichment</quote> means the acquisition of covered compensation by a covered party from the target firm during the 10-year period preceding or succeeding a triggering event if any of the following aggravating circumstances are established:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75ec114cacea44759e7f7a388180d78d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The covered compensation was obtained through a dividend recapitalization, a sale-leaseback of real estate or equipment, or a related person transaction, as set forth in section 229.404 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d2e7359d0de4c55a6d79166e3d2913b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The covered party has been implicated in any white-collar crime, as defined in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>), committed in the course of the current or former employment of the covered party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a5485329f2e444eb10eb8928a4910fe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The covered party has charged the target firm accelerated monitoring fees or fees for services not rendered.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c3baf44384348da83aabdb4e28eb727"><enum>(D)</enum><text>At the time of the issuance of the covered compensation, or as the result of the issuance of the covered compensation, the target firm had an interest coverage in excess of 100 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H448583A0C1CB440BBF4390668D08FD3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76D060998D994332A804986813E40420"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">671. Unjust enrichment clawback and criminal penalty.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">672. Criminal penalty.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">673. Civil penalty.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">674. Clawback.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id253aec2a7dd044c4b83a49eb3d255e3a"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting payments from Federal health care programs to entities that sell assets to or use assets as collateral for a loan with a real estate investment trust</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1128(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25A8D7B7279E4E95B67BD81120DB36C5"><paragraph id="id9232d2ff04f44f32b1e73a1ac68b2bda"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Selling assets to or using assets as collateral for a loan with a real estate investment trust</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4ada74e185f474b8ad6dc42f3ade9d9"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Any individual or entity that, on or after the date of enactment of this paragraph, sells any assets to, or newly pledges any assets as collateral for a loan with, a real estate investment trust (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/856">section 856(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea3a978542a7445eaee744b65329c0ac"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case where an individual or entity agreed to pledge an asset as collateral for a loan with a real estate investment trust prior to the date of enactment of this paragraph, including with respect to any future agreement between the individual or entity and the real estate investment trust regarding that same asset.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id1efcb75752384c5399915850e7fcfe7a"><enum>4.</enum><header>Repeal of special rule for taxable REIT subsidiaries with interests in certain health care property</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f3a8ba82cfe41e0b877c949bc28fe9b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/856">Section 856(d)(8)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph id="idc2737a2e188b497a8b20fae47864475d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or a qualified health care property (as defined in subsection (e)(6)(D)(i))</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1e90966e5f5484da3e34f17625b46a4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>qualified health care property or</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5886e7d0a68e4babbede5249e71de2e2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 856(d)(9) of such Code is amended—</text><paragraph id="id4bf412e565d84f45a5b117050da5fe4a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph id="idaad08c907fb24916a8832d6bbfa5544e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or a qualified health care property (as defined in subsection (e)(6)(D)(i))</quote>,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id582dbc46a1184923b80f7ec42556c0a6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or qualified health care property</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39bcfaf17f6746ea89ecd6185a52ee20"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or qualified health care properties</quote>, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf462e44c9ca749b2b54930df8ef1224b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bdceede4e7b45aebfd595a97604aa8a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or qualified health care property (as so defined)</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8645331686f44454adbd99455f734952"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or qualified health care property</quote> each place it appears in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii)(II).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d1a4a86171d4c3ea08be7e2511a2e7b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="idaa3fa4229d7746dcae63f95cfdc94b69"><enum>5.</enum><header>Elimination of qualified REIT dividends from qualified business income</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id036e19413ac04c98a33a2c21cd351f5f"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/199A">section 199A(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id218663306DF742D391DDFAD6F103EE23"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79a549cfc43b488fb3b8ef9fb69d2b6d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>combined qualified business income amount</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, an amount equal to the sum of the amounts determined under paragraph (2) for each qualified trade or business carried on by the taxpayer.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4b29a5fcde844c7a8f6784af8aa27c1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc81e8e943192462a9dbba73237f4ff93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 199A(c)(1) of such Code is amended by striking the last sentence.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62bef285b3d6417380a341bf7a5ed3cb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 199A(e) of such Code is amended by striking paragraph (3) and by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b29f9b9ddd249b9bcb711bb6e72a361"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="idb80677bda8224c539cf42dcef02990e5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Mandatory reporting with respect to certain health-related ownership information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title XI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f411fcb6a2340ccab02d60499feaa79"><section id="id098b5dfbdc764754bbfc56d8ea814064"><enum>1150D.</enum><header>Mandatory reporting with respect to certain health-related ownership information</header><subsection id="ide9d821cfe1404fc5ba1a696907cd7e10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting with respect certain health-Related ownership information</header><paragraph id="id9188d8ccd42a4b1da60b54d49cc94584"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027 (or in the case of a specified entity formed after January 1, 2027, within 60 days of becoming a specified entity), and each year thereafter, each specified entity (as defined in subsection (e)(8)) shall submit to the Secretary, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, a report containing the following information, subject to paragraph (3)(B):</text><subparagraph id="id522c97df0a1e4adb96644ff77ea9d558"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Data on mergers, acquisitions, changes in ownership, changes in control, transactions to form new affiliations, changes in partnerships, joint ventures, and/or management services agreements, to which such specified entity is a party for the previous 1-year period, including—</text><clause id="id9ca9dcdf51f94e548aaf659278e6fbd5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the primary reason the reporting entity completed the acquisition; and</text></clause><clause id="id6b9d8949682c4f10bbb4a43c6362e50a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the acquirer obtained control of the acquiree, and the percentage of ownership acquired (i.e., voting equity interests).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bc3eebb7eed4c819fb57ce3b476f27b"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>As applicable, the name, address, tax or health plan identification numbers (including, without limitation, the tax identification number, National Association of Insurance Commissioners identification number, State insurance identification number, Medicare provider number, and the standard unique health identifier (as described in section 1173(b))) of all health care providers within the specified entity that furnish items or services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id038eca34327940c5b1aaa85157a585e1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The business structure of any controlling entity, including the business type and the tax identification number of such entity, other affiliates under common control, subsidiaries, and management services entities of such specified entity, as of the date of the submission of such report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7df1f5655ae44b994c1bc3639fd6af7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information regarding—</text><clause id="id3b38429d62f04474a3f7364607d5ff08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the debt-to-earnings ratio of the specified entity;</text></clause><clause id="ide812d44bb4a34f9a860ffb2bc801b442"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of debt incurred—</text><subclause id="ide328872bf48e469db93ca2b6104c0aaf"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by each hospital or separate entity within the health system; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb9b02a2d617f4a73b091afa95f98d06a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by the entire specified entity;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3e04b99e4aaa43158d50e9a6b7986904"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>real estate leases and purchases for property used, or intended to be used, to furnish or otherwise support the provision of health care services, including expenditures on rents and maintenance, property taxes paid, and the name of the company leased from;</text></clause><clause id="id0b1ac1ce7a214e64a614306a9a018b44"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>details of other companies' revenue sharing arrangement;</text></clause><clause id="idf6fed2c92c4c4890bcc0ebac6b65a6fa"><enum>(v)</enum><text>fees charged or dividends paid to investors;</text></clause><clause id="id9c2970f1e17044cb935e74a4ffe4a481"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>in the case of a non-profit hospital, a subsidiary of a non-profit hospital, or a 501(c)(3) entity that shares common ownership with a non-profit hospital, capital gains investments (disaggregated by the type of investment) and any taxes paid on such gains from such investments; and</text></clause><clause id="id0064317a94a5429e9d4853004cc6e7c1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>information with respect to any controlling entity of such specified entity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1f66ddd1bbd43c3b154e91cd794a6de"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The value of quality payments received for performance under any value-based or other performance-based program such as the shared savings program under section 1899.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2cb84c092a8d4a459ec1d6e4e68d31ea"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other information with respect to ownership or control of a specified entity, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4411f34d3b5642e9a63fcf439eee9ae3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any changes to the health care providers within the specified entity that furnish items or services during the previous 1-year period, identified by the National Provider identifier described in section 1173(b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id748d709ba89c49e599fa8a272bd2baed"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The domicile and business registration information for any controlling entity or subsidiary of such controlling entity that is domiciled outside of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f6dc53e4b894d128a2b4e77ea4c9d8f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Avoiding duplicate reporting</header><text>If a specified entity is owned or controlled by an entity described in subparagraph (G) of subsection (e)(8), only the entity described in such subparagraph (G) shall be required to submit reports under this subsection with respect to such entity and any specified entity owned or controlled by the entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f6d7c3873af4bedb7447a7aa7ceed51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of information and public reporting</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19db1b55ae6a40a495727d56435a338e"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2028, and annually thereafter, subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall post on a publicly available website of the Department of Health and Human Services the information reported under this subsection with respect to the previous 1-year period for which the information was collected.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideec99a55dffe40edbd4e81f48f739cde"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making information reported under this subsection publicly available under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall do so in a manner that does not disclose the social security number of any individual provider of services or supplier.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2798cbdea6b9464eab8e9f5b4f84cf9a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an annual audit consisting of a random sample of specified entities to verify compliance with the requirements of this section and the accuracy of information submitted pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide4ba5ebe0e454639bf6c167c5fcd4ca5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty for failure To report</header><text>If a specified entity fails to provide a complete report under subsection (a), or submits a report containing false information, such entity shall be subject to a civil monetary penalty of not more than $5,000,000 for each such report not provided or containing false information. Such penalty shall be imposed and collected in the same manner as civil money penalties under subsection (a) of section 1128A are imposed and collected under that section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfbfa15cb9bf7468780ee253599992e8c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inapplicability of paperwork reduction act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to collections of information made under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2e30d88741a14583b9c6616a9fb034c6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id8c66141d27904bccb0701cb51e034b2b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Control</header><text>The term <term>control</term> means the direct or indirect power through ownership, contractual agreement, or otherwise—</text><subparagraph id="id28a72d12e5ca45638efc8e0725e451e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to vote more than 5 percent of any class of voting securities of a specified entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf73dcc3142f741b39a4f07f70296f9b7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to direct the actions of the specified entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id05cf296dbcae483e8d3eae0bf73b4220"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Controlling entity</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd59fa9d99f7440fc8ca0ae4a56ffb0b9"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The term <term>controlling entity</term> means, with respect to any specified entity, a parent company or other entity that owns or controls the specified entity through ownership, contractual agreement, or otherwise.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8109f6606ffa4d32899d5ca4f1721b21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of REITs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term includes, with respect to a specified entity, a real estate investment trust (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/856">section 856</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) that owns property where the specified entity furnishes health care items or services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25f455679f184b98b13cbb87df67362c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health plan</header><text>The term <term>health plan</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1128C(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida776c5c1fafd4938a57bee20fae0156b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Health system</header><text>The term <term>health system</term> means a group of health care organizations (such as physician practices, hospitals, skilled nursing facilities) that are jointly owned or managed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id346587695b7948198cd1c5cedca74f6a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hospital</header><text>The term <term>hospital</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1861(e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79e55238e0e6476ab6b116e4ef8eb5ba"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Independent freestanding emergency department</header><text>The term <term>independent freestanding emergency department</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2799A–1(a)(3)(D) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde632ff4cd6e452885ad20cef59eecab"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Private fund</header><text>The term <term>private fund</term> means a corporation that—</text><subparagraph id="idd03c2c6fc2ba462e8cd0f1fc396af293"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would be considered an investment company under section 3 of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-3">15 U.S.C. 80a–3</external-xref>) but for the application of paragraph (1) or (7) of subsection (c) of such section 3;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63da79381efa4cbaa79041df8d2bea0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a venture capital fund, as defined in section 275.203(l)–1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id528f7aac7aff4c34ba0579abb6e348ef"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not an institution selected under section 107 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4706">12 U.S.C. 4706</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9384d590539a414b8156fa5fe4a524a4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Specified entity</header><text>The term <term>specified entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id72025cda4ff04350bcac90b9092ee3a3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a hospital or health system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b80a264a24546e69e2297a7e61a9ebf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a physician-owned physician practice (other than a practice described in subparagraph (C)) that is enrolled in the Medicare program under title XVIII under section 1866(j);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8fe02f7c80746cbb19c0a5fc9d19d47"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a physician practice owned, controlled, under common control, or under management agreement by a hospital, health system, a health plan, a private fund, a venture capital fund, a public or private corporation, or any subsidiaries or entities under common control thereof;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f6d153b8f3d4e23b4af5b94d53ec8da"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an ambulatory surgical center meeting the standards specified under section 1832(a)(2)(F)(i);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd847452058cb4f3897291c6654f26096"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an independent freestanding emergency department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7193aa8eb9204322bcb3febca4b0b64e"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a behavioral health treatment facility, a hospice program (as defined in section 1861(dd)(2)), a home health agency, a provider of services or renal dialysis facility that furnishes renal dialysis services, or an assisted living facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e1ac70fca474bb9831cefe735366a75"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any entity that owns or controls 1 or more specified entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a7e36bb12ae45a282a2d2573c3fb2d6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other entity specified by the Secretary that furnishes health care items and services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6d781f4577b45c8bb91df7d83447906"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Venture capital fund</header><text>The term <term>venture capital fund</term> has the meaning given such term in section 275.203(l)–1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id0579d3e9c9f248fb9ec1b47b566b5687"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on moral injury in health care</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c773c2e488c4c28a3d51c3c9b7054ce"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc09e515500eb43bc944ff3740644487e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a study that evaluates profit-driven practices, including cost-cutting practices and revenue-enhancing practices, in health care delivery; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f95cebdc5bd42879b2dce8b10ddc9d7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report describing the results of such study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id211728579fea473f86df0b937cf50684"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study conducted under subsection (a)(1) shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bea66b758174b21a5a9eb8b2a06dc1c"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of profit-driven and revenue-maximization practices in health care delivery, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78c6b57bde2a4b01bb39654a471a49ad"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">overbilling or up-coding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e3a7bb9f7a349ba8ab773c127ef6959"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inflated patient severity or patient risk scores;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75a2d78b2455491e85cbc5bbaffd1882"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">executive and provider compensation designed to increase revenue or profits, such as bonuses based on productivity, relative value units, or service volume;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c306fde9e75472b85188d4d12d445b0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reductions in staff and substitution of patient care staff with technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida866f91cdbd6495e98e16375fb1ba898"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">changes in the mix of services provided in order to maximize revenue;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id629efdc382ea4b339735a63694b664c2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>efforts by private health insurers that are designed to restrict, delay, deny, or discourage health care access services, such as prior authorization or utilization review mechanisms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ea9ebb0e1ef4ffe871e22a3579d3dec"><enum>(G)</enum><text>efforts by private health insurers, private equity firms, and other corporate entities to evade State corporate practice of medicine laws;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b9de5b0f413459293a684c0037d0415"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of the impact of such practices on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe6963e801654761a9466fd00da6e7f8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the quality, safety, and outcomes of patient care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbeeb4d4f240435f970859c2f2c284ad"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the well-being of personnel providing health care services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1421d37696074a549f71581a7954a676"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac929a95dc6e4886acf541b6d922c85a"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc08018b206e4e5f926f916bc9c8b0d5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">health care furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f636425004f43f7956975c49e148bbb"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the health insurance program carried out under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided684666ac174e419996f577199438e6"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified health plans offered through American Health Benefit Exchanges established under section 1311 or 1321 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031</external-xref>, 18041); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9038c5a08ac54be1b64c5a53b0ae5c61"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">group health plans and group and individual health insurance coverage, including managed care plans;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55ce03577a654bd7ae1188f2540035cb"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of the financial returns accruing to parties that benefit from such practices, including investors and other entities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id923990fdb5584ac281f024cff6b92057" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the adequacy of Federal policies designed to prevent and penalize health care fraud and abuse, given health care consolidation and integration, including the transparency of health care entities’ financial practices, the enforcement resources of Federal agencies, and the adequacy of financial and other penalties as deterrents.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

