<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-NEW26258-SLW-WP-84F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4715 IS: Offshore Leasing Standards and Accountability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4715</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to establish fitness to operate standards and decommissioning escrow accounts for offshore oil and gas operators, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H27450CD318FE4298918DBB0F48F7E9A9"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1026E6B769204A9D88D984A5ADE0E737"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Offshore Leasing Standards and Accountability Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1ACF47728DB240529F63FFCA0FF329E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fitness to operate standards for oil and gas operators on the outer continental shelf</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E06F5959D954258928CC6BBCA1B008D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC5F9EA1491947F38795C4F6E711485C"><section id="H46DCB7FE3EFB4881A2D851A93CF9ED02"><enum>34.</enum><header>Fitness to operate standards for offshore oil and gas activities</header><subsection id="H70405D0301304BB6B1AA58021DA771D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for approvals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date on which the Secretary issues or revises regulations under subsection (b)(5), the Secretary may not issue, extend the term of, or approve the transfer of a lease, easement, or right-of-way for oil or gas exploration, development, or production on the outer Continental Shelf with respect to a recipient responsible party unless the recipient responsible party is certified as fit to operate in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H097D3CB874A14ADBA2B675431E4CF24D"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Certification of fitness To operate</header> <paragraph id="H56DFAD2A916B4ADEBBD3D23896A1AE3C"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall certify a recipient responsible party as fit to operate based on—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HA5EC839785A64583B90E14B93F76E62B">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the past compliance of the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, with Federal, State, and local environmental and safety laws and regulations, including deadlines and requirements related to environmental reclamation, decommissioning, and worker safety;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HB262DC2684D0453C943FBE4E5A040072">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the financial solvency and capacity of the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, to weather market shocks and fulfill current and projected decommissioning liabilities; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HB32D6A7748AF42A4A14299B1C7D10E84">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other criteria with respect to the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, the Secretary may establish by regulation.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H8DD60E46791A4962B5A9C52C47EB7880">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Minimum qualifications</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not certify a recipient responsible party as fit to operate unless the recipient responsible party—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HDA3132BEA01E4F13B1750B175E6343EE">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>demonstrates, and the Secretary verifies, that—</text> <clause id="H8DFD8030F66C43DABEA067D21615E20B"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, did not violate any deadline or requirement of Federal, State, or local environmental or safety laws or regulations related to environmental reclamation, decommissioning, or worker safety during the period of 10 years ending on (as applicable) the date on which the request for certification was made or the date on which the Secretary makes an assessment under paragraph (4)(B);</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H255DC473A47C48E19ACDBC0BC85B15CB">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, are not in violation of this Act or any other Federal, State, or local environmental or safety law or regulation, including with respect to any overdue decommissioning orders for oil and gas infrastructure located on the outer Continental Shelf;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="HBAD39A84843B46C1A2CB3760EE4EAD27">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, took timely and effective corrective actions to address any worker safety incidents, oil spills, or other unauthorized pollutant discharges, and infrastructure failures or disruptions disclosed under paragraph (B)(iv);</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H70855288A9C84DEC849FDEA6D9C5F300">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, do not owe any rentals, royalties, or other fees for any Federal or State lease, easement, or right-of-way;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H782220EA35CF48FD8ACEE224EDFEAA3B">
                    <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal or State authority did not reduce the rate for royalties on oil or gas produced under any Federal or State lease held by the recipient responsible party, or any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, during the period of 10 years ending on (as applicable) the date on which the request for certification was made or the date on which the Secretary makes an assessment under paragraph (4)(B);</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H03BA5DA4FC444753967575FF32C9FE3E">
                    <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recipient responsible party, and any parent company of the recipient responsible party, possess an investment grade credit rating from a nationally recognized statistical rating organization, as such term is defined in section 3(a)(62) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H48E1E8CA19924F2AA75DD342F0E48879">
                    <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recipient responsible party, and any parent company of the recipient responsible party, have not filed a petition for bankruptcy under title 11, United States Code, during the period of 10 years ending on (as applicable) the date on which the request for certification was made or the date on which the Secretary makes an assessment under paragraph (4)(B); and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H1B7539D9132D4F6A9CE7C2C1FACB6181">
                    <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, have sufficient financial capacity to—</text>
                    <subclause commented="no" id="H1AEB171B2B6241FFBEEEF07E4F141B85">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fulfill all current and projected decommissioning liabilities, including demonstration that the liabilities disclosed under subparagraph (B)(i)(I) are fully collateralized or otherwise financially secured;</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause commented="no" id="HB34F9ADA16AB41C088917579D7F82D15">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement and maintain up-to-date risk mitigation technologies, environmental protection measures, and worker safety measures, including the use of effective blow-out preventer systems and well-control processes pursuant to the requirements specified in section 250.730 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations); and</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause commented="no" id="H0EDE793A5D0F47ED9E2E2089216FE2D7">
                      <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support a sufficient amount of staff needed for maintenance and oversight of oil and gas infrastructure on the outer Continental Shelf in accordance with environmental, health, and safety requirements; and</text>
                    </subclause>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB6C84A0870154C1FA08B3D20E1D04DC9">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides to the Secretary a disclosure of—</text>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H30299A2A116A4648A204A94F6AE3DEEF">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">current and projected decommissioning liabilities of the recipient responsible party, and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, related to all leases, easements, and rights-of-way administered by a Federal or State authority, including—</text>
                    <subclause commented="no" id="H139F7A14013843B8932749D83D1AAECF">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">domestic and global oil and gas decommissioning liabilities; and</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause commented="no" id="H98292B51F9D54CB088EB62F4FAA9FBE5">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the value of decommissioning obligations relative to the proven value of oil and gas reserves of the areas subject to such leases, easements, and rights-of-way;</text>
                    </subclause>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H62F1CCAF249C48E7B5543E6AE4B51D7C">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">past results of inspections of oil and gas infrastructure operated by the recipient responsible party and any covered entity of the recipient responsible party;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="H33B4986C9B1141C29B7F06382FEB5362">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number, length of ownership, and decommissioning status of each non-producing oil and gas well located on an area subject to a State or Federal oil and gas lease held by the recipient responsible party or any covered entity of the recipient responsible party; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" id="HF22E8C44DB3E4E30894CD7E115145010">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of worker safety incidents, oil spills or other unauthorized pollutant discharges, and infrastructure failures or disruptions that have occurred on areas subject to State and Federal oil and gas leases held by the recipient responsible party, or any covered entity of the recipient responsible party, during the period of 15 years ending on (as applicable) the date on which the request for certification was made or the date on which the Secretary makes an assessment under paragraph (4)(B).</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H5C41EDAE21D2405EB5BE3CBFBF53DDEF">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Initial request for certification</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient responsible party may request to be certified as fit to operate pursuant to the process established by regulation under paragraph (5).</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HC2D4F766DF404037943896E2A805645A">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Maintenance of certification</header>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE44D6AD2DC6F445A83F68CB69EEEC0A7">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Requirement</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification that the holder of a lease, easement, or right-of-way for oil or gas exploration, development, or production on the outer Continental Shelf issued, extended, or transferred after the date on which the Secretary issues or revises regulations under paragraph (5) is fit to operate shall be maintained in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HD5D06926258148F49B7089ADD13B4C65">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Annual compliance verification</header>
                  <clause id="HA9960F76CA714C6B9B7923FE3A76AE7F">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually assess whether each holder of a lease, easement, or right-of-way described in subparagraph (A) remains in compliance with standards established pursuant to paragraph (5).</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H99B98D77EB784740985F24B2E02DAC4C">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <header>Suspension of certification</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines under subparagraph (A) that a holder of a lease, easement, or right-of-way described in subparagraph (A) is not in compliance with the standards established pursuant to paragraph (5), the Secretary shall suspend the certification and impose one or more of the following penalties until such holder complies with such standards:</text>
                    <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline"
                      id="HA6B0F525A9A142B2A296997AF3BC12A9">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Suspend the applicable lease, easement, or right-of-way pursuant to section 5(a)(1).</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="HDD8B558B201347A29018E1E2C26C586C">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Issue fines or other civil penalties.</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="H165E8641274540BDA75A2922F8920F68">
                      <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Require supplemental financial assurance in an amount equal to the total expected cost of decommissioning.</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="H1871E237AC6E47979F1E69C12A8CA7C3">
                      <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Issue an order to the holder of the lease, easement, or right-of-way to commence decommissioning, including a requirement that such entity develop and submit a decommissioning plan pursuant to section 250.1704 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), for approval by the Secretary, and issue a notice to any previous holders of the lease, easement, or right-of-way to commence joint and several liability proceedings.</text>
                    </subclause>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="H9C73C6116EEF4EFBB68EAA85A6E0C8EA">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Regulations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue or revise regulations to—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H6E244F997DC94125BB89359E9FF763A3">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish standards which the Secretary shall use to determine whether to certify a recipient responsible party as fit to operate;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HCDEA7A21883F49A68AAE4693F329EB66">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a process for recipient responsible parties to request such certification; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2658D68F590446799B49599E1ECC42E3">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>carry out any other requirements of this section.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC809CEF1172E4B65B97D5855783E38AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the Secretary issues or revises regulations under subsection (b)(5), and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H1E2D6D2819A3467CB4BB75BDF5266316"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the most recent assessments made under subsection (b)(4)(B), including a list of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD4606A237493488E896A8258831E63D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each person that holds an active or inactive lease, easement, or right-of-way for oil or gas exploration, development, or production on the outer Continental Shelf that failed to meet any of the standards established pursuant to subsection (b)(5);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC44EB97C42AB491083CFE1A97ED6EC5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the specific standards for which the person is or was non-compliant, disaggregated by—</text><clause commented="no" id="H7FBE339E61A54B3BACCF154F647C3322"><enum>(i)</enum><text>person; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF47EA04246464912A4C9BE5E3645A5AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lease, easement, and right-of-way; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5D64B0AE57BF46B585B68D995D181B14"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enforcement actions taken by the Department of the Interior against each person identified under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE13CB0E6DF604F8E9BDB521E8D183A45"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">decommissioning cost estimates for each lease, easement, and right-of-way for oil or gas exploration, development, or production on the outer Continental Shelf, as calculated by the Secretary pursuant to section 5(k)(2), and any modifications to such estimates since the previous report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAC3A48A17ACC4E08936AC26BCD26403B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of funds currently held in each decommissioning escrow accounts established pursuant to section 5(k).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BB2BDF0FEA44679BF19211B37947F03"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to carry out the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA25FC79FCC3540BB93CD3F3256A91857"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H6497C789F4094BA787BCEF2FD01DB8E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term>, with respect to a recipient responsible party, means—</text><subparagraph id="H15DF15E0A7324C8CAA70BA531EC26077"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any parent company of the recipient responsible party;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA80F1188E8114DD0A2E167D4E0AA9C93"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any subsidiary company of the recipient responsible party;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB175FCEC97D5442A85DD4D6943A44F88"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity that the recipient responsible party enters into a contract with to construct, develop, or operate a facility on the outer Continental Shelf; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2E16CE3150240A0BCC49ED6B5340DE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity that—</text><clause id="HBDC10D2C549D4B1CA48F1229B12BA056"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shares officers, directors, or key managerial personnel with any entity specified in subparagraph (A) or (B); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H08CFE88748C540BEB0739B728EDABB23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a predecessor to any entity specified in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF67EEEC4634F93B72033D5962C03F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decommissioning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>decommissioning</term>, with respect to oil and gas infrastructure on the outer Continental Shelf, means—</text><subparagraph id="HE1A36601B7D44DD1BB908AB1A8F969F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ending oil and gas operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34B292F199E94741B98639D0E6251495"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permanently plugging all wells;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H675DE054FC0849A390FEE0559E7EE897"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitoring the efficacy of activities to end such operations, including monitoring the safety and soundness of plugged wells; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H551F290582504D5DB18CB9DA08662913"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">returning the area subject to the lease, easement, or right-of-way to a condition that meets the environmental reclamation requirements of the Department of the Interior and any other Federal agency that has jurisdiction over such operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD801C99E4FC4ADEB79F5A036C28CA8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parent company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>parent company</term> means a company that directly or indirectly controls another company.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H605840441235451EAD303FCDCFAF4D65"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recipient responsible party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recipient responsible party</term> means a person seeking the issuance, extension, or transfer of a lease, easement, or right-of-way for oil or gas exploration, development, or production on the outer Continental Shelf.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D4E1655620F4875BFE3191E8498BB69"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Subsidiary company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>subsidiary company</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H7E1674CEB7D0484F86287607F3286EFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any company that is owned or controlled directly or indirectly by another company; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H203A5022E7834AE9813853D19E7B8F3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any subsidiary of the company that is so owned or controlled.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1268FB3EA2F346608AA5A6B9D04B4FF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(b) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1334">43 U.S.C. 1334(b)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including the regulations issued or revised under section 34 relating to fitness to operate</quote> after <quote>regulations issued under this Act</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H93C77BD0B20F43488DB5BC6B1803D859"><enum>3.</enum><header>Decommissioning escrow accounts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1334">43 U.S.C. 1334</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FF9D6C55D314773AAF8A84825CD89C8"><subsection id="H1AE16C5D05E549A292CCE7B086A67F9A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Escrow account for decommissioning liability</header><paragraph id="HA5BA6C280A63416BAB1527AFE89B3926"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The holder of an oil and gas lease shall, in accordance with this subsection, make payments to an interest-bearing escrow account, established and administered by the Secretary, in order to fully meet the total cost of decommissioning the oil and gas infrastructure located on the area subject to the lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F83CF8CC5314D71A0AA7CF5035221EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decommissioning cost estimate</header><subparagraph id="H780DEE98707F4C3292AB1B79D7BC5775"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each oil and gas lease, the Secretary, or an independent third-party entity designated by the Secretary, shall calculate and periodically update a probabilistic estimate of the total cost of decommissioning existing and proposed oil and gas infrastructure, including platforms, wells, and pipelines, located on the area subject to such lease.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF4FC4ABF69F4F05A38223A8216EB2B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial estimate</header><text>The Secretary, or the independent third-party, shall calculate an initial estimate of the total costs described in subparagraph (A) prior to the issuance of a new lease.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE1CB59F282E4702B4C63EE56D745B9A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reevaluation and updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, or the independent third-party, shall reevaluate and, if necessary, update the estimate of the total costs described in subparagraph (A) at a minimum—</text><clause id="H2BA95AC006A249D48278C7944AF9A6D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less frequently than once every 2 years, to reflect any changes in such total costs;</text></clause><clause id="H72607F7A0EB54DB790A48BEB41289888"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to the approval of a development and production plan pursuant to section 25;</text></clause><clause id="HC1A33CCE8FE64AB49626C5A678BDD20F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to the end of the schedule for payments established under paragraph (3); and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FCBF2350C8649EF8DCA43FE854B061A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">following the disbursal of funds from the escrow accounts for a use approved under paragraph (4).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H738582C76CFC45F1A1A21E77215A2388"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payment schedule</header><subparagraph id="H91F1E5A6BE6049E9B97A1D22AB943CA5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a mandatory schedule for payments required by paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2633E8E986E4BB0974280DC7F278110"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadlines to establish schedules</header><clause id="H2B3B89B8F6094F4D99C9C3A0DD39E86D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>New leases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the issuance, extension, or transfer of an oil and gas lease after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish the schedule for payments prior to such issuance, extension, or transfer.</text></clause><clause id="H5B1CA5CDB86D44998C6072FDED381097"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Existing leases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any lease in effect as of the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish the schedule for payments by not later than 1 year after such date of enactment.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93355FB7D91343E88B9144579C5EAC91"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Minimum payments by 5 years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each schedule of payments established under subparagraph (A) shall provide that the total amount of payments made to the escrow account by the date that is 5 years after the schedule is established be not less than the total decommissioning costs for all oil and gas infrastructure located on the area of the applicable lease.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8781B52F24F7461FA5FF6E7E47AE6293"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Initial payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No lease may be issued, and no development and production plan may be approved under section 25, unless the recipient responsible party or leaseholder makes a payment to the escrow account in an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="HC64C53D7C5884F3DB7A1BE650D8F21DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">25 percent of the average cost to decommission oil and gas infrastructure located on a typical lease at similar depths; and</text></clause><clause id="HA8942F1ADE254226B6824C533080BA8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">25 percent of the total decommissioning costs for all oil and gas infrastructure proposed to be installed on the area subject to the lease pursuant to the plan.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE8D53861BD44161A42F3DDF9C62BB5E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Lease extensions and transfers</header><clause id="H5A9060E820EB4F4DA706A27F0666690A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Missed payments</header><text>The Secretary may not extend the term of, or approve the transfer of, a lease if the holder of the lease owes any outstanding payments to the escrow account.</text></clause><clause id="H33C280B69795483D853A23535CFBE7CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adoption of payment schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not approve the transfer of a lease unless the recipient responsible party agrees to adopt the schedule for payments established for the lease.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E97A61CF0604ED9AE7E0AF593960E05"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall adjust a schedule for payments established under subparagraph (A) to reflect any update to the applicable cost estimate under paragraph (2)(C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1A6B717CF58C4657B7BF24F58DDEAEB0"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Supplemental financial assurances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the combined amount of the funds in an escrow account for a lease and any supplemental financial assurances provided by the holder of the lease exceeds the total decommissioning cost estimate calculated by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall correspondingly reduce the supplemental financial assurances required until the combined figure is equivalent to the decommissioning cost estimate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B9F7BAE6D6044428A8CF38EA1EAEBD1"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any interest paid on funds in an escrow account established under paragraph (1) shall become part of the principal funds in the account.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDA4D4AB4B2B542FFB46ED6FF664CA3C7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Amounts from joint and several liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All funds accrued from previous holders of an oil and gas lease as a result of joint and several liability for the purposes of decommissioning shall be deposited into the corresponding escrow account.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H915055FE95B54955AC3E0C80386A8F05"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Return of remaining funds after decommissioning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After decommissioning is complete, any funds remaining in an escrow account for a lease established under paragraph (1) shall be returned to any parties that made payments to the escrow account, excluding any amounts deposited pursuant to subparagraph (I), based on the proportion of the payments made by the respective party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA504779824794C959695CCF7D937D33A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph id="H55BF24AE86A44B40B292E1905C74FEFD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The holder of a lease may only use funds in an escrow account established under paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H43DE7946D05D4F22B211CEE183C03F3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the purposes of decommissioning the oil and gas infrastructure located on the area subject to the lease; and</text></clause><clause id="H57E6F700371E42D5AC781519F381CC9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the use is approved by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4AA1D10BA7F34AD39BE8B6C38A3E3754"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No use as collateral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person may commit funds held in an escrow account established under paragraph (1) as collateral.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5BEE40B788324F0699147D3C458B1021"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the required payments into an escrow account established under paragraph (1) are delinquent by more than 60 days, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H72390E3C0EF04FE783D6F95F645BB741"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raise the royalty rate for the applicable lease at a rate sufficient to recover the delinquent amount within 6 months and deposit the recovered amount into the applicable escrow account established under paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3C2C339BAB3D4C84BC8D6D5F0F6AC005"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">suspend the lease, pursuant to section 5(a)(2), until the holder of the lease provides the delinquent amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5450FF017A824D65A7A3A8684A1BCF4A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the terms <term>decommissioning</term>, <term>parent company</term>, and <term>recipient responsible party</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 34.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7FFA9387E50B483C92E35077A41CD82C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Restriction on temporary abandonment of wells</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1334">43 U.S.C. 1334</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H511DD51B59754C5A983AF6C3F6C2AE97"><subsection id="H2997807BAD1A401CAEAA27DAFCD39DBF"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Restriction on temporary abandonment of wells</header><paragraph id="H5B3037F23F2242D7A6D12A2164BCCAF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H4C1187AAE1B649EF96881CE140653755"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not approve the placement of an oil well in temporary abandonment status for a period longer than 3 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A6632B1B25B438491DFBC266AE3C0E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may only approve such placement after submission and validation of an accompanying economic analysis verifying the potential for temporary abandonment to improve operational stability of the oil well or mitigate environmental impacts of operating the oil well.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A7FEDD3D6F145B6921850D97E6D61C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary may, on a one-time basis for an oil well, extend the maximum period the oil well may be placed in temporary abandonment status to 5 years if the Secretary determines such extension is necessary to ensure operational stability or environmental safety.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

