<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5F91A1F7838A4607A18010811D124037" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7040 IH: Stopping Adversarial Foreign Exploitation of Kids In Domestic Surrogacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7040</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260113">January 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent citizens of foreign adversarial nations from entering into or enforcing surrogacy contracts in the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1DFC87AA1C3948309402138EB2181BCA" style="OLC"><section id="H02A67410C90E479FB8842B2CB9D726DA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Adversarial Foreign Exploitation of Kids In Domestic Surrogacy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE KIDS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5A2E7475AFA4448A87420D3A9E04D4F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header><subsection id="H966DBAF01910437AB4BEBD50967EE59E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H73CA720E15074773B7BD1805FCE4AEBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Citizens of foreign entities of concern are exploiting commercial surrogacy laws in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D345B838B4B438DB37942C2A1EF60FA"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>Many developed countries ban international commercial surrogacy altogether. The United States, however, presently allows even citizens of foreign entities of concern to solicit and pay financially distressed Americans to give birth to their children in the United States and then send these infants abroad.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6EBF0AA4A8142FD8D88F1DB5CAD1BC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>This presents an acute national security threat, and recent events in Arcadia, California reveal that surrogacy is even being used to facilitate human trafficking.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDC3B4419A3C475DB5AC7A7542F88B32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>This Act—</text><paragraph id="H327C3BB0B1CC4ED6B86FD76E37514D56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acknowledges that foreign persons (including nationals of foreign entities of concern) are abusing surrogacy agreements to exploit women in the United States and to obtain United States citizenship for their children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H204CF06D69304C0C9B467B33BE5C7F5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>invalidates surrogate parentage contracts between prospective parents from foreign entities of concern and a surrogate mother in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DCC9F8BD9EB4D0B891BB2A93517FCA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>imposes criminal penalties on surrogacy brokers who commercially facilitate such invalid agreements.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF510E63F38AC488DA5C09C7FBD81C405"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB33D69C8D79F47FDA5D457CAC330E20F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> means any foreign nation listed under section 4872(f)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC25AC6D13A514C23A7C5E607E487BDBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prospective parent</header><text>The term <term>prospective parent</term> means an individual who, directly or indirectly, enters into a surrogacy agreement to become the legal or custodial parent of a child birthed by a surrogate parent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2F849A6FE78450DBB43154D28F0CB22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Surrogacy agreement</header><subparagraph id="H136AEA24825340A08CDB68B81F975C03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>surrogacy agreement</term> means a contract, agreement, or arrangement, without regard to whether it is oral or written or is direct or brokered, between 1 or more prospective parents and a surrogate parent, under which the surrogate parent agrees to become pregnant and give birth to a child, and, subject to subparagraph (B), to relinquish all parental rights and responsibilities to the prospective parent or parents.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF8CC4082E7F42F5B48608CCCD0455C7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Presumption</header><text>With respect to a contract, agreement, or arrangement, without regard to whether it is oral or written or is direct or brokered, under which a surrogate parent agrees to become pregnant and give birth to a child that does not expressly addressing parental or custodial rights, there shall be a presumption that the surrogate parent has agreed to relinquish her parental or custodial rights, and that the contract, agreement, or arrangement is a surrogacy agreement, if the contract, agreement, or arrangement is with a prospective parent who is a citizen or permanent resident of a foreign entity of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC80973637A434582ED74A2B41A4C4C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Surrogacy broker</header><text>The term <term>surrogacy broker</term> means any individual or entity that induces, arranges, procures, facilitates, or otherwise assists in the formation or execution of a surrogacy agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ECB1CC2C9D941A5BD89D98309A88844"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Surrogate parent</header><text>The term <term>surrogate parent</term> means a person who agrees to become pregnant and give birth to a child, and to relinquish all parental rights and responsibilities to another person under the terms of a surrogacy agreement.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA5B7F0AF902D472D9BC4E22255F7FDAA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Certain international surrogate parentage contracts void and unenforceable</header><subsection id="HE1C0B61578214EC0BA915DA304606BA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), a surrogacy agreement shall be void and unenforceable if the agreement is between a surrogate parent who is in the United States at the time of birth or who is a citizen or lawful permanent resident of the United States and—</text><paragraph id="HC5580EE285854D95A5494936BBC9C47C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a prospective parent who is a citizen or permanent resident of a foreign entity of concern; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACF4331D8054464888CFC371B80CA69D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a surrogacy broker who arranges a surrogacy agreement with a prospective parent who is a citizen or permanent resident of a foreign entity of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF16A54F4E7C24397AA4AE0B77005D425"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not invalidate a surrogacy agreement between a surrogate parent and 2 prospective parents, if—</text><paragraph id="H953DA013540A43C2A152E47E0E35E28E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the 2 prospective parents are legally married; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE577807439450C82E6CFE5EC8DED97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at least 1 prospective parent is a citizen or lawful permanent resident of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H08C1C4E445484DA7AF68202D5B09D6A8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Commercial facilitation of foreign surrogacy prohibited; penalty</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A surrogacy broker who knowingly or recklessly induces, arranges, procures, facilitates, or otherwise assists in the formation or execution of a surrogacy agreement that is void and unenforceable under section 4 shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></section><section id="HF09DAEEB894D406492E2C9FB348D624E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Custody of child when international surrogate parentage contracts are void and unenforceable</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Legal custody of a child born pursuant to a surrogacy agreement that is void and unenforceable under section 4 shall be decided based on a determination of the best interests of the child under the law of the State where the surrogate parent resides, with no effect given to the surrogacy agreement or any other purported agreement, contract, or understanding concerning the custody of the child.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

