<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB837F2EDCB17400CB00822D085B954AE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6946 IH: Temporary Protected Status Reform Act of 2026.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6946</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260106">January 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to terminate Temporary Protected Status designations for certain countries.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF6BD376563AC482BBB56F12AA1CB6917" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1062F4A151374C3A9D92509CE1E7E8C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Temporary Protected Status Reform Act of 2026.</short-title></quote></text> </section> <section id="H967627B77FC94D259693E05C8DEC5B8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HC6A6C578F16A490A8922BE41812FCAA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statutory purpose of temporary protected status</header><text>Temporary Protected Status (TPS), as established under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, was intended by Congress to provide temporary and humanitarian relief to nationals of designated countries experiencing armed conflict, environmental disaster, or other extraordinary and temporary conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H555DB49144964CE28F6B8269966D09C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration and repeated extensions</header><text>Since its enactment, TPS designations for certain countries have been repeatedly extended for periods spanning multiple decades, resulting in populations residing in the United States for prolonged durations under a status intended by statute to be temporary in nature.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H105F5A1F9BF5424182A76535FF624F24"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive branch discretion</header><text>The designation, extension, and termination of TPS have been exercised primarily through executive branch discretion, which has led to differing interpretations across administrations regarding the scope, duration, and application of such authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28F15992241A4273A86A7EBC0F10EF33"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Impact on the immigration system</header><text>Long-term TPS designations raise policy questions concerning the interaction between temporary humanitarian protections and the broader immigration system, including issues of lawful presence, work authorization, and eligibility for other forms of immigration relief.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31DA4995312B47A8B60E82DCD627C7CF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Congressional oversight and legislative authority</header><text>Article I of the Constitution vests Congress with the authority to establish a uniform rule of naturalization, and Congress has a continuing responsibility to review, clarify, and amend immigration statutes to ensure they reflect legislative intent.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD6F6CF577810498D8827C16FA461630D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Termination of temporary protected status for certain countries</header> <subsection id="H926547429C6143C4865A006C6DD0DC6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block id="HED532AB252C64C82B6571EE15D325E30" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HFCAFB9B037B4411688C0F7CFA2EC6778"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Termination of designations for certain countries</header>
<paragraph id="HBA7B72E3952347918DBF68B64264754D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or any other provision of law, the designation of a foreign state under this section shall terminate with respect to nationals of—</text> <subparagraph id="H090EB5A4A5924CC9AC3AD5B214787B78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Somalia;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8C4DD13373A2494B8732D32B5022318E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Sudan;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FDCF777DB594A69BA096725507F0EA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Syria;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H81569D3D98E549F4B501E09DBC69538C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Yemen; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H204CB89D5DB442DBAC9445394BEDC561"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Lebanon.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4932F91C3BEB4C52B5568B9435DEF3A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on redesignation</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not designate or redesignate any country listed in paragraph (1) under this section on or after the date of enactment of this subsection, except pursuant to a statute enacted after such date that expressly authorizes such designation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H110A0130896D45159991B1EF4B175D24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The termination of Temporary Protected Status under subsection (o) of section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB9AAEFE630FB453A9F72FB1D30F28BEE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Orderly wind-down and departure requirements</header>
<subsection id="H2239774590384256B62D26EBDD8FD747"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cessation of lawful presence and required departure</header>
<paragraph id="H72D931922B114309AB47305C29B9E95C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), any individual whose Temporary Protected Status is terminated pursuant to section 244(o) of the Immigration and Nationality Act shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HC222D04AAAD44E298FA11E3743DF31C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>depart the United States not later than the effective date described in section 2(b); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H13B5AE48552140D58241FCBAD680DDC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cease to be considered lawfully present in the United States on and after such date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA60DC9087FB4476B5C6061FC8B7E900"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for independent lawful status</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an individual who, on or before the termination date, has been granted—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDBDBAAEB68BD48AA8258B828D7DE6BD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lawful permanent resident status;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2813F7CCBDC453F8291800F8677CF50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nonimmigrant status under section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFFB6E05D6A8B40C7B910740E29198F41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>asylum under section 208 of such Act; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD6937E12583460B88D7692157781F8B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other lawful immigration status independent of Temporary Protected Status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC09FDC430946471CBF498E00960BACA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No continuing protection from removal</header><text>An individual described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to removal under the Immigration and Nationality Act if such individual remains in the United States after the termination date without lawful status.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H84026A9ADE5C406C9DD85858485ADDC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limited stay of removal prior to termination date</header><text>During the 180-day period preceding the termination date described in section 2(b), the Secretary of Homeland Security may not remove an individual solely on the basis of the termination of Temporary Protected Status.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0D3677D4B5564E1D8A01C3B0230B4AE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employment authorization</header><text>Any employment authorization document issued pursuant to Temporary Protected Status for an individual described in section 2(a) shall expire on the termination date specified in section 2(b) and may not be extended thereafter.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H11D8217F81214546A8976F21E352C630"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text>
<paragraph id="H8B838C993DF14DFC8816C632A2861681"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require the Secretary of Homeland Security to grant any form of discretionary relief from removal;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A8B0AB1139643459DFE5AC13A12686A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limit the authority of the Secretary to deny any application for immigration benefits; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71D0184BFF2344AFB2328A44056457BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>confer any right to remain in the United States beyond the termination date described in section 2(b).</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

