<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H056BBCA11ED446F083EF893214ADB4A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6521 IH: Immigration Court Due Process Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6521</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restrict the Department of Homeland Security from arresting or detaining individuals in connection with appearances before immigration courts of the Executive Office for Immigration Review, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H429B41990DE24C9D916AAA6102F5EAC7" style="OLC"><section id="H15C7454AEB7547689B3AE71E3E27B946" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Immigration Court Due Process Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2A6B5584A45B42DCA87132ED7019AC71"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restrictions on enforcement at immigration courts</header><subsection id="H4DDB680B41394258B99E0D4A5CFFB2C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law except as otherwise provided explicitly in this section, officers or agents of the Department of Homeland Security may not—</text><paragraph id="H8BD0C44166D149DCAB75A3954828DE3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>arrest or detain any individual while that individual is physically present at an Executive Office for Immigration Review immigration court facility for the purpose of attending or participating in a hearing, except pursuant to a judicial warrant; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBE973A94AD649388BDE629F6E138295"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arrest or detain any individual immediately upon their arrival or departure from an Executive Office for Immigration Review immigration court facility if they are arriving or departing the facility for the purpose of attending or participating in a hearing, except pursuant to a judicial warrant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H807101746CA2488A8ADE1A28DAFCE931"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pending Proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The restrictions on enforcement described under this section shall apply to any individual whose proceedings before an immigration judge or the Board of Immigration Appeals have not resulted in a final order of removal, and shall apply to any individual during the pendency of any appeals or motions to reopen, reconsider, or otherwise challenge a final order of removal.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE81DC725BEC749D49B5E3DEA4C7B40FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit an officer or agent from taking action when necessary to prevent an imminent act of violence or specific, articulable threat to life, public safety, or national security.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4621D0F04E4B4ECABD58D0AAE5EA2801"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Arrests at Scheduled Check-Ins</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An officer or agent of the Department of Homeland Security may not arrest or detain any individual while the individual appears for a scheduled appointment or check-in with any component of the Department of Homeland Security, or upon their arrival or departure for such appointment or check-in, unless—</text><paragraph id="HD49A6A4D0CDA45D1B1BD8CD478356740"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">written authorization for arrest or detention is approved by a supervisory official of the Department, at a level not lower than the senior field management level, specifying the legal basis for arrest; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEFDCDE5A4A94AD8AD0644A3ECF8EC2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the arrest or detention is reported to the Inspector General within 30 days, and included in the report required under section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF943144BF28B490FB3EF0A929305D1D3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Oversight</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date that is 1 year after the effective date of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report evaluating compliance with this Act by officers and agents of the Department of Homeland Security, including—</text><paragraph id="H927902002D394EEDBFD5E2CC25C33AA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of attempted and completed arrests referred to in section 2.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98DB2081E5334DA9B30CAE4B6C165E90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The basis for each such arrests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42A6205165B642348C69C6A6AC9C91E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The procedural posture of each individual’s immigration case who was arrested.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BA52BBB674946CBAFB3FCF2C81B704B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Steps taken by the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure compliance, including information provided as guidance or training to employees of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

