<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE220961F514B42D38D81621925C07039" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8254 IH: Water Access and Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8254</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260413">April 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a low-income water assistance program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7589A29B503141908D1911F7758302BD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0C58D19CB1E140909FB7C2FAB9132808" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Access and Affordability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB06560CAEB904B86A612D913835A3008"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9C9A945DB8DD47588097254635E0BE72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Safe, accessible, and affordable drinking water is essential to the protection of public health.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H002F74163D8F4CF0ADFAA9E193CE9763"><enum>(2)</enum><text>After 50 years, the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f et seq.</external-xref>) has demonstrably improved drinking water quality across the nation. However, millions of Americans are unable to afford their water bills and many water utilities have been unable to fund and maintain infrastructure critical to providing high quality, reliable, and affordable drinking water. Therefore, the Federal Government needs to increase water assistance to households and communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40820C1AE63E4D72AA9AB44360983B87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Federal Government provides low-income household assistance for basic necessities, including food, housing, and energy. Water is also a basic necessity and requires assistance from the Federal Government.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82893B5B2CFD4D80A135959F79B964CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Every low-income household should be able to access water assistance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC128EAE7C5B4BB18333A5E856583D5E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Other programs that provide financial and technical assistance for safe drinking water should incorporate water affordability as a goal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43FEB06CA2364A9FA6107E0FC0C87B03"><enum>(6)</enum><text>More effective protection of public health requires—</text> <subparagraph id="HA978F26C05224F12B09244DAF9FE24B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal commitment to ensuring the collection and transparency of data on water safety, access, and affordability at a national level;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB5AE99BECA614B8BA2ED7B7240F1BA8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Federal commitment to water access for all Native American Tribes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC107AF84EFC24DDE80DDFFA43C4BD349"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Federal commitment to having water utilities capable of serving safe and affordable drinking water to all households, including support for and oversight of State drinking water programs in the areas of financial and technical assistance, equitable utility consolidations, workforce development and training, community engagement, and enforcement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E6A2A6B585E4B8F861849AB3030D274"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Consumers served by public water systems should be provided with easy-to-understand information on the cost of their water, opportunities to reduce their bill, and bill payment assistance programs.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE63ED44E8D9C4C38AD55186D6DFEB2D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Low-income water assistance program</header> <subsection id="H08C538B64E224C18988F2AD37518FBDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4936FDF1FA04E7891279F440B7F0920"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05D084DECC5F48F3A571D9DE2C410B4C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Area median income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>area median income</term> means the unadjusted median income for an area determined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under section 16(a) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437n">42 U.S.C. 1437n(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H577F5718BC1A4F17A60D4601AECA9787"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community water system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community water system</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6F1532ACEE7409B80FC997307BB85A7" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an eligible water system, a State, or an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8B18050488E4AC7B34887925E3947F8" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible water system</header><text>The term <term>eligible water system</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H97028F9F974242DDB9E6420806B520BD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a community water system that serves a population of 100,000 or more; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3FEBC3B691344FDB517CE810759F678" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a treatment works that serves a population of 100,000 or more.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04B14A5E281D487EB692D149E90F21DF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Household</header><text>The term <term>household</term> means any individual or group of individuals who are living together as 1 economic unit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H296F6AC0CE0240998595D520D7BBD85D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Low-income household</header><text>The term <term>low-income household</term> means a household—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD6C34BEF3C447BF929EF7EEC0B36283"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which 1 or more individuals are receiving—</text> 
<clause id="HEE4F2DFA165C464387AEF1D7D51A0DCD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="HB72FF0B65AF34F748E36F1D04AA28041"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supplemental security income payments under title XVI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1381">42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H178FF6A373744B3FA476CF61F0C98071"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="HE6FD635F46674948BD5AF5769BC0E1A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>payments under—</text> 
<subclause id="H8B744B4DFD7A4150B94C7CDC79CAC163"><enum>(I)</enum><text>section 1315, 1521, 1541, or 1542 of title 38, United States Code; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB619D99778C04A5B96967241921D0DA1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>section 306 of the Veterans’ and Survivors’ Pension Improvement Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1521">38 U.S.C. 1521</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/588">Public Law 95–588</external-xref>);</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H5A0274A9E0BF4949B3F846F143892410" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>assistance under the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8621">42 U.S.C. 8621 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause> <clause id="HDFC366F94A124EF08689D04F39D6A54A" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>); or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H666D0A5A6A1F49FBAC506E1498F9426A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that has an income that, as determined by the entity that is implementing a water service access program in the area in which the household is located, does not exceed the greater of—</text> <clause id="H4BFA423274F246CE8ECE2222E4B82AE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an amount equal to 200 percent of the poverty level; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H15262DA2D36D44EEA3960B788B5E9D0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to 80 percent of the area median income.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04FBBEE1FBD04A37B475C1899E919A55"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Poverty level</header><text>The term <term>poverty level</term> means, with respect to a household in a State, the income described in the poverty guidelines issued by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pursuant to section 673 of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902</external-xref>), as applicable to the household.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F68DBB1609F491C8E77304899D113B4" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Small and mid-size water systems</header><text>The term <term>small and mid-size water systems</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H52737E5E36C0462B81FB50B9F9389B90" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community water systems that serve a population of less than 100,000; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89DEB6699D4F42DDA3A5E774F827026A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>treatment works that serve a population of less than 100,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40623AE30BF841A9B576917ACB3A136E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BD9CE7C5D59435F87DD61A4CC1F2569" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Technical assistance provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>technical assistance provider</term> means a community-based organization, environmental justice organization, university, rural assistance corporation, energy utility, business, or other organization identified by the Administrator as having relevant expertise in community outreach, assistance program enrollment processes and administration, utility data and billing systems, developing applications for funding, or other areas determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31054385E219424AB7D637A96752F7E0"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Treatment works</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>treatment works</term> has the meaning given that term in section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA85AAA90F92240FD9A458AE7F721BCD5"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Water crisis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>water crisis</term> means a weather-related or supply shortage emergency or other household water-related emergency, including disconnection of water service for nonpayment, imminent disconnection of water service for nonpayment, or other emergency threatening a household’s access to safe water services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB6A59A75262465F932F9F588E083BCA" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Water service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>water service</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A0EBA1DD1F74DB096982C14B8C04828" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>drinking water service provided by a community water system; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4054184DC91746B495C81CE1DA87BC47" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sanitary sewer service provided by a treatment works.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H931C3BB8C5864504AE8B2CB1C29A96FF" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Water service access program</header><text>The term <term>water service access program</term> means a program to provide low-income households the ability to maintain access to water services through the receipt of Federal financial assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0D74E0295F7748179C5D26002692D455"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Federal low-Income water assistance program</header> <paragraph id="H6740BE29CCDF4BFE81E4C217A9F6E3E2"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Establishment</header> <text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish a Federal low-income water assistance program to assist low-income households in maintaining access to affordable water services, which program shall include—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HE3782830A303466B8324CC2031C8BC84">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>development and implementation of water service access programs that include funding to assist low-income households;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H3C95493ABE1149C3AAE1B0ADDB58304C">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>technical assistance for the implementation of such water service access programs; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H5B7FCB40F60F4363B1E5A26F50E403FC">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>data collection and reporting.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9BD27D9A4A24B78B73E213F6395E2B5" commented="no"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Community advisory committees</header> <subparagraph id="HF7A68F68621D4C73B60A4FAC833051C3" commented="no"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Establishment</header> <text>The Administrator shall establish a community advisory committee for each region of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide advice and recommendations to each entity implementing a water service access program under subsection (c) within the region.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HF04BA5F27E8F418B80DDF450D7751624" commented="no">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Membership</header>
 <text>The Administrator shall include in each community advisory committee established under this paragraph members from low-income communities, non-governmental organizations, and other stakeholders determined relevant by the Administrator.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE81A24CFD1B40208613D5C59B46B78B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Water service access programs</header> 
<paragraph id="H438149F024554E459D6A94EA2FAAF9EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H8FEE734331A94F98B4608CC45BAD8068"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a water service access program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4024D0583E144E6CAD41D4407433F82B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implement such water service access program in each State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H778BB3BF87A74182A8DA4421C9A52C15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delegation of implementation</header> <subparagraph id="HBD941B0E053A4D9BA6622B2A9930A6A8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority to delegate</header> <clause id="H61D7D23ED7994C46A968466B1C77C09C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Delegation of areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), upon application by an eligible entity under subparagraph (B), the Administrator may delegate to the eligible entity the implementation of a water service access program for—</text> 
<subclause id="H797DF241A70443CF89E11591D8A57ECB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to an eligible entity that is an eligible water system, the service area of such eligible water system;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H61DA36172FF54D759AF3DC52295CB3C0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an eligible entity that is an Indian Tribe, the geographic area under the jurisdiction of the Indian Tribe; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3CA219D165244116B561E288F4038DCC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>with respect to an eligible entity that is a State, the area within the geographic boundaries of the State.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF2566F31987B44EB91C680D0DC95E6D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Non-overlapping programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator delegates the implementation of a water service access program for an area to an eligible entity that is an eligible water system or an Indian Tribe, the Administrator shall withhold or withdraw, as applicable, delegation for such area from the State in which such area is located.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD70F9D806BBF467195DD3EAF7C2FC166"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To implement a water service access program under this subsection, an eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator an application that demonstrates that—</text> <clause id="H43257C3505E14C088146EFF7E669D9AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the water service access program proposed to be implemented by the eligible entity—</text> 
<subclause id="H0E6F2ACBFDAC4125BE89162D5254E446"><enum>(I)</enum><text>meets the requirements established under paragraph (3); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2B9E42632F974208839A58FC99B21E62"><enum>(II)</enum><text>was developed in accordance with paragraph (4); and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H883097FA163A4DB2B48C0272EB254E89" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the eligible entity has the capacity to—</text> <subclause id="H7A92604C5A0D4C81B76889CB1E376A98"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make assistance under the water service access program available to all low-income households in its jurisdiction or service area, without regard to where that household resides within the jurisdiction or service area;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HEDDBE1E4FE1D47D2B5331D1043DC71A8" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>fulfill the data collection and management requirements set forth in subsection (e); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9601BC3C2C01422395959FCB1D7E134D" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and implement, in coordination with technical assistance providers, an effective community outreach plan to inform low-income households of the water service access program and assist with enrollment.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55EE283F34F046B58A74A844F4C4088A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Grants</header> 
<clause id="HD323D93F483F43D29070812DA073710F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator delegates implementation of a water service access program to an eligible entity under this paragraph, the Administrator shall award a grant to the eligible entity to implement such program.</text></clause> <clause id="HE9291DB0B2244EFDA28A024CB6CACEE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>A grant awarded under this paragraph—</text> 
<subclause id="H774A88A892CF4702AC6104743E4B1752" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be used to replace funds for any existing similar program of a State, community water system, or treatment works to assist low-income households in maintaining access to affordable water services in the area for which the water service access program will be implemented; but</text></subclause> <subclause id="H32BF8C98A9364AB6ABA42CB0886F8D64"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be used to supplement or enhance such a program.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA358218A15FD4B66959A0758DE599A98" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Revocation</header> 
<clause id="H1ECAB96C38C14DE28823EFA045A510F4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notification and opportunity to remedy</header><text>If the Administrator determines, based on information required to be submitted to the Administrator under this section by an eligible entity implementing a water service access program under this subsection, that the water service access program is not being implemented in compliance with all requirements of this section, the Administrator shall promptly notify the eligible entity of such noncompliance, the necessary remedial actions, and a deadline for promptly implementing such remedial actions.</text></clause> <clause id="H29A6396CD86A4C6B99E5B0AEBBC8EDD2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Failure to remedy</header><text>The Administrator shall revoke delegation under this subsection to an eligible entity if the eligible entity fails to take the necessary remedial actions by the deadline set by the Administrator under clause (i).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H52F639ACEA2B4B879CACB98659AF0E4C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator revokes delegation under this subsection to an eligible entity, implementation of a water service access program under this subsection for the previously delegated area shall revert to the Administrator, who may delegate such implementation to the State in which such area is located if such State is implementing a water service access program pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9F22D694DB04BA19A4AAA981029A476"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum water service access program requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H9C129F07279F443582F61D220F8E513B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish minimum requirements for water service access programs developed and implemented under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCED030F3C98744FFB41A3DF5A0AF395F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall—</text> <clause id="HAD21C7DF54B747A6A6977A7145F29018"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consult with relevant stakeholders, including frontline community groups, Tribal communities, and technical assistance providers; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H37D8959E27464974BAFFB0BE0E7BB6A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for public comment on the proposed requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9A98C123B394E1188CB2EE4095D6CDB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The minimum requirements established under subparagraph (A) for a water service access program shall include—</text> 
<clause id="HF359F6BBB95A4FC1B1BD3505698E4A47" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provisions to promote universal access for low-income households to assistance under the water service access program (including low-income households in which none of the individual members is a named account holder of the applicable community water system or treatment works), including provisions for—</text> <subclause id="H954F399EED444C5A8CCFFA2533510359" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>sharing of data from other administrators of Federal, State, or local income-qualified assistance programs to facilitate automatic enrollment in the water service access program of all households participating in those other programs that are eligible to receive assistance under the water service access program, without the need for those households to apply separately for the water service access program;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6A2A600BF5B446818F69D5CFC2245CEB" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allowance for community water systems and treatment works to receive program funds for low-income household debt reduction and directly apply such funds to customer accounts;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5385BE015C934F21A262BBFFA86C9E6A" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>allowance for self-attestation by households served by community water systems or treatment works of eligibility, including self-attestation of income qualification or enrollment in an existing Federal, State, or local assistance program on the basis of income;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H703902B519A945E6AE44A068EDAC71D9" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any portion of the process for enrollment in the water service access program for which a signature of a member of a low-income household is required, allowance for the use of an electronic signature; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEEFC336D36BB4BAD822D3B984B4DC983" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibitions on—</text> 
<item id="H5D5DE7741EB144FC837BBDFF493D58FE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>asset tests and in-person enrollment appointments as requirements to receive assistance under the water service access program; and</text></item> <item id="H7B772AC6E14C44D3921D151EB0FC60BE"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">citizenship or legal residency requirements for members of a low-income household in order for the household to receive assistance under the water service access program;</text>
                                </item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H04771B9646BB4789974D0F10CD0E512C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance to low-income households served by community water systems or treatment works (including low-income households in which none of the individual members is a named account holder of the applicable community water system or treatment works), with greater assistance amounts provided to households with higher water service costs and lower incomes, taking into account household size, in the form of—</text> <subclause id="H56B690C77B5A4531AFFB2803F3A55754" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct financial assistance, including bill discounting, percentage-of-income payment plan, a lifeline rate, or any other form of direct assistance identified by the Administrator;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HED6F6D7C6C6C4DBC906A23B1B399AE48" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>debt relief;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H291507A61CB94AB08CB34ECDBCB1398C" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>water crisis assistance; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1A3E0CD8FF184F26AA001087BB380B0E" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>water efficiency assistance, including providing or subsidizing the cost of installation of water-efficient appliances and fixtures or leak detection and plumbing repair work;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1545AFA8A5CB4BCA9FF5081783580349" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provisions prohibiting the inclusion of eligibility restrictions or enrollment requirements not specifically required by this section;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7364919CB62F47178938778D2FC3D08D" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provisions, including penalties on community water systems and treatment works for violations, as established by the Administrator, to ensure that no household receiving assistance under the program—</text> <subclause id="H7BC7C07B123249B0BCF3C5671832B9E8" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is disconnected from water service, loses access to or ownership of its current housing, or is otherwise denied access to an amount and flow of water sufficient to meet its essential needs because of the household’s inability to pay bills owed to a community water system or treatment works, or, where the water service account-holder for the household’s dwelling is not a member of the household, due to the failure of the account-holder to pay bills owed to the community water system or treatment works; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6FB0269D354543F18557E51733275352" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is required to pay any fees, charges, or deposits associated with late payments, unpaid bills, service initiation, or service reconnection;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE784B9B2BFD74739BBEF7D95A18EEDC7" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>procedures that minimize burdens on low-income households of filing a complete application for assistance under the program, including allowing for alternative forms of identification;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H25A9793ECFD94279941709FA73935192"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provisions that require equal access to assistance to households that pay bills for water services directly and households the water services of which are included in rent or other payments, including by providing for households that cannot receive assistance through a bill for water services other types of assistance, such as cash assistance, credits on a different utility bill, and receipt of water quality and efficiency upgrades and devices; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3C82347FB45B481685E54FA788647404" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>coordination of development and implementation of the water service access program with other existing water assistance programs, energy assistance programs, and other relevant Federal, State, and local programs that provide financial or other assistance to low-income households.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25A0BFF26E6749EB880E885CB6921396"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public process</header><text>Each entity developing or implementing a water service access program under this subsection shall, each fiscal year—</text> <subparagraph id="HF85D688E98E540239D1012292B64AB84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with the applicable community advisory committee established under subsection (b)(2), Tribal communities, and other community representatives, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8BD29275A5FA4647A7424B9247B38AAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide an opportunity for a public hearing and public comment on the water service access program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4BE4761131344203AA2CFE33D48B6E0C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> <paragraph id="HDA813B0662CF4473B63806C8B0F387E6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide funding to technical assistance providers to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6CA5D91FB81D4FE78D271BB566695D04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate enrollment by low-income households in water service access programs implemented under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F68E1877AAB413AB7D0124EC74BEF8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist small and mid-size water systems in participating in water service access programs implemented under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5862B040DEA14D4CA329BC39F725FF51" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum requirements</header><text>The Administrator shall establish minimum requirements for technical assistance provided under paragraph (1), which shall include requirements for—</text> <subparagraph id="H3980D54E6AC242F2AC13D639EF68262B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>outreach to low-income households in communities with high incidence of disconnections of water service or that may face difficulty enrolling in or accessing assistance through a water service access program, including households in geographically remote locations, households lacking access to telecommunications networks (including home broadband internet service), households with limited English proficiency, and households in which an individual with a disability (as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)) resides; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC2C0F14B3A54CAA993004959BC14204" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing the capacity of small and mid-size water systems to—</text> <clause id="H3A1D167B6B4247049D49579CAF8C1F52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carry out any applicable activities necessary for assistance to be provided pursuant to a water service access program implemented under this section; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE2BB2FDB26D14246BA5AFD17B67CD571"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide complete and accurate information to the entity implementing an applicable water service access program as necessary for such entity to comply with the reporting requirements of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H940978545E5D4E778C5C142ED5E10633" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Set-asides</header> <subparagraph id="H5ADA90CB06614CF98CB89D104BB44A94" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Data management systems</header><text>Of the funds made available to carry out this subsection, the Administrator shall ensure that a minimum of 20 percent is used for—</text> 
<clause id="H9651C862D7DB40EDB49B177ECA88894B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the improvement of data management systems, including billing systems, websites, and electronic customer communications, for small and mid-size water systems; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF7F01D2CF5514840BE0BA3D38493A840"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>implementation of easily accessible enrollment and data transmission technologies, such as smartphone applications.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA448AC6F346D40168A019B246C2147C7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Under-resourced communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available to carry out this subsection, the Administrator shall ensure that a minimum of 20 percent is provided to technical service providers that are environmental justice organizations and community-based organizations to build capacity and provide assistance for under-resourced communities to fully access a water service access program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1959FBF9F1B645579537DCFEF40D121B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Community engagement</header><text>The Administrator shall engage with environmental justice organizations and community-based organizations—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8F7980D09F634C27BE45B38F06F074C8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in establishing the minimum requirements under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DF081AD12D043DAAD863117B2396FBF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage their participation in the provision of technical assistance under this subsection, including by making them aware of the funds set aside under paragraph (3)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5D55D80E83E244558D26679148217C39"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header> 
<paragraph id="H0F735B51D40F4E3DB3564FB2159F4527"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting to the Administrator</header> 
<subparagraph id="H836A67014D544E8B976551EF5660B4B4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity implementing a water service access program under this section shall annually submit to the Administrator, in a manner determined by the Administrator, information regarding the applicable water service access program, including—</text> <clause id="H3ED919CDA4E84CBF84D23391ABC435D1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demonstrable impacts of the program on bill debt and timely bill payments for low-income households that receive assistance under the program, based on data from before and after the implementation of the program, including, for each county and ZIP code within the geographic area served by the program—</text> 
<subclause id="H8EC60389285D4082A7C9FFA351F7710F" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of households that experienced a disconnection of water service for nonpayment and the number of households for which disconnection was avoided directly due to the provision of assistance under the program;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1C73B91F5B2045CFB8273755E0903778" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of households and amount of debt subject to sale or enforcement of property liens and the number of households for which sale or enforcement of property liens was avoided directly due to the provision of assistance under the program;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF621913076314D708AF0C36B0639FB0B" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the number of households enrolled in the program;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBEC4266513AB4AE3A372F3BCF1B522F1" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the benefit levels, amount of debt reduction, and total amount of assistance provided to enrolled households; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6E072D780202404BBDECA563A629EFDB" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the number of enrolled households reconnected to water service and a summary of the fees and charges waived for enrolled households, including disconnection and reconnection charges, late payment fees, and interest charges;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HFB0E9927C48F473AB35D40250ADD0346" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>revenue collection information from each community water system and treatment works within the geographic area served by the program, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H62CD81B3363D43D0B795C451CC0B3C90" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>rate design for residential customers;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H26C7B9FAEA184CD792ADE03F7B9438C2" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>billing frequency;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4304A7B70582483B9247A722CD1BD43D" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>fees, taxes, and other charges that are included on every residential bill or that are billed to a residential customer under specific circumstances but are not included on every residential bill; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H60AE6E14EF4F4F41988B36BD838D47BA" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>projected rate increases during the 5-year period following submission of the information under this subsection;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H00D157382B3D48DFABA894266443B00F" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding any other water service customer assistance programs within the geographic area served by the program, including information about such other programs relating to rate structures, rebates, discounts, billing methods that average rates over the course of a year (known as <quote>budget billing</quote>), and procedures that ensure that households receive notice and an opportunity to dispute charges before service is disconnected or interrupted due to non-payment; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDA5327F236A340A6A0154D3D3C233CC9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other relevant information required by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CBEBE547432465CBF2CDAB2A7C41C13"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional time for completion of certain reporting requirements</header><text>The Administrator may postpone a requirement to include in an annual submission data required under subparagraph (A), taking into consideration the availability of technical assistance pursuant to subsection (d) related to data reporting.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26194DD7450C4E1A847F42020A79A7DA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Administrator shall annually—</text> 
<clause id="H61DAEF9EFF3549E4806AB064369A818A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make information on water service access programs implemented under this section available in an easily accessible format on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency, including—</text> <subclause id="H26D568D1F87048CCAE551B5A22215E7C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a list of all such water service access programs and contact information for the entities implementing such programs; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4F0788E8929C4812969E68A84E28A596"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the information submitted under subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE5D218A2290547BCBF2C5B48F8EE386E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publish a report that compiles and summarizes the information submitted under this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE94F8746E8644BDA42C8AFA91DA098E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible water system that is implementing a water service access program pursuant to this section shall report to each agency or office of the State in which the water service access program is implemented that funds or regulates water systems—</text> <subparagraph id="H95E6C69F3BC64C43AEF4B55F0FB30C1A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of all grants it receives under this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC5A8EDC51CE4BF8AE7E83BEBB9A66FF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all information it submits to the Administrator under paragraph (1) and subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5B17D1B550F0470CB2B092A9B4A48D63"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header> <paragraph id="H6A51A98B2EA844E6A09F63F80714256D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistance exempt from inclusion as income</header> <subparagraph id="HA46EED19724B478EBD49D85059B39DE6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Individual assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any individual who is a member of a low-income household receiving assistance under a water service access program implemented under this section—</text> 
<clause id="HAE8D8807A7934AAD9F57013A19F400D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, gross income shall not include any such assistance provided to such individual; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB3C12AD1E4CC446B93D960554257BB57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding any other provision of law, any such assistance provided to such individual shall not be considered income or resources of such household (or any member thereof) for any purpose under any other Federal or State law, including any law relating to taxation or governmental assistance programs.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFADE9FB66307470B949061A7D3698E83" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assistance to eligible water systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant received under this section by an eligible water system that is subject to Federal or State income tax shall not be considered income for purposes of any Federal or State income tax law if the Administrator determines that the eligible water system complied with the requirements established under subsection (c)(3)(C)(iv) during the year in which the grant was received.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BB1364A6DD94A41A6E9965BC61CF09B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance not a Federal public benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 401(c) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1611">8 U.S.C. 1611(c)</external-xref>), assistance provided to a low-income household under a water service access program implemented under this section shall not be considered a Federal public benefit for purposes of title IV of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1601">8 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68A94508168F448B9A2130102A851C6B" commented="no">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Financial terms for private utilities</header>
 <text>A community water system or treatment works that is not wholly owned by a governmental entity may not use any funds received under or pursuant to this section to provide any financial benefits to the owners of the community water system or treatment works, including increased rates of return on capital investments, dividends, and interest.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9EF97EDCA1ED480AA61422DA78B198CA" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date on which grant funds are first disbursed to an eligible entity under this section, and every 5 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the Federal low-income water assistance program established under this section, which report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HFA34D8C3E946458590AE90B1536734AC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the remaining need and obstacles to achieving universal water service access and affordability; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8356910890784BB8917EC02B8B3838FC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant findings and information from other programs and assessments, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H698E85BF62B44EC9A104651DED1BC730"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State revolving fund programs under the Safe Drinking Water Act and the Federal Water Pollution Control Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC987F82FA4A04B5BBD726B6D618DDF0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State drinking water program plans, as applicable;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H532AAD380AD14A78A8C1AF28A89AEA11"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national drinking water infrastructure needs survey and assessment conducted under section 1452(h) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12(h)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC4A0962487648FFA68D8A5317ECE173"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Climate Assessment carried out pursuant to the Global Change Research Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2921">15 U.S.C. 2921 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCF8C4DEF8C604D55A2F4998AFB5AB73D" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Use of national surveys</header> <paragraph id="H071A7FAD398542B689D81FF4B8375867"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Questions</header><text>The Director of the United States Census Bureau shall, in coordination with the Administrator, add one or more questions into the American Community Survey to ascertain whether households have faced difficulty paying for water services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H690450A6A13D45F89664EC33A55F89CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall use information from the American Community Survey to inform the reports submitted under subsection (g).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCAB9BB12BF5647DD9B3BE2FB9ED40626"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="HDA0531B4A37F4B528829DA43E4F1C879"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2037.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC1AB12A17DE4CA1AB32ABD25DB066D5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6DF3CA626B514FF181546BD18D10CDFB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a formula to annually allocate funds made available to carry out this section among entities implementing water service access programs, based on—</text> <clause id="H415FA521F17641A3B1B0F46CC0746384" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>number of low-income persons and households served by each such program;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAD7B0BB165FF4CF4BA0D2A2E104E7770" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>technical assistance needs of eligible entities implementing such programs, including needs for enrollment support, community outreach, and data collection and reporting;</text></clause> <clause id="H7BED37F292924FF0B013786AA168408B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>administrative costs of implementing such programs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEB48AFE8ABBF4C91841051AF38ED85C0" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">water service costs in the area served by each such program;</text></clause> <clause id="H5C502DBD6C26417AB163EE07DEF9A72B" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>exceptional community needs owing to water quality and water scarcity; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E56289B45914C8B8A1EAF436454C182" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other criteria determined relevant by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5EA0D1ECB7F4F558D73185EE3726E56"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In establishing the allocation formula under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<clause id="H4AD1DBC751C04BD19FC1ADB7C98D675F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that equal amounts of funds are made available with respect to drinking water services and sanitary sewer services; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCE0FD88E4A2C4718B3466A7A2A697C57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determine appropriate allotments for the provision of technical assistance through each water service access program.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C650EFA9619432D98C7ABCCEA23D6B1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may reserve up to 10 percent of funds made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year to provide supplementary funds for water service access programs that serve—</text> <clause id="H1D09340F3AFA4AEEB879970F529226BB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>territories, or areas under the jurisdiction of an Indian Tribe, that have historically lacked equitable access to Federal and State financial assistance for drinking water and wastewater infrastructure; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H207E047487CB42E48607C67AF2689382" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communities experiencing lack of access to safe public drinking water services to meet essential household needs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF079C7AE3F9E41599767FC476855161D"><enum>4.</enum><header>State revolving loan funds</header> <subsection id="HCA4A505C16E447E88B8797C56095E526" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Safe Drinking Water Act</header> <paragraph id="HE22D4C0E4D354BD9AB91844627BAD88E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intended use plans</header><text>Section 1452(b) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5621E1DD1EE2440A86F752ADEAFD454D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>in accordance with paragraph (4)</quote> after <quote>public review and comment</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFC3BA06CB5842769449D2AAF3987D62" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF3F333EAC5184D69B7661939FA8D6BF8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H2A94E98D9C2E4B68A6FD0472AEF758B5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public review and comment</header><text>In preparing an intended use plan under paragraph (1), a State shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H94C0B85CC41F451B921511B377D64FFE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>before adopting a final plan—</text> 
<clause id="HF6FC44F1C33D4D149576ACD27A7155E3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make a draft of the plan, and instructions for how to provide comments on the draft, available on a publicly accessible website;</text></clause> <clause id="H851BA3117A4E42DB92772E1D002001D3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide a minimum of 30 days for public comment on the draft;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD0BF2E580E084AEF90B638966B944A5F" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide written responses to timely submitted written public comments on the draft; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAE781EA675774A15A30FC1FD0EA61FBC" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>after providing such written responses, hold at least one public hearing on the draft;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A969C24B8B04ED29F6CB6977975C5A2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the final plan available on a publicly accessible website; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2292A004A2144DF6BC7E66DC010730B6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for submission of applications for financial and technical assistance at any time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04EC6BD81E61430088F3554F4ED5AA82" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transparency and evaluation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H85FA850358F84921B6D995DD06BE71E6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regulations</header> 
<clause id="H74FCBC76580F423482D01E63C7223724" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Promulgation</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations to increase transparency and promote evaluation of—</text> <subclause id="H034DC4AD982E41F3A1BD5D75C2BBACC7" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the distribution by States of the amounts available to the State loan fund among the intended uses identified in a plan under this subsection; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5D450C97A13E422BA5C28AEC2AAAFC1D" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the criteria and methods established by States under paragraph (2)(B) for the distribution of funds.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2F64F7CAC53843E4910DA8EF623402D0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The Administrator shall include in the regulations promulgated under clause (i)—</text> 
<subclause id="HEE8E7DB228644E1A9EE2A1DE95E4519D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a requirement that States provide to the Administrator data about—</text> <item id="H66D29CCCF1564DE0BFFECCF879F5AE3B" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>funded and unfunded projects that are eligible for assistance from the State loan fund; and</text></item> 
<item id="HD35F9B72B94D41989A594E44CC3B8144" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the geographic and socioeconomic distribution of such funded projects, including the amount and percentage of assistance allocated to projects that serve disadvantaged communities;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H7E0A9A53C8A646FBAA37AD34BF3E36AA" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>creation of a central online repository for intended use plans and data provided pursuant to subclause (I); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB0AA19E81E9649B388C0D871E9BD2852" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>creation of an advisory group within each State to provide advice and recommendations on intended use plans, State loan fund policies, and implementation of such plans and policies.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A8E40391A664519B8F14BB6CCFE0CAE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make available on a publicly accessible website an annual report, prepared based on the data provided pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) and feedback from State advisory groups created under subparagraph (A)(ii)(III), which shall include—</text> 
<clause id="H6F3D5496399547A4828CDBCE5F79891B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on and analysis of the use by each State of the amounts available to the State loan fund of the State, including, for each State, the amount of assistance provided under this section, and the number of public water systems receiving such assistance;</text></clause> <clause id="HA1EFD7A87AB24060B344BE87F80A369D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data and metrics on disadvantaged communities served and technical assistance and outreach efforts; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8A641C94EF4A4A2F879B46B0E38C36D1" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ongoing challenges at the national and State level.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD76FE7B7AB3143778D97B2E7BB177821" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance for disadvantaged communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1452(d) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEE021020D57647AAB6E54E2C09B33F10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following: <quote>Each State shall, during calendar year 2027 and every three years thereafter, conduct a review of, and if appropriate revise, the affordability criteria established by the State under this subsection.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE39E67F46CD4649A9447F87327FA50A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA7E3C37251544A5F9599DD36EDFF46BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H148BA90F975845DCABB2E1E5BCCE6511"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations to expedite the provision of assistance to, and provide flexible repayment options for, disadvantaged communities receiving assistance under this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69B462046AD94BFF85C07E5074A1106E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration of State Loan Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1452(g)(2)(A)(i) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12(g)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H48A422719C1D4A1786E87A2F06987A60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I), by striking <quote>may</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8726B4BC469D43D4A34CA9C4A2E53C4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>, except that a State may not use more than 30 percent of such amount to cover costs under this subclause; and</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27323397B0D442A2B6CA18BE1933B7B4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Water Pollution Control Act</header> 
<paragraph id="H7654FE4561F646CDA5BBB918E4D026B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Water pollution control revolving loan funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="H64D38B3595784CEB929401CDF10F5A1B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Additional subsidization</header><text>Section 603(i)(2) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1383">33 U.S.C. 1383(i)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBBC08CE65F4F4B06A7EB3C64C67E8685" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H016AE4610FD74468A68A5CF165C69CF6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Review and revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall, during calendar year 2027 and every three years thereafter, conduct a review of, and if appropriate revise, the affordability criteria established by the State under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAA1573789BB4D43AEFD2C4AC6B1BCDA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations to expedite the provision by a State of assistance to, and flexible repayment options for, municipalities that meet the affordability criteria established by the State under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23ADC752BF3E4367BE1AF77270F54815" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 603(k) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1383">33 U.S.C. 1383(k)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>may</quote> and inserting <quote>shall</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60B0F51B67EC420DB6A02A4174CBEC65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audits, reports, and fiscal controls; intended use plan</header><text>Section 606 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1386">33 U.S.C. 1386</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H88762BD6496F43EEA41FC47CE28F3487"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>in accordance with subsection (g)</quote> after <quote>public comment and review</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72F67F2565D149A5A2EF202E49FD4BA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H01F87E6A153140EE9F1077ED5CD49C9E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HCF64BE6913874DCF99160A1BE1F28CA9" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public comment and review</header><text>In preparing an intended use plan under subsection (c), a State shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD6000C33FDCD42FB840114D74A9FE07F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>before adopting a final plan—</text> <subparagraph id="H74056EA89378458D8930C50BC83553AE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make a draft of the plan, and instructions for how to provide comments on the draft, available on a publicly accessible website;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H279E5A5924094E69BC539B242C2FCDDF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a minimum of 30 days for public comment on the draft;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC03F9779B7BD4097AF9E84B517564D7B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide written responses to timely submitted written public comments on the draft; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAA86F6351FF04E2EB2CF92A89B46CB13" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>after providing such written responses, hold at least one public hearing on the draft;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE98A8C5569A34D19AC8850CBEB47B158" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the final plan available on a publicly accessible website; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9ABE846D2E5446C68FB0815A5D183758" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>allow for submission of applications for financial and technical assistance at any time.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1614D9F948BE4C7086D714F5981B91C1" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Transparency and evaluation</header> <paragraph id="H983DAE3F6B4A4492B67C646355EED2DC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regulations</header> <subparagraph id="H2460E1E6C4974FEDB3C5213A7FDE0337" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Promulgation</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations to increase transparency and promote evaluation of—</text> 
<clause id="HBC3A07832C524930892FC06707263C5F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the distribution by States of the amounts available to the State water pollution control revolving fund among the intended uses identified in a plan under subsection (c); and</text></clause> <clause id="H03AE2F891FD044E7A03B59D72C6BEBC4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the criteria and methods established by States under subsection (c)(5) for the distribution of funds.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD372D5AF4E7C4655A63393EACBC32367" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The Administrator shall include in the regulations promulgated under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HB10C17CD54A34BB28929A77C561224D4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a requirement that States provide to the Administrator, in each annual report provided under subsection (d), data about—</text> 
<subclause id="H4E5994395D3E4F8BAB3E186164A882F4" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>funded and unfunded projects that are eligible for assistance from the State water pollution control revolving fund; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0AD31355E3DD49179C0EE971A89B82DC" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the geographic and socioeconomic distribution of such funded projects, including the amount and percentage of assistance allocated to projects that serve municipalities that meet the affordability criteria established by the State under section 603(i)(2);</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H3FB805AE8A4C4AC09FC9E80DFF86D21A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>creation of a central online repository for intended use plans and data provided pursuant to clause (i); and</text></clause> <clause id="H5E293190A8924A8FA5A53B6FDD20A44E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creation of an advisory group within each State to provide advice and recommendations on intended use plans, State water pollution control revolving fund policies, and implementation of such plans and policies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36A8EC8FC1DA429FB2AD5C5889AF466F" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Annual report</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make available on a publicly accessible website an annual report, prepared based on the data provided pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(i) and feedback from State advisory groups created under paragraph (1)(B)(iii), which shall include—</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="H268AB9A26FE9481A9A5FB16CEA7301A7" commented="no">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on and analysis of the use by each State of the amounts available to the State water pollution control revolving fund of the State, including, for each State, the amount of assistance provided under this title, and the number of treatment works with respect to which such assistance was provided;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="HB3B90098EE244A069A1D522AD1950BC3" commented="no">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>data and metrics on disadvantaged communities served and technical assistance and outreach efforts; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H70837EDA34F14BD599ADF6907762A613" commented="no">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>ongoing challenges at the national and State level.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

