<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7087291FAB754F128C49C39FEB8D9BB8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6522 IH: Coordinating and Aligning Records to Improve and Normalize Governance for Our Veterans Health Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6522</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require implementation by the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs of certain recommendations relating to the provision of health care through community care providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C937499D82B4E7CB5EA994E2B3748B3" style="OLC"><section id="H2C2758835ECE4045ABEA62365BD17B19" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coordinating and Aligning Records to Improve and Normalize Governance for Our Veterans Health Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CARING for Our Veterans Health Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5D2BF915C524AABA38274CBA9A24538"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation by Department of Veterans Affairs of certain recommendations with respect to care in the community</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31DA9E25B7CE4101B16FEAF988A7E9AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that the Office of Integrated Veteran Care, or successor office—</text><paragraph id="H89B3BB2B3DCB4827A5C586FBFC3F8069"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develops guidance for the efforts of medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs in obtaining final medical documentation after a veteran receives services from a community care provider pursuant to a referral from that medical center;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94CFDC820B9749E58DD07B1946C3B715"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishes goals and related performance measures for medical centers of the Department in obtaining initial and final medical documentation from community care providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB699401E774F2A95FAB445D3C0339F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishes and monitors goals and related performance measures for the completion by such providers of core trainings and ensures that such providers complete the required training course; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68339E1C5A7C4B7693982CCC848772D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>takes steps to ensure that the Office of Integrated Veteran Care, or successor office, and any contractor for that Office communicate clear and accurate information to such providers regarding the core trainings recommended or required by that Office, including whether such training is recommended or required.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1760DD05AB704D5789EB5E4F13CBE210"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 120 days thereafter until the requirements under subsection (a) are fully implemented, the Under Secretary for Health shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on steps taken by the Under Secretary to implement those requirements.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

