<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8FD7FEAF65AE478E8EC6796549A2623F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 159 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to the duration of authorizations of the use of force.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 159</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to the duration of authorizations of the use of force.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment" id="HF80AA9B6375D4C7BAB28549E0F88F986"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA38D5A11C8BB44ABBACD99D90F932B76"><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification: </text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="HAE1CF3C2688641A08DCEEE3852BBB4E1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><constitution-article id="H1234"><enum> —</enum><section id="HB8A8C2DE6B334DB9BD1E9FB8B0F647C5" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An Act of Congress enacted after the date of the ratification of this article that authorizes the use of military force by the United States outside of the United States, and with respect to which there is not in effect a declaration of war enacted by Congress, shall cease to have effect on the earlier of the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of such Act or the date of termination of such authorization provided for in such Act.</text></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

