<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA34DD4805D77417A813489631AEE46F7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8937 IH: Early Childhood Workforce Advancement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8937</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001231">Mr. Mannion</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to award competitive grants to eligible partnerships to establish, expand, or support career and technical education programs of study in early childhood education.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7EAB27E722AB46528CBBC96E1A04EDD1" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC99590D42B344C28945E65B41ED85878"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Early Childhood Workforce Advancement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC20A86BEB34D49DAA83C2747D4F1388B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for career and technical education programs of study in early childhood education</header> <subsection id="H6F77B20790AF494DB22FBB793B1C15DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships for the purpose of establishing, supporting, or expanding career and technical education programs of study in early childhood education.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H60702A109ECD4610A47A151CC5E0D8EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be considered for a grant under this section, an eligible partnership shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H7F38BC9DB7C74E3C83D5ADDE2EC63BCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the eligible partnership will use such grant to establish, support, or expand a career and technical education program of study in early childhood education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B432F4ACA8D43A7A7D6D8CE788F5944"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the roles and responsibilities of each partner of the eligible partnership;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3B68AE00DD7428DA29EDAF2DA8CF04F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how such funds will be allocated for necessary expenses for the career and technical education program of study described in paragraph (1), including the use of additional funding provided by State, local, or private entities, and plans to maintain and sustain the program;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H333C73F44DB94EA9926ED21B04709CE3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of how the grant will directly benefit students, including special populations, served by the eligible partnership;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H764FB468802B4D638DD3B32E4F8A1CB1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of how such career and technical education program of study will be coordinated with the activities carried out under section 124 or 135 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2344">20 U.S.C. 2344</external-xref>; 2355);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3CB9C89E9F6747C2AF2D7F6B90B3BE96"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the program reflects the needs of regional, State, or local employers, as demonstrated by the local comprehensive needs assessment under section 134(c) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2354">20 U.S.C. 2354(c)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CC606FE80A54889B53FDC495213E4EE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of how the program will benefit the child care system and early childhood education workforce;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE35D1B6CA0104E538877FC116BB6224E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>an assurance that the eligible partnership will—</text> <subparagraph id="HB603A2A1681145A29EBCB3AE1B2F994F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide information to the Secretary, as requested, for evaluations that the Secretary may carry out; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H10F324DC2E4140979B3B350D1947388B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make data available to third parties for validation, in accordance with applicable data privacy laws, including section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>, commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE099C0A8F5A3448DAEAB0C5E3C51C744"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a description of how the program will include education and training opportunities focused on infant and toddler development, including the developmental needs of infants or toddlers with a disability (as defined in section 632 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1432">20 U.S.C. 1432</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H011F3E0FFD614B2286373A86DD0F1870"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description, if applicable, about how the program will respond to the needs or goals identified by the applicable State in the statewide needs assessment or statewide strategic plan developed, updated, or implemented for purposes of a preschool development grant under section 9212 of the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3134C62B974B49B2A4E6EF7C0554A8C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HAA5D2CEDD495488DA0DA67002E4351AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure an equitable national geographic distribution of the grants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H975E561C638B4C2E983CC5FC06D4DDF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">award grants to applicants that propose to serve communities in rural areas and to applicants that propose to serve communities in urban areas;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4A29905D82C54ACC881BB9F76BEDF5FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>give priority to applicants located in areas with a documented shortage of childcare providers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H140ECCF6B9634D5AAAAD1A7AFB108A40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>give priority to applicants that provide child care services for infants and toddlers, child care services during nontraditional or extended hours, and inclusive child care services for children with disabilities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE7CA1B3419EE4A56A02D785391C4948D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>give priority to applicants that include an institution of higher education with a program of study in early childhood education or a consortium of such institutions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA7D8A823E48B4924B2FCEBA8F0535416"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give priority, if applicable, to applicants that demonstrate, in the application submitted under subsection (c) for a grant under this section, that the program to be funded with such grant will respond to the needs or goals identified by the applicable State in the statewide needs assessment or statewide strategic plan developed, updated, or implemented for purposes of a preschool development grant under section 9212 of the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDF1E809F23DA4CD8B9A9B6826045CDFD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Each eligible partnership receiving a grant under this section shall use such grant to establish, support, or expand career and technical education programs of study in early childhood education, which shall include one or more of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD0D07CD9F76348FF864A1DB334769D10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Educational materials and resources, including classroom instruction, work-based learning, support attainment of dual or concurrent enrollment credits, industry credentials such as a Child Development Associate, a preapprenticeship, and an apprenticeship through career and technical student organizations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5695150170F34CF9B1F1A90621718BC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Supporting the recruiting, hiring, and training of effective educators in early childhood education, including educators who became certified through State and local alternative routes to certification.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6687B1546CE64D5B91D64C4DE1269515"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improving career and technical education outcomes of students served by the eligible partnership through activities such as—</text>
<subparagraph id="H273C9EEAA72E4606B431EE3A9B51E31B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting the development and enhancement of innovative delivery models for career and technical education-related work-based learning (including school-based simulated work sites, mentoring, apprenticeship programs, work site visits, job shadowing, project-based learning, and skills-based and paid internships); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49E93534DEFD4DF697DEC7AA24F98DF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing academic and nonacademic wrap-around supports and services, including advising, tutoring, test preparation, child care assistance, dependent care assistance, transportation, and financial assistance (which may include scholarships or stipends), during the period in which such students—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="H954A83C540FE4B299CF57971994D03AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complete a Child Development Associate credential, early childhood education associate degree program, or baccalaureate degree program, as applicable;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HF1649F07083741CABE66547B119B6E15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access and complete State licensure or certification examinations; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HAA32C5C997D445CE8B9BD224F746DC26"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>receive opportunities to develop the necessary content knowledge and teaching skills in early childhood education.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3F2A3A928E34F0CB30BFA189E4E398A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Creating or expanding recruitment, retention, or professional development activities for career and technical education teachers, faculty, school leaders, administrators, specialized instructional support personnel, career guidance and academic counselors, and paraprofessionals, which may include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7D99CD4657A04C2496D5B306B9F3E1D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">high-quality teacher mentoring by experienced teachers in early childhood education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF30C9E070ACB4C969140D945FE45BD8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing resources and training to improve instruction for, and provide appropriate accommodations to, special populations, including the unique needs of teaching in rural or urban communities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H17CADD935A4F4F3A900A4B9AFD438C46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the integration of coherent and rigorous academic content standards and career and technical education curricula, including through opportunities for appropriate academic and career and technical education teachers to jointly develop and implement curricula and pedagogical strategies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9E93FF9034E47FA8FD87BBC2AAA838F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing resources or assistance with meeting State teacher licensure and credential requirements;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF083A906E08441568E094790C9E3590F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing initiatives that increase compensation for early childhood educators who attain a Child Development Associate credential, or an associate or baccalaureate degree in early childhood education; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5AD42CB3DA414F72AC81508038F8C314"><enum>(F)</enum><text>training for career guidance and academic counselors at the secondary level to improve awareness of postsecondary education and postsecondary career options in early childhood education, and improve the ability of such counselors to communicate to students career opportunities and employment trends in early childhood education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HED6DA6CAB2CA41E4BA0E4CCC4F8AA098"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation and annual report</header><text>Each eligible partnership receiving a grant under this section shall provide for an independent evaluation of the activities carried out using such grant and submit to the Secretary an annual report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HBDBC598AD510464F9A6A1BC80CDF36E8"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how funds received under this section were used;</text>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96CFFF3153904CE0BC0B468AAA4E7455"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the performance of the career and technical education program of study funded with such grant with respect to, at a minimum, the performance indicators described under section 113 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2323">20 U.S.C. 2323</external-xref>), as applicable, and disaggregated—</text> <subparagraph id="H2918C65A92C84BDBB0F87E828D7C432F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by subgroups of students described in section 1111(c)(2)(B) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(c)(2)(B)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF175E04C1F0A4A10AD59E69245DB12F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by each special population; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3848412978534553A129E49FA3DF232C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a quantitative analysis of the effectiveness of such program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD7F0E2A700A34D0BA018E646441170E8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant duration</header>
<paragraph id="HAAB16BD1369544D297F33FCF1FC00EB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a grant awarded under this section may not exceed a 5-year grant period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6DF6EAFC50E406BBA9BF9CC401CA60E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Secretary may extend the grant period for an eligible partnership for not more than 1 additional 2-year period if the eligible partnership demonstrates to the Secretary that the eligible partnership—</text>
<subparagraph id="H578D223C8F4E47DABD1081E3580D6FFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is achieving the program objectives for which the eligible partnership is receiving the grant; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H355E7A92D6B44A928B6659B7F495CBB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has improved education outcomes for students participating in the programs funded by such grant, including special populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF4B64B5FBBD942BEB77A4FA41AA3BF7D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26231396F6DD48A5AE4EA742E7E92992"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Perkins terms</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, any term used in this Act that is defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>) has the meaning given that term in such section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H76B2232E9CCA4D0883B965CA98C70A0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early childhood education</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2364A0600E804876B9C7CA7B2B73C8D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible child care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible child care provider</term> has the meaning given such term in section 658P(6)(A) of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858n">42 U.S.C. 9858n(6)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H892C6B48E4B844BE93746A5B6DBA6D75"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text>The term <term>eligible recipient</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(21)(A) of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302(21)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H68FA4E59B37A4117AB2559528420D73D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible partnership</header><text>The term <term>eligible partnership</term> means a partnership between or among—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H23112C782930402CA85BEFAABFA98508"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an eligible recipient; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H98E73738B9A444C2B0C62BB7D956BC45"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one or more of the following:</text>
<clause id="HFDD495617C8F4E67B66A4DFFF865A626"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An institution of higher education with a program of study in early childhood education or a consortium of such institutions.</text></clause> <clause id="H35300AF1CD5446D288ED5EB462BEA7AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An eligible child care provider.</text></clause>
<clause id="H7EC6926BDBCA4BC0ACC3F9D23400B7CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community stakeholder relevant to a career and technical education programs of study in early childhood education to be funded under this section, including a labor organization, a local or regional business or industry, or a local workforce development board.</text></clause> <clause id="HF86D62653E754367AD2B6F31689C73E6"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Child Care Resource and Referral Organization (as described in section 658E(c)(3)(B)(iii) of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858c">42 U.S.C. 9858c(c)(3)(B)(iii)</external-xref>)).</text>
                        </clause>
<clause id="HF99E79561A81401984066367CEB75D33"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A staffed family child care network.</text></clause> <clause id="HF3C5A7A53AFF4192BF43414432D5DD05"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A Head Start program (including an Early Head Start program) carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause>
<clause id="H444A82AEA3C34615A9AD590F707B9D85"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>An early intervention service provider.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A6A90643334480193692B9763EC8CA2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H15603C53F6B9430982B18D592FB9D0A3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Staffed family child care network</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>staffed family child care network</term> means a nonprofit organization—</text> <subparagraph id="HCBFDAA07DAC44C25B11E5166FFDF62D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that may be a component of a State or local child care resource and referral organization;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA2E14ACF1EE342F1B86F04D879246E24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that has at least one paid staff member; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD5C165A617544351AA2D0AFF761EBC8F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that offers evidence-based professional development, quality improvement support, business support, and technical assistance, including on achieving licensure as an eligible child care provider, to family child care providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

