<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5249FC52DC9044279EF395EC3A98D8AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6649 IH: Fit Vets Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6649</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a pilot program on providing access to a senior exercise program for enrolled veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7C8AEFF3488F4AF19969FF00D53B85C5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA8859FC1D1E84A769821F24DE12B3EF8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fit Vets Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCC480C5C448248BEBDAEC7291E232F53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on access to senior exercise program for enrolled veterans</header> <subsection id="H4818D35C48AA499192FD78728CF91B9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to provide to eligible veterans described in subsection (b) access to the health and fitness program referred to as <quote>SilverSneakers</quote>, or another evidence-based senior exercise program the Secretary determines comparable to such program, as part of the health care furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H196BBA4AE1324CFDA7CE3E3F77592B6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible veterans</header><text>An eligible veteran described in this subsection is a veteran—</text> <paragraph id="H64F7B71DED9A49649C9B7BBB25C3D785"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enrolled in the patient enrollment system under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D8B77D85A444F7184C97938CB79218B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>who satisfies the criteria for participation in the pilot program under subsection (a), as established by the Secretary in regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF7D9807B9E0F4BD39F38903C1D62696E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The Secretary may carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) on a national or regional basis, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF8E405E1751476393B526C8ECF1E3BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is three years after the date of the establishment of the pilot program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1055ED6473C74A94B9C1AA74B27A8CEE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (c), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report containing the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6850504A381C4431B3B9D44DD741AA93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rates of participation in such pilot program by covered veterans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8FCDCA04A57405999BF60DD3E675B17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The costs of such pilot program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA88C1324F1BE430EA15CF712E987E875"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An analysis of the effect of such pilot program on the health outcomes of participants, including with respect to physical fitness and chronic disease management.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2763E80127184F96B49655E9A6D36E32"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations by the Secretary on whether to make such pilot program permanent.</text></paragraph> </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

