<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR25062-Y5D-D0-YJ7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3998 IS: Promoting Innovation and Offering the Needed Escape from Exhaustive Regulations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3998</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a regulatory sandbox program under which agencies may provide waivers of agency rules and guidance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Innovation and Offering the Needed Escape from Exhaustive Regulations Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PIONEER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id3BB8540E4724431DB703D6851267B01E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idB4ABB3582550425D996BE5B16C2C4C69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id228F592817F441D58C04B4F2C6C8A1A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency; rule</header><text>The terms <term>agency</term> and <term>rule</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id17ece33c2b944490afa4f38f95a59564"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable agency</header><text>The term <term>applicable agency</term> means an agency that has jurisdiction over the enforcement or implementation covered provision for which an applicant is seeking a waiver under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1042BED7D698411089C9EA0CD09E0953"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered provision</header><text>The term <term>covered provision</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idD733BE5E20FE41B7AD7311C9C0A1D6B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a rule, including a rule required to be issued under law; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6C5EA2F8D3B841D8A8D921460C4716F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance or any other document issued by an agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id37f1fdf06cb3496aa04c197d8a59b04a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b2a3d1991c64862afebd5bc2dda747e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Economic damage</header><text>The term <term>economic damage</term> means a risk that is likely to cause tangible, physical harm to the property or assets of consumers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc5b7cfd88de4c1097bcf9a177e0ebaf"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Health or safety</header><text>The term <term>health or safety</term>, with respect to a risk, means the risk is likely to cause bodily harm to a human life, loss of human life, or an inability to sustain the health or life of a human being.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7647D720C6514C8E853E486B142FCA13"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Federal Regulatory Relief established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72DA6B1D7C224696BD5DB1992CB53FF6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the program established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFADDC8C6C1C3472EBBDC47AABE9FE610"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive trade practice</header><text>The term <term>unfair or deceptive trade practice</term> has the meaning given the term in—</text><subparagraph id="id5DC2D747510C4A04AC46A41F6B5F8479"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Policy Statement of the Federal Trade Commission on Deception, issued on October 14, 1983; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id596484117735405B8635828C9933957B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Policy Statement of the Federal Trade Commission on Unfairness, issued on December 17, 1980.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id349F44AB05D042E4A2B960189D1A07E2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Federal Regulatory Relief</header><subsection id="id25FB320F06F044DEBFC8EAF23394DF73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs within the Office of Management and Budget an Office of Federal Regulatory Relief.</text></subsection><subsection id="idCFA4BEFEECD24E02B6C6B5216E4CF402"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><paragraph id="id96EE4A5623B847FBA872005B9F8B3A38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be the Administrator or a designee thereof, who shall—</text><subparagraph id="id1905BE3F1E4E40D6992EB8C00057E178"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be responsible for—</text><clause id="idACE3CF0907664F879C382D8903498D52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establishing a regulatory sandbox program described in section 4;</text></clause><clause id="id853e3c023f4942b6af1cc0a04db0fb4e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receiving Program applications and ensuring those applications are complete;</text></clause><clause id="id30afff7451ea4851a5492bc418198dc0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>referring complete Program applications to the applicable agencies;</text></clause><clause id="idd6abfa82b25b44b7aa50cef968a7d9e7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>filing final Program application decisions from the applicable agencies;</text></clause><clause id="ide7549a0f64ac46d79e1c30a7a57f559b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>hearing appeals from applicants if their applications are denied by an applicable agency in accordance with section 4(c)(8); and</text></clause><clause id="id1F64B0EAB12D479DB3D9620531E55C4E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>designating staff to the Office as needed; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2C483997EE5D470088839D2F34E06103"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><clause id="id8efc881370f040abb829ebec2caa5d94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish a process that is used to assess likely health and safety risks, risks that are likely to cause economic damage, and the likelihood for unfair or deceptive practices to be committed against consumers related to applications submitted for the Program, which shall be—</text><subclause id="id2BB2AD8768D7465CA4DADB3653DACDAD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>published in the Federal Register and made publicly available with a detailed list of the criteria used to make such determinations; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4E6CB00BB4EA42C59A719D46536EDD7F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subject to public comment before final publication in the Federal Register; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7617F17968684C3FB078919F245C0F06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish the application process described in section 4(c)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3A608E7A3B054A9EA2686B23BC51B0B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory boards</header><subparagraph id="idEB60209B51BC4C46BBEE73146E5D053C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director shall require the head of each agency to establish an advisory board, which shall—</text><clause id="id0A802C4BA9F94BC798583DE122DDAF51"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be composed of 10 private sector representatives appointed by the head of the agency—</text><subclause id="id61b3a1e95f0c43259d3790dccb466af9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with expertise in matters under the jurisdiction of the agency, with not more than 5 representatives from the same political party;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3dc936f1e3c548239c748ec034277a42"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who shall serve for a period of not more than 3 years; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id0ab08dfb8c14416dbb7748af37f0a665"><enum>(III)</enum><text>who shall not receive any compensation for participation on the advisory board; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5136A46875FA42E3BDF7FBE2A1B3EA5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be responsible for providing input to the head of the agency for each Program application received by the agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88147f31622746a4bfc05075b9dc9f23"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>A vacancy on an advisory board established under subparagraph (A), including a temporary vacancy due to a recusal under subparagraph (C)(ii), shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment with an individual who meets the qualifications described in subparagraph (A)(i)(I).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC877C17713A148378DF38701B71263CD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conflict of interest</header><clause id="id86913CD7F4C646E79D19FA5A2F623675"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a member of an advisory board established under subparagraph (A) is also the member of the board of an applicant that submits an application under review by the advisory board, the head of the agency or a designee thereof may appoint a temporary replacement for that member.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4009FAFC490F4169A84BFBA9B1FD4A13"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Financial interest</header><text>Each member of an advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall recuse themselves from advising on an application submitted under the Program for which the member has a conflict of interest as described in section 208 of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id973f31991389464cb909f1dda69275dc"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Small business concerns</header><text>Not less than 5 of the members of each advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall be representatives of a small business concern, as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57077a30b27a45ed845ae8dfff58d776"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent an agency from establishing additional advisory boards as needed to assist in reviewing Program applications that involve multiple or unique industries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3A399A491836474382434231E64EF9D6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulatory sandbox program</header><subsection id="id356e3e2035134168be383de4af6af1d8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall establish a regulatory sandbox program under which applicable agencies shall grant or deny waivers of covered provisions to temporarily test products or services on a limited basis, or undertake a project to expand or grow business facilities consistent with the purpose described in subsection (b), without otherwise being licensed or authorized to do so under that covered provision.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9F378F0A572F484DB7DE43016C8A6AAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Program is to incentivize the success of current or new businesses, the expansion of economic opportunities, the creation of jobs, and the fostering of innovation.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2B1457579AF740B18438D462C0895996"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application process for waivers</header><paragraph id="id8d877d48426d434d8d3871219280de30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall establish an application process for the waiver of covered provisions, which shall require that an application shall—</text><subparagraph id="id9B7389DD83C5470A85D62B03CADB552D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>confirm that the applicant—</text><clause id="idFFDA962494974895962FC5E4AA0096B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Government; and</text></clause><clause id="id922092b77f6043899a8f994ce075dd61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has established or plans to establish a business that is incorporated or has a principal place of business in the United States from which their goods or services are offered from and their required documents and data are maintained;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4590d64605fd4c20afb7481109c7357f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include relevant personal information such as the legal name, address, telephone number, email address, and website address of the applicant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c52aac004c44176a24b4419b908fada"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disclose any criminal conviction of the applicant or other participating persons, if applicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0cf0df70ef04454f9ed7938de8d5836f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>contain a description of the good, service, or project to be offered by the applicant for which the applicant is requesting waiver of a covered provision by the Office under the Program, including—</text><clause id="idcd1c48ab59a941e9955ec493ccbddedd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how the applicant is subject to licensing, prohibitions, or other authorization requirements outside of the Program;</text></clause><clause id="idc5d2ae3e5aa145e2a60e528163f4efa2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each covered provision that the applicant seeks to have waived during participation in the Program;</text></clause><clause id="ide2e5b2ec274a417d9bf32748158c8a0a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how the good, service, or project would benefit consumers;</text></clause><clause id="id5ba72e6a5b0740a5805c54968ca3d633"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>what likely risks the participation of the applicant in the Program may pose, and how the applicant intends to reasonably mitigate those risks;</text></clause><clause id="id75efce4809e042fa936ef35a92e0245b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>how participation in the Program would render the offering of the good, service, or project successful;</text></clause><clause id="idf145a907d0aa458c885db55b01abaa5c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of the plan and estimated time periods for the beginning and end of the offering of the good, service, or project under the Program;</text></clause><clause id="ida5a720937319418abb7202e1f3169df9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a recognition that the applicant will be subject to all laws and rules after the conclusion of the offering of the good, service, or project under the Program;</text></clause><clause id="idb129ba64a58b48df816e83ec2c42bdc1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>how the applicant will end the demonstration of the offering of the good, service, or project under the Program;</text></clause><clause id="id3e2e300f266441cbabe5b7d063d12948"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>how the applicant will repair harm to consumers if the offering of the good, service, or project under the Program fails; and</text></clause><clause id="id0ca3b361771e402f9d1b97eda475c487"><enum>(x)</enum><text>a list of each agency that regulates the business of the applicant; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29D5700A107443B6B9406EC4B076ACDB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include any other information as required by the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0FC31DF47B8B4BA18EE2BD192F06DDD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Office may, upon request, provide assistance to an applicant to complete the application process for a waiver under the Program, including by providing the likely covered provisions that could be eligible for such a waiver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19CBCAFD41344F24BADCA5734BDFD3FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency review</header><subparagraph id="id3750C4D3A0E84A43B4B152837B4E1E30"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Transmission</header><text>Not later than 14 days after the date on which the Office receives an application under paragraph (1), the Office shall submit a copy of the application to each applicable agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f172f2b26ef42eb856f4da948702cf6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The head of an applicable agency, or a designee thereof, shall review a Program application received under subparagraph (A) with input from the advisory board established under section 3(b)(2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC8F18ED8180D42C0A4105CB7E8E9D785"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In reviewing a copy of an application submitted to an applicable agency under subparagraph (A), the head of the applicable agency, or a designee thereof, with input from the advisory board of the applicable agency established under section 3(b)(2), shall consider whether—</text><clause id="id7375229170044680B17687987B416B58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the plan of the applicant to deploy their offering will adequately protect consumers from harm;</text></clause><clause id="id42c5676150b54c1f9d24916ff2730ec1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the likely health and safety risks, risks that are likely to cause economic damage, and the likelihood for unfair or deceptive practices to be committed against consumers are outweighed by the potential benefits to consumers from the offering of the applicant; and</text></clause><clause id="id1a582f281a3744f9a47f0f74b4bcf407"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>it is possible to provide the applicant a waiver even if the Office does not waive every covered provision requested by the applicant.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF169451DF6E5455B907B4002EA4EFFE0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Final decision</header><clause id="idD7450E24174A4BC08012883B04802674"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the head of an applicable agency, or a designee thereof, who receives a copy of an application under subparagraph (A) shall, with the consideration of the recommendations of the advisory board of the applicable agency established under section 3(b)(2), make the final decision to grant or deny the application.</text></clause><clause id="id42B5DA0B31934909AC6E8109CC9B5B58"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>In part approval</header><subclause id="id11ED45AE7EF049C4AFD62B63ED8A0EE7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If more than 1 applicable agency receives a copy of an application under subparagraph (A)—</text><item id="idb478559cb8ed47e7a435ed2edad7be9a"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the head of each applicable agency (or their designees), with input from the advisory board of the applicable agency established under section 3(b)(2), shall grant or deny the waiver of the covered provisions over which the applicable agency has jurisdiction for enforcement or implementation; and</text></item><item id="idDF9904AA2D05453295CBD0DA3D57DD10"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if each applicable agency that receives an application under subparagraph (A) grants the waiver under item (aa), the Director shall grant the entire application.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id1E71F4048B264B72BC5773080AFA09B3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>In part approval by Director</header><text>If an applicable agency denies part of an application under subclause (I) but another applicable agency grants part of the application, the Director shall approve the application in part and specify in the final decision which covered provisions are waived.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde411f6f5d62483394c60bc857d2df39"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Record of decision</header><clause id="id431de16c71b344029012ee85970c823c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a copy of an application under subparagraph (A), an applicable agency shall approve or deny the application and submit to the Director a record of the decision, which shall include a description of each likely health and safety risk, each risk that is likely to cause economic damage, and the likelihood for unfair or deceptive practices to be committed against consumers that the covered provision the applicant is seeking to have waived protects against, and—</text><subclause id="idfd083f0810194047a64a481a5b681369"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the application is approved, a description of how the identifiable, significant harms will be mitigated and how consumers will be protected under the waiver;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida60957a09c4d42d5810b727e9b21078c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the applicable agency denies the waiver, a description of the reasons for the decision, including why a waiver would likely cause health and safety risks, likely cause economic damage, and increase the likelihood for unfair or deceptive practices to be committed against consumers, and the likelihood of such risks occurring, as well as reasons why the application cannot be approved in part or reformed to mitigate such risks; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id13349bab24e84ff69fa17194339eb5ab"><enum>(III)</enum><text>if the applicable agency determines that a waiver would likely cause health and safety risks, likely cause economic damage, and there is likelihood for unfair or deceptive practices to be committed against consumers as a result of the covered provision that an applicant is requesting to have waived, but the applicable agency determines such risks can be protected through less restrictive means than denying the application, the applicable agency shall provide a recommendation of how that can be achieved.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id3bbaa2a2914b49ba9baf3691966b0c30"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No record submitted</header><text>If the applicable agency does not submit a record of the decision with respect to an application for a waiver submitted to the applicable agency, the Office shall assume that the applicable agency does not object to the granting of the waiver.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id6049b358203943f4aeda8f9aa78e0946"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The applicable agency may request one 30-day extension of the deadline for a record of decision under clause (i).</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id7BC06A74FAB243188A7F50B0537649EE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text>If the applicable agency provides a recommendation described in clause (i)(III), the Office shall provide the applicant with a 60-day period to make necessary changes to the application, and the applicant may resubmit the application to the applicable agency for expedited review over a period of not more than 60 days.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1A6DD569E5C9475BB74510705CE87165"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text>In considering an application for a waiver, an applicable agency shall not unreasonably discriminate among applications under the Program or resort to any unfair or unjust discrimination for any reason.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7F7A949E01D54102905E2DD424A3E0AF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fee</header><text>The Office may collect an application fee from each applicant under the Program, which—</text><subparagraph id="id0224649A24C1482AB8DBB506080DDD3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be in a fair amount and reflect the cost of the service provided;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA4BCC50C667A40F2B06031D2E6C302DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury and allocated to the Office, subject to appropriations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9F0C2EBBA0CE4B87A513A760442AE195"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall not be increased more frequently than once every 2 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCC18427D1BF144829685A398631D30BF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Written agreement</header><text>If each applicable agency grants a waiver requested in an application submitted under paragraph (1), the waiver shall not be effective until the applicant enters into a written agreement with the Office that describes each covered provision that is waived under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFACCC27B91444FC3B288E562550909F7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An applicable agency may not waive under the Program any tax, fee, or charge imposed by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59E9CFF327A84A51A3F0F88D10CF38F1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Appeals</header><subparagraph id="idB3AEBC80CFA94C66A1CFCF1A8A9DFE09"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an applicable agency denies an application under paragraph (3)(E), the applicant may submit to the Office one appeal for reconsideration, which shall—</text><clause id="id4A9C0256F58349A18BA2823E01352A3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>address the comments of the applicable agency that resulted in denial of the application; and</text></clause><clause id="id81adf775f315454db041564513dd7abc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include how the applicant plans to mitigate the likely risks identified by the applicable agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id246E190C01F0456985EA3CD91F44D26C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Office response</header><text>Not later than 60 days after receiving an appeal under subparagraph (A), the Director shall—</text><clause id="id7DA62AA79B284EC1A4A507F96E69A2C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine whether the appeal sufficiently addresses the concerns of the applicable agency; and</text></clause><clause id="idB33559523E2D4B6A9BAAF831635D9C8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id24116270629D4A9FB324E20A57D06CE8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the Director determines that the appeal sufficiently addresses the concerns of the applicable agency, file a record of decision detailing how the concerns have been remedied and approve the application; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id6DF2F7E3791340CDA75C83AAA3FD0068" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Director determines that the appeal does not sufficiently address the concerns of the applicable agency, file a record of decision detailing how the concerns have not been remedied and deny the application.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08B3231AD29843168EDF51E345E3A84E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text>The Office shall not unreasonably discriminate among applications under the Program or resort to any unfair or unjust discrimination for any reason in the implementation of the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7CD679D1838641758E56A2DB9483DE25"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><subparagraph id="id8536CA40FD39456882C0521269B6180B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Record of decision</header><text>A record of decision described in paragraph (3)(E) or (8)(B) shall be considered a final agency action for purposes of review under section 704 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05988BDB61664B62B2E99F12753C670A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A reviewing court considering claims made against a final agency action under this Act shall be limited to whether the agency acted in accordance with the requirements set forth under this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01D3340C127641139309A779ADC482AD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Right to judicial review</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to establish a right to judicial review under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF076C4A3E15E4EF88E13AABEAF5D4913"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of waiver</header><paragraph id="id71067B5F8F8E465FA7A67555131CD30C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial period</header><text>Except as provided in this subsection, a waiver granted under the Program shall be for a term of 2 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCA9A0A7F0C6E4454A6A93982D3296FC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuance</header><text>The Office may continue a waiver granted under the Program for a maximum of 4 additional periods of 2 years as determined by the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9408FB60E0C041148F6714F191399369"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 30 days before the end of an initial waiver period under paragraph (1), an entity that is granted a waiver under the Program shall notify the Office if the entity intends to seek a continuance under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD8FC2E5AD6074CD78B1B52B4ADE41FC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revocation</header><subparagraph id="id6fa4b992efcf4430ba7d8ba084fe84b4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Significant harm</header><text>If the Office determines that an entity that was granted a waiver under the Program is causing significant harm to the health or safety of the public, inflicting severe economic damage on the public, or engaging in unfair or deceptive practices, the Office may immediately end the participation of the entity in the Program by revoking the waiver.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4152092dd9dc4932aaf77859b68984fd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>If the Office determines that an entity that was granted a waiver under the Program is not in compliance with the terms of the Program, the Office shall give the entity 30 days to correct the action, and if the entity does not correct the action by the end of the 30-day period, the Office may end the participation of the entity in the Program by revoking the waiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id492E9B2857AB4EA7B7A8A01C71F545F9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>An entity for which a waiver is granted under the Program shall be subject to the following terms:</text><paragraph id="id22941a95073f4136b637458a7f2e2897"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A covered provision may not be waived if the waiver would prevent a consumer from seeking actual damages or an equitable remedy in the event that a consumer is harmed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ecfa39916b941af87024e984e9d5808"><enum>(2)</enum><text>While a waiver is in use, the entity shall not be subject to the criminal or civil enforcement of a covered provision identified in the waiver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c107994e290454e81f2b5b4a0f13569"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An agency may not file or pursue any punitive action against a participant during the period for which the waiver is in effect, including a fine or license suspension or revocation for the violation of a covered provision identified in the waiver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida241396c95ad4c9e9682613439666191"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The entity shall not have immunity related to any criminal offense committed during the period for which the waiver is in effect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80dab16785d6475f84e57e56519d39de"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Government shall not be responsible for any business losses or the recouping of application fees if the waiver is denied or the waiver is revoked at any time.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDA74F371A9F5434AB14A70E42F25CBAF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consumer protection</header><paragraph id="idC87A279A1F1D4148A2C6F5C103A6087A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before distributing an offering to consumers under a waiver granted under the Program, and throughout the duration of the waiver, an entity shall publicly disclose the following to consumers:</text><subparagraph id="idae3f00b078a54ae6a3878e5245ee52cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name and contact information of the entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65fcea4e111145d29e3285240c3771d1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>That the entity has been granted a waiver under the Program, and if applicable, that the entity does not have a license or other authorization to provide an offering under covered provisions outside of the waiver.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b74a3cdc7f44a6a81c4f3dd49b564f9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If applicable, that the offering is undergoing testing and may not function as intended and may expose the consumer to certain risks as identified in the record of decision of the applicable agency submitted under section 4(c)(3)(E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8f998deef8d40f9ae13b90929d13eb1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>That the entity is not immune from civil liability for any losses or damages caused by the offering.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac26d0bd7adb452eb11b8f876f5f4baf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>That the entity is not immune from criminal prosecution for violation of covered provisions that are not suspended under the waiver.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce6f68fbd659468682e198f7ef5ee91b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>That the offering is a temporary demonstration and may be discontinued at the end of the initial period under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d8abde3ec50463aaa83a5627dae4d6a"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The expected commencement date of the initial period under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida217e227592d443f82632d5272f4050c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The contact information of the Office and that the consumer may contact the Office and file a complaint.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id62c83e620419487ab8868606665ae037"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Online offering</header><text>With respect to an offering provided over the internet under the Program, the consumer shall acknowledge receipt of the disclosures required under paragraph (1) before any transaction is completed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0248a94172474deda8435d2845b60661"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Record keeping</header><paragraph id="id2CD6502A448D426E92ACE932A4534442"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity that is granted a waiver under this section shall retain records, documents, and data produced that is directly related to the participation of the entity in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id407b125d2ab54afdb9846e4c7b60b9f0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification before ending offering</header><text>If an applicant decides to end their offering before the initial period ends under subsection (d)(1), the applicant shall submit to the Office and the applicable agency a report on actions taken to ensure consumers have not been harmed as a result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2ac5159ea7548dc8fc4d7d4f384f2fa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Request for documents</header><text>The Office may request records, documents, and data from an entity that is granted a waiver under this section that is directly related to the participation of the entity in the Program, and upon the request, the applicant shall make such records, documents, and data available for inspection by the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddce0e8b117d243f98e44381d8ebb1914"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification of incidents</header><text>An entity that is granted a waiver under this section shall notify the Office and any applicable agency of any incident that results in harm to the health or safety of consumers, severe economic damage, or an unfair or deceptive practice under the Program not later than 72 hours after the incident occurs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBEDB1626BE2645F2B8C6E23AD5E4B71B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="id93BB9C80C2784DFE803E7CDF8E81AE91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entities granted a waiver</header><subparagraph id="idC704A54E3A0544E09635C92F11BD2712"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any entity that is granted a waiver under this section shall submit to the Office reports that include—</text><clause id="id822584dd02d945519e4dc2fdd2e53c26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how many consumers are participating in the good, service, or project offered by the entity under the Program;</text></clause><clause id="id934c1260d6b94550bb98549d2c83ed44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of the likely risks and how mitigation is taking place;</text></clause><clause id="id3294957c62b2452f84995fa747b1e786"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any previously unrealized risks that have manifested; and</text></clause><clause id="id1225992435614e4892e376130c1f5d63"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of any adverse incidents and the ensuing process taken to repair any harm done to consumers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA8AEB1792C16403BB147C5EA07FA381E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>An entity shall submit a report required under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="id6ce06b4241e34f5595eaad05b2b298d0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>10 days after 30 days elapses from commencement of the period for which a waiver is granted under the Program;</text></clause><clause id="id1EE0AF56F8D94D94B73732DAD2F62CD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>30 days after the halfway mark of the period described in clause (i); and</text></clause><clause id="idD0E0C910B19E44E3804143236FA81CBE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>30 days before the expiration of the period described in subsection (d)(1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1F8B9FD8907943D4B9703BB127AB8CE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report by Director</header><text>The Director shall submit to Congress an annual report on the Program, which shall include, for the year covered by the report—</text><subparagraph id="idd07de6922381430c9fbf057719b88c38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of applications approved;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d3a2c28defa47158e96956cee72abaf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name and description of each entity that was granted a waiver under the Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74f420002ab849aca81b1b49139f59d1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any benefits realized to the public from the Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0cc117f05e77473a977648fc27611e8f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any harms realized to the public from the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idec353261fbf44979a76694789d8816df"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Special message to Congress</header><paragraph id="id3ebb673b1bd54ecf9d4e8ea1205254da"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered resolution</term> means a joint resolution—</text><subparagraph id="id8374bfa987404cd096da9da178449b14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which contains only—</text><clause id="id588a3efa73ba47b4a1a2f63ed6bc82e3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of some or all of the covered provisions that were recommended for repeal under paragraph (2)(A)(ii) in a special message submitted to Congress under that paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="ide5bcd5b0952d46ee9c517bfd23813e68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a provision that immediately repeals the listed covered provisions described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii) upon enactment of the joint resolution; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35bb3849cae542bbae4b756d347acd56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon which Congress completes action before the end of the first period of 60 calendar days after the date on which the special message described in subparagraph (A)(i) of this paragraph is received by Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bd8872b2c5145c4b56bd6584ccac22a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><subparagraph id="idebd7cd76a85b42b3b08dad4b301548e8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the first day on which both Houses of Congress are in session after May 1 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress a special message that—</text><clause id="idc0e2b8245d8a4bacafa4539c2deb321b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>details each covered provision that the Office recommends should be amended or repealed as a result of entities being able to operate safely without those covered provisions during the Program;</text></clause><clause id="idc0b3433f72224be481856bd776f5703e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lists any covered provision that should be repealed as a result of having been waived for a period of not less than 6 years during the Program; and</text></clause><clause id="id68c143e9b474462392f5d45fd4f85969"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>explains why each covered provision described in clauses (i) and (ii) should be amended or repealed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0472eec859b44c2cbdc587f4a25b1148"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Delivery to House and Senate; printing</header><text>Each special message submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text><clause id="idbc55b57d9ac54288a6efd2cc807782fd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>delivered to the Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="id734b683053c24d47a8de3d7263d1b4cf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>printed in the Congressional Record.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9d32cc3a7a940d7afd2a4c0f31487b1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedure in House and Senate</header><subparagraph id="id5aaafb06b15e4f9a877ceef021b28ed4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>A covered resolution shall be referred to the appropriate committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb8d4d50179c495998995fde5eac5ff5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Discharge of committee</header><text>If the committee to which a covered resolution has been referred has not reported the resolution at the end of 25 calendar days after the introduction of the resolution—</text><clause id="idedbb57932bb145b2b3f189ac89ad601e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the resolution; and</text></clause><clause id="id26cd5e7a70b3495c96d6fd83e43a6dcb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb865fd28a756424491f3af37484217a0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Floor consideration in the House</header><subparagraph id="id6ba42fdc98174a8e8c28bc0b81ffc3f4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Motion to proceed</header><clause id="idf545beb553864ad29abaa38c082aa606"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>When the committee of the House of Representatives has reported, or has been discharged from further consideration of, a covered resolution, it shall at any time thereafter be in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution.</text></clause><clause id="id8fd88c7ba6bf45479f6f8f55e67a6427"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Privilege</header><text>A motion described in clause (i) shall be highly privileged and not debatable.</text></clause><clause id="idc158629343084d7ba6aaa41952581be8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>No amendment or motion to reconsider</header><text>An amendment to a motion described in clause (i) shall not be in order, nor shall it be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba386fd6f268418490341b4778b63e62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Debate</header><clause id="id4448293bf1aa476aa49fd44008f00d7f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Debate in the House of Representatives on a covered resolution shall be limited to not more than 2 hours, which shall be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the resolution.</text></clause><clause id="id635069f7bf034a23803fe4645856ad43"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No motion to reconsider</header><text>It shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to move to reconsider the vote by which a covered resolution is agreed to or disagreed to.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee33354a998840a6a953f42a7a6fe62b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No motion to postpone consideration or proceed to consideration of other business</header><text>In the House of Representatives, motions to postpone, made with respect to the consideration of a covered resolution, and motions to proceed to the consideration of other business, shall not be in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65107078b66640658def4181e381267f"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Appeals from decisions of chair</header><text>An appeal from the decision of the Chair relating to the application of the Rules of the House of Representatives to the procedure relating to a covered resolution shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id891cf5e9a3a243ad8c0b5bce69b8afd7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Floor consideration in the Senate</header><subparagraph id="id4767bf3970e44a9f8da1a9a4bf19d7f0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Motion to proceed</header><clause id="idfb87227aa7cb4469bbbb85ae57aa08c9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, when the committee of the Senate to which a covered resolution is referred has reported, or has been discharged from further consideration of, a covered resolution, it shall at any time thereafter be in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution and all points of order against the covered resolution are waived.</text></clause><clause id="id5d2fc3158af1478b9455c148732cd043"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Division of time</header><text>A motion to proceed described in clause (i) is subject to 4 hours of debate divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the covered resolution.</text></clause><clause id="idf89ebe36b0d14405ba2858a3523aaef2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>No amendment or motion to postpone or proceed to other business</header><text>A motion to proceed described in clause (i) is not subject to—</text><subclause id="id657278feaf8f40a99aec2ca938e55bd9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>amendment;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida88fe2fa3cf04db3afee13da151355e3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a motion to postpone; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id0a065277508e490482a7a9449fcc9a5c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9302f6654a4043df9498c8c55b00fd2e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Floor consideration</header><clause id="ide3753a5634bd475c88dc76172dc19342"><enum>(i)</enum><header>General</header><text>In the Senate, a covered resolution shall be subject to 10 hours of debate divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the covered resolution.</text></clause><clause id="id75dcc909402748b9bb26521787d23254"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>In the Senate, no amendment to a covered resolution shall be in order, except an amendment that strikes from or adds to the list required under paragraph (1)(A)(i) a covered provision recommended for amendment or repeal by the Office.</text></clause><clause id="idef56db647e3440a9bf5a4d27be353303"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Motions and appeals</header><text>In the Senate, a motion to reconsider a vote on final passage of a covered resolution shall not be in order, and points of order, including questions of relevancy, and appeals from the decision of the Presiding Officer, shall be decided without debate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8193ff81268740189c4760f0fd2843dc"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Receipt of resolution from other House</header><text>If, before passing a covered resolution, one House receives from the other a covered resolution—</text><subparagraph id="ideb61ac6208fb4f0abdbedec720941965"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered resolution of the other House shall not be referred to a committee and shall be deemed to have been discharged from committee on the day on which it is received; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1df821fa8cd14c579006e1bb80a17e20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the procedures set forth in paragraph (4) or (5), as applicable, shall apply in the receiving House to the covered resolution received from the other House to the same extent as those procedures apply to a covered resolution of the receiving House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2062ac327b54b8ea7f491d9c95c7814"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rules of the House of representatives and the Senate</header><text>Paragraphs (2) through (6) are enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph id="idf711717c4c5f4e88915a37fab5ddd0cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives and the Senate, respectively, and as such are deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedures to be followed in the House in the case of covered resolutions, and supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent with such other rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01af86267f3347c6911f92e7f0871338"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1744C5E7C1364962964F70463CA28B3C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCCD557354C344A61AACCA7935A582617"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require an entity that is granted a waiver under this section to publicly disclose proprietary information, including trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAC32C803B535432FB1A899653A945D13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affect any other provision of law or regulation applicable to an entity that is not included in a waiver provided under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99342D7F720A46A584F4B1AD4CC58B47"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Office to carry out this section an amount that is not more than the amount of funds deposited into the Treasury from the fees collected under subsection (c)(5).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

