<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFD1AA3A9C9A4C319E479D3B20067348" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9502 IH: Protect Seniors and Veterans from Health Care Fraud Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9502</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to avoid duplicative, improper, or erroneous billings or payments for hospital care and medical services furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC972D9FFF9EF4526AADB728025FDB7A2" style="OLC"><section id="H3C83CE2D45C14592A07B8BC24F616A1C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Seniors and Veterans from Health Care Fraud Act of 2026</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H7E107B227B614B6FA4F9D1A9FC529765"><enum>2.</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding for reciprocal access to certain health care data between the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Health and Human Services</header><subsection id="H588148B062A549BAB72E881914F4653F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, for purposes of avoiding duplicative, improper, or erroneous billings or payments for hospital care and medical services furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to reciprocal access between the Veterans Health Administration and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to data and information on veterans who are concurrently enrolled in the patient enrollment system under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code, and—</text><paragraph id="HC4C04949456743F68A59CC1E5D50A4BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Medicare program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5882EFC66C27496A8672415AE864CD38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Medicaid program; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H116C1F679595466C992516B5F6E5BE04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a Medicare Advantage plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59A4DE66155C4CBA8AFAB9EA3880E2E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The memorandum of understanding required under subsection (a) shall include an agreement through which—</text><paragraph id="H77D5F080B44742F38E8A25364AA9F93B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Veterans Affairs transmits to the Secretary of Health and Human Services—</text><subparagraph id="HE709907666894370A794330135CBDF66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information relating to veterans who are—</text><clause id="H9DFC1F7EEFB248778AC9D2A0C5F02A1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enrolled in such system for patient enrollment; and</text></clause><clause id="H6CD356E8099B40028139DDBD7014C6B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in receipt of hospital care or medical services under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2855C47889641049B9CA7D735A70817"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines appropriate, including billing codes and diagnostic codes for such hospital care or medical services; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC51F6DC9078438C93D4870E72CE812F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services—</text><subparagraph id="H801659AE7EAA4487BB8016F2A063271C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses information transmitted pursuant to paragraph (1) to identify veterans who are concurrently enrolled in such system for patient enrollment and—</text><clause id="H1176D5FB49BA4102B04A9244D920B17D"><enum>(i)</enum><text> the Medicare program;</text></clause><clause id="H56326D9936464C159FFB010A32D3F757"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Medicaid program; or </text></clause><clause id="H20D7B52F6DFD41FBADFC33F0F2FE5604"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Medicare Advantage plan; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CC1CF91F9704D28B9597252C1315D15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transmits to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs—</text><clause id="HA6129FA154FB466DA97A710FF70C7B95"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of the veterans identified pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="H9B9DDFB3EA9C4A64A5A38A64D75440F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCAB87CFF8DA4FD5AE4450ABFE80996A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The memorandum of understanding required under subsection (a) shall be effective for a two-year period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs enters into such memorandum.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEDB70811D61D4B16BA2E70A39526CE46"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs enters into the memorandum of understanding required under subsection (a), and on a biennial basis thereafter during the period such memorandum is effective, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HECEA7BD4CED5430395379F07444A0021"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the activities of the Secretary carried out pursuant to such memorandum; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82E43353F9F34C86AFA764DAB473EF9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the Secretary with respect to the effectiveness of such memorandum in avoiding duplicative, improper, or erroneous billings or payments for hospital care and medical services furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2249167F303548B5A8174E0D4D0B15C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H79FD28D9579B4999BC29120DE1290801"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Medicaid program</term> means the program of medical assistance established under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0010828086F5497082BB897A9A67C5FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Medicare Advantage plan</term> means a Medicare Advantage plan under the program established under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA2A0C7C10104491B3F2165318B1304B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Medicare program</term> means the Medicare program under such title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

