<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL26235-425-MN-R21"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 S4319 IS: Rehabilitation Through Reading Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4319</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260416" legis-day="20260414">April 16 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require an independent review process for the prohibition of books at Bureau of Prisons facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rehabilitation Through Reading Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32dd3332ad8249c58d5f6357de962fd9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1054d0c64a144647a71e78dfc8a318bd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Bureau of Prisons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5caafc7c3d9b4e9eb7875cede940e397"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Professional librarian</header><text>The term <term>professional librarian</term> means a librarian who has a master's degree from a program accredited by the American Library Association.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21d155e5b9024c418ffe3ba9dbfdfc4f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Banned books in prisons</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cbb04ee4a154153b81722bc786d30f5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish a Publication Review Committee for the purpose of approving or disapproving the availability of books at Bureau of Prisons facilities.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf64fd2374f241a89d5c9ccc098bc88a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Publication Review Committee shall consist of not fewer than 5 members, including the Ombudsman established under section 2 of the Federal Prison Oversight Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/71">Public Law 118–71</external-xref>), 1 individual who is a professional librarian employed by the Bureau of Prisons, 1 individual in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons, and 1 individual with knowledge or expertise in First Amendment law.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcde631e9807e4c0db2bf8030bcb7346a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3196eca2e2a4f2c8e3711e32315298d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibiting a book</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the date of the establishment of the Publication Review Committee, the Director may only prohibit a book at Bureau of Prisons facilities if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42cd734efe154c97a1e27273058250e2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director submits a request in writing to the Publication Review Committee to approve such prohibition, including a detailed explanation of the reason for prohibiting the book; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3f955f92a4e41a7b1d4fc513d237c8e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Publication Review Committee approves such request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1173ef09737445658d2c1f5120edb2e7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appeal of a prohibited book</header><text>An individual in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons may submit to the Publication Review Committee an appeal to reverse the prohibition of a book in Bureau of Prisons facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cebc5c69912469291f593b896f894db"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determinations</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6c1e55d5c5f4482809f5513fd2350fb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which a request or appeal is submitted to the Publication Review Committee under paragraph (1) or (2), as applicable, the Publication Review Committee shall issue a final determination in writing approving or disapproving the availability of the book at Bureau of Prisons facilities in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb86a506f95b545ee93752083bad79187"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reason for prohibiting a book</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd55d1dac5dbc4887986142d1d63a7708"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A book may not be prohibited in order to eliminate a disfavored viewpoint or disfavored content.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id074d405b5e8343238c9af8cc046c4089"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether the prohibition of a book is based on a disfavored viewpoint or disfavored content, the Publication Review Committee shall determine whether the prohibition is substantially motivated by the viewpoint of the book, including if the book is deemed unpopular or repugnant, or otherwise violates the rights of incarcerated individuals to access information.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id364027c387de4a8db6f083df7280266a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Discretion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a determination issued by the Publication Review Committee shall be at the discretion of the Publication Review Committee and shall not require approval from the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id782b4d445f1c4ec788ecc1ec68df4039"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Maintaining access to a book</header><text>If an appeal is filed under paragraph (2) prior to the removal of the book from any library of any Bureau of Prisons facility, the book shall not be removed until the Publication Review Committee has made a final determination regarding the appeal.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb5428834a60a471db60467c5b8c1649a"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year following the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> an annual report detailing any books that were prohibited during the preceding fiscal year, including a summary of each appeal filed pursuant to section 3(c)(2) and the status and final outcome, as applicable, of each appeal.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

