<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25C78-R5D-2L-1SK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3544 IS: Federal Firearm Licensing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3544</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to require licenses to acquire or receive firearms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H23DA5D6C37C14E61A370A31C8788E6EE"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Firearm Licensing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idBD8D4AAAC3F94724A3366B4797C9C3BF"><enum>2.</enum><header>License for the purchase and possession of firearms</header><subsection id="H3190C4E4D1B646C5B3ABFAF1CA3DD3D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC18FCE3178E4DFEB098A99A7F3E129B"><section id="H926072B08C8E4B7AB7E9707A26221325"><enum>935.</enum><header>License for the acquisition, receipt, and possession of firearms</header><subsection id="HA46CE53AC9D94FDB88A9E809E4F2CB94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d), it shall be unlawful for any individual to purchase, receive, or possess a firearm unless the individual has a valid Federal firearm purchasing license.</text></subsection><subsection id="id04C73BA7DD91444182E45334E2AD6611"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Federal license to purchase, receive, or possess firearms</header><paragraph id="id689BA5605B3A4D7EA3DE548707DAB337"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish a Federal system for issuing a Federal firearm purchasing license to eligible individuals for firearms transferred to such individual or possessed by such individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63899221A46341D994522622F3F6C226"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The system established under paragraph (1) shall require that—</text><subparagraph id="HAB343B8FDC4D47BD94E9171892E67892"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual shall be eligible to receive such a license if the individual—</text><clause id="H11A56EF5905E4BA581860A15A705A1A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has completed training in firearms safety, including—</text><subclause id="idE7387CF30769410189C880C12FFF51F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a written test, to demonstrate knowledge of applicable firearms laws; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idB1AC0ED400824931AD6AE05598DBEC41"><enum>(II)</enum><text>hands-on testing, including firing testing, to demonstrate safe use and sufficient accuracy of a firearm; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD32D6190B3C242BD94608EEB6579E6EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as part of the process for applying for such a license—</text><subclause id="HFBA0FE1D89FF4D9BB2E5ECF1C47B1A40"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has submitted to a background investigation and criminal history check of the individual;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2982915C733F4BD9BB5A36258B8C1288"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has submitted proof of identity;</text></subclause><subclause id="H644784FE37F44DE2B792CA0E6CD11824"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has submitted the fingerprints of the individual; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id636cd1fb910b448f84021b9b4c1a8f7c"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>has submitted identifying information on the firearm that the person intends to obtain, including the make, model, and serial number, and the identity of the firearm seller or transferor;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7BB8A40C796D42F49FE43D456368CDB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a license issued under the system is available at a designated local office, which shall be located in both urban and rural areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5584CAC6F4A34F738819D5EC01E4086C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall issue or deny a license under this section not later than 30 days after the date on which the application for such license is received;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF916434B232B44548BC691003199E0D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>each license issued under this section shall be valid for the purchase of a single firearm, which shall be purchased not later than 30 days after the date on which the license is issued;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F88D59C7BA64B1BA2286F9EEF431250"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a license issued under the system shall expire on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the license was issued; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4EE5489BBF95449CB68B3B0BC5647023"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall provide notice of an application for a license under this section to the relevant State and local officials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF41ADF73FDDF45F387C22654C0F3BFD5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Background investigation</header><subparagraph id="idCD65829D6CB149C18D124616ADFB7963"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before issuing a license under this section, the Attorney General shall—</text><clause id="idA2972B47FC374C468B6F4858AAC55CFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct a background investigation on the applicant; and</text></clause><clause id="id53C6A0E2E31F49B2BF651E7741A56974"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>deny any license if receipt or transfer of a firearm would violate subsection (d), (g), or (n) of section 922 or any provision of State law.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBA382CD180A34BBF8F81984DD7B639BB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Poses a danger of bodily injury</header><clause id="id0222749B5E54464FA9DEA6A8E574B3F3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Information from State and local officials</header><text>After receiving the notice described in paragraph (2)(F), relevant State and local officials may submit to the Attorney General information demonstrating that the individual poses a significant danger of bodily injury to self or others by possessing, purchasing, or receiving a firearm.</text></clause><clause id="id4C404662CFF7469AB510CF99A1DEBEB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Denial</header><subclause id="idB7948BD1B3CA44F6A6D1ED97C0C93506"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may deny a license under this section if the Attorney General determines that the applicant poses a significant danger of bodily injury to self or others by possessing, purchasing, or receiving a firearm, after examining factors the Attorney General considers are relevant to the determination, including—</text><item id="id85e0336c61774e37bc65c6dafd6c4641"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>history of threats or acts of violence toward self or others;</text></item><item id="idB82F0A60AEC345EF82A43EFE6C6C74DC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>history of use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force by the applicant against another person;</text></item><item id="id3E8F5FECD4044A0CB9321E086D58F13A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>whether the applicant is the subject of or has violated a domestic violence or stalking restraining order or protection order;</text></item><item id="idB2756842946B4CE290D13E6E9224C8EC"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>any prior arrest, pending charge, or conviction for a violent or serious crime or disorderly persons offense, stalking offense, or domestic violence offense;</text></item><item id="idE1E3E6A87BB1413799C1B7B2DA6362C2"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>any prior arrest, pending charge, or conviction for an offense involving cruelty to animals;</text></item><item id="id4F7388C3765744B996CA6956EB58C4ED"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>history of drug or alcohol abuse or involvement in drug trafficking;</text></item><item id="idD29F435D21CA4589B0D5C81E199BE832"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>any recent acquisition of firearms, ammunition, or other deadly weapons;</text></item><item id="id1418bedf48ce4e4882e7ca3301cbe597"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>involvement in firearms trafficking or unlawful firearms transfers; and</text></item><item id="id16c5db84e23448b7838c2e23b708deff"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>history of unsafe storage or handling of firearms.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id2097145FBF0046AEA9734EB7E25DF191"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>An applicant denied a license under subclause (I) may file an action in the appropriate district court of the United States for seeking review of the denial.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB26830C4DE4143E49620AFF14D7AD5C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to modify any other requirement for a background investigation relating to the acquisition or receipt of a firearm in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id99D711A61C1D42ADB02BBFB48E8DBFEC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revocation</header><subparagraph id="id5A182A0A46AD47968D2399D7CB4251C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall revoke a license issued under this section if the Attorney General determines that—</text><clause id="id16E27EBACCA14F01830F7D6197C60EDA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the licensee poses a significant danger of bodily injury to self or others by possessing, purchasing, or receiving a firearm; or</text></clause><clause id="idC6D1C0A818A049B6BAE3759277BB3720"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after a regular background investigation conducted by the Attorney General, the receipt or transfer of a firearm would violate subsection (d), (g), or (n) of section 922 or any provision of State law.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50592D4DCE724CD6A672E3F496EC2EC6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice and opportunity for a hearing</header><clause id="idBC733E68465C40A0B62B54DBB70AB6C3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon determining that the licensee should have their license revoked under subparagraph (A), the Attorney General shall provide notice to the licensee and to relevant State and local officials of the determination.</text></clause><clause id="id63EE1D91B06D429DB8065796DEE9ED18"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text>For revocations under subparagraph (A)(i), the Attorney General shall provide a licensee an opportunity for a hearing in the appropriate district court of the United States not later than 30 days after the date on which a license is revoked under this paragraph to appeal the revocation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF933D6FE417149DFAA2425ACB4CF35F3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish procedures to ensure that any firearm is removed from any individual when the individual’s license is revoked under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7B19D3011E6A40E78A632D675468174B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Return of firearms</header><text>A firearm removed under the procedures established under subparagraph (C) may be returned to the individual only if the individual’s license is reinstated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8185CA5D780E44A5BC2F9672897ED86D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The Attorney General—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8df8c4dd6938493e901d7e5401291c64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall establish procedures for the renewal of a license that requires that the applicant satisfies the requirements described in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id871003cb8d7846e8a67eaffc5e9e46cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may develop procedures and processes to consolidate renewal applications for individuals with multiple firearm purchasing licenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id96CD8B3F3478459BB17552DBE5CD4CAD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Enrollment in Rap Back</header><text>The Attorney General shall enroll each individual who is issued a license under this section in the Rap Back service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id177bea89df5448268229f6a899d6158a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any individual to sell or otherwise dispose of a firearm to a person unless the individual reports the transaction to the Attorney General not later than 3 business days after the date on which the firearm is sold or transferred, which shall include identifying information on the firearm seller and on the firearm transferee, including the make, model, and serial number.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3855250FAB5A4B2A81F7B75064C0B3EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State licenses</header><paragraph id="id2D6F6D384ED641D9A084DF8DEF3C3219"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to an individual in a State if the Attorney General determines that the State has a process for issuing a State firearm license to eligible individuals in the State with substantially similar requirements to those described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1A2BB726D993406CADED684D6419E11B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Attorney General may promulgate regulations that the Attorney General determines are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3CBDF07675FD4844BFD9CB12FC243265"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section"><quote>935. License for the acquisition or receipt of firearms.</quote>.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCFB5CC12746C4E12AB79CF391100A1EC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Point-of-sale background check</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7ec71844e69449680fde9e59df9b080"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFEF6C609533D409D8EB59CC0F7F858CD"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Point-of-Sale background checks</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6C3C6FB0D8ED48C0A29C0A58DE67F35C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person who is not a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer to transfer a firearm to any other person who is not so licensed, unless a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer has first taken possession of the firearm for the purpose of complying with subsection (t).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8C213AB4FB1343379019A6EA78B10078"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Upon taking possession of a firearm under paragraph (1), a licensee shall comply with all requirements of this chapter as if the licensee were transferring the firearm from the inventory of the licensee to the unlicensed transferee.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5E7E25364A6A42FEAC8B627AA7F03E0B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Return</header><text>If a transfer of a firearm described in paragraph (1) will not be completed for any reason after a licensee takes possession of the firearm (including because the transfer of the firearm to, or receipt of the firearm by, the transferee would violate this chapter), the return of the firearm to the transferor by the licensee shall not constitute the transfer of a firearm for purposes of this chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7FB6EFBC88314503933B6682CFBCDD77"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on transfer to certain unlicensed persons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 3 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9D78CD95F7624C048B64218156B97426"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69B427A606784AD894D4486DB7C22053"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Prohibition on transfer to certain unlicensed persons</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52F8E78F84544FED9CC581AFB4B4D520"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sell or otherwise dispose of a firearm to any person if such person does not have a license issued under section 935 or a substantially similar State law, as determined by the Attorney General, during the previous 30 days; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE2E575C0C64442CA89BE05A6AB76DCCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fail to report to the relevant law enforcement agencies the sale or disposal described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

