<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H916CA0BF7BCF4C59BFE36F15E5DE23FB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6431 IH: New Opportunities for Business Ownership and Self-Sufficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6431</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules governing the State administration of self-employment assistance programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H368B8A8A90554B549155D325364495A2" style="OLC"><section id="H2D01CA381C154CB29A432B604276CB0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New Opportunities for Business Ownership and Self-Sufficiency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB018ECCA4FC645119AD753BD1FD52BFB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of rules governing State administration of self-employment assistance programs</header><subsection id="HA167DACC58FD461C9E89B6609BB21A4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elimination of requirement that participants are likely To exhaust regular unemployment compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3306">Section 3306(t)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subparagraph (B) and by redesignating subparagraphs (C) and (D) as subparagraphs (B) and (C), respectively.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEC3FEBC039E14AC2BF4141ABED13BEE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of requirement To participate in self-Employment assistance activities</header><text>Section 3306(t)(3)(B) of such Code, as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF21C085F70D34FF8BEFEDC82916D327B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H09FB860910434B32ABEF8AEB5F2E20DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are participating in self-employment assistance activities which are approved by the State agency and either—</text><clause id="H1CD190E535834300AC811A4FAE49D182"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include entrepreneurial training, business counseling, and technical assistance; or</text></clause><clause id="H69B5FB54D8D846DE9FF2A9BDF707E2D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are performed pursuant to a business plan and market feasibility study submitted by the individual and approved by the State or an agency designated by the State; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H418BBF0DB12741C6AB290C4CE334E35D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Weekly certification requirement</header><text>Section 3306(t)(3)(C) of such Code, as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended by inserting <quote>and are certifying such activities on at least a weekly basis to an agency designated by the State</quote> before the semicolon at the end.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6B1479A21029434095ED4113E0EC0BEC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Adjustment of limitation on number of individuals participating</header><text>Section 3306(t)(4) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>5</quote> and inserting <quote>10</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB6513EB0D924407BB49E7D0B767EF0C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, except that nothing in this section shall be interpreted to prevent a State from amending its law before the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BEFCA544A1949F08124E9B2DD0307FC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Issuance of regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall, after public notice and comment and subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget, adopt regulations to administer this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

