<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP26321-0V0-WN-4HM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4007 IS: Family Grocery and Farmer Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4007</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To restore competition in the meatpacking industry by reducing excessive concentration and market power and ultimately reduce prices for American consumers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Grocery and Farmer Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id7fad4074fe4f42019adaccfb272349e0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header><subsection id="idd427bd9f986c433b9509a93a2c3711a8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idfb5c4da1b29a4d09bf449ddd7e6b2e31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The meatpacking industry in the United States is highly concentrated, with a small number of firms controlling a dominant share of beef, chicken, and pork slaughtering and processing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff70c86d12904b429727ea5f6bbe0e08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>4 firms control 85 percent of the beef market and 67 percent of the pork market, which is up from 36 percent and 34 percent, respectively, in 1980.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13f194720ba44f0cb9a3cdb0344476e9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>4 firms control more than 60 percent of the market in chicken processing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id236539dd07914f5d9dc4c7f5524d880d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The scale and market dominance of large meatpacking firms create substantial barriers to entry and expansion for independent and regional processors, limiting competitive alternatives for producers and consumers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11b8613b67d7482aa3dd38b1622a67d8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>This highly consolidated meatpacking market has real consequences for farmers, workers, and consumers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd26955c900e1406dbcc3ce8175218ec2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Meatpackers have repeatedly used their market power in ways that suppress wages, destroy jobs through strategic plant shutdowns, and subject workers to extremely dangerous conditions while prices are to their advantage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88efcd52959a4e098f6f2ea03c1a4ccd"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Extreme concentration in meatpacking has resulted in diminished bargaining power for independent producers, increased vulnerability to unfair and discriminatory practices, and reduced economic viability for rural communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9442dd9ede3843398a0a8f63926a81f7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Consumers are paying more for meat, with the Department of Agriculture reporting that ground beef prices have increased about 16.4 percent since last year. Meanwhile, increased revenue is not flowing to farmers and ranchers as—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id209ee06a86ef4025bc65a47b34dd38c8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 1970, 70 percent of the consumer’s beef dollar went to cattle ranchers, but today, ranchers’ share of the consumer's beef dollar is closer to 30 percent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83b6f133628c4a399aef308bfbb443e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">profits remain with the big 4 covered meatpacking enterprises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id40261d358c0b46258fa9f47ba9448c0d"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The public interest requires competitive, transparent, and resilient markets for essential food products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id25870af69e26439abcc7ba27bd974a71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text><paragraph id="id8403fdf59b7c4e209454a32229f8c9d4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>restore competition in the meatpacking industry by reducing excessive concentration and market power;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef5ef625e9594250838da9c55249308c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit and reverse mergers and acquisitions in the meatpacking sector that have materially lessened competition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id870712cc3c2d4b5f90c58f4b4b0d2a9a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>authorize and require structural separation, divestiture, or breakup of dominant meatpacking firms, where necessary, to restore competitive market conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9548f673ed6241dfae52fd6f3f098902"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that no firm retains or expands market power in United States food and agricultural markets through capital obtained by corruption, bribery, or other unlawful conduct;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1bbbbcc3813440ed81bbecbd1f24696e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>deny competitive advantage derived from foreign state-backed or non-market financing that undermines fair competition in United States markets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd53997cffca14d2c9d19fe389f9589b3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>protect independent cattle producers from abusive, coercive, or discriminatory practices arising from excessive buyer concentration;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe957190b3944828bf8a54f90b158e5f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure that any restructuring of the industry results in safer, fairer, and more sustainable jobs for workers across the supply chain;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida034e72573094f31beeff120b9ce8edc"><enum>(8)</enum><text>promote the growth and viability of independent and regional meat processors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecabb2e5433d46d6a7025a957c73cd87"><enum>(9)</enum><text>help bring prices down for families in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id63efd81d6bf0448eb658c38c7cbb0d52"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2a14190bb754c9eb57cf059925c9896"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beef meatpacking market</header><text>The term <term>beef meatpacking market</term> means the market for cattle slaughter and beef processing in the United States, including the national beef market and regional beef markets.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida063753c096a47cd85f67734a6608528"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c57881d069c46d499c7c641f8e9afcf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered feedlot</header><text>The term <term>covered feedlot</term> means a feedlot with a capacity of 24,000 head of cattle or more.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35073685ab744674bf027db2c5efbb46"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise</header><text>The term <term>covered foreign-controlled covered meatpacking enterprise</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3d9bd9440cb468ba29061efca296803"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">JBS S.A. and its affiliates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b507db5ffa04cccb214282311500e70"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other entity, as determined by rule by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b1e5af9ada842bc8b3bb68f280d836c"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered meatpacking enterprise</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fd9572a75bc42d3b104f88638dc6d73"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>covered meatpacking enterprise</term> has the meaning given the term <term>packer</term> in section 201 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/191">7 U.S.C. 191</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3a2a78f7f634c239320afa1b1112e52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall, by rule, define for purposes of this Act—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9474fb7a62dc4550989de64aba21e42a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a de minimus threshold of volume or revenue below which a person shall be excluded from the definition of a covered meatpacking enterprise under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id8adb69f7dd384594a2df2f4c94195103" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirements that place a person under common control or in affiliation with a covered meatpacking enterprise such that the entity shall be included in the definition of a covered meatpacking enterprise under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b06f25859ae4efaa785593b65ed2dad"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>CR<enum-in-header>4</enum-in-header></header> <text>The term <term>CR4</term> means the sum of the market shares of the 4 largest firms in the relevant market.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf14232ccc9a4120baee5461d5047061"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Farmers’ cooperative</header><text>The term <term>farmers’ cooperative</term> means an organization exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/521">section 521</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf4eb14094994cc7ba1f3b7aec46990d"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Feedlot</header><text>The term <term>feedlot</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52442b5824d4403fbc34efc5ea0e4602"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any facility that is used in its entirety or in part for the purpose of feeding livestock to be slaughtered, or to be sold for slaughter, by another; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id874656a84faf48e18c89517cdf176a8d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include feeding incidental to the sale or transportation of livestock.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb532bbce77fa47c8977ff272b2051d3e"><enum>(9)</enum><header>HHI</header><text>The term <term>HHI</term> means the Herfindahl-Hirschman Index, calculated as the sum of the squares of the market shares of all firms in the relevant market.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9585a6d4821403da20e039cbd8f2cba" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(10)</enum> <header>Line of protein</header> <text>The term <term>line of protein</term> means livestock, livestock products (as defined in section 2 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/182">7 U.S.C. 182</external-xref>)), poultry, poultry products (as defined in section 4 of the Poultry Products Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/453">21 U.S.C. 453</external-xref>)), meats, or meat food products (as defined in section 1 of the Federal Meat Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/601">21 U.S.C. 601</external-xref>)) in each of the following product categories:</text>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1aebc4f2f6b646a4b4633c0e9ca10bff">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Beef (including cattle slaughter, beef processing, and beef products).</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id0e92e1b32df84e2e8cc869c5dab864d9">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Pork (including hog slaughter, pork processing, and pork products).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idc3bbd5a29f1041379a81fb62961b93e4"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>Poultry (including chicken slaughter, processing, and chicken products).</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id04cd65f462934211a865e622f7c0f83f" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>Any additional category, as the Commission may, by rule, designate to prevent evasion of this Act.</text>
                </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e3b10a0decf424ebd12edb29f5916a9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Market share</header><text>The term <term>market share</term> means the share of total slaughter or processing capacity, volume, or sales in the relevant market, as determined by rule by the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida25ec7309ae245d69f53294aa6e81ccb"><enum>(12)</enum><header>National beef market</header><text>The term <term>national beef market</term> means the market of the United States as a whole, or such broader integrated geographic market as the Commission determines appropriate, for the slaughter of cattle and processing of beef products.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88253221131541dbbc654cf046a89780"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Regional beef market</header><text>The term <term>regional beef market</term> means a geographic market defined by reference to the regional direct slaughter cattle reporting regions of the Department of Agriculture, or any successor system of regional delineation the Commission determines better reflects competitive conditions.</text></paragraph></section><title id="id39c8f2dfc1f942e796d7f2fc5a07cea1" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Breaking up the meatpacking industry</header><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7967c2500ffc49878ae4a04fc6453f20"><enum>101.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation on operation in multiple lines of protein</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c721fcfbc2c4b8fb408a2a643b2587e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9942aff477f4f79b84cda250feb5d64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for a covered meatpacking enterprise to own, control, or operate any entity or combination of entities that engaged in more than 1 line of protein in the United States, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea59d96ca8cc4e45b5dcad78e166de39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on new acquisitions</header><text>On and after the date of enactment of this Act, no covered meatpacking enterprise may acquire, directly or indirectly, control of assets or operations in a line of protein other than the line of protein in which the covered meatpacking enterprise already engages, in violation of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10cf0f1c115c42d48dfb3d105d791a41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Divestiture required</header><text>The Commission shall require divestiture pursuant to section 102 of any covered meatpacking enterprise that violates subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="ide3e02890dac54731acf6617f8b78a742"><enum>102.</enum><header>Divestiture authority</header><subsection id="idc91ce08fb72f4da9b1a636d4b780bc0c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Commission authority</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d5f402067d54589aec39adb3dd97a84"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>With respect to any violation of section 101, the Commission shall develop and oversee a divestiture plan for the covered meatpacking enterprise that provides for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9ca8fca217843b4a31094b6dd0b5be4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sale of assets to 1 or more independent entities; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2bc570a9972c4720823ae4013c7b4479"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the creation of 1 or more new, independent entities through spin-off or other structural separation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5db4382f43154d9d8d15ec76ec84004f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>In exercising its authority under paragraph (1), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4092f0e359cb42ba9f189fac2720300a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">act in a manner consistent with the public interest in promoting competition, protecting consumers, producers, and workers, and ensuring a resilient food supply, as described in section 602; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62e40aa49d2940b0886406188d855766"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the maximum extent practicable, structure divestitures under this section so as to—</text><clause id="idad1993d1e2074334b10222a35671595f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>avoid reconcentration of assets;</text></clause><clause id="id5a772ee37d4446c9afc49dce9a87bc74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage ownership and control of divested assets by farmers’ cooperatives, worker owned enterprises, and other small or mid sized businesses; and</text></clause><clause id="id561a0a2e259a40cbb693047b0b162161" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prevent reacquisition of divested assets by firms whose market power contributed to the need for divestiture.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id27ce48d199ad4d329f9b4b6f50eea4e3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition; compliance plans</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id483889fc25754d2b938ab879375c7c2d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall develop a plan for the divestiture of each covered meatpacking enterprise that, as of the date of enactment of this Act, is engaged in the processing of more than 1 line of protein in violation of section 101.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id672ffe6616ad411ea0142f33201112e1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the development of a plan under this section, a covered meatpacking enterprise shall submit to the Commission any comments on the plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id941732c8f4a5471aadfc84ffd6d373cc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval of plan</header><text>Following the end of the comment period under paragraph (2), the Commission shall consider and respond to significant comments received under that paragraph and approve a final version of the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="id8260bf3cccc643eda9edf1a6a6ad3b22" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Specific rules for consolidation in beef meatpacking market</header><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id831aa48c2a4c43e9b3efbc12f773db64"><enum>201.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on unlawful horizontal consolidation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall require divestiture pursuant to section 202, as applicable, if in a regional beef market or in a national beef market—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09f81370c1244847b89c755091ddbb7a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the HHI exceeds 1800;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55baed7110714278b8a654f047da6f4d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the CR4 exceeds 50 percent; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1cd8a30743b48fdb383517574494b84"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any covered meatpacking enterprise has a market share of 30 percent or more.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id8919bdddf5f74ca6a703e36911acdbfe"><enum>202.</enum><header>Regional and national beef market divestiture authority and process</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id926f6a70acc2434195b4ba28fb11093c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Divestiture under this section may consist of—</text><paragraph id="idb9eae2efd14f430fac58391ef7d8bfa5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sale of 1 or more entities, facilities, or business units to 1 or more independent entities; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1bc13d9805874f1780b3b1bb5bca025e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the creation of 1 or more new, independent entities, including through spin-offs or other structural separation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5ab024a3b285423baa93e481f1d697e8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Divestiture in regional beef markets</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d3182e9cad84e20a636dc0b6f6f1d66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd16ec1235ebd47f489d5808f1ec0f458"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Violation under HHI or CR4 measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a condition described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 201, the Commission shall order divestiture in the regional market as follows:</text><clause id="id61a49fc43a0442ee91ff79787870245d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The largest covered meatpacking enterprise in the regional beef market that owns multiple beef slaughter or processing entities in that region shall divest its largest entity, facility, or business unit in that region.</text></clause><clause id="id0d852ce062e9405c992f9d6cd515e39a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>After the divestiture required under clause (i), the Commission shall reassess the concentration in the regional beef market under section 201(a).</text></clause><clause id="id916a7b3091724a74926938c226101310"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If 1 or more thresholds described in section 201 is met after the reassessment under clause (ii), the Commission shall repeat the process described in clauses (i) and (ii) as necessary, including by ordering further divestitures, until no threshold described in section 201 is met or until the Commission determines that further divestiture would not reduce market concentration.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8c70e580182415b9de8f2461e9694f5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Violation under single firm market share measure</header><text>With respect to a condition described in section 201(3), the Commission shall order divestiture in the regional market of the covered meatpacking enterprise meeting that condition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfdfca0fbc76141a082a98a1a9c1a0e15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of equitable powers to deconcentrate the market</header><text>If the Commission is unable to order further divestitures under subparagraph (A)(iii) of paragraph (1) and 1 or more thresholds described in section 201 is still met, such as if the largest covered meatpacking enterprise has only 1 entity, facility, or business unit in the market which cannot be divided, the Commission shall use all equitable powers to otherwise deconcentrate the market until the Commission determines that none of the thresholds described in section 201 are met.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id846ae578a2c949ccb58e80661f50a1e0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Divestiture in national beef market</header><text>In the national beef market, the Commission shall apply a substantially similar process to the process described in subsection (b), as appropriate, to require divestiture by covered meatpacking enterprises (including by ordering divestiture of specified entities, facilities, or business units, or other assets) and use all equitable powers to deconcentrate the market until the Commission determines that none of the thresholds described in section 201 are met.</text></subsection></section><section id="idddede866be024f1db9e7acd8a00536c6"><enum>203.</enum><header>Vertical consolidation</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ab19ada282f457f804a9ffa81f3448f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that the long-term supply contracts and similar arrangements between large packers and large feedlots can be functionally equivalent to ownership, leading over time to consolidation of feedlots, reduced demand for cattle from independent producers, and diminished competition.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9fedd51d82a4062a1affb869cc4a67e"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No covered meatpacking enterprise in the beef line of protein may slaughter, in any calendar year, more than 10 percent of the cattle produced by any single covered feedlot.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26c6971fe3b6440e91af3182ef0bc4a4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c967f3b3f0d458fbaca80dadfc7e76c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered meatpacking enterprise violates subsection (b), any feedlot owner or operator that sold some percentage less than 10 percent of its cattle to that covered meatpacking enterprise during the calendar year of the violation may bring a civil action against the covered meatpacking enterprise in the Federal judicial district in which the feedlot is located or in an appropriate United States district court to recover—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54ef2deb60e14579bac690495e456320"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to 3 times the difference between the highest price the covered meatpacking enterprise paid for cattle from any covered feedlot and the lowest price the feedlot owner or operator received for cattle during the calendar year of the violation multiplied by the total number of cattle the feedlot owner or operator sold overall during that calendar year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09275f26c7464edeaf2baed1a2d38fc1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reasonable costs and attorney’s fees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc8c9d6c769e8414bb520294305bf7764"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalty to address private injuries</header><text>The Commission may impose on any covered meatpacking enterprise violating subsection (b) a civil penalty equal to the amount described in paragraph (1)(A) with respect to each feedlot owner or operator that sold less than 10 percent of its cattle to the covered meatpacking enterprise and shall use the amount recovered to compensate such feedlots.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="id8e652122af0b4c56963ecfd8f76f8ec9" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Prohibiting foreign leverage over the domestic beef and pork markets</header><section id="id577500919acd480bb986ed6843ea207e"><enum>301.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b52840d1ede4207a54245b9838cc02a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A significant portion of domestic beef, pork, and chicken processing capacity is owned or controlled by foreign-based multinational corporations, raising concerns relating to food system resilience, transparency, and national security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e71ea31e87f4fc19b30da32432bbe6d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>JBS S.A., a foreign-based multinational corporation, is the largest beef processor operating in the United States and has obtained substantial domestic meatpacking assets through a sustained acquisition strategy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc56ed9c8887b4e6ca4eea2918b82a6e8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2020, J&amp;F Investimentos S.A. (the parent company of JBS S.A.) agreed to pay more than $280,000,000 to settle Department of Justice and Securities and Exchange Commission charges relating to bribery and other corrupt practices involving foreign government officials to obtain preferential financing and other financial advantages from state-backed institutions. Capital obtained through such corrupt practices was used, in whole or in part, to finance acquisitions of meatpacking and food processing assets in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb49da660e7e84b02b8a500822d0677ab"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The use of corruption-derived or preferential state-backed financing to acquire United States agricultural assets distorted competitive conditions and disadvantaged firms that relied on lawful, market-based financing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7430e450d86443bb99665484f2289ec"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China has an increasing footprint in the food supply chain in the United States, with Smithfield Foods, owned by the WH Group of the People's Republic of China, holding a major position in United States pork processing and announcing in January 2026 its acquisition of Nathan’s Famous, an iconic brand of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb33e1998623d44ae8ab4f95633087591"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When major processing capacity and widely recognized brands in the United States move under the control of a foreign parent company, the public deserves to know how that affects competition, pricing power, and national security.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id787e6d2f407849178ebd4ec6918a3044"><enum>302.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Divestiture plans for covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprises</header><subsection id="id5fea110cfcd04d11b1b7a5bea7a71a45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise to operate in interstate commerce in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98c5c53a6c7e4de88574e8518b2a14bb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Divestiture required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ccb6f6a26fd44b2b7b2a401d121f4c9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall require each covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise violating subsection (a) to carry out a divestiture plan under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd32b49ed599141d581315e43136171af"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Structure</header><text>A divestiture plan of a covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise under this paragraph shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bacca230fff4fb39ff685cfd84adc92"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be developed by the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9e73e5ab1094452b040e60047c4153b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise to divest its United States meatpacking and food processing operations, which may require that such operations be—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadda5922dfee44aa9768171bfc114768"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transferred to 1 or more new, independent entities headquartered, incorporated, and controlled by persons domiciled in the United States; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5325da786ebb4fd1a38dfc40729a9b81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sold to 1 or more entities, subject to conditions necessary to preserve and enhance competition and safeguard national security interests, including, as appropriate, in consultation with relevant national security agencies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e08ce6dbf09455ebda7f9ff8732f297"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>In exercising its authority under paragraph (1), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7200933fdea047dc80205bf66b6e7698"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">act in a manner consistent with the public interest in promoting competition, protecting consumers, producers, and workers, and ensuring a resilient food supply, as described in section 602; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f8ed12b8bc24a3488c82fe1fd3dd561"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the maximum extent practicable, structure divestitures under this section so as to—</text><clause id="id3a199b0ce0c14f8cbd06d81cffbe0a1e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>avoid reconcentration of assets;</text></clause><clause id="id5e396d00ff484a11ae7abdc2250a789c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage ownership and control of divested assets by farmers’ cooperatives, worker owned enterprises, and other small or mid sized businesses; and</text></clause><clause id="ide0123d19bb8d474b8ae842339bdb3e30" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prevent reacquisition of divested assets by firms whose market power contributed to the need for divestiture.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb6799c17ac2a43899c6ac228127af0da"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration of corruption and unlawful conduct</header><text>In designing the divestiture plan under this paragraph, the Commission may take into account prior admissions and findings relating to corruption, bribery, and other unlawful conduct used to obtain financing for United States acquisitions, including settlements and judgments under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78dd-1">15 U.S.C. 78dd–1 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9206a99bc49749a6b7b24e243767cfae"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>With respect to a covered foreign-controlled meatpacker, the Commission may grant a single extension of not more than 90 days of the date on which the prohibition under subsection (a) would otherwise apply to the covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise if the Commission certifies to Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="ida09aee12913d451fb559773454651d0b" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a path to executing a divestiture under this subsection has been identified with respect to such covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b38a20ad7204e3da1d51ddfe04d0140" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evidence of significant progress toward executing such divestiture has been produced with respect to such covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde1287f401db47f9ae8f92196799f86c" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>there are in place the relevant binding legal agreements to enable execution of such divestiture during the period of such extension.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id105a7e5c96e54a2f99a6ec2ed58b4125"><enum>303.</enum><header>Review of other foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprises</header><subsection id="id1bbc26df896444ae881d7898c21cdcba"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall complete a study of the business practices, financing, ownership structures, and competitive effects of all foreign-controlled entities with significant meatpacking and related operations in the United States, including those of entities engaged in beef or pork production and processing.</text></subsection><subsection id="idaa44963b48964a0e95b4519340cdd547"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Commission shall consult with appropriate national security agencies, including the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Justice, and any other relevant agency as determined by the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="id43620fbd843d4ad7b0f40ff660c69998"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Authority To determine need for divestment</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd34a2fc857ab4d9e9a05f68bfae377c7"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may determine, based on the study and consultations under subsections (a) and (b), that divestment, structural separation, or other remedial action is needed with respect to such foreign-controlled entities to protect competition, national security, or the resilience of the United States food system.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id47693ef0578642429d2478f762dcc85f" commented="no">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
                        <header>Congressional review</header>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                            id="idb6f301e0068d4955b34ed12acec9b4b4">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
                            <header>Submission</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the Commission may require divestment, structural separation, or other remedial action under paragraph (1), the Commission shall submit to each House of Congress the determination under that paragraph and Congress shall review the determination pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                            id="id8e6591c78a93405b8bdfeff6835b48f7">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
                            <header>Review</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress may, by an Act of Congress, block a determination submitted under subparagraph (A) through the congressional disapproval procedure set forth in section 802 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="id3bcb04df55f644a1864e4a88e03d4686">
                            <enum>(C)</enum>
                            <header>Requirement</header>
 <text>Upon the expiration of the review period under subparagraph (B), the Commission may require the divestiture, structural separation, or other remedial action determined under paragraph (1).</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab8495e658834688ba0559de365cb5e8">
                    <enum>(d)</enum>
                    <header>Report to Congress</header>
 <text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> a report that includes a divestment decision with respect to each foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprise.</text>
 </subsection></section></title><title id="id75c1ab8a7c414b67a35217609a110614" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Bringing Prices Down for the American Family</header><section id="idc061e1db14884389bf02322fbf31a827"><enum>401.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idae8d06a43beb4801b0b54364303476fb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Families across the United States face persistently high prices for meat, which contribute significantly to overall food costs and household financial strain.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1eb7e55d215468eb4748f74b7756d0d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Concentration and limited competition in meat supply chains and retail markets can facilitate unfair and unjustly discriminatory pricing practices, including price discrimination that disadvantages certain retail grocers and the communities they serve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a407394661c47eb9a03c5bffa8da60e"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>Unfair and unjustly discriminatory prices and price discrimination for meat products can result in higher prices, reduced availability, and fewer choices for consumers, particularly in rural areas, low-income communities, and communities already experiencing limited grocery access.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc3977aef8a494139a19bcc7c9a3dcd73"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 406 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/227">7 U.S.C. 227</external-xref>), confers authority on the Commission with respect to the retail sale of meat, meat food products, and livestock products in unmanufactured form. Under section 406 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/227">7 U.S.C. 227</external-xref>), the Commission may exercise its authority, including its authority under the Federal Trade Commission Act, to prevent unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce in connection with such retail sales.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id37af21079eed43ce88944792bd484285"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The authority extends to conduct that results in unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail meat prices and to price discrimination in meat, which drives prices higher for independent, smaller, or neighborhood grocery stores, where such conduct constitutes an unfair method of competition or an unfair or deceptive act or practice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaf7322cf1654707b454a8ed9f88747c"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) declares unlawful unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce and authorizes the Commission to prevent such conduct through investigations, administrative proceedings, and judicial enforcement, including with respect to retail and wholesale sales of meat, meat food products, and livestock products in unmanufactured form where such sales are in or affect commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a1bc5c4314640719de2a6961a516f95"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Commission's authority under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), including as informed by its policy statements and enforcement precedent, provides an important tool to challenge unfair methods of competition, coordinated conduct, exclusionary practices, and unfair or deceptive acts or practices in retail and wholesale meat markets that may drive up prices, restrict output, or otherwise harm consumers, small and independent grocers, and fair competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id614181dd30e7468992c992f95d76d321"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Congress intends that the Commission fully and proactively utilize its authority under section 406 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, its authority under Section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), and all other applicable laws, to identify, prevent, and remedy unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail and wholesale meat prices and price discrimination that harms consumers, honest businesses, and competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3dc62a76f0bd4d238e7ee6ef77181b17"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The authority of the Commission under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/46">15 U.S.C. 46(b)</external-xref>) to require reports and answers to specific questions from persons, partnerships, and corporations enables the Commission to study and report on market structure, pricing practices, and competitive conditions in retail and wholesale meat markets, thereby informing effective enforcement and policymaking.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id670f0d5a051c483caa5813a4e3f091a8"> <enum>402.</enum> <header>Report on maximizing authority under section 406 of the packers and stockyards act, 1921, and related Federal trade commission authorities</header> <subsection id="iddce18261ce21485cad7e82d8fd0da13f"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Report required</header> <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the congressional committees described in subsection (c) a report describing how the Commission is using and maximizing, and plans to further maximize—</text>
                    <paragraph id="id83dbd546801742b5b9a14162680eb36d">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>its authorities under section 406 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/227">7 U.S.C. 227</external-xref>) and section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to address—</text>
                        <subparagraph id="id0d97180fc45e4a449515c7e43b2e3288">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail and wholesale prices for meat, meat food products, and livestock products in unmanufactured form; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="ideb9d1003d2214c3782e0fab2ce32007e">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>price discrimination in meat, including beef and pork, that results in higher prices or otherwise less favorable terms for independent, smaller, or neighborhood grocery stores; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ida78d5199e4ce40c6a36ac750a2801af6">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>its authority under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/46">15 U.S.C. 46(b)</external-xref>) to conduct studies and obtain information, including compulsory process where appropriate, regarding the structure, conduct, and performance of retail and wholesale meat markets, and the pricing, contracting, and merchandising practices of firms operating in those markets.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="idb8d8e8ae40044ea1962f822a3abee9af">
                    <enum>(b)</enum>
                    <header>Contents</header>
 <text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum—</text>
                    <paragraph id="idd2d956d14ad44d7ea97ff7d7156ae3cc">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>a description of the Commission's interpretation of its authority under section 406 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/227">7 U.S.C. 227</external-xref>), and section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), as those authorities apply to unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail and wholesale meat prices and to price discrimination in meat affecting retail grocers;</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id6d431b0dc51245079a082ed570b5bba2">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a description of any policies, guidance, rules, or enforcement priorities the Commission has adopted, revised, or is considering to better detect, deter, and remedy such conduct using its authority under section 406 of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/227">7 U.S.C. 227</external-xref>), section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), and other applicable statutes;</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id5ba50a93750a4d65a60c8cb86f1be18b">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>a summary of any investigations, enforcement actions, or other proceedings, initiated or completed during the 180-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, that involve alleged unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail or wholesale meat prices or price discrimination in meat affecting retail grocers, to the extent practicable and consistent with the protection of confidential or law-enforcement-sensitive information;</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id6a52574e4e704137bb2139d379164ab4">
                        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of how unfair and unjustly discriminatory pricing, and price discrimination in meat affecting retail grocers, may contribute to higher prices or reduced access to meat products for consumers in particular geographic areas or demographic groups;</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id8d69ed1912c646b9a9a67333df71b12e">
                        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>a description of the Commission's coordination with the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Justice, and any other relevant Federal or State agencies with respect to unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail and wholesale meat prices and price discrimination affecting retail grocers;</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="iddc10ae4ff1174fdbb22eda180fbbc475">
                        <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>any recommendations for additional statutory authority, resources, or other measures that the Commission determines would enhance its ability to address unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail and wholesale meat prices and price discrimination in meat that harms competition and consumers;</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id9020b38024c347b89f580236299bd352">
                        <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>a description of how the Commission has used, or plans to use, its authority under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/46">15 U.S.C. 46(b)</external-xref>) to study and obtain information regarding retail and wholesale meat pricing, fees, discounts, allowances, and other terms or practices that may result in unfair or unjustly discriminatory prices or price discrimination affecting independent, smaller, or neighborhood grocery stores; and</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id022db23f541f4c8fb9fbe4f884884c1a">
                        <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>an identification of any studies initiated, ongoing, or completed under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/46">15 U.S.C. 46(b)</external-xref>) that relate to retail or wholesale meat markets, food retailing, or related pricing and merchandising practices, and a discussion of how the results of such studies inform, or are expected to inform, the Commission's enforcement, policy development, and coordination with other Federal or State agencies with respect to unfair and unjustly discriminatory retail or wholesale meat prices and price discrimination.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="id4b1b3d7684d24fae8a1fe94e3cf23733">
                    <enum>(c)</enum>
                    <header>Committees</header>
 <text>The congressional committees described in this subsection are the following:</text>
                    <paragraph id="id078b88a7c8744ff7a545baa56047c979">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id5b77531751fd445c9d08b2952084dbe4">
                        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate</committee-name>.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="ide02251fbcce040c7821d1ad84a92d876">
                        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id7ed53764e53e4b3a90b4ad74c947f8e6">
                        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="idbf2cc3954a5d4c779e4925a9bad72f9e">
                        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <paragraph id="id432b8b55104a4a6cb2b34376fab71106">
                        <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>The <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection>
 </section></title><title id="idf410ed1b84c64bff9d64475df24e843f" style="OLC"><enum>V</enum><header>Funding the development of new competitors</header><section id="idf458ca89396c41679cdd3332c328a377"><enum>501.</enum><header>Funding for farmer’s cooperatives and small business concerns</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e4013f97a7b4164bfbac19951ee83fa"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56b05d4122e84632bdce98002127d2a2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34e3699a18004715a9c216225afeedc1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9acfa033f10649c380bac2b59fbe0529"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a farmers’ cooperative; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ff6c97028a74a0389367824add2b3ec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a small business concern (within the meaning of section 3 of the <act-name parsable-cite="SBA">Small Business Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddfd0b77f8e424b748901e483aeef454c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Administrator may provide financial assistance, loan guarantees, technical assistance, and other assistance to eligible entities for the purpose of acquiring, operating, or expanding meatpacking plants or facilities divested pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68106aa71f1c486da72ae998480152c9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity seeking assistance under subsection (b) shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3a49b4d91b5d4113bb9b36bd8b64cdb8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In evaluating applications submitted under subsection (c), the Administrator shall, to the extent consistent with sound underwriting and program integrity, give preference to eligible entities proposing to use such assistance for locally or regionally focused operations that will enhance competition for livestock and benefit producers and consumers.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6efefdf078c849e1b7fdc70c9ba5ed19" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="id7fafeb33dfe446459de118a4594c07fb" style="OLC"><enum>VI</enum><header>Rulemaking and enforcement authority</header><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5f2a252f8dd497fad0fcb7423640161"><enum>601.</enum><header>Enforcement authority</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id258400be0e604be4be3b16d468e1c7f1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc29887ad8ad441f8b40d2f39960b0268"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Failure to divest as required</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1192c1ab0ca44f5d9fafc6f40f1e121d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A failure to divest pursuant to this Act shall be deemed to be an unlawful method of competition in violation of section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>). The Commission shall enforce divestitures under this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc7d7217d047411f872ed363bed13fd6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Persons subject to the Packers and Stockyards Act</header><text>Notwithstanding section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) or any jurisdictional limitation of the Commission, the Commission shall also enforce this Act, in the same manner provided in subparagraph (A), with respect to persons, partnerships, or corporations insofar as they are subject to the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/181">7 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53cd0ee5908e4ba2bb97c0c13e3a5483"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Penalties for failure to divest</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5dd5799113c4c60b5f97972b709fde7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall impose a civil penalty equal to 10 percent of the revenue of the violator during the period of violation for any failure to divest pursuant to this Act.</text></clause><clause id="id528b44bcea44432197a48b933d39bad0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Enhanced penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall impose a civil penalty equal to 3 times the amount of any damages under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) for any knowing violation of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ac34a7698c24ae184a66cfd58f84e1d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil action</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfae7c6447aec41788aa6e4b4e379dde8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission is authorized to bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States to enforce any divestment plan, order, or condition imposed under this Act, including to enjoin violations, compel compliance, or obtain other appropriate relief.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e77d2d1b06e444a86c8a9fed23bc5a4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>In an action under subparagraph (A), the court may grant any appropriate equitable relief, including specific performance, modification of divestiture terms (only on motion of the Commission), appointment of a monitor, disgorgement or restitution, or such other relief as the interests of justice and competition may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7687cb6ed0948e59a6a89f69683d825"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of penalty funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall use any civil penalties or other amounts recovered under this Act to promote competition, including by funding the development of new competitors under title V.</text></subsection><subsection id="id466426b95124460db0a2dec0f2ba9382"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requests for information and assistance</header><text>The Department of Agriculture shall comply with all requests for information and expert assistance made by the Commission in carrying out this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="ida3904e1581114ea1bcbc6db7ab701089"><enum>602.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide35bdddf78fb43ed9c599a5f1f416880"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In promulgating all rules under this Act relating to required divestitures and divestment plans, the Commission shall aim to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcad84baf2464bfdbe74ceb862ad5efb"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discourage monopolistic practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc49defedb68c4746b110190d1e22cd81"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthen and preserve the competitive position of small business concerns;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c25b066831343d8bf69446a0983d413"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foster the development of new independent enterprises; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb574ff00de0f446d9bbce0510647c6f6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preference farmers’ cooperatives and small businesses in divestment plans.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide92155ca1f364e34a77d741aec645ca8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd46a95025754c7aa1fd1ffc992ef2e2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out this Act, including rules relating to—</text><subparagraph id="id655f1b8182de4563a0cac4eedbff9389" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">definitions of markets for cattle slaughter and beef processing in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83e3138bdfbf4ad8a2b49d5f5bb0e9e1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>standards and requirements for divestitures under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f25afa81153496fb6ee77444141e50a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in consultation with national security agencies, an identification of all covered foreign-controlled meatpacking enterprises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e23b809fdfd4f7f826dc2df5e2a03b4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to promulgate regulations</header><text>If no regulations have been promulgated by the Commission on or before the date described in this subsection, the requirements of this section shall still apply.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>

