<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDBEBFB0884FD46B987443916171D0863" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6774 IH: FHA Small-Dollar Mortgages Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6774</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, acting through the Federal Housing Commissioner, to establish a pilot program to increase access to small-dollar mortgages, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94AD11AB9DD144128208857E83BCFA22" style="OLC">
<section id="H2B90D2FB5512484994D197952396833B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FHA Small-Dollar Mortgages Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3868F1C711ED4EB2A6A2CF237B30161E" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>FHA small-dollar mortgages</header> 
<subsection id="H0E4C9BA733CA4D56ABDCBC3013314155"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, acting through the Federal Housing Commissioner, may establish a pilot program to increase access to small-dollar mortgages for mortgagors which may include—</text> <paragraph id="HA4152AEF0AFA44A08B1246D7F8FEBC6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorizing direct payments to mortgagees to incentivize the origination of small-dollar mortgages;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3ABD0594210249D0A52828DAF85B74DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjusting terms and costs imposed by the Federal Housing Administration with respect to small-dollar mortgages;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF18B7BB29F74EB59833DBF0803D540C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing direct grants for mortgagors who obtain small-dollar mortgages to cover costs associated with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDBB41A4E7856418DA4A99CCEFC764EA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>down payments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF3953833CDE4134B2AB197A9827E2A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>closing costs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40CCC83763CD4FCD9328B5D8D5F10D90"><enum>(C)</enum><text>appraisals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9976FB5F5F8428DB0377A420F5BF699"><enum>(D)</enum><text>title insurance;</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69C3E3AF1BA64DE28BD2E583357037A7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conducting outreach to potential mortgagors about the availability of small-dollar mortgages; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBCD5F8894D244E0A8916934D8247803"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing technical assistance for mortgagees that originate small-dollar mortgages.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA78800F1F0C846F08D0BC7D9350327A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the establishment of the pilot program under subsection (a) and ending 1 year after the sunset of the pilot program, the Federal Housing Commissioner shall submit to the Congress an annual report that—</text> <paragraph id="HF06B0263773A4423B35DC2BE8AD5F0AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tracks and evaluates the outcomes of small-dollar mortgages originated by mortgagees as a result of support provided under subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7AEC179F7F54A5E938A5FC1057EDF1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyzes risks of the pilot program to the solvency of the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC826B2DDA42495BBFE00C15A90A3E01"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes data with respect to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAE4D6D804A354B7E8933BDDDC4A60BD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of small-dollar mortgages originated in the 10-year period preceding the date of the enactment of this section, including small-dollar mortgages insured or guaranteed by the Federal Government and small-dollar mortgages not insured by the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8E4F0BBBBAD84F87B0AE7C4DA0A4D88F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the original principal balance of each small-dollar mortgage identified under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7231714F8BA94BF8A9B39F1F0022BD7C">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>demographic information about the mortgagors associated with each such small-dollar mortgage; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1195F650E981446DA9A4C23AFAC74BB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number and type of mortgagees that offer small-dollar mortgages;</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B3DD274F1A94AEC9BEC066C3846B341" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides a description of the fixed costs that are associated with mortgages and the impact of such costs on the ability of lenders to earn a market rate return on small-dollar mortgages; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H200C0069A6674860A7C53F2ADE5A545D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>includes analysis, by regions of the United States, including rural regions, that identifies regions with the greatest need for, and the highest likelihood of, the origination of small-dollar mortgages and regions that could benefit the most from increased availability of small-dollar mortgages.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB96A1B9FBD9408986177576D2E0C9D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pilot program established under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 4 years after the date on which the pilot program is established under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H277D74A46D64436AAF6530018BDA50E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expiration of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the expiration of the 3-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this section, neither the Federal Housing Commissioner nor the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may newly establish a pilot program to increase access to small-dollar mortgages for mortgagors.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H309FEDA932F44399AE0189221683DDF9"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Small-Dollar mortgage defined</header> <text>The term <term>small-dollar mortgage</term> means a mortgage that—</text>
        <paragraph id="H0887B75F23E64E7D8516B14CAC5897D8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>has an original principal balance of $100,000 or less; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H542752B8703B49FFB033FC101EDA0F7B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>is secured by a 1- to 4-unit property that is the principal residence of the mortgagor.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

