<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI26097-3K8-CC-7W2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3924 IS: We Can't Wait Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3924</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title II of the Social Security Act to permit disabled individuals to elect to receive disability insurance benefits during the disability insurance benefit waiting period, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HEAE29D91091D478F84AEC6E023F9C0CE"><section section-type="section-one" id="H45A764D8858F4987B284DD799FD95034"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>We Can't Wait Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H389FEEE7A9C9464F81F48A298D44980E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Election to receive</header><subsection id="HEB8CB307D8D24A0EA9003FDF7B45C150"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 223(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">42 U.S.C. 423</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1FA2321F46B94B52ABFBCCED60A3EE4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter following subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>(i)</quote> and all that follows through <quote>, (ii) in</quote> and inserting <quote>(i) for each month beginning with the first month after the individual’s waiting period (as defined in subsection (c)(2)) in which the individual becomes so entitled to such insurance benefits unless the individual elects to receive insurance benefits during such waiting period in accordance with paragraph (3), (ii) in the case of an individual electing to receive insurance benefits during the individual’s waiting period pursuant to the preceding clause and in</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE8A66F93744C049DE0C517F09595F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and section 215(b)(2)(A)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>, section 215(b)(2)(A)(ii), and paragraph (3) of this subsection,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC183352962D40768813A6CDF14C89EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE2E53AC72EC4521B2A13CA3AEAD1F65"><paragraph id="HAF5EA9B5263F4AFF99833D8AEB02D0C8"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1230472180EC42BD898CB4EA71DE7C51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An individual who has not attained early retirement age (as defined in section 216(l)(2)) may elect to receive disability insurance benefits during the individual’s waiting period pursuant to paragraph (1) if such individual or their appointed representative makes such election in writing (which may include selecting an option on a benefit application form) during—</text><clause id="H02D0C6C780C04466980D75B27D43D5E5" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who has applied for but not yet received a decision on their application for such disability insurance benefits before the date on which this paragraph takes effect—</text><subclause id="H46E153FABC50486CB906C06F96D70C14"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the 45-day period following such date, or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB3B415A4D7FC40D4A9FA9D37E5238A35"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the 10-day period (if such period ends later than the end of the 45-day period) following the date on which such individual receives a decision on such application which is favorable to such individual, </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H558B7CF3F67E4FF1B9E5DD02CAA9A76D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an individual applying for disability insurance benefits on or after the date on which this paragraph takes effect—</text><subclause id="HA729845CDD86419D9F9F318386197727"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date on which such individual files an application for disability insurance benefit, or during the 10-day period following such date,</text></subclause><subclause id="HD978887268D241B58FAA03D878413539"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date on which such individual requests reconsideration of the initial determination, or during the 10-day period following such date, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H429741E3EC6F45DB8E764994F82D4BD6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the date on which such individual requests a hearing by an administrative law judge, or during the 10-day period following such date, </text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCD75FC46281F495B98AF3A68AE40B252" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual whose interest the Commissioner of Social Security determines would be served by making payment of the individual’s benefit to a representative payee (within the meaning of section 205(j)), such individual’s election may be revoked or confirmed by such representative payee during the 10-day period beginning on the date on which such representative payee is selected, and</text></clause><clause id="H410F9462716A4E34AE16A3592687CE90" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who elects to receive disability insurance benefits during such individual’s waiting period pursuant to paragraph (1), the individual may revoke such election during the periods described in this subparagraph, except that in no event shall such elections or revocations occur in the first month of an established period of eligibility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB82240A05C4A4DAAAC3DDDA0745A11" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of an individual electing to receive a disability insurance benefit during the individual’s waiting period pursuant to paragraph (1), such individual's disability insurance benefit for any month during or after such waiting period shall—</text><clause id="H1B58C1125DEB47CAAA89957DDC4AE2B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be equal to the product of—</text><subclause id="H1B08443116534DB9AD90B4543CA24A75"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the disability insurance benefit amount determined under paragraph (2) (as determined before application of this paragraph), multiplied by</text></subclause><subclause id="H0601DF1D6A474683ABFA26002219562C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage determined under subparagraph (C) for the month during which such individual first becomes entitled to such disability insurance benefit,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF04E049F811B4D2D85496EFFAD3F866D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>continue unchanged for the entire period of eligibility for such disability insurance benefit, and without the effect of recalculations described under subparagraph (C), and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e17da5228354675a7cdef82db7dd246"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if applicable, be paid as part of a claim of entitlement to past-due benefits under this title and included in the total dollar amount of such past-due benefits.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C8F8516B5A14B64BE26E4973E5B98C0" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The percentage determined under this subparagraph shall be—</text><clause id="H99650E5CCF684E65AB24651EB46B8515"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for any month in the 36-month period beginning with the first month that begins after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, 94.25 percent, and</text></clause><clause id="H7A6C9823382448AF90F64CD2514A300B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for any subsequent month, the percentage most recently certified by the Commissioner under paragraph (D)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FCC4CBC173044CBBB517E43782990D8" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7A5A3EFFA8FA4E8384DE5DF11BD3219C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Not later than the end of the 36-month period described under subparagraph (C)(i), and not later than the end of every 5-year period thereafter, the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration shall calculate a percentage such that the fiscal impact over a 75-year period upon the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund if all individuals who applied pursuant to paragraph (1) to receive disability insurance benefits made an election to receive benefits during their waiting periods is equal to the fiscal impact over such period upon such Trust Fund that would have been made if all individuals who applied had not made such election.</text></clause><clause id="HF0436F2F59474A939355EECA0DA8881A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 36-month period described under subparagraph (C)(i), and not later than the end of every 5-year period thereafter, the Commissioner—</text><subclause id="H7B5DD35C3D7E453CB9642BE9EE066D7D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the percentage calculated by the Chief Actuary in accordance with clause (i) is greater than or equal to 91 percent, shall certify to the Managing Trustee such percentage, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H409AAFC9363A438EB76B84A60BBD4063"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if such percentage is less than 91 percent, may elect not to certify such percentage to the Managing Trustee.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7A97EEEE56DA4BCC94A51447AE961282" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the Commissioner elects not to certify any percentage calculated by the Chief Actuary, the Chief Actuary shall prepare and deliver a report to Congress, including detailed recommendations for administrative or legislative actions to permit individuals eligible for disability insurance benefits to receive disability insurance benefits during the disability insurance benefit waiting period such that the fiscal impact over a 75-year period upon the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund is actuarially neutral.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89838DF0E7494D53943F41AE81E76C9C" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No election made or not made by an individual pursuant to this paragraph shall be construed to have any effect on any benefits payable to any other individual on the basis of such individual’s wages and self-employment income.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32B46B02C2174159A69A4E7040963833" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall make available to the general public by posting on a website information relating to electing to receive disability insurance benefits during the waiting period, including a calculator which an individual may use to determine the effect of electing to receive disability insurance benefits during the waiting period on the individual’s disability insurance benefit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idb4c004dcbdb84ed39e5748a109c79db1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Each application for entitlement to disability insurance benefits that may subject the individual to the waiting period pursuant to paragraph (1) shall allow for new elections or revocations under this paragraph. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA42C9A24062425F8FCB9AA2BB00F255"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to applications for disability insurance benefits that are made or pending on or after the first day of the first month that begins after the date which is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83e0c3e8b1d94106b619a553b9d16cda"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Update to Social Security disability forms</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of Social Security shall update the application forms for applying for disability insurance benefits to include an option for applicants to elect to receive disability insurance benefits during their waiting period.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

