<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6AAB62073FD8485ABA6F148A9DD0CBC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9564 IH: Military Housing Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9564</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on the use of point-access block design for military construction projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBB67F5C25B03477DA84B0ADB5EE3563C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9031FB07E8564445A358B120C271655D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Housing Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H77DF7685EAD64823A63E7DFFC1C86A64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on Unified Facilities Criteria guidelines relating to model housing codes</header> <subsection id="HD1415778F125436D97D7AF72E97AD5F6"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Study</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States, in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall conduct a study that examines the costs and benefits associated with revising the Unified Facilities Criteria/DoD Building Code (UFC 1–200–01) to allow the use of point-access block design for covered projects.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H860C1C67B63D448AAE699D6B65794FAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study required by subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF3AAF89B0DD0439E86FD5DCE17890C51"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quantify, to the extent possible, how such a revision would—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H296CA8C207E74A99B6BB3117FF7A6198"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase the quality of available and affordable military housing through the construction of new military housing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6717EF0749E42A9861C6770E67F1E14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have an effect on the rental housing market located near military installations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55E878EE795A442281A8A0DC3C7F2714"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">result in a reduction in the amount expended for the basic allowance for subsistence under section 402 of title 37, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDCB47A4BD67452A84E0FD2147F5537A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>result in fewer members of the Armed Forces seeking private housing by reducing barriers to building additional units of covered military unaccompanied housing (as defined in section 2856 of title 10, United States Code) or military family housing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53F827A541D04C359A4028F0084B519D"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect design and construction costs of covered military unaccompanied housing in the United States or military family housing that is Government-owned and Government-controlled in the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A846BC714BF46839F24F1DFBE2DA169"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improve the feasibility of commencing covered projects on sites or lots that would otherwise be difficult to develop;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D9FB2200C9841C29B3403FED75A770B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess, with respect to the use of point-access block design—</text> <subparagraph id="HFBFA5780EA9445EEB50CDC855BBDFD3C"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">life safety outcomes, including a comparison of such outcomes with outcomes in covered projects that does not use point-access block design; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45BD4DB73624426E8E586C6F0C554909"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fire safety improvements, including sprinkler coverage, smoke detection, ventilation, and building egress performance; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4620E6BBF3AA43A189F2CDEA56B1ED2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compare the fire loss outcomes for covered projects that use point-access block design with covered projects that do not use point-access block design.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H53733FCDFA1D47E7A82C5B75E7A9FA78"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General, in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the study conducted under subsection (a) that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H4C6AED26167A4AF6BB83D7D36EF51BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of actions that the Secretary of Defense may take to update the Unified Facilities Criteria/DoD Building Code (UFC 1–200–01) to allow the use of point-access block design for military construction projects; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BF4CF3CE1DF40E1805DBC8CE28B7F32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other recommendations relating to the use of point-access block design for military construction projects.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCC08E1B94004EC5967913F3571D5D02"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7910E15AB3F14F5794728CA52665331A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered project</term> means a residential or mixed use military construction project (as defined under section 2801 of title 10, United States Code).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D37D2B1B01B409F8787A0FE99A1D726"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>military family housing</term> means housing provided under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/169">chapter 169</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DE3B26989D24E43B7FC87EE791BBF8A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>point-access block building</term> means a Group R–2 occupancy residential structure, as such term is defined by the most recent edition of the International Building Code, in which a single internal stairway provides access and egress for all dwelling units in a building that is not greater than six stories in height.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

