<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDD60EC6B4A7742BD94ADC724D5290634" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4624 RH: Muhammad Ali American Boxing Revival Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 449</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4624</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–524, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250723">July 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 23, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 to establish requirements for unified boxing organizations, to further enhance the well-being of professional boxers, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H7CC95B6FB0B04A2A869FA1CC8FDBEE29"><section id="HF3E9A61FE26A44FB871151DAE050CEAD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Muhammad Ali American Boxing Revival Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9C5AA8A20C0C4093B5A81106C8508435"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="H06429391D27946468428960D99562701"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide increased choice and opportunity to professional boxers by allowing a professional boxer to choose to participate in the alternative system offered by a unified boxing organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFC10FBBAA7846669DD11210F76777E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to further enhance safety precautions that protect the well-being of professional boxers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2C1618A43DF24A16A8E09C12B031074D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unified boxing organizations</header><subsection id="H7D4946C410F045B994CC9A3CF0B621EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6301">15 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDF3806B18B3042C0B325C9281FC3E0BE" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><section id="H2708C703ADFE49999166056040DBD011"><enum>24.</enum><header>Unified boxing organizations</header><subsection id="HFE0D3129F7A14D8E801B2CDC083BB89B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Alternative system for compliance with the requirements of this Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A unified boxing organization (in this section referred to as a <quote>UBO</quote>) shall be deemed to be in compliance with the requirements of this Act if the UBO meets the requirements of section 5 and the conditions of this section with respect to—</text><paragraph id="HD46C54A6C14E451888EFFD5311B49D43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each boxer under contract with the UBO; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF77DC5B606C4D64BC9D71AC772AA09C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each professional boxing match organized by the UBO (in this section referred to as a <quote>covered match</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5799BB73CDE24407A7DFDEC5DC75EC0E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safety and industry standards; medical examinations</header><paragraph id="H12DA89C318DA4F73A38516C2258FFB47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A condition of this section is that a UBO meets the requirements of paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, in addition to the requirements of section 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA0EC64FFF644494A222FC2D701C13BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule relating to knockouts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a boxer who suffers a knockout during a covered match, a UBO shall require that (in addition to the examinations required for such boxer pursuant to section 5(a)(1)(B)(iii)) the boxer undergo the applicable examinations described in section 5(a)(1)(B)(iii) relating to brain health prior to participating in the boxer’s next covered match. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25C0C498410F4D709C68A47A80A10BEF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplemental physical examinations for boxers who are <enum-in-header>40</enum-in-header> years of age or older</header><subparagraph id="H765551B084BC4D249017110131E2324E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A UBO shall ensure that a boxer who participates in a covered match at the age of 40 or older undergoes (in addition to the physical examinations required pursuant to section 5(a)(1)(B)(iii) and paragraph (2) of this subsection, as applicable) a supplemental physical examination conducted by a licensed physician that affirms the fitness of the boxer to safely participate in a covered match.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B5280CD802C483593A989F6319B5D20" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A supplemental physical examination under subparagraph (A) shall include each of the following:</text><clause id="H7351BAA5871549AEBC11163CAAEA72C4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A chest X-ray.</text></clause><clause id="H6AB3BE91E5B34B0294B35018CE1256A1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive metabolic panel blood test.</text></clause><clause id="H4A8B07F30C0045549CDA6EFC3BBDE0B0" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A urinalysis to measure the overall health condition of the boxer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB52F1A797320425E9305F7EC36137757" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The supplemental physical examination to be conducted under subparagraph (A) shall occur at least annually, except that the chest X-ray required under subparagraph (B)(i) shall occur at least once every 6 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE203E637C9F2405CAD5A2B96D44C1972" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of medical care during matches</header><paragraph id="H1E8AA4B5B7524CFFA69C38EE28A8A3DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ambulances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition of this section is that a UBO provides (in addition to the ambulance required to be provided by such UBO pursuant to section 5(a)(2)) for at least 1 additional ambulance to be continuously present on site of a covered match.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DA972AD453D463CBDE4D38D9D497F1E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ringside presence</header><subparagraph id="H1F2BC12A308F4212A62C1A2CE0FA2DE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A condition of this section is that a UBO provides (in addition to the licensed physician required to be provided by such UBO pursuant to section 5(a)(3)) for at least 1 additional licensed physician to be continuously present at ringside during a covered match.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A4C6AFFB60F4751BE4C76E866A8EE77" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification requirement</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Muhammad Ali American Boxing Revival Act of 2026</short-title>, each physician required to be provided by a UBO shall have a certification obtained through a certification program administered by the Association of Boxing Commissions in partnership with the Association of Ring-side Physicians (or any successor organization).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14FCB0BF1A674315A4865584296300A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support services for boxers under contract with a UBO</header><text>A condition of this section is that, during the period in which a boxer is under contract with a UBO, the UBO shall ensure such boxer has each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H8F32BCD3622343CDB17CC540A469188D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Equipment and facilities for training and rehabilitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The boxer has access to equipment and facilities that are operated by the UBO for training and rehabilitation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8809B822637D4E4E97E4C16821C89753" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insurance policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the health insurance provided to the boxer pursuant to section 5(a)(4), the boxer has in effect an insurance policy that provides medical coverage for any injury sustained by the boxer during the period of training for a covered match.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E648A9427D7450F9D3E7C902B29D0CF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medical coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A medical coordinator is assigned to the boxer to assist the boxer with satisfying medical and licensing requirements related to the participation of the boxer in a covered match.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F748F9D712B4A71BE2E916353334805" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comprehensive anti-doping program</header><paragraph id="HE368ED1B5BEE4E6FB4E4ED3F0EC05470"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><subparagraph id="H44AC4ED4B1FC4A6E854087AFF6D68086"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition of this section is that a UBO has in effect a comprehensive anti-doping program that includes the testing and requirements related to such testing under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58A05E3F6571414389BF6D9367A29112" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>List of prohibited substances and penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A UBO shall, on an annual basis, publish, and make available to the public, a list that identifies, with respect to the preceding year—</text><clause id="H5C20E5ED2D784FCCA895E8AAA5FAA0A6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each substance tested for under the comprehensive anti-doping program of the UBO; and</text></clause><clause id="H24E4CD58AD984CDA96A64E55E9B5C97F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each penalty imposed on a boxer under paragraph (6).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFBA54997A4E4FBE84F59784C8C6EA35" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In-competition testing</header><subparagraph id="H5A4C9C03F0A34129AB0FB45603CB8767"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The UBO shall ensure that testing is conducted, in accordance with paragraph (5), for at least half the boxers participating in each covered match organized by such UBO for an event.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FF0CEE991B14C92B2ECAFF1A7512F04"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Testing required under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="H0A966F23F232476C9665C3D95FFE0E1B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>occur during the period beginning on the date of a weigh-in for a covered match and ending on the date of the match; and</text></clause><clause id="H7E51C5C8142B41A7AEED1DFB98684B69" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether a boxer is positive or negative for each substance prohibited by—</text><subclause id="HFC1B592F8FAA4299BB4DCEC18F64A159" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the boxing commission of the State in which the match is held; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H20C13154E87A43A3BF128BF734DD3016" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a covered match held within a reservation (as defined by section 21), the tribal organization (as defined by section 21 and that meets the requirements of section 21) regulating the match.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C554994B9C9486ABFEA77BA5B0F5294"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No-notice testing</header><text>In addition to the testing required under paragraph (2), during the period in which a boxer is under contract with a UBO, the UBO may conduct testing, with no advance notice to the boxer and in accordance with paragraph (5), to determine whether such boxer is positive or negative for each substance prohibited by the UBO.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86CA51DA4FF24910AD25EEACF5C2B648"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Substances prohibited by UBO</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The UBO shall prohibit any substance described in section 7(a)(2)(C)(ii), except that the UBO may elect to not test a boxer participating in a covered match for any substance that is not prohibited by the boxing commission of the State in which the match is being held or the tribal organization described in paragraph (2)(B)(ii)(II) that is regulating the match.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H796D806BFDBA4C778ADC9EE213F9782A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administration of tests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An independent third-party shall conduct the testing under paragraphs (2) and (3), which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HBF30F88EB1234187B9D65ADF3C85273F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out each such test;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11C1A7FE30E24B07B8A74805E92D1917"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determining the result of each such test; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF23720B750B54645BF330E427D267BCE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reporting a positive result of such a test to—</text><clause id="H62502991E9FE453BB3E8D9B2C08DC6D5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the UBO concerned; </text></clause><clause id="H5CDEADA8BBCB4D2A830A9A0E74B3C378" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the boxing commission of the State in which a covered match is held or the tribal organization regulating the match; and</text></clause><clause id="H398D1B587DFC46F28E01F0A442EBCB97" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Association of Boxing Commissions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2A54BA7B37F44548F3F7E86B042B6B8" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Penalties</header><subparagraph id="HA7386D4AA22F42F6A6838EE8AB37951A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A UBO shall implement any penalty decided—</text><clause id="H01CEE2C86A84481FAFDD02C532B814DD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a positive test result related to the testing conducted under paragraph (2), by—</text><subclause id="HE4D9592747AB4574B80C343F08012F25" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the boxing commission of the State in which a covered match is held or the tribal organization regulating the match; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HDD66196E9E2A4D2994F50EF7E2BEA997" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Association of Boxing Commissions; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6948BD3B596644BE98CE8A58B6A37ACF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a positive test result related to the testing conducted under paragraph (3), by the independent third-party conducting such testing.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AC0231C385B4DFC85F65C53F76FB389" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment for penalties</header><text>In imposing a penalty on a boxer for whom the independent third-party reports a positive test result under paragraph (2) or (3), the boxing commission, the Association of Boxing Commissions, or the independent third-party described in subparagraph (A) shall consider—</text><clause id="HA33AA8CB3B56435CBC44B5706A188753" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the seriousness of the positive test result in relation to the participation of the boxer in a covered match; and</text></clause><clause id="H0727520339F243738EF1686ADB169408" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the degree to which the boxer is at fault for the positive test result.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58F4477D21564758BCCDFD0C4E3E76CB" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Contract requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A UBO shall include in any contract entered into between the UBO and a boxer regarding participation in covered matches such terms and conditions as may be necessary to require the boxer to submit to testing under this subsection during the period of the contract.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE279235BF858412492E671F5DDFEDA1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Required contract provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the requirements described in subsection (e)(7), a contract between a UBO and a boxer shall meet each of the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="H480DA5473D0E4204AFE2C0451B30F2B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 30-day period ending on the last day of such contract, the boxer may not be prohibited from communicating with another UBO or a promoter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E82D63577D44A8BA077FE8961656CD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such contract shall—</text><subparagraph id="H586FDE48DC0D4D0A9E22AC8D9ACB10F2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specify the minimum payment that such boxer will receive for participating in a round of a boxing match, which shall be at least $200 per round; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H538A2A1A0D6D451190B21FD5BE3787AA"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H66D2AC2645D94733B009347B94B9A6C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>arrange that such boxer fight in a minimum of 1 boxing match every 6 months; or</text></clause><clause id="H757788B5370541A99D9E4531A412E824" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that such boxer is paid an amount that is not less than 10 times the minimum payment for such boxer for 1 round as specified pursuant to subparagraph (A), except that this clause shall not apply if an injury prevents the boxer from fighting and the boxer is collecting insurance for such injury pursuant to subsection (d)(2), or the boxer refuses or is otherwise unable to fight for reasons beyond the control of the UBO, including inability of the boxer to travel or the boxer’s failure to maintain relevant licensure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75A265B4720E40699B549ABA0D4D5572"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such contract may not exceed 6 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71C5197F2FB7478F9A6D66DEAFBFBD51" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Boxing conduct policy</header><paragraph id="H8E46A61AABCB4BD7B36142322C2979F6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition of this section is that a UBO implements and ensures compliance with a comprehensive boxing conduct policy that prohibits a boxer, or any covered individual, who is directly involved with or participates in a covered match from—</text><subparagraph id="H89DFDBEB2D0648D494EEFF07664EC28D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">placing a bet or wager, directly or through a third party, on the match; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H063ED923A13647E4A526B11D23D4791E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sharing non-public information with a third party that is material to the performance of a boxer participating in the match or the outcome of the match for the purpose of assisting the third party in placing a bet or wager on the match.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C97BFE4EAE440C6B69B80E645BA415C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A UBO shall implement and ensure compliance with procedures for monitoring and enforcing compliance with the boxing conduct policy implemented under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF5016F5F8834A7C81A611189291507D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered individual defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered individual</term> means, with respect to a boxer who participates in a covered match, any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8ACB6C57D4FE4D3CBA2CE9D398A1569E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An adult living in the same household as the boxer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE05351966F894BEA941284C8A930B7FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A coach, manager, or athletic trainer of the boxer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA62061C49434FCFB1C8E1F803174FF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A physician or other medical professional who provides services to the boxer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1999623AFD7C465989D5AAAD226820AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An employee, officer, or director of the UBO concerned.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11D3DFC9CE964287A758AD1A31A25173"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An agent of any such person who is directly involved with or participates in a covered match.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FEB6771B29E44F2BCC423A64855D5F2" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition of this section is that a UBO implements prohibitions against the officers or employees of the UBO, or any representative of the UBO, engaging in any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H843FB82EE66E4BA7BE8319FCA0F23C7B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any direct or indirect financial interest in the management of a boxer in relation to the participation of the boxer in a covered match.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16CB9F495DAA4956B6EF1DEEC36887EF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employment of, or making a payment to, a manager who represents a boxer who participates in a covered match, except—</text><subparagraph id="H7A17BF9F22884084B89861DDC55FBA5F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when the boxer acts as the boxer’s own manager; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5A32536F8BB445DBF8F812D78AD9B1B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any consideration paid by the UBO to the manager under the contract between the manager and the boxer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90016E292D0D4CE9AD94C4DA5707276C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Receiving or requesting from a boxer the payment of a fee related to—</text><subparagraph id="HABB00550A5854567A2B8052D9EB73FBA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ranking of the boxer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1CD9C044BFA404291A794AD397CB3B4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the participation of the boxer in a covered match—</text><clause id="H1BCE6510CC554DDFA4D83A914B08FEAE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>including any fee related to a boxer participating in a covered match in which the boxer will be challenging a champion or defending a championship, including any award; and</text></clause><clause id="H73804F4846AD435DBBF2E2AD33227A8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>excluding any cost related to a boxer reimbursing a UBO for reasonable expenses incurred by the UBO on behalf of the boxer in relation to the participation of the boxer in a covered match, including any medical expense and travel expense.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCFD24A7E5598473287AB729E7632EBBC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Boxing commissions</header><paragraph id="HA186992AF22C4B99957685D1254A546F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition of this section is that a covered match may not be held—</text><subparagraph id="H59BCCAE2B1284BBAA32B51A36FBA6F4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a State without a boxing commission; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H111AF096EAB94EF3AE73FA2A95717FB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within a reservation (as defined by section 21) under the jurisdiction of a tribal organization (as defined by section 21) that does not meet the requirements of section 21.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H917836862E4F4834918BAD964974405F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Judges and referees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition of this section is that a UBO meets the requirements of section 16.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04405FAEA2C64DCE877C676CE0D72250"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Financial responsibility</header><paragraph id="HA0967C21C1AB479E99CCC1AD2266BB08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a condition of this section is that a UBO is financially responsible for the costs of meeting the requirements of section 5 and the conditions of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07283435EF134C0B8648DD120FCC7B6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost of any deductible</header><text> The cost of any deductible for any health insurance required to be provided by the UBO for a boxer shall be the financial responsibility of the boxer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE62FB0489DF94A8F88FB5A0C0D21ADF1" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Federal trade commission filing</header><paragraph id="HBFD7D75D6A054C558F4E602BF37800E9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition of this section is that, on the date in which a UBO intends to claim status as a UBO for purposes of this section, the UBO submits to the Federal Trade Commission and to the Association of Boxing Commissions information regarding the UBO, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF405EE3A90994EFCA6724755FA728058" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The State in which the UBO is incorporated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB53EEFB357F47CC88CFA1A76D227756" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The business address of the UBO.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0DEDD5F862143FF8C70D624E97F350C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The website of the UBO.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09BAB40D435F4BCDABD40EFFAD048AC5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Format; updates</header><text>To meet the condition of this subsection, the UBO shall—</text><subparagraph id="HB7A13E7F53264F3EA2688A647A0C505F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the information described in paragraph (1) in—</text><clause id="HA765F5CBFAD44307A18F6641E404EF60" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>writing; and</text></clause><clause id="H2AC21642D92A41848DA0AA2B83F8AF8D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for any document greater than 2 pages in length, electronic form; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EF78CE5D8E04F2E8D232310DD9F0A36" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promptly notify the Federal Trade Commission of any material change in the information submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3064E7B9D0F14B60BDA29CAA321598F0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal trade commission to make information available to public</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission—</text><subparagraph id="H37B6134E3286434298E21A1F477073A7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall make information received under this subsection available to the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEFCC570B01C46A7B1A0F59D9778583C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may assess the UBO a fee to offset the costs the Commission incurs in processing the information and in making the information available to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A633F9D6EF49B2B85684D66A63808B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Internet alternative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In lieu of submitting the information described in paragraph (1) to the Federal Trade Commission, a UBO may provide the information to the public by maintaining a website on the internet that meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H3253289C1B51440187360FE8D5A1FD99" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Is readily accessible by the general public using generally available search engines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAC971C66ECD49748CA9AD6EE78BB61A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For full access to the information, does not require a password or payment of a fee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB537E961DF75453CBE8FB62687F87E51" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contains the information described in paragraph (1) in a format that is easy to search and use.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD23828850294AEBBD4B77F930ACC9EF" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Is updated when there is a material change in the information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FEFFCF2A4DB4BBC837178D5848CD5C4"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Relationship with State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall prohibit a State from adopting or enforcing supplemental laws or regulations not inconsistent with this section, or criminal, civil, or administrative fines for violations of such laws or regulations.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD3985A0C019D4721B365555C242803DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Section 18(b) of the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6309">15 U.S.C. 6309(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9FA5EE3022C34E6BBFCE3F752B67EB31" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H739F6D4B2367453397288CB728A6D15E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unified boxing organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any officer or employee of a unified boxing organization who willfully and knowingly violates, or coerces or causes any other person to violate, section 24 shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined not more than $20,000, or both.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H77F0F6E90B93429CBFF9167850B3BE2D" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6301">15 U.S.C. 6301</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H26BA6F7FCBFA4BFF86872009771A2C8F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (7) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBA2CACC2542C426C81952997D9673E2A" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="HA74FBF5E92054063BCD98CEA037C1904" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Physician</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>physician</quote> means a doctor of medicine, with a degree of Doctor of Medicine or Doctor of Osteopathic Medicine, who is legally authorized to practice medicine by the State in which the physician performs such function or action.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DA172845CA14B848AA58E7482628F64" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F7CD7F1C79F44C8AE9A7C9A22B4C552" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H219534393D5F4CF0BEB4222733E6382B" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Unified boxing organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unified boxing organization</term> or <quote>UBO</quote> means an association, a league, or a centralized industry organization in the private sector that—</text><subparagraph id="HC193A5867A7643DB9B6E0E3D37447D3A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">organizes a professional boxing match in a system in which a boxer under contract with such association, league, or centralized industry organization competes against another such boxer pursuant to unified rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H344194FF8AA343F7874456EF855CA72F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without reliance on a sanctioning organization operating independently of such association, league, or centralized industry organization, implements a system for title belts and ranking for boxers under contract with such association, league, or centralized industry organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC476DBE8DEF548EB8129FFB0FD2F0914"><enum>4.</enum><header>Boxing industry standards</header><subsection id="H33C2DB5D4FC3477E8496054A42CC135C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Boxer safety and industry standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5 of the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6304">15 U.S.C. 6304</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5FB4C72CCA2B4FF98CD297E625C4194F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and industry</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Safety</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4975C5749FD84D98A8CC608DA13B392C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HF6B635C85243493DAA0B429FE2636CFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>No person</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE490078E4EFF4D69B4EF2CF40E1645ED" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subsection id="HEBFA135B26C7426DA7038D7902BF63AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Health and safety of boxers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8844F0C89F834547BAC6B964020E1C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, at a minimum,</quote> after <quote>that provides</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A189622A4D446C999318672B4C98E24"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), as so designated—</text><subparagraph id="H535AAC648A9F4C7F86E7A6664C757A8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF786CC5F08EB4C7F8C9892A4E3532CE6" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H91D77D8772334EE998A31355CA044F85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Physical examination</header><subparagraph id="HB2602D4CC939414D8E852F7486921EF2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A physical examination of each boxer by a physician certifying whether or not the boxer is physically fit to safely compete, copies of which shall be provided to the boxing commission by such physician.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76C0D5D4D6564554AA988D3E40BEEAD7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimal medical requirements</header><clause id="H924F059143DA4210A2B3D5FDA2544032" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A physician may certify as required under subparagraph (A) only if the examinations described in clause (iii) are conducted, which examinations shall be valid only for the amount of time prior to a match indicated in such table.</text></clause><clause id="H52FF12FD5D5446B39C2E6359B4FA0487"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Validity</header><text>No examination shall be valid unless it is conducted by a physician, in person, and includes a written opinion that the result of such examination does not contraindicate that a boxer is able to compete safely.</text></clause><clause id="H7716BB3FF9F749C1BE48FE53B666C640"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Required examinations</header><text>The examinations described in this clause are those set forth in the following table:</text><table table-type="" table-template-name="Generic: 1 text, 1 num" align-to-level="section" frame="topbot" colsep="1" rowsep="0" blank-lines-before="1" line-rules="hor-ver" rule-weights="4.4.4.0.0.0"><tgroup cols="2" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt-no-ldr" colname="column1" min-data-value="200" rowsep="0" colwidth="269pts"></colspec><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column2" min-data-value="10" rowsep="0" colwidth="56pts"></colspec><thead><row><entry align="center" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="1" colname="column1">Required examinations</entry><entry align="center" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="1" colname="column2">Validity</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="left" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">Complete physical examination, including blood work</entry><entry align="right" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" colname="column2">1 year </entry></row><row><entry align="left" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">Dilated eye examination</entry><entry align="right" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" colname="column2">1 year</entry></row><row><entry align="left" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">Heart examinations (Electrocardiogram, and for a boxer aged 40 years or older, a stress test)</entry><entry align="right" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" colname="column2">1 year</entry></row><row><entry align="left" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">Antibody tests (Negative Human Immunodeficiency Virus antibody, Hepatitis B antigen, and Hepatitis C antibody)</entry><entry leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" colname="column2">6 months</entry></row><row><entry align="left" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">Brain health examinations (For a boxer aged 40 years or older, a magnetic resonance image (MRI) scan and a magnetic resonance angiography (MRA) of the brain; for a boxer under age 40, an MRI of the brain or neurologic examination conducted by a neurologist)</entry><entry align="right" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" colname="column2">1 year</entry></row><row><entry align="left" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">In the case of a female fighter, a pregnancy test</entry><entry align="right" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0" colname="column2">14 days</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21D73E15961C4B6F8A6BB6E2BF3110C8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="HBA7226BE659B4E83A99ABBBDEA3EC596"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Ambulance; equipment</header-in-text>.—Except</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H7A2D30ADF73D45248974AA67BA22E855"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an ambulance or medical personnel</quote> and inserting <quote>an ambulance and medical personnel</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H042493DACDF8497C84A46B8348B1DFC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HF91EEE0224274CD2B396D743DAE931CE" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H01CCE8C2E57849A5A61698398BE87C3F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Physician</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A physician continuously present at ringside who, beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Muhammad Ali American Boxing Revival Act of 2026</short-title>, shall have a certification obtained through a certification program administered by the Association of Boxing Commissions in partnership with the Association of Ring-side Physicians, or any successor organization.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ED9D8203C424CE28C505B2C5D568FEC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCB8EFA5387494B7783A8A48B81E55259" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H105D0F5AC2C34ED088711B2F25C0CAA5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Insurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each boxer, health insurance that—</text><subparagraph id="H26C9B7704DE84DB38A3ACAD607FDE4A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a minimum of $50,000 in medical coverage for any injuries sustained in the match and $15,000 in accidental death coverage for any fatality arising from such match; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBFF6C32DD5C47B98AA258FD65217352" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any premium, is not the financial responsibility of the boxer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3647021F79C4A31983E4094FFA663D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding after subsection (a), as designated by paragraph (2) of this subsection, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDCAEDDDA0DA847EAACA3CF7830302C4E" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subsection id="H57C7A8E810D34962B1BEB965FA2AE915"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum payment to boxers</header><text>A promoter or unified boxing organization shall pay a minimum of $200 to each boxer for each round in a match in which the boxer participates.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H51AFCD89F3144388B3EF88E6D4E30AD8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HEC8C83BAD48044A590D23F12BFFC0525" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subsection id="H86C2EA8656A7486D8148699BCE03B2A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Simplification of titles</header><paragraph id="HD45E7F8CD91A48449579A092592846E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Singular titles</header><text>A sanctioning organization or unified boxing organization shall award only 1 championship title for each weight class.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0E660859B514F5FBB0A0D6607F0BAC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interim titles</header><text>A sanctioning organization or unified boxing organization may not award an interim championship title except in the case of an injury or illness to a reigning titleholder, refusal or inability by the reigning title holder to defend his title, or for reasons beyond the control of the boxer, including inability to travel.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A99BB4A2C14409A8103319D60A923A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Section 7 of the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6306">15 U.S.C. 6306</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD5F3F8E0B9F64E2E864515ED07DB05C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsection (a) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H11000B6DF76E4CAEBC453ED023A485E7" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H63D685F1C3EA43D0B30601250A75A311"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Procedures to ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="HD537D82F4CE14FA9B19D4BD3CED4A926" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>drug tests shall be administered—</text><clause id="H99D62B6274724CB6B113E3EB7C32F40D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for any title bout; and</text></clause><clause id="HFFA88A9A8B734130BC47D10DAD509CF4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at random for all other bouts, provided that tests are administered for not less than 50 percent of such other bouts; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H184E8228D4DA4060A8AF8CF4FE65C5BF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such drug tests shall screen, at a minimum, for any substance listed on the most current edition of <quote>The World Anti-Doping Code, The Prohibited List International Standard</quote> of the World Anti-Doping Agency, except that a boxing commission may elect not to screen for such a substance if the use of such substance is not prohibited by the State in which the match is being held or the tribal organization (as defined in section 21) that is regulating the match.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9491186E050640388B7BB0EDF3CE342B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H78929845653B4D8CB441B25F2EA609FD" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subsection id="H3A518C8E53114108BE43E4E8C09B733E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consistent standards</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HF32A460D718445539FE515B8E415036C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>uneven development of standards and practices by boxing commissions (including tribal organizations in compliance with section 21) has enabled matches that would not have been authorized by boxing commissions with robust standards and practices, and that boxers have been seriously injured or killed as a result;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ADC9FE5DC1A4E8B80FD8DB93EF38702" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Association of Boxing Commissions (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>ABC</quote>), in partnership with the Association of Ringside Physicians, is well-positioned to identify policies and practices most conducive to boxer safety and wellbeing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H347BFC392B6B4ECC86EF9B1E0C313FB9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the ABC should, accordingly, publish and maintain—</text><subparagraph id="H3785C72CD2D54814828552FFB355B69D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a model legislative and regulatory code for professional boxing, derived from—</text><clause id="H29E7CD4317A64F91B4065C030C0BA115"><enum>(i)</enum><text>State policies that are most protective of boxers’ safety, health, wellbeing, and economic opportunity;</text></clause><clause id="H7DD1BA65007C49F5BA97458568394BB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>rigorous sporting authority guidelines, such as the USA Boxing protocols for medical suspension; and</text></clause><clause id="HEE442A3BC37F4DA4B64C6516708B7257"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>expert consensus statements from the Association of Ringside Physicians and other sports medicine organizations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC18C1DC33AFE4FE0A5A388CEF7BAE030" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>best practices recommendations for oversight of professional boxing and implementation of legal duties by boxing commissions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCF65AC395404AE79B8988783C16EEE6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an annual report card of boxing commission conformance with such model codes and best practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67FE836B90884523B8EADC14CC3FFF70" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judges and referees</header><text>Section 16 of the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6307h">15 U.S.C. 6307h</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEBA26D2974D84DA3B76030DDA58751C0" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><section id="HE7DF5E665DB24FDFBB250099FFA2F3B3" commented="no"><enum>16.</enum><header>Judges and referees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No person may arrange, promote, organize, produce, or fight in a professional boxing match unless all referees and judges participating in the match have been certified and approved by—</text><paragraph id="H856E82AD52984661B36FC3F8D2B2F62D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the boxing commission responsible for regulating the match in the State where the match is held; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AC6FDE338A444CC88D7C9EA6105A478" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Association of Boxing Commissions.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H86D0288B97464E4A90EB128426279A49"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text>Section 17(c)(2)(A) of the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6308">15 U.S.C. 6308(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or reasonable expenses in connection therewith</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1CFAE78C6BA842BDA92106CB653A6488"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 21(a) of the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6312">15 U.S.C. 6312(a)</external-xref>) are amended by striking <quote>25 U.S.C. 450b</quote> and inserting <quote>25 U.S.C. 5304</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H48A784C57D61461CAC05C21966473C98" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date and application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act, and shall apply with respect to boxing matches that take place on or after the date that is 30 days after such date of enactment.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc><action-date>February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

