<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFD2799B78EC4CB6B6CA97EBF8C7DB76" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9449 IH: Global Climate Resilience Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9449</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for debt reduction for developing countries for purposes of developing resilience, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H05862F07C6244384B6F4768516423E0D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC1D8A5AA62FF4C6C88B87FF9EED7DFA8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Climate Resilience Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H803EA371A85A482087F5CBB294B90653"><enum>2.</enum><header>Debt reduction for countries vulnerable to effects of extreme weather events and slow-onset disasters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54C4C565AA5643079E3A2F82C8CD46BC"> 
<part id="HC869FEC3A93F4D3CA7D058534CF62350" style="OLC"><enum>VI</enum><header>Debt reduction for countries vulnerable to effects of climate change</header> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70E9B5A426584DCC85591EC11F3BB5C3"><enum>901.</enum><header>Debt reduction for countries vulnerable to effects of extreme weather events and slow-onset disasters</header> 
<subsection id="HF97258C76CE24D7085F718BFFF156C92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="H6B69A60FA47A4E38A702B2DCEB60A72E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support the ability of countries to adapt to effects of extreme weather events and slow-onset climate disasters; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBA2A52F193A49E3AA248C3FFB670E8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure that resources freed from debt in such countries are targeted to developing resilience to the effects of climate change.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E6561E4EAD846A5B7D1A9E73649F625"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility for benefits</header> <paragraph id="H7D67EABBDF164DBE9670D22BF3BDA9D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A country is eligible for benefits under this section if the President determines that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5BE9C998D3044AF994C72B3C6A51CC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country is—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HC60B4A39EE9D4536B18E94FF8870701E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a low income, lower-middle income, or upper-middle income country, as determined by the World Bank; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5316E3883FF44CDA586829C2BD76738"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a small island developing state, as determined by the United Nations;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5032FE1D46C3407B979A4188CB773AD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the government of the country is democratically elected;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0D799DA49FC43FF9692D929B5D36A9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the government of the country (including its military or other security forces) does not engage in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally recognized human rights; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE17FFDECB164CA4975B35158A4D694D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the government of the country has developed a plan to use the benefits made available under this section to conduct—</text> 
<clause id="H5DB929962A714A9E8E9DF9807C127432"><enum>(i)</enum><text>resilience activities;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23C62E5359774020AC29994075411CB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preventative disaster risk reduction planning, including nature-based solutions; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8034D03B5C844B0E94E8E1DAFE596CB0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>activities to recover from extreme weather events or slow-onset climate disasters.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EDCA99665BC449EADDD246E4A1A049E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Not less than 15 days before formally determining under paragraph (1) that a country is eligible for benefits under this section, the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the intention of the President to determine that the country is eligible for such benefits.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6AF01FDC793E448FAD818482DDE919D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preferences</header><text>In providing benefits under this section, preference shall be given to countries with plans described in paragraph (1)(D) that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0F0A99746B94EE0B483A5E213921D55"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involve local communities and Indigenous peoples in the planning and execution of activities described in that paragraph; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB8FBC15D1CB4A96A5070267C9289191"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aim to reduce gender, income, and social inequalities through such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9CF87B8D7B54F7D8761615782CF0284"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduction of debt owed to United States as result of certain loans</header> <paragraph id="HBD81BC2DC50F437391B69944C88D0E34"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to reduce debt</header> <subparagraph id="H6367BD57C9B44C24B0CD73AFC4F2CF33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The President may reduce the amount owed to the United States (or any agency of the United States) as a result of loans made to an eligible country by the United States under part I of this Act, chapter 4 of part II of this Act, or predecessor foreign economic assistance legislation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E005DD14C774020B6BAD961E1FA210F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FE366125522442B817BE99C14259F3F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Certain prohibitions inapplicable</header> <clause id="H3CB3A560901346378FFCEBE7A86AB44E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A reduction of debt pursuant to this subsection shall not be considered assistance for purposes of any provision of law limiting assistance to a country.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE44E3E177214D9BAFFE0AAFBB7A34E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of certain restrictions</header><text>The authority of this subsection may be exercised notwithstanding section 620(r) of this Act or section 321 of the International Development and Food Assistance Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/161">Public Law 94–161</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2220a">22 U.S.C. 2220a</external-xref> note).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H654D891718314FC19A247C0722DDFDDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation of debt reduction</header> <subparagraph id="H949B9E2AD1CE45C59BC830C82D0A85D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any debt reduction pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be accomplished at the direction of the President by the exchange of a new obligation for obligations of the type referred to in that paragraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6816673B2F2C447383624018E28D271B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exchange of obligations</header> 
<clause id="H4F2AD0B28F184251A8C8D7538E24AD9A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The President shall notify the agency primarily responsible for administering part I of this Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) of an agreement entered into under subparagraph (A) with a country to exchange a new obligation for outstanding obligations.</text></clause> <clause id="H9119484E7D1A41EE9875E59D7B85DC19"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Cancellation and issuance of new debt</header><text>At the direction of the President, the old obligations that are the subject of the agreement entered into under subparagraph (A) shall be canceled and a new debt obligation for the country shall be established relating to the agreement, and the agency primarily responsible for administering part I of this Act shall make an adjustment in its accounts to reflect the debt reduction.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31DD64E6826C43789CD5298725A10C3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To engage in debt-for-Resilience swaps and debt buybacks</header> 
<paragraph id="H7A8BFD2501A04A3693085825DD2DF7A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Loans eligible for sale, reduction, or cancellation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H43F54047AF3E4788BD7AFED557F6132D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Debt-for-resilience swaps</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE677A8538CE485C8D974965560153A6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sale, reduction, and cancellation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may, in accordance with this subsection, sell to any eligible purchaser described in subparagraph (B) loans described in subsection (c)(1)(A), or on receipt of payment from such a purchaser, reduce or cancel such loans or portion thereof, only for the purpose of facilitating debt-for-resilience swaps.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H244EDC1A86A6439CA4B835A5CE1719FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Purchase of privately owned debt</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2704A0912A84C4AAFB928F73F63D86E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may, in accordance with this subsection, purchase privately owned debt of an eligible country, if that debt is purchased for not more than 65 percent of the face value of the debt, for the purpose of facilitating debt-for-resilience swaps.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55CA431502C146AB8370FDA958B7FC03"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Use of proceeds</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code, the proceeds of any purchase under subclause (I)—</text> <item id="H7F7B7272482F44289A80E9DBFBD17DDF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall be credited as offsetting collections to the account that finances the activities under this section;</text></item> 
<item id="H51442CDE675C420EA2B97107AA02DFE3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall be available for expenditure only to pay the costs of activities under this section; and</text></item> <item id="H3C456420EABB45D09C2DD10F75744B52"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2DCCD376630A4907B58FBD2EC0EEEBC9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible purchaser described</header><text>A loan may be sold, reduced, or canceled under subparagraph (A) only to a purchaser that presents plans satisfactory to the President for using the loan for the purpose of engaging in debt-for-resilience swaps.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H202DEBBC7F524A668D852B638B1AE82D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header><text>Before the sale under subparagraph (A)(i) to any eligible purchaser described in subparagraph (B), or any reduction or cancellation under subparagraph (A)(i), of any loan made to an eligible country, and before the purchase of privately owned debt under subparagraph (A)(ii), the President shall consult with the country concerning the amount of loans to be sold, reduced, or canceled, or debt to be purchased, as the case may be, and their uses for debt-for-resilience swaps.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2530DE6020A94F29B5AA6A786165B1C0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7839706C8164938BD609FC5A36B23E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Debt buybacks</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may, in accordance with this subsection, sell to any eligible country any loans described in subsection (c)(1)(A) or on receipt of payment from an eligible country, reduce or cancel such loans or portion thereof, only for the purpose of facilitating a debt buyback by an eligible country of its own qualified debt in order to support resilience activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EA7EF79178D4D4986B0C786521A64F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall, in accordance with this subsection, establish the terms and conditions under which loans may be sold, reduced, or canceled pursuant to this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD4F22EBE5044A709F0B4698B743484E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deposit of proceeds</header><text>The proceeds from the sale, reduction, or cancellation of any loan sold, reduced, or canceled pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited in the United States Government account or accounts established for the repayment of the loan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF678AD17185A40C08880A92124C17059"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultations with Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees on a periodic basis to review the operation of this section and the eligibility of countries for benefits under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B289987FD0149FF93D515DC51CA26B7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E587CAAAD844566816CB0A648A1AD68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 15 of each year, the President shall prepare and submit to Congress an annual report concerning the operation of this section during the preceding calendar year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA3D8C618CE84D928237C2C06E17CF4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H88676191A77F48DB9A624440F3D49E94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the activities undertaken under this section during the preceding calendar year; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06684BFC38D44521B2F1BDE81E15DEBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of any agreement entered into under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFAE598D3EE974A40B15333CD75A2CDDD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HEA23EF5398B244D4B0C1038EE09184A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE81109DC1FA4C258C64DCB8187FD716"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H15776901F3124F13B0988097C79C95BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H749A4F34DDE746F89F3CE362E24D031F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Debt-for-resilience swap</header><text>The term <term>debt-for-resilience swap</term> means the reduction of amounts owed to the United States (or any agency of the United States) by an eligible country in exchange for the commitment of that country to conduct resilience activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78055ED1B84E4E5EB77C4F2286439F12"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible country</header><text>The term <term>eligible country</term> means a country determined under subsection (b) to be eligible for benefits under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HDAEF5421904B46688F1FDF16A197A773"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Extreme weather event</header><text>The term <term>extreme weather event</term> means an occurrence of unusually severe weather or climate conditions that can cause devastating impacts on communities and agricultural and natural ecosystems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H1BC675E1A99A483885248F69FBB4C2AC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Resilience activities</header><text>The term <term>resilience activities</term> means activities undertaken to make changes to processes, practices, or structures that moderate potential damage from hazardous events, trends, or disturbances associated with extreme weather events and slow-onset climate disasters.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BB1311D6F3E43F3A4D443E895D2D9C7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Slow-onset climate disaster</header><text>The term <term>slow-onset climate disaster</term> means an event that evolves gradually from incremental changes occurring over many years or from an increased frequency or intensity of recurring events, such as sea-level rise, loss of biodiversity, desertification, increasing temperatures, or ocean acidification.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CB8554B547347E7B1AB2FD59F260E20"><enum>3.</enum><header>Support by international financial institutions for reducing debt load of countries with high vulnerability to extreme weather events and slow-onset climate disasters</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EAA4BE7FBEE4DEA9CA698C68B35B521"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Executive Directors at the international financial institutions shall use the voice and vote of the United States in those institutions to support eligible countries with high vulnerability to extreme weather events and slow-onset climate disasters by advocating for policies that reduce or restructure the debt load of those countries, such as by facilitating—</text> <paragraph id="HD1218747ED3048A79C3CFC8EED12BF15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>debt forgiveness agreements;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H645B8948F05D4CF4973323B599776E94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>debt buybacks;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC902D8CE57ED46DE8C14CE8EE7EB4EB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>debt-for-resilience and debt-for-nature swaps; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE4D0FB5894040B9B1711B92701950EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other similar programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDCCA159E198847019D239644BE3D8254"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAA60DF8CF11E4493A40896CF3F835C31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible country</header><text>The term <term>eligible country</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HA182C8DE81A842A0AF635BE5DAA9E355"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a low income, lower-middle income, or upper-middle income country, as determined by the World Bank; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAB23484F5C149529EB18D6516A10533"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a small island developing state, as determined by the United Nations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E5E68E1D280439AB02D3737A4FB8387"><enum>(2)</enum><header>International financial institution</header><text>The term <term>international financial institution</term> means each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7A656BC413314B458DAFB2A447A3EF28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The International Monetary Fund.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F91B664D0B74565BF4FE1F7619A0AFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F5CECB1B9F142C3A0437957025D94F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The International Development Association.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H410B824A290E4EB399A0716CAE00E0BB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The International Finance Corporation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD204E1CCAC9A4DECA7E1EE688DDB3E7B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E07766D18BD480C8A89BFFF2871E22A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The African Development Fund.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3DFED37FEF64C07B5FD18C92E7A8D5E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The African Development Bank.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87DBEADF70B9461ABE60BE073924C351"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Asian Development Fund.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97E9B6EC544C4A13BCF21B1591F2CE91"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Asian Development Bank.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE0DC27F4A514830A4459B95D17B6E8B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9765DEB6E1954BEEB169E5CB3DB1BEB1"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Inter-American Development Bank (in this section referred to as <quote>IDB</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8D54AA8AA0E4284BDCA82779781BC5F"><enum>(L)</enum><text>IDB Invest.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC45ED452ED964C0999FBBB5074FCFCF0"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The North American Development Bank.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0358E89C2D054ABD97DDE03CDF6416D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>The terms <term>extreme weather event</term> and <term>slow-onset climate disaster</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 901 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by section 2.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD24CF96FD48A42E1B52B8CD96F1D8BC7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advocacy for international climate insurance program at World Bank</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACFC3C8CF4FF4B20AB97B8CFE29DA651"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The representatives of the United States to the World Bank shall use the voice and vote of the United States to advocate for the establishment of a parametric international climate insurance program that provides immediate financial assistance, in the form of insurance payments, to eligible countries to meet recovery needs following natural disasters.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9DBFBA462CA4C94BD16158943AFBF3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The structure and requirements of the program described in subsection (a) shall be determined by the World Bank, but may include—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7321106E54104FCDA7B8D2CA9A60341A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>payments to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42CFE8B69D5E4D1F8B931E0DAD859690"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">small producers and vulnerable sectors affected by natural disasters; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FEA2FD18F0F4CBD9698C1C729AE032C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the governments of member countries affected by natural disasters for—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB39BC39057434B709B13EAE583F3C4A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">program restoration;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B5FA0B29B944F5BB7D5357E1539525D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaster cleanup;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B979250896744289A8D5934A2FB2FDF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">climate adaptation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H677DFACBD7C04455A268A3C989D8038C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>ecosystem restoration and nature-based solutions; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8B27E62E38243259D58308777C876A6"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other recovery efforts;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE679835886D04116ACF4B8310CCD2DBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligibility criteria that are comparable to the eligibility criteria for debt reduction under section 901(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by section 2;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70CE25562A9941A5B286FD6B02E31AAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consideration of the aggregate risk of natural disasters across eligible countries to reduce premiums; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5395708BBCBF4686AC8CB734A335DC0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support for existing international climate-related insurance programs such as the Caribbean Catastrophe Risk Insurance Facility.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6AAF121D8534B6DA75D33C4E13FF06F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6AE9D5AE250D42F5961EE886A37438E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible country</header><text>The term <term>eligible country</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H2F135B03CD634842A1A0BBCFBBA3969A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a low income, lower-middle income, or upper-middle income country, as determined by the World Bank; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04B1E98C2F8545BF8A0210D1AC889F06" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a small island developing state, as determined by the United Nations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H844285416E5B4C31B67E8EECBD3C65DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Natural disaster</header><text>The term <term>natural disaster</term> means any hurricane, tornado, storm, flood, high water, wind-driven water, tidal wave, tsunami, earthquake, volcanic eruption, landslide, mudslide, snowstorm, drought, fire, or other catastrophe that causes, or may cause, substantial damage or injury to civilian property or persons, ecosystems, or services of ecosystems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E5FE16683F743AEA74CC2AA2FF2008F"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">World Bank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>World Bank</term> means the following, collectively:</text> <subparagraph id="HEEF15CF1E8144F19A9756A738E53FB9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF530D2C152174E72A755ADB7C9DDBD46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The International Development Association.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37404BC259D749F0B5D25819783D64D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The International Finance Corporation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4543EBC151742148EE39F83D8456767" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

