<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAA2111AAB6FC4CF7A6E3DD1BF7B9012A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7654 IH: Advance Global Health Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7654</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the consolidation of reports required to be submitted by the Bureau of Global Health Security and Diplomacy of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF226F2067AA541719AB11523B068E78D" style="OLC"><section id="HFEB6375D97D246AA9021F1E2C26F5969" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advance Global Health Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H292CA13400154A0DA0427945F4757C1D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization for consolidation</header><subsection id="HBD831C47E101407081E7B9F1CFD2F3F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual consolidation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date of the enactment of this Act and except as provided in subsection (b), each report required to be submitted to Congress or to any committee of Congress that is produced by the Bureau of Global Health Security and Diplomacy of the Department of State shall be consolidated into a single annual report that is submitted not later than September 30 of each year. Such consolidated report shall be submitted in a machine-searchable format and contain all statutorily required information.</text></subsection><subsection id="H84CFB7CBB91A4E2599B9A0D81470D8C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The consolidation required by subsection (a) shall be subject to the following exceptions:</text><paragraph id="HE3A9C5505B794648B7D4B9CE8894C17B"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any report that cannot be consolidated into the annual report during the 1-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act without the loss of required information, the Ambassador at Large for the Bureau of Global Health Security and Diplomacy shall include a notice in the consolidated annual report naming the excluded report and certifying that the report shall be made available on the statutorily required due date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FD3C500D56040DE96F2F5BA6110CACF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any report required to be submitted on a quarterly basis and any report required in advance of the expenditure of funds related to the budget of the Department may not be consolidated into the annual report under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1A64D122D1C4FA6A90CDC83702CB1EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to waive, alter, or affect any requirement to provide congressional notification.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

