<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9EA9669E0A594E109164DD55D6315663" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7110 IH: Eliminating Bias in Algorithmic Systems Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7110</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require agencies that use, fund, or oversee algorithms to have an office of civil rights focused on bias, discrimination, and other harms of algorithms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE39793594D344A42A063ADBC4CE91A65" style="OLC"><section id="H14C9DD36778147B993C68856F603CF09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminating Bias in Algorithmic Systems Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H83DD72EF93FE4ADBBA2F0CC5F4F65C1C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H943EECEAB3B844BA8DFAA9062223C5DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B25E7BB256C4336B7CB47044158FAAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <term>covered agency</term> means an agency that—</text><subparagraph id="HEBAFE3CE023B439E94DD24749D4896A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses, funds, or procures a covered algorithm, or funds or otherwise participates in the development of a covered algorithm; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D27D09566944DA08A0BB1BF152DE70D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>oversees, regulates, or advises on the development or use of a covered algorithm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D04194E76E641CAB3962BF41C3B11D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered algorithm</header><text>The term <term>covered algorithm</term> means a process that—</text><subparagraph id="HD4F7402FC27040C4943251F2AC141137"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is—</text><clause id="H3CAB88A128144C1C8C44F0BDFAAE1778"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a computational process that uses machine learning, natural language processing, artificial intelligence techniques, or other computational processing techniques of similar or greater complexity; or</text></clause><clause id="H110C44E29CE94694BFCF4F593FC1AEF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a computational process derived from a process described in clause (i); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8DF3283EB8D4064A7EFD844F087E453"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the potential to have a material effect on the impact of, access to, availability of, eligibility for, cost of, terms of, or conditions of—</text><clause id="H4DFB1ECDEF7D4E1C81288B3053FE768F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a program operated or funded by an agency;</text></clause><clause id="H08DA7F042A924319A3E195BC1FC9E3B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an economic opportunity regulated by an agency; or</text></clause><clause id="H38D518FF4AFE42A4983140687845DF70"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>rights protected by an agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E8922DDEA948B4BB886A7AE6D9C0DD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protected characteristic</header><text>The term <term>protected characteristic</term> means any of the following actual or perceived traits of an individual or group of individuals:</text><subparagraph id="H29FF24C0293F49B381EBF9CECFA0772A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Race.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE2EDA4B9764969B1FC357406A7BB64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Color.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05D9D3F4BA57403BA550EE31046C97FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Ethnicity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF246E56B2DE34009A3C8192D81849565"><enum>(D)</enum><text>National origin, nationality, or immigration status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49CC84427CE94AAC8DD0AB771AE5ABFA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Religion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C2B4DACA550429C8FAAE7364D1B3C82"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Sex (including a sex stereotype, pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition, sexual orientation or gender identity, and sex characteristics, including intersex traits).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6398A024AB1D4C88B4BE104DDABCB396"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Disability.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69FF8F9D67124E1DADDC1B9570CAF3EA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Limited English proficiency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA68FDA1533B94355A4EC5BF3D7A4BCEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Biometric information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCB0DB8E29F14BC1B049B2E303755086"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Familial or marital status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F13177824204718B0DDFB980426E6BB"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Source of income.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A669ED521D04F86AB86C62400227B49"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Income level (not including the ability to pay for a specific good or service being offered).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7DC92BF50BA4E6C80226084818F7E76"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Age.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD25E019B82EC4DD99CB9899E3C97C946"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Veteran status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H280B67EF6674447DB8B30977448A5205"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Genetic information or medical conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DFD590C7197486DB3E5A9ECD40C64B6"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Any other classification protected by Federal law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HCA760AE074204DADB55990AA2A0CB004"><enum>3.</enum><header>Civil rights offices and reporting on ai bias, discrimination, and other harms</header><subsection id="H754692CF0BAE45518CBD6B253DCE8BDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offices of civil rights</header><text>The head of each covered agency shall ensure that the covered agency has an office of civil rights that employs experts and technologists focused on bias, discrimination, and other harms, including the effect or tendency to subject communities, groups, or individuals to bias based on, discrimination based on, or other harms attributable to possessing or being perceived as possessing a protected characteristic.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0E2C6D1FBBF14F62B3A3575DA9CF97AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bias, discrimination, and other harms reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, each office of civil rights of a covered agency established under subsection (a) shall submit to each congressional committee with jurisdiction over the covered agency a report that details—</text><paragraph id="HC7CB9FAA0F354779B2398C61C396C642"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the state of the field and technology of covered algorithms with respect to jurisdiction of the covered agency, including risks relating to bias based on, discrimination based on, and other harms attributable to possessing or being perceived as possessing a protected characteristic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF329ED555614350AE5683768752DFA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any relevant steps the covered agency has taken to mitigate harms from covered algorithms relating to bias based on, discrimination based on, and other harms attributable to possessing or being perceived as possessing a protected characteristic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95E592DE33F74FB0BB5D5CCFCA95C7CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>actions the covered agency has taken to engage with relevant stakeholders, including industry representatives, businesses, civil rights advocates, consumer protection organizations, other relevant civil society organizations, academic experts, individuals with technical expertise, organizations representing workers, and affected populations, regarding bias, discrimination, and other harms including the effect or tendency to subject communities, groups, or individuals to bias based on, discrimination based on, and other harms attributable to possessing or being perceived as possessing a protected characteristic; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA686995DBF9453B915FC1B5A4192FC1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any relevant recommendations for legislation or administrative action to mitigate bias based on, discrimination based on, and other harms attributable to possessing or being perceived as possessing a protected characteristic from covered algorithms, as determined appropriate by the head of the office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H669DBFA781C24A2D89D285C3B60D22B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency working group</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice shall establish an interagency working group on covered algorithms and civil rights, of which each office of civil rights of a covered agency established under subsection (a) shall be a member.</text></subsection><subsection id="H573015CC463643B3B8042095DE22D9B9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to each covered agency such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

