<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EDW26392-RHT-PG-691"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4962 IS: Securing America's Water Supply Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4962</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish an Office of Water Supply, Water Conservation, and Drought Resiliency within the Directorate of Civil Works in the Corps of Engineers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing America's Water Supply Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21707db7be504984893de320ef3b46c6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Water Supply, Water Conservation, and Drought Resiliency</header><subsection id="HCFA1CE89C19C46998649A46CCAF0A3A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish within the Directorate of Civil Works an office to be known as the <quote>Office of Water Supply, Water Conservation, and Drought Resiliency</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE31D099B4724C05973678F475A44AFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HBCA9F40102F94C42B195FE8F94BA313C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate a Water Supply, Water Conservation, and Drought Resiliency Program Manager, who shall head the office established under that subsection and report directly to the Deputy Commanding General for Civil Works and Emergency Operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A8F224D2AC40109A1225F9FC881D37"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">staff the office with personnel who may reside in any district or division of the Corps of Engineers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DDA8497EF4C42E39A35BFA026734D23"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the office with sufficient administrative, technical, and budgetary support to direct, perform, and coordinate the tasks described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f808d60bb8047eda692e867175854ab"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tasks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The office established under subsection (a) shall carry out the following tasks related to the water supply mission of the Corps of Engineers:</text><paragraph id="HD9BC88E440724366BC12DCD2CC8A6CB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify and evaluate opportunities using authorities of the Corps of Engineers to promote water supply, water conservation, and drought resiliency at water resource development projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F17A6F1E19440BB960C285F3EF42CAE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Provide to the Corps of Engineers, States, and non-Federal interests information on existing policies and guidance documents of the Corps of Engineers related to, and make recommendations on new policies and guidance documents to improve, water supply, water conservation, and drought resiliency, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF0C05CC73AB746929547A5E641A18DEF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the implementation of subtitle B of title I of the Water Resources Development Act of 2024 (138 Stat. 3046);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B2EE56C77CA403B973E26420808E8C9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the method for the accounting of storage use under water supply storage agreements at Corps of Engineers reservoirs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA02237FC1EB943C680EEDB85C42DA198" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the reallocation of storage space at Corps of Engineers reservoirs to water supply;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H333305A1F18349E5BCCBC7D5702D7A27" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the interpretation and implementation of section 301 of the Water Supply Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/390b">43 U.S.C. 390b</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F4868CFCAFA41819B089AE2E0E9D9AC" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the interpretation and implementation of section 6 of the Act of December 22, 1944 (commonly known as the <quote>Flood Control Act of 1944</quote>) (58 Stat. 890, chapter 665; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/708">33 U.S.C. 708</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9B9FE4A14FA43B88AC33FA5654E0581"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assist and provide guidance to States and non-Federal interests on accessing programs, services, and other technical and financial assistance made available by the Corps of Engineers for water supply, water conservation, and drought resiliency efforts related to water resources development projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47072F43701F452D9B53CBBC17397A52"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordinate the review and completion of water supply reallocation studies and reports to clear backlogs and ensure new studies and reports are completed in a timely manner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD78A744671694CE6BC086D83ACD70AC5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Act as a liaison between the Corps of Engineers and non-Federal interests for studies, projects, and agreements for water supply, water conservation, and drought resiliency efforts related to water resources development projects, including efforts—</text><subparagraph id="H985AFAFB078A4B30A4302D63A7846795"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reallocate storage space in projects to store water for municipal and industrial water supply purposes pursuant to section 301 of the Water Supply Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/390b">43 U.S.C. 390b</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF0DE4677FA046298194EEA31F30F8B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enter into surplus water contracts pursuant to section 6 of the Act of December 22, 1944 (commonly known as the <quote>Flood Control Act of 1944</quote>) (58 Stat. 890, chapter 665; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/708">33 U.S.C. 708</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A9E8C8E9C254535BE16F3EB44006640"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modify the operation of projects under other authorities to produce water supply benefits incidental to and consistent with authorized purposes, including by—</text><clause id="HC752B9E8DBC444EF9FF5C64CC227BE79"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjusting the timing of releases for other authorized purposes to create opportunities for water supply conservation, use, and storage;</text></clause><clause id="H909AEC4502234E48AE66A479BF55F3E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">capturing stormwater;</text></clause><clause id="H20355BB184B9482AB55D9A77997A7720"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">releasing water from storage to replenish aquifer storage and recovery;</text></clause><clause id="H926D026CA4F148289531143F30C37B82"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">releasing water from storage to augment storage at another Federal or non-Federal storage facility; and</text></clause><clause id="HB6D580BF40A545D096DEC0A668D047D4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other conservation measures that enhance the use of a Corps of Engineers project for water supply.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A2E1D4A54864B678495E7E0DCE6C56A" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conduct outreach and workshops for potential non-Federal interests to provide information on the authorities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE11BEFC9827F461E93893E2CC53DFF5D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Evaluate budget requests to ensure sufficient resources are requested and allocated by the Directorate of Civil Works to fulfill the tasks described in this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5E79A054C5149F2A798330ECF02242A" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Cooperate with State, regional, and local government and planning authorities to identify strategies to augment water supplies, enhance drought resiliency, promote contingency planning, and assist in the planning and development of alternative water sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BD0BB48ED19403D865A4C672C496F1C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Other tasks in furtherance of the water supply mission, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAABCA36D541F45C49CB7141C68445BBC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text><paragraph id="HC7D5039C4F60431FB93CFCA9FD6C68DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the progress of the Secretary in establishing the Office of Water Supply, Water Conservation, and Drought Resiliency, including a description of the status of implementing subsection (b)(3);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8171E693B7EC42BEAD71B143385C8A42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of staff assigned to the office; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4DF7CB694BD4D7CAA2FE241BAC12BE8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for each water supply study or project being conducted or implemented by the Corps of Engineers as of the date on which the report is submitted—</text><subparagraph id="HA15B75FEA79141B7AD83D41396812CEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the status of the study or project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49384DD410E446A9AFA54C9C366824F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the study or project commenced;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88D8BD58B95E44818EA1CB1F9C91308D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the estimated date of completion of the study or project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD135758987C44F77AABAF11E5EA52EEA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any significant impediments or obstacles that may reasonably affect the timeline to complete the study or project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

