<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E1620146CE0477794E74A10B2713FED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6796 IH: Military Care, Access, Reporting, and Evaluation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6796</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to establish a digital system for the submission of complaints relating to access issues at military medical treatment facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC50A5BA2889B4672B106956F3EB64AE9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H35CBC3AF63FF4291A88F5B7A9F28B93A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Care, Access, Reporting, and Evaluation Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Military CARE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HFF01770A3BB64B8B9CF376BB3E54E3B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Digital system for access assistance at military medical treatment facilities</header> <subsection id="H3E4D95EF7C9B4681BE468E78E0B26302"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Digital system for access assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a digital system under which—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6A23874CA0AA41F7A661334A0D48789D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a covered beneficiary who receives health care at a military medical treatment facility may electronically—</text> <subparagraph id="HA08595F9CDA542ACBEF6B0B3ADB1DC8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>file a complaint relating to access to care at such military medical treatment facility; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5640FD3EC7DE4585BBE0C499E589EF0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">view the status of such complaint at any time, including the status of any interim or final action taken to address the complaint;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9E37BBC47AF4FC68B960BD6902DDDDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any complaint filed under paragraph (1)(A) shall be promptly transmitted to an appropriate patient advocate of the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F850BA9150C45B9BFD6E6BAC9BD23A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complaints filed under paragraph (1)(A) with respect to a military medical treatment facility may be automatically aggregated and submitted to the Director of the Defense Health Agency on a quarterly basis.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H28A7B563D2AE48ED96584D77473997D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on complaints filed under digital system</header> <paragraph id="HC87FF0FA0F0C440788D460C8A0B6C79C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1 of each year following the establishment of the system under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the total number of complaints filed under such system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A902BBAF4184326A8CC493BBC7F10A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, for each military medical treatment facility with respect to which a complaint was filed under the system under subsection (a), the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H533AA03749D34CF8AF391761A744A57C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the most common access to care complaints filed by covered beneficiaries with respect to such facility.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB128EBFB7CAD4212AEE207498DBC813E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of the number of complaints so filed regarding access to specialty care versus access to primary care.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H029354AC0F294592B73684E42CD1CD02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A comparison of the number of complaints so filed regarding access to pediatric versus non-pediatric care.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H004850DB84D04AB39299C885CC0A461F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A comparison of the number of complaints so filed regarding administrative hurdles to access versus other access issues.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A3B55CDBC624481A184F52BB0E43DE5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A summary of steps taken at such facility to reduce access to care complaints by covered beneficiaries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3689F8804BA54B16A56BF53B08BC7977"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered beneficiary defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered beneficiary</quote> means an individual enrolled in a health care plan under the TRICARE program and eligible to receive care at a military medical treatment facility.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

