<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26668-1W4-C6-DPK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4364 IS: Speedy Tariff Refund Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4364</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the refund of duties imposed under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id606d4d486e4d45e3b1be441320ce47b6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Speedy Tariff Refund Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bf63fd6c34048d89b0952e7b74cf650"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id081f49fce51449de9b8790ff641c369c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in light of the holding by the Supreme Court that duties imposed under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) are unlawful, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection must pay refunds of those unlawfully collected duties;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id516e602f40f34973bf37d300a8d1dc06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Commissioner must process those refunds as swiftly as possible and without imposing additional requirements that disproportionately hinder individuals and small businesses from obtaining refunds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ab149623b9349e5afbc6904058077f0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Consolidated Administration and Processing of Entries (CAPE) system for refunds is seriously flawed and places unjustified burdens on importers, particularly small businesses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id916dec5474324e0d98d09c1b1b96cad8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>importers, wholesalers, and larger businesses, especially those that raised prices or passed on direct costs from those unlawful duties while they were in place, should pass on the refunds to their customers, including small businesses and families impacted by those duties.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9df7cff841f4a3eafbc469310504d00"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Refund of duties imposed under International Emergency Economic Powers Act</header><subsection id="id6724b21854624d8295a756890d0c2670"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 514 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1514">19 U.S.C. 1514</external-xref>) or any other provision of law, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall, not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, automatically refund, with interest, to each importer of a covered article all duties imposed under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) and paid with respect to the article.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf604ce35a6374d64a393d4eb207c28b4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reliquidation authority</header><text>In the case of an entry of a covered article that was liquidated before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner shall reliquidate the entry at the rate of duty applicable to the article in the absence of any duty imposed under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) in order to pay a refund required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc0bfcfd62e54b219c17a0c9b52d8e61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization of small businesses</header><text>The Commissioner shall, to the extent practicable, prioritize the payment of refunds under subsection (a) to small business concerns.</text></subsection><subsection id="id38d7c3b5f01c431b8deadaf93749f3cb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No request or documentation required</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Commissioner may not require an importer to make an explicit request for a refund under subsection (a) or to submit documentation in order to receive such a refund.</text></subsection><subsection id="id90517132f04c4a1589f5e032db8e3a55"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id9f34124453f542f0a914497b2dbbff6e" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered article</header><text>The term <term>covered article</term> means an article with respect to which the President imposed duties under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5f6fe72f77040a6835584fee546a389"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enter; entry</header><text>The terms <quote>enter</quote> and <term>entry</term> include a withdrawal from warehouse for consumption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida256180932f5433d87a5bc090d9c5cfa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

