<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4962DBCD20C40F8AC64098D90C4F0CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6411 IH: Preshevo Valley Discrimination Assessment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6411</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to prepare a report on the treatment of ethnic minorities in Serbia.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H57B3F3E2EC9D42EFB2C3F29B1063C6B9" style="OLC"><section id="H2EE4941EA066404AA8576B596AD20213" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preshevo Valley Discrimination Assessment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA7AA1066331346748DCA7359EFDE56AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on treatment of ethnic minorities in Serbia</header><subsection id="HE8CE0AF1B5E24866A3E0B5F24EB60FAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the treatment of ethnic minorities in Serbia.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1ED63040CFB24369A3BDBA5221506D73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) should include the following:</text><paragraph id="H47F23A500E6F498D8AB1707F5150D4F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The deactivation of registered residences, referred to as <quote>passivation</quote> or <quote>passivization</quote> of addresses by Serbian government authorities, belonging to ethnic Albanians in the Preshevo Valley (also referred to as the <quote>Preševo Valley</quote>, <quote>Presheva Valley</quote>, or the <quote>Presevo Valley</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DC4A25A8D9949B2AC1F4C90608654AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If such occurrence is confirmed, whether such passivation is preventing ethnic Albanians from renewing identity documents and exercising basic rights that require identification, such as voting.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4640C6F69D2A46DFA8FC83271EA2A50E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Whether Serbia disregards a proportional integration of ethnic Albanians in state and other public institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0901CE074EAA4AF382BB46E113FFC014"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether Serbia neglects or refuses to recognize diplomas and degrees earned in Kosovo by Albanians who live in the Preshevo Valley.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H377950064D66479A96E0701344714D19"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Whether Serbia restricts or prohibits the use of the Albanian language in public institutions at any level or on any personal documents, including personal identification, driver’s licenses, health cards, birth, marriage, or death certificates, particularly in Serbian municipalities where most of the inhabitants are Albanian.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD46136B738147A086E5D652A0A01B49"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Whether Serbia is preventing or hindering the regular and timely provision of school textbooks in the Albanian language to ethnic Albanian students in the Preshevo Valley.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB0E270DA1C24A488EB3AE4FCE574A63"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Whether Serbia actively opposes or disregards a proportional integration of ethnic Albanians in state or other public institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6BA32A1A8754F9796782154C1F8153D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Whether Serbia provides low amounts of central government grants to majority-Albanian municipalities relative to majority-Serb municipalities, and whether if such grant funding adequately enables local governments to maintain or build new infrastructure or provide other public goods as needed by local residents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93CBA2CB9746491FA92920B91A99E935"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Whether Serbia suppresses or restricts the use of symbols which are a feature of one’s ethnic identity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B9E4839242B4391A5136C537F81597B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Whether Serbia uses police or any law enforcement forces to interrogate, threaten, and intimidate local ethnic Albanians without due cause or process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H995988D6DE7640A5A7226CB284C078CB"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The level of support provided by Serbia for Albanian language media, press, or cultural activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD324A3E928724D4285C260BBC5D07F8A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Serbia’s consideration to implement mandatory military service for ethnic Albanians.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D504B8D3E7D4A5F83A8D3DE2A4DFF0A"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether Serbia takes any measures to deliberately increase poverty or make life unsustainable in the Preshevo Valley for ethnic Albanians.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32759E56CF7940FD9CEEA128526B6F3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) should be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

