<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D9EEA65F17A442AACA072435D841F07" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7745 IH: To establish certain requirements relating to wellness checks for the health and welfare of certain members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7745</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000139">Mr. Van Epps</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish certain requirements relating to wellness checks for the health and welfare of certain members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2C4A4236F114CE381E315FD073B433B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H147AF61BD48B412A9313F9887175A12A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requirements relating to wellness checks for health and welfare of certain members of the Armed Forces</header> 
<subsection id="H6A3E4DACDF924B8F80D8B86D6A02EEFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Wellness checks</header> 
<paragraph id="HA8C5337510DA49B7946AD887B3D18286"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Wellness checks required</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall issue such regulations, policies, and procedures as may be necessary to require that, whenever appropriate following a member of the Armed Forces sustaining any significant injury or illness or being on sick call, a wellness check is conducted to account for the health and welfare of such member.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF33520BEB0564C60AEA0DEB97A91B8EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methods of contact</header><text>In conducting a wellness check for a member of the Armed Forces pursuant to paragraph (1), if the member does not respond to such check conducted via an electronic or telephone communication method, the individual conducting the check shall progress to an in-person method of contact.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6B7D10C05DB47E590C60DDB95D5652D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Result of failure to locate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, as a result of a wellness check conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) for a member of the Armed Forces, the individual conducting such check is unable to locate such member, the individual shall refer to the applicable regulations, policies, and procedures of the Department of Defense regarding the determination and reporting of such member as missing, absent unknown, absent without leave, or duty status-whereabouts unknown.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A4C4953CCDA4B79BAB8E3FA4066BF2C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation by unit commanders</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each unit commander coordinates with the judge advocates assigned or attached to, or performing duty with, the unit under the command of such commander for assistance in the implementation of any regulation, policy, or procedure required under subsection (a) with respect to such unit.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7B7C2E964E3E4F9D9BF8CC7456F33159"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional actions by unit commanders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a routine basis, each unit commander shall—</text> <paragraph id="H93FC6A38757A49BCA9834730F19B22C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the requirements contained in the document titled <quote>Commander's Critical Information Requirements</quote>, dated January 2020, or such successor document, to ensure such requirements—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC30BD08A3D584C17A8388AD8E3E4210B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been issued or updated during the three-year period preceding any such review;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D18241102B549C1B020D47C08E25805"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reflect such medical issues or safety incidents of members of the Armed Forces that the commander deems sufficiently significant; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96167DBBB14E4A9394553BBAFA879480"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have been distributed to the unit under the command of such commander; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H840A26384A024B4EA2748CF653C8336E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">host confidential wellness meetings with subordinate commanders at which such commanders may discuss with one or more medical officers assigned to such unit any significant injuries or illnesses affecting members of the Armed Forces serving in or with such unit.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B3190B62E5243EFA26F77E2DC89A0E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training courses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Secretary concerned, and the Secretary of Defense with respect to civilian personnel of the Department of Defense, shall develop and implement training courses to ensure each member of an Armed Force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary (or each civilian employee of the Department of Defense, respectively) is aware of the importance of accountability with respect to health and welfare and of the significant negative outcomes that may occur when accountability procedures fail. Such courses shall be offered at leadership and supervisor trainings and shall include content relating to the conduct of wellness checks in accordance with subsection (a) and other related actions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBDAFE3EE00C8445693C5B69ED4F058AF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Secretary concerned defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Secretary concerned</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

