<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H15EA449ED669447ABED5D10BBC06CC8A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7151 IH: Artificial Intelligence Public Awareness and Education Campaign Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260120">January 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Commerce to conduct a public awareness and education campaign to provide information regarding the benefits of, risks relating to, and the prevalence of artificial intelligence in the daily lives of individuals in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2E464DF2B60B421DB22A1A7EE822DA48" style="OLC"><section id="H63E9388523A54209844512084DFEA32F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence Public Awareness and Education Campaign Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70615ACAB1C542858083125254B17C6B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence public awareness and education campaign</header><subsection id="H27813D2F198442CFA6D3CC01176EF0A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCF86EAFEAE19431CA5CFB5DDEF900A6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>AI Campaign</header><text>The term <term>AI Campaign</term> means the public awareness, education, and consumer literacy campaign established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H374F5BD89C1A4E2F90E2F5E0B835C3A8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>AI consumer literacy</header><text>The term <term>AI consumer literacy</term> means an understanding of the capabilities and limitations of different kinds of artificial intelligence, and the ability to understand and use information provided about products and services that employ artificial intelligence, to support responsible decisions about exposure to and the acquisition and use of those products and services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A1D14DD697B4BB9BFFD198A259F0052"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77852063FC6E4A7C8F83DE86EC97857C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>agency</term> in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5FDA432F39848CEB255152C9DE8E028"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Key performance indicator</header><text>The term <quote>key performance indicator</quote> means a quantifiable metric that demonstrates how effectively an initiative is at achieving the objectives of the initiative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB18CDB823A604402A39EAA2E7741CF73"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H873942D701074C6E9C09E452ED10E098"><enum>(b)</enum><header>AI Campaign</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, including the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, shall establish a public awareness, education, and consumer literacy campaign to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA1E5B31E225485B8B1D2C95884C47A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide information regarding the prevalence of artificial intelligence in the daily lives of individuals in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B68ACC0771A4187B48E98754FBAB4DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve AI consumer literacy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACD0C17B31D04318A6D3B56464BF3A8D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>AI Campaign requirements</header><text>Pursuant to subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E631587BA6C408C984A09DDBC7B633C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the key performance indicators necessary to evaluate the effectiveness of the AI campaign, obtain any baseline data necessary for a comparative measurement of success, measure those key performance indicators, and accordingly evaluate the success of the AI Campaign, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H92764BF717C5406DA2D2FFE060B5A519"><enum>(A)</enum><text>audience reach;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD53688AE231433C91F4FA7059E91D0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>audience engagement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3086E20443104A168AF87CCD1D2613D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>audience adoption of best practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB447A1E0C714B879F08844837B49E7A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>audience satisfaction relating to interfacing with AI Campaign materials;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54E80F2EE56F412DB6DC947A8592033C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate access to, and the exchange of, information regarding the rights of an individual under law with respect to artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42E678C1977442C98D20941DABF9A6C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify, promote, and encourage the use of best practices for the detection of provenance information with respect to digital media, by—</text><subparagraph id="H19CB574DDA6B47089FF7275672A8A92D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>including such media that is generated by human beings and such media that is generated or significantly modified by algorithms, including artificial intelligence, which may include—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AB6CFFDF26C49CE9A2AF7DFF836D7F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">media commonly referred to as <quote>deepfakes</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F8F29E1148F49358588D76D8875AFD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">content created by the programs commonly referred to as <quote>chatbots</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C103DC7846046079E9C934911F06755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing resources and guidance on available tools and methods for detecting or differentiating media described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC119183C9C44AEEBC492B53FD537095"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying populations particularly susceptible to artificial intelligence-enabled fraudulent activity, including senior citizens, and conducting targeted outreach to inform those populations of, and inoculate those populations against, artificial intelligence-enabled scams and fraud;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF095F2D578984CE99F1951416F083F46"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct outreach to the general public by developing and distributing materials relating to the prevalence of artificial intelligence in the daily lives of individuals, including consumers, in the United States, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDF092C5CE6D54542A7D4112874B33B42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>artificial intelligence tasks (including classification, prediction, product recommendation, autonomous decision-making, voice dictation and machine translation, and the generation of content such as text, image, video, or speech);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC5796CC906548F995C24147294CB2CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applications that enable increasing the productivity of individuals, such as text-to-speech functionality, real-time route planning, and predictive text suggestions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE14DF0510FA342E9B43D4F607797046D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>applications in use commercially, such as automated decision-making, fraud detection, and financial trading;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF0C685C2E3441D8B5EC993B9C10F7A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the capabilities and limitations of artificial intelligence consumer products and services, including what questions to ask of a provider of those products or services to gain understanding and legal considerations regarding use of those products and services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4020C4C19CB34D0DB9E62CC2DDFA9159"><enum>(E)</enum><text>specialized use cases to address AI consumer literacy for tasks as those tasks manifest in domains including personal finance, healthcare recommendations, communication, creative work, and business management and operations across a range of contexts, including mobile device applications, computer software, and internet platforms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H183BD4DBF80B41D3ADED273AA6CD0996"><enum>(F)</enum><text>widely accepted best practices for the protection of personal data and personal identifying information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C631EBC6D9C42779AADBA276E068BB6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>workforce opportunities, including opportunities to work in the Federal Government, for technologists and others with experience in the development, deployment, and use of artificial intelligence, and including opportunities to work in institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA278A0318684B809A1BDD83A4807519"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consult the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to develop AI Campaign elements relevant to small business owners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4272ED87B34A49B79F63336854991B16"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consider the specific needs of different regions, economies, and subpopulations that may interact with artificial intelligence products and services in different ways; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2722E52451E4D75986654429831C144"><enum>(7)</enum><text>coordinate and promote AI Campaign efforts at the State and local level, including by promoting partnerships among Federal, State, and local governments, nonprofit organizations, and private enterprises.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B5983B30362421688C532450429ECA5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual update of AI Campaign materials</header><text>The Secretary shall annually update the AI Campaign materials and key performance indicators developed under subsection (c) as needed to incorporate any significant changes due to new innovations, products, or services available to consumers, in light of new consumer concerns that are identified, or in response to the key performance indicator measurements until the sunset date described in subsection (h).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBCFC52DF10D64D789C817ECB98DCAF4B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Dissemination of AI Campaign materials</header><text>In disseminating the AI Campaign materials developed under subsection (b), the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H40481B22A0FC4A1C9340404C20E63451"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD61451AC05134D34B9E404BB3266916E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure all AI Campaign materials are made available in a variety of languages, including by means of machine translation, as deemed appropriate by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1CE07CDE05346DF81019A17AB82160C"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>create a mobile-friendly website or web page where all AI Campaign materials will be published;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75EECA50D3844E17AB6F12F1E211ED70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>distribute core messaging materials of the AI Campaign to the public using multiple channels of communication, including through the use of television, radio, and internet platforms and advertisements on those platforms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B4545A498B043E49638FFE479A08A87"><enum>(D)</enum><text>coordinate with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration on the distribution of AI Campaign materials relevant to small business owners through resource partners of the Small Business Administration, including small business development centers, the Service Corps of Retired Executives (commonly known as <quote>SCORE</quote>), veteran business opportunity centers, and Apex Accelerators; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FFB9C9F42C74E98B2A4567B5ECD80C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may select 1 or more private or nonprofit organizations that are well-qualified in the distribution of public service campaigns to aid in the dissemination of AI Campaign materials.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4290E68BE3414AEFB05579CDFDCE7D19"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expert consultation</header><text>In conducting the AI Campaign, the Secretary shall consult with—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16BF3238D6D74444AE61DBED501F1046"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a variety of stakeholders from—</text><subparagraph id="H7786F0CBD07E40D8991DA8950B01FF28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>academic or research communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC60F78FC703A49CCA341AB951B369794"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private industry, including companies with different roles in the use of artificial intelligence and the developers and deployers of artificial intelligence systems in those companies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0F15C1C42384A4597C6B7E1B2FB094B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>community development organizations with expertise working with artificial intelligence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A9400C4675D41EEB1846A7DDC8DF97D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>private, nonprofit, and public organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H941D00AEB6AB402C8227A22D56244308"><enum>(E)</enum><text>State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEAFE45979AF4A0E96AB8A8591518678"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Government officials who have relevant consumer and artificial intelligence expertise, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2368B079EBAC403D9BA0D900CE9C36BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Chairman of the Consumer Product Safety Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDC0DD314B2A4CEC9EF9E66CF2826B47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA37EEFFF88A34F35873D5534744998A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H941CD22EE3A64F46989D4F1B098EC7CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Director of the National Science Foundation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17B33FCC21124CE18B23F6511F56382D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8C876C070064B68B773A10280BFD753" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Small Business Administration; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9C9050850E74A1E802FF4D259E0B416"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other official the Secretary identifies as having relevant expertise, especially in the development of domain-specific artificial intelligence use cases.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE29AA3E88334E5194A9BEA4DB2B667C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary initiates the AI Campaign, and annually thereafter until the sunset date described in subsection (h), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the activities conducted under the AI Campaign, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="H7B1EF95F32CE4566AE77B88425963034"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the key performance indicators developed under subsection (c) for the purpose of evaluating the overall effectiveness of the AI Campaign and the measured values of the key performance indicators;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E19E76DA74547A7A1F33B1D39714155"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of all AI Campaign materials developed under subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC5D76E6D6B4FABA16319F064E710F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for subsequent action, including in key areas in which the outcomes of the AI Campaign were identified as insufficient as measured by the key performance indicators; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H996A17657FC24F52B1B4BEE997C15C1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other information relating to the duties of the Secretary under this Act that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC73F29809284DDA89F5D718BC0224DF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The AI Campaign shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB03E5ED018D940EDB8A1CD24D1292C6A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

