<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H547D9CCEE8D04628831850911BD18360" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7598 IH: Veterans Assistance for Loan Origination Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7598</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260217">February 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to refund the amount of fees for a housing loans guaranteed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for certain veterans with pending disability claims, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H92ACAAC1F2954CD1A6EC0548D14C4572" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6F0703722C8E4BC4BBFAF06FE2E2439A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Assistance for Loan Origination Relief Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VALOR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H86DAC97480AF420CAFED5969F9F9C9B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Housing loan fees: clarification on overpayments and refunds for certain veterans with pending disability claims</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3729 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF7F46DCDBDCE428EA6E01A2A8A61CE3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H43CD62B395084F33B7526227FCE198D0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HB4115A77E8D94046B02FC6B7A26541C6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fee collected from a person in violation of paragraph (1) shall be treated as an overpayment. In the event that the Secretary collects a fee from a person in violation of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1807EF8F6FDE4C1990CEC46861C54A33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>refund the amount of the fee to the person; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F50B2785FA64C9185FB088D277BFC46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a fee so collected that was paid as part of a loan, credit the amount of the fee to the loan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98B5D4C7EA5B4BE6AA23871A7984C699"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H81610BE60AFD42DA800A828F9C050BCA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HA1C2AC9AF29746BEBBD24EA0A8015C44"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of veterans with pending disability claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a veteran who, as of the date on which the veteran applies for a housing loan guaranteed, insured, or made under this chapter, has submitted a claim for disability compensation under the laws administered by the Secretary or a notice of intent to file such a claim but has not received a decision with respect to the claim, a fee shall be collected from such veteran under subsection (a). If such claim for disability compensation is approved, and the veteran receives disability compensation pursuant to that claim, after the date on which the veteran pays such fee, the Secretary shall reimburse the veteran the amount of the fee.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

