<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26011-X4S-6K-7K2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 578 ATS: Congratulating the University of Washington men’s soccer team on winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division 1 Men’s Soccer National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 578</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108" legis-day="20260107">January 8 (legislative day, January 7), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the University of Washington men’s soccer team on winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Division 1 Men’s Soccer National Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 15, 2025, the University of Washington Huskies men’s soccer team (the <quote>Washington Huskies</quote>) secured a 3–2 overtime win against No. 15 seed North Carolina State to win the national championship before an estimated 10,000 fans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this win marks the first national title in program history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the 2025 playoffs, the Washington Huskies defeated the Oregon State Beavers, the Southern Methodist University Mustangs, the Stanford Cardinal, the Maryland Terrapins, and the Furman Paladins, before defeating the North Carolina State Wolfpack in the championship game to win the College Cup;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Zach Ramsey and Joe Dale scored the 2 goals during regulation time and Harrison <quote>Harry</quote> Bertos scored the winning goal for the Washington Huskies during overtime in the championship game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every member of the Washington Huskies men’s soccer team contributed to the successful 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I National Championship season and the championship match;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the coaches and staff of the Washington Huskies men’s soccer team played a vital role in the success of the Washington Huskies during the 2025 season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Washington Huskies overcame a 3-game losing streak at the end of the regular season to win all 6 of their NCAA tournament games away from home, becoming the first team to win 6 road matches in the tournament; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Washington Huskies showed immense strength, resilience, and teamwork to win the national championship: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id6418bbf67c0d40909011d9b1ba8c4c97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the University of Washington men’s soccer team for an incredible season and for winning the National Collegiate Athletic Association Division 1 Men’s Soccer National Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ea2c24adf764d718335c3c96258e165"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements of all players, coaches, and staff who contributed to the team’s success; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f9f48a6dba64a4093e132d30aab8599"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="idb751b87d6c7c4b08828e907270a81955"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Jamie Clark, head coach;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44a3df2d67f0406e908e730e64558c5b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Patrick Chun, athletic director; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b575778965e4711ae81502d83ff1382"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Dr. Robert J. Jones, president of the University of Washington.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

