<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3D0282BB48FE4DA79170405F3FDF87E1" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
  <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 176 IH: 2026 Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iran</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
    <distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
    <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
    <session display="yes">2d Session</session>
    <legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 176</legis-num>
    <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
    <action display="yes">
      <action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date>
      <action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> submitted the following joint
        resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on
          Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
    </action>
    <legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
    <official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of the United States Armed Forces against the
      Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</official-title>
  </form>
  <preamble>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Islamic Republic of Iran is the leading state sponsor of terrorism and an adversary of the United States;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Islamic Republic of Iran seeks to pose a threat to the United States, its Armed Forces, and allies through its ballistic missile program, its sponsorship of terrorist proxy forces, and continued pursuit of a nuclear weapon;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas should the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran obtain a nuclear weapon, it would not hesitate to use such weapon on the United States or its allies;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Constitution vests Congress with the sole authority to declare war under article 1, section 8;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the President of the United States took military action on February 28, 2026, against the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran and later submitted a report to Congress on March 2, 2026, pursuant to the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/148">Public Law 93–148</external-xref>);</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Congress has not declared war with respect to, or provided any specific statutory authorization for, hostilities involving United States Armed Forces against the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the sixty-calendar-day period specified in section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1544">50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</external-xref>) has expired; and</text>
    </whereas>
    <whereas>
 <text>Whereas Congress recognizes that the members of the Armed Forces and all other Americans deserve to know the clear mission scope and objective for the use of any military force: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas>
  </preamble>
  <resolution-body style="OLC" id="H1D07DD5CD6C84F97BBBB72D1E7415AF4">
    <section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="HF577B50ED2284E478DB29B2117E6FF75">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Joint Resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>2026 Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iran</short-title></quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H10C035BC1C4B4C2D98603174E301CD72">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Authorization for use of United States Armed Forces</header>
      <subsection id="H84C57AF3EDAF49E9AD33AC339FCD5031">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authorization</header>
 <text>The President is authorized to use the Armed Forces of the United States as the President determines to be necessary and appropriate in order to—</text>
        <paragraph id="HC207C6B270B9438D89FEEA8F874F473F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">successfully demolish, degrade, or defeat the nuclear weapons program and associated delivery systems of the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H5BECFE8347A2455995DAA09E8E2C5C0A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>address imminent threats to the Armed Forces or to United States facilities posed by the Islamic Republic of Iran or Iranian-backed forces;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6AD7A212842249E5BE61EDA57252797F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>enforce a blockade of Iranian ports; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H01AF2735B1EC41D5AC363B9ECCC9C985"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>ensure safe passage for United States and allied vessels throughout the Strait of Hormuz, as well as any other vessels the President determines appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H32E630A92B74455C8070B119F8928CA6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limitations on use of ground troops</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority granted in subsection (a) does not include any authorization for the deployment of the Armed Forces for the purpose of—</text>
        <paragraph id="H884C68B1CAA94296B4D2B2FF29BA7DC9" display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>conducting sustained ground combat operations in the territory of Iran;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7935E8ABE0CA4F149B61BE918E073E97"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>occupying, seizing, or holding territory within Iran; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA0999151CE3E4CFBA5499056E4BE8B90">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>engaging in nation-building, stabilization operations, or the establishment of long-term security governance within Iran.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H7F3762554DA24BBE843F197606689E6F">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Limited exceptions</header>
 <text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit the use of the Armed Forces for—</text>
        <paragraph id="HD6F63D31B8934577AFB3153E2C3B9D08">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the rescue of United States citizens or members of the Armed Forces; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B6EC448D23E4989AD99BA45A6D92708"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intelligence collection or sharing activities in support of the national security of the United States, or in support of an ally or partner force.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H72029B72FC304B48ABFFC028DADD40E5">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>War powers resolution requirements</header>
        <paragraph id="H16622A4E3D75483BB4C92EDDABC72493">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Specific statutory authorization</header>
 <text>Consistent with section 8(a)(1) of the War Powers Resolution, the Congress declares that this section is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA0E307B5FC664F4E94C412CE89FF36EF">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Applicability of other requirements</header>
 <text>Nothing in this joint resolution supersedes any requirement of the War Powers Resolution.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H6120BF0912D3486C89A2FA4A9A08D671">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Report to Congress</header>
      <subsection id="H6212C0D69BB44BA8ABB2DB12D4DB57A8">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, at least once every 30 days, submit to Congress a report on matters relevant to this joint resolution, including—</text>
        <paragraph id="H50EE44D6360147AAA4F8CED33C13645D">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>actions taken pursuant to the exercise of authority granted in section 2;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFE83B556BB843EDA1E805C3F3BBC9AC"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>a description of any military operations conducted in reliance on authorities other than the authority granted in section 2;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA2034BD40D6C44FC81928ED82F3047E2">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of the legal authority for each action and operation described in paragraphs (1) and (2);</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H321D317570574C048B33D07027850A90">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>policy justifications for each action and operation described in paragraphs (1) and (2);</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE1B13F5C077C488AB363A19504645F32">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the expected scope and duration of hostilities associated with each such action and operation; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB3215643185541589DE9ADFFD79C76E1">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of civilian and military casualties.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H3038B2F4751441F1863CAE13420843CC"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Form</header> <text>The report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form and may contain a classified annex.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section id="H5F9BA979AFB740F186D3745BD0145F67">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Sunset</header>
      <subsection id="H6941F4FAC895408A9D863DBAAF5A3FA1">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
 <text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the authority provided in section 2 shall terminate on July 30, 2026.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H47CD5B997C7A417A9913636447EFC9D3">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Limited wind-Down period</header>
 <text>For an additional period of not more than 30 days after the date described in subsection (a), the authority provided in section 2 may be exercised only as necessary to end the deployment or engagement of the Armed Forces.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </resolution-body>
</resolution>


