<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B13ABD9E40547C68755A5E087CD0C6E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9325 IH: Lone Star Coastal National Recreation Area Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9325</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Lone Star Coastal National Recreation Area to conserve, protect, and promote the economic benefits of the natural, cultural, and recreational resources of the Upper and Middle Texas Gulf Coast as a unit of the National Park System.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA491414F8C14F129314FA724F12796C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H97D68FBF777F48C999F54B062E306FBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H0E13EE7E786B453EB4A7FAA34245F14E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lone Star Coastal National Recreation Area Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC655B84EBF3C4F91AF6E092F3386030D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H97D68FBF777F48C999F54B062E306FBC" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HABAF7E27F1B047F5BDABEAC359B3C0CF" level="section">Sec. 2. Purposes.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC20B2F85741C4BFAAD449A4AC163C943" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H024FD1CFC9774F329BE40BDB1592DFF4" level="section">Sec. 4. Establishment; boundaries; land acquisition.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H39F3445A476545B98D6FFCFF60ECA805" level="section">Sec. 5. Administration.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H372447BB60284519854E0285E7398B49" level="section">Sec. 6. Lone Star Coastal Partnership.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE1D1B9961E7244DEA04F50A230063064" level="section">Sec. 7. Integrated resource management plan.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBFD1429D7E2C451B9408F63F94AA5A69" level="section">Sec. 8. Savings provisions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H123987D39029414C9820DB81C414C792" level="section">Sec. 9. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="HABAF7E27F1B047F5BDABEAC359B3C0CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of establishing the Lone Star Coastal National Recreation Area as a unit of the National Park System are—</text> <paragraph id="HF08C7256FCF54FD780916274AFEF7490"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote the expansion of access and opportunities for outdoor recreation, including hunting and fishing, conservation, and heritage tourism in a way that supports the local economy and rural communities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7143DFE2DCCF48588D5DF04E3B15320D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conserve open space on voluntarily participating public and nongovernmental lands, with a principle focus on those lands and habitats that contribute to improved public access and programs that enhance the coastal area’s attractiveness;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C13E76E19A54911BA1F8EFBCAD793CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to protect the long-term health of the natural coastal ecosystem, with a focus on nationally significant flora and fauna of the coastal area; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25F9155AAF4849F29AEE6CC1F9B394FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to preserve the long-term coastal, natural resource-based economy reliant on recreation, nature and heritage tourism, and traditional land use.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC20B2F85741C4BFAAD449A4AC163C943"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H13B180CF498C4A93B73FB63562D1D773"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Associated sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>associated sites</term> means land or a facility within Jefferson, Chambers, Galveston, Brazoria, or Matagorda Counties in Texas that participate in the Network through a cooperative agreement, interagency agreement, or other voluntary agreement authorized under this Act, without regard to ownership or transfer of administrative jurisdiction.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF002119A1FD24E30BE72A1F4AD1A4733"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land</header><text>The term <term>land</term> includes surface waters and submerged lands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E4717A90E2D4F6BB32DF51659CA0F1C">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Map</header>
 <text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Proposed Lone Star Coastal National Recreation Area</quote>, numbered LSCNRA–001, and dated June 2026.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90D983F3220C470C919C9FAD6CCD14BD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National recreation area</header><text>The term <term>National Recreation Area</term> means the Lone Star Coastal National Recreation Area established by section 4.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2239063AF7174DB482F4F3A50D51909A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Network</header><text>The term <term>Network</term> means both the National Recreation Area and the associated sites.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29E474AE24C74D738A29CC429DF7F9B9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Partnership</header><text>The term <term>Partnership</term> means the Lone Star Coastal Partnership established by section 6.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1A41A2006594D1BAB80EB015CE679C0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>The term <term>Plan</term> means the Integrated Resources Management Plan developed under section 7.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H177002307EB04DF08243256BB531B92D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H932E936C25B14773B2EB1A1C380397F8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Texas or a political subdivision of the State.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H024FD1CFC9774F329BE40BDB1592DFF4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment; boundaries; land acquisition</header> 
<subsection id="H3E2D72FF12724E0CAD46320F047DD7D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="HDB23EA7F24AC4D67BFE987C01513BD50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), there is established the Lone Star Coastal National Recreation Area as a unit of the National Park System to conserve, protect, interpret, and promote the economic, natural, cultural, and recreational resources of the Upper and Middle Texas Gulf Coast for the benefit of current and future generations, and to protect the historical significance of the region to the State of Texas and the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6F07AD6B2F34E2AA8540F04AC7BC83C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Condition</header><text>The National Recreation Area shall be established on the date that the Secretary determines that sufficient lands or interests in land have been acquired to constitute a manageable unit of the National Park System.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0DF17F1BB2B145E48F403C1C62B820FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the establishment of the National Recreation Area.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2711C038BA4E41C1BEA57AE30F6D30D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundary</header><text>The boundary of the National Recreation Area shall include any area acquired by the Secretary from the sites depicted on the Map.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27CE063D0F6E46CFA292226B9074B8EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of map</header> 
<paragraph id="HE6C056FBE58C4D609C24DAFAE9FE9560"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date the Secretary approves the Plan, the Secretary shall publish an official boundary map of the National Recreation Area and associated sites. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service and made available to the Texas Parks and Wildlife Department.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD38E0AB42CFF450BBA06EEB66662EA82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Boundary revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary acquires from willing landowners additional land or interests in land in accordance with subsection (d), the Secretary shall make revisions of the boundary of the National Recreation Area by publication of a revised map or other boundary description in the Federal Register.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E991A500EB249BAA589148F59796A3A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acquisition authority</header> 
<paragraph id="H35E97720DE4A49499ECA13FC22EC1755"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize the acquisition of any lands or interest in lands that are not currently designated public lands or lands currently held for preservation or conservation by State, local, or nonprofit organizations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A92F21137524594974ED6BF9324D081"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acquisition</header><text>The Secretary may acquire any land or interest in land from the sites designated on the Map by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6BFACC8F84FB43D3B007E3FE25EBF9B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>donation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H186D2F678ACF42C6AD10EFC2AEBEAACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchase from a willing seller with donated funds;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB845B84A926147ABBAD167EFD72DD1E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>exchange; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6AC646C262245989605224A92DD838A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transfer from another Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA79186310BC848FE828CF8A18BCC8291"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Condemnation</header><text>No land or interest in land for the National Recreation Area may be acquired by condemnation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H91012581B3D2425D9CDE74250C52894C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal lands</header> <paragraph id="H9914E89D97834078B66E7B76DA22E24A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), administrative jurisdiction of the Federal land generally depicted as associated sites on the Map may be transferred to the Secretary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6B2F8E162AA49CF9FE817FC44875280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the Secretary requests, from the head of the agency administering such Federal lands, a transfer of administrative jurisdiction for purposes of inclusion in the National Recreation Area; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A2F780DD7C84E9DB38777E2C0E401A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the head of the Federal agency consents to such transfer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50F85B3541A64D75A8B07A8DC7A51E16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>USFWS land</header><text>The following lands may not be transferred to the Secretary for inclusion within the National Recreation Area:</text> <subparagraph id="H5AC1B6D7A0394964AC6E0636F1903588"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Land within the National Wildlife Refuge System.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFEF83F44F06B455180695E69F58D5EDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Land administered by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE641ADF2D82C4AC0B3DCA57C91920946"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative determination of eligible sites</header><text>In determining the eligibility of lands, waters, and resources for inclusion in the Network, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD52C5F79EC3444FB90A646541EB99934"><enum>(1)</enum><text>work jointly with the Partnership; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7937218AA5FC4A099C023AF7C733F751"><enum>(2)</enum><text>base each determination on locally produced documentation submitted voluntarily by landowners, local governments, conservation organizations, and the Lone Star Coastal Alliance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7C06EE212BC64F09BC6A57F746CC8EE3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Network participation</header> 
<paragraph id="H9AA1808FAD94485E9CB643CBF68E63CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A parcel, site, or resource may only be included in the Network with—</text> <subparagraph id="H52B0181DC97844EB85BB7B77B049539B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the written consent of the landowner or administrator of the resource; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA35ECA9D29C469CB3B5749B13927C61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the voluntary submission of supporting documentation for review pursuant to subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7ABBE107AB6149BFAF1D6F9AF90F92D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ownership and management</header><text>Participation in the Network shall not be construed to confer Federal ownership or management authority over participating lands or resources.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H39F3445A476545B98D6FFCFF60ECA805"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administration</header> 
<subsection id="H3F63995A2BEF44D8A65D1EA5DA72923B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="H27CCE06188A749D3AB7BB076695CEDD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National recreation area</header><text>The National Recreation Area shall be administered by the Secretary in partnership with the State, local subdivisions, private landowners, and others—</text> <subparagraph id="H85130DF965EC4AFBA4CDB9A0CE1CA1F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with this Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HADAC59B929484B4AA8286DAF96590C82">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the National Park Service Organic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/100301">54 U.S.C. 100301</external-xref>) and the Act of August 21, 1935 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/320101">54 U.S.C. 320101</external-xref>).</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BEB1E652C764DF1BCD1420F57B9EC4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Associated sites</header><text>Among the associated sites, the Secretary shall carry out the agreements authorized by this section in consultation with the partners described in paragraph (1) and in accordance with the Plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H65A6C746EFA347BAA8BF077CDA635904"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>Consistent with the purposes of the National Recreation Area, the Secretary shall coordinate the management of the National Recreation Area with the Partnership.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H03B55BED48554FB194D70ADE6469489A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agreements</header> 
<paragraph id="H7D4CEBD5F4544AE4A29FA503CF556FD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interpretation agreements</header><text>The Secretary may enter into agreements with other entities to provide informational, educational, and interpretive resources throughout the Network, including with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H7BF328F46F47417B8BD7A4F06BFA2C16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resources located within a national wildlife refuge among the associated sites;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A1EB5F06C4A428D83E177803141FF34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Flower Garden Banks National Marine Sanctuary and other marine and maritime resources of national interest;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38755B028EF44CB580AB139968193851"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Galveston Bay, through the Environmental Protection Agency’s National Estuary Program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59D3F29DA4ED4B67B65E360978527855"><enum>(D)</enum><text>National Historic Landmarks and Districts.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF083C7DA93A42B5AAE7F79806EB9EA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cooperative management agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this Act, the Secretary may enter into cooperative management agreements with associated sites, governmental entities, or other members of the Partnership to provide for the interpretation, coordination, protection, and management of resources within the Network.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71D99BC0554C451EB3043C1D3DAF1E53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header> 
<subparagraph id="H07F48639056B425595EB6483D8BD3868"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To further the purposes of this Act and notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with other Federal agencies, State agencies with a focus on coastal resiliency, members of the Partnership, and nonprofit organizations whose properties have been identified as associated sites—</text> <clause id="HC617732105E94E4C82D7AA20D3661FA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to provide technical and financial assistance for natural, historic, or cultural resource protection, interpretation, access, education and outdoor recreation projects or programs, and in accordance with the Plan; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA7ECBFD9016E479EA6CACF4BD9A81394"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to the availability of appropriations, to provide not more than 25 percent of the cost of any natural, historic, or cultural resource protection, interpretation, access, education and outdoor recreation project or program that is consistent with the Plan.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD177EEB687440428CB38470266AD6A8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>Any cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection shall include terms for reasonable public access to the applicable site as appropriate, consistent with the purposes of such site.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H032D39C150DE4EFF8DC89E850A295226"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H16B68AC219064044B4657233331D7685"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may accept and use donated funds, property, and services to carry out this Act.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D68B94DA62F415DA300BDD9999574EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval required</header><text>Funds appropriated or donated pursuant to this Act may not be expended until the Secretary approves the Plan, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H41B335F8526847EE8B4CB57B4C827D7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any amendments to the Plan; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1523756F423B48E5AB302B75478B9E97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interim administration.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8FBBAD77E854556BBA99975FA2713C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Large acquisitions</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFAB6D05FA44F4208A6CCD31B7CE3F2BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any large acquisition carried out pursuant to this section shall be conducted in accordance with applicable Federal procurement and competitive bidding requirements, including requirements relating to public notice, competition, and transparency.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2D82443DB1A49FAA7A529C5F25BADD0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>Any payment made by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to an agreement that the conversion, use, or disposal of the project for purposes that are inconsistent with the purposes of this Act, as determined by the Secretary, shall result in a right of the United States to reimbursement of the greater of—</text> 
<clause id="H417F0C6FE1C9452A9B8FEDED1E84910A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount provided by the Secretary to the project under subparagraph (A); or</text></clause> <clause id="HCC5BF15151954AECA33CB4A71685C2E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to the increase in the value of the project that is attributable to the funds, as determined by the Secretary at the time of the conversion, use, or disposal.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0000A86DC4DB448AAA32D7DEA162CD8E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>As a condition of the receipt of funds under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H4278D4ECDBB24A1587131A07F5B3BF0C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary shall require that any Federal funds made available under a cooperative agreement entered into under this paragraph shall be matched on a ratio of at least three non-Federal dollars to every Federal dollar; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCDEA3BF241474DF88E10C107A20B2F04" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the non-Federal share of the match may be expended prior to the date of the agreement and may be in the form of cash, services, or in-kind contributions, fairly valued.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H0371809642D646BEBF290F8DB1EA0F5C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Construction of facilities on non-Federal lands</header><text>In order to facilitate the administration of the National Recreation Area and associated sites, the Secretary is authorized, subject to the availability of appropriations or donations, to construct essential administrative and visitor facilities on willing non-Federal lands consistent with the Plan.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDA8DBD8856E8434A8E63413AF379750B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Management in accordance with an integrated management plan</header><text>The Secretary shall preserve, interpret, manage, and provide educational and recreational uses for the National Recreation Area, in consultation with the owners and managers of lands in the Network, in accordance with the Plan.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H372447BB60284519854E0285E7398B49"><enum>6.</enum><header>Lone Star Coastal Partnership</header> <subsection id="HFE8BC5C2E78A425992833CF8B43B8954"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the Lone Star Coastal Partnership to facilitate cooperation among and to coordinate the activities of Federal, State, and local governmental entities, nongovernmental organizations, individuals and private entities in the development and implementation of the Plan for the Network.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2F28EE3697EC435E86C784CE05A37CC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="H116A5E215451442F83ADAEB51BE6C9D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Partnership shall be composed of up to 31 willing members as provided for in this subsection, with not more than 49 percent from Federal and State governmental entities, representing fee or less than fee interests in land, and such others as appointed by the Secretary within 180 days of the effective date of this section as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H1023738FFE674FAAA64F2F3F62AC29AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One individual, appointed by the Secretary, to represent the National Park Service.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88918540D22E49F293084541FEC38056"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One individual, appointed by the Secretary, to represent the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80BF96107D264482895EFAB02CFFEBFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Texas Governor’s Office of Economic Development Tourism office, ex officio.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB28DB0CB8A124A8290D67155331DE289"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the Texas Parks and Wildlife Department, ex officio.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H58C0168A7B8B46A9942945FA9F69CB86"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Director of the Texas Historical Commission, ex officio.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA070792E6E7B4BB4B27682F61B1D36FD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The County Judges of Galveston, Brazoria, Matagorda, Chambers, and Jefferson Counties, ex officio.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB32547A4517E4070AC8099EEA529AD59"><enum>(G)</enum><text>One individual per county to represent private landowners in the respective counties, as recommended by the participating County Judges from Galveston, Brazoria, Matagorda, Chambers, and Jefferson Counties, and appointed by the Secretary. These individuals serve at the pleasure of the respective County Judges.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E1CC6EBDB7847DFBDB82958A15154AE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Local land managers, ex officio, of each of the associated sites, not to exceed 15 board members at one time.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD89445B281D34299B0CD9F02444CD012"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Board, ex officio, of the Lone Star Coastal Alliance, to represent the Alliance, a nonprofit organization the sole purpose of which is to support the Network, including but not limited to fundraising.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFF5674BB4D64635BF44B17EC1F49036"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ex officio members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member serving on the Partnership ex oficio shall serve by virtue of holding the office that provides for such service and shall continue to serve only for so long as the member holds that office.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HBD9C638956E0415C8890415201978A7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Resignation</header><text>Any member of the Partnership may resign at any time, removing themselves and their sites from the Partnership. Sites owned by a former partner may remain in the Network by written agreement between the former partner and the Partnership.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H313298E8532242C79B4B75DB691497B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Partnership shall serve without pay, but while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Partnership, members may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC335FD3CA93C4E7B97B56F516FB85809"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Election of officers</header><text>The Partnership shall elect one of its members as Chairperson and one as Vice Chairperson. The term of office of the Chairperson and Vice Chairperson shall be one year. The Vice Chairperson shall serve as Chairperson in the absence of the Chairperson.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBE45C2B4CFE74C0F87EFE317157390EC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>Any vacancy on the Partnership shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE2CA8F7F2D424B2C8AC170FF247DD412"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Partnership shall meet at the call of the Chairperson or a majority of its members.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82AFA9201ACB4F89A47E7E20A20157C7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the Partnership shall constitute a quorum.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4644ADA9062F4CBAB2C592A5502C9FB9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The Chairperson may establish committees and appoint to the committees members and non-members of the Partnership. The purpose of the committees shall be to make recommendations to the Lone Star Coastal Partnership on issues related to the development and implementation of the Plan, as well as to undertake special activities as requested by the Chairperson.</text> 
<paragraph id="HB70EAA242BDB40689DF4FEB9B95B2191"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>In addition to members of the Partnership appointed to the Committees, the Chairperson may appoint nonvoting advisors with knowledge related to the purposes of the committees from the following categories of entities, including but not limited to—</text> <subparagraph id="HE3BBE49F768A4572B54A9BFC6089A525"><enum>(A)</enum><text>municipalities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE611E13F3D74F81A97222D7AC406990"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educational and cultural institutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA86EF0D35E3492E8746E885EF5E2083"><enum>(C)</enum><text>environmental organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E7B9465DD3F4117A94D35A8277E5ABB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>business and commercial entities related to transportation, tourism, energy, and the maritime industry;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B597CB409E74963ABAAE3671E425F36"><enum>(E)</enum><text>organizations focused on coastal issues; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E786223013D4F1BBDB6BD17CB41AA28"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local agency representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81E3BD4003EC41C6800F38789F21EED3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Officers</header><text>The Chairperson of the Partnership shall appoint members of the Partnership to chair respective Committees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA3FA592607345A4A4C9B2583F48C2F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>All meetings of the Committees shall be open to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7441C9C44EBA417A992C153F20EA93B6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Executive committee</header><text>The Partnership is authorized to establish an executive committee through a two-thirds vote of the full membership of the Partnership for the purposes of overseeing the development and implementation of the Plan.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2FE0E18FA90343838B50C629DAA01F96" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Staff of the partnership</header> 
<paragraph id="H965D2ADBCA1B474F96DB0DF3BF4212AB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>The Secretary may provide the Partnership with such staff and technical assistance as the Secretary, after consultation with the Partnership, considers appropriate to enable the Partnership to carry out its duties. The Secretary may accept the services of personnel detailed from the State, or any entity represented on the Partnership.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBE17444A4DD444EA66C03A5851722D1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional staff</header><text>The Partnership may hire staff to accomplish the goals as set out in this Act, as deemed appropriate, and through means determined by agreement of the Partnership and Executive Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5DD41B6557134E68A827FF44E1EB18BC"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Partnership may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence, as the Partnership determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A598D32124848F18B808CA202982BD1"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Partnership may seek and accept donations of funds, property, or services from individuals, foundations, corporations, and other private and public entities for the purpose of carrying out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H46CD6BD719D24FECB44A6C9378268243">
        <enum>(n)</enum>
        <header>Use of funds To obtain money</header>
 <text>The Partnership may use its funds to obtain money from any source under any program or law requiring the recipient of such money to make a contribution in order to receive such money.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC77CA8E109B4F5CBC53D9DBA8C0B489"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Mails</header><text>The Partnership may use the United States mails in the same manner and upon the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBECA45F55B56454786323B4027453405"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Obtaining property</header><text>The Partnership may obtain from willing parties through agreed upon means, such property, facilities, and services as may be needed to carry out its duties, except that the Partnership may not acquire any real property or interest in real property.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0B7079F2D6FB430485822A8D5A912164"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Ethics</header><text>All members of the Partnership are expected to comply with applicable ethics rules and regulations, which, along with usual and customary conflict of interest disclosure requirements, will be established in the Partnership charter and bylaws.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE1D1B9961E7244DEA04F50A230063064"><enum>7.</enum><header>Integrated resource management plan</header> <subsection id="H2D31A1475FE1492F80933F21C7353ED9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after its establishment, the Partnership shall submit to the Secretary an integrated resource management plan.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A79EC2D29CA40DB89DCF600AEC3FE48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents and development of plan</header> 
<paragraph id="H4DDD4A2E4C0F4F7786E9D62DC9DD5A8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>To further the purposes of this Act, the Plan shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H0ABDBC24A1054E3EB2322B56286F82EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identifiable management plan for the National Park Service owned and managed lands consistent with the requirements of section 100502 of title 54, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H848C789C422148638D61E72BE1337A35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identifiable management plan for associated sites in the Network to facilitate cooperation and coordination among willing owners of the associated sites.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1383BDB7A86F4FE8ACCA32D45B5112D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional factors</header><text>In developing the Plan, the Partnership shall take into consideration—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H638DBBFD26124FBCB3CF84A35CEB0331"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purposes for creating the National Recreation Area as stated in section 2;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF07D7C126400478499952D58D31523EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a strategy to finance and support the public improvements and services recommended in the Plan, including allocation of non-Federal matching requirements set forth in section 5 and a delineation of private-sector roles and responsibilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13785F2BF38547F98D38589398736200"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a strategy for the coordination of activities that may be carried out by Federal, State, and local agencies having jurisdiction over land within the Network;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5CA8E5158AD84038B6E59C13B877657F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>criteria for entering and administering agreements, interagency disaster coordination, funding, and all other provisions authorized under this Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F4CC679CE214D1F90ED2730435382AD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>emphasis on local control, including but not limited to, the voluntary submittal of land through cooperative agreements as it relates to inclusion and exclusion into the National Recreation Area and associated sites by willing landowners;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6DC1A5F1D934EC19AB770F272D5B9C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>that this Act is prohibited from affecting—</text> 
<clause id="H9927F3041B0D4F5699D7883E1406EA4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>landowner rights to the adjacent and nearby parcels of land included in the National Recreation Area and associated sites; and</text></clause> <clause id="H857B236CD4DF437093439B5FAF08C729"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>existing specific regulations of Federal, State, and local government entities as listed in subsections (a) and (c) of section 8;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A0BBADA54ED4703AE9944D319B7A43F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>including a policy statement that recognizes existing economic activities within the area and a program for voluntary coordination and cooperation of willing parties; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73924DA28752467B981950B091A3B3C4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any additional savings provisions listed in section 8 of this Act that is not otherwise included in this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFFC36ECEA6E4887B233E79D9A4B1169"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission to State Governor</header> 
<subparagraph id="H08520B40B819491682C0074BFCF4BC0A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to submitting the Plan to the Secretary, the Partnership shall—</text> <clause id="H55A4996ABD214FA490DE1884B403D67C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit the Plan to the Governor of Texas for review; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBFB83384987744DE9CA04625B3ED038A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consider the Governor’s recommendations with respect to the Plan.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7928868157644E0D8CF13DAF35F87603"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to respond</header><text>If the Governor does not respond to the Partnership with recommendations within 90 days of receiving the Plan from the Partnership, the Partnership shall submit the plan to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA19AEB1A504242B09FEF884A32CA3155"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Approval of plan</header> 
<paragraph id="H2FFBCC8512024654A0EBC138B44E6233"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timeline</header><text>The Partnership shall submit the Plan to the Secretary, and the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the Plan not later than 90 days after the submission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B08C623E996493485DB6A701C5F0CC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>In determining whether or not to approve the associated sites program, the Secretary shall consider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFE41104721B64841AC28AD93A1041BFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the adequacy of public participation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69682AD8D47B41B8B3CBAF0EC1F68A23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assurances of Plan implementation from State and local officials; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29D8720EC23348C2B5A4D5E57442B142"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the adequacy of management and financial tools in place to implement the Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91CF783E5DD44F728EB382AF043F95F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disapproval</header><text>If the Secretary disapproves the Plan, or any portion of the Plan—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC1F69C8460274DADB43357A977F3D297"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date of such disapproval, the Secretary shall advise the Partnership in writing of the reasons for disapproval and recommendations for revision;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE91893598B3948BDB59616D585FD2C56"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>not later than 90 days of receipt of such notice of disapproval, the Partnership shall revise and resubmit the Plan, or respective portions to the Governor of Texas for a 60-day review period;</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H456E78E8377B4A3C95A1110FF3140A92">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>upon receipt of recommendations from the Governor of Texas or the expiration of the review period described in subparagraph (B), whichever occurs first, the Partnership shall resubmit the Plan to the Secretary; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB20D5D2AD30C4F41B8FCB72BC500F3D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after resubmission under subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the revised Plan or portion of the Plan.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H52DA79DE214C486CBD0BB4CA4B9E4800"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim program</header><text>Prior to adoption of the Plan, the Secretary and the Partnership shall assist the owners and managers of land within the Network to ensure that existing programs, services, and activities that promote the purposes of this section are supported. The Secretary and the Partnership will develop interim criteria to address eligibility for the establishment of an associated site and criteria and eligibility for entering and administering cooperative agreements as provided for under subsections (c) and (d) of section 5.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBFD1429D7E2C451B9408F63F94AA5A69"><enum>8.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header> 
<subsection id="H8E873218488A4E248FE4C6ADB602D5DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State and local jurisdiction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to diminish, enlarge, or modify any other Federal authority or program, and any right of the State or any political subdivision thereof, to exercise civil and criminal jurisdiction or to carry out State laws, rules, and regulations, including those relating to fish and wildlife, or to tax persons, corporations, franchises, including on lands owned by the associated sites.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC6FEFF70242E4BB6AB230B00E0DC55B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship to private property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maintenance, operation, and use of private property, including the lands in proximity to lands administered by the National Park Service, shall not be deemed to be inconsistent with or otherwise subject to any restriction or regulation as a result of this designation.</text> 
<paragraph id="HBD64542A1AA847B294343AED5FD93567"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No new regulations</header><text>Landowners shall not be subject to any new regulations, directly, indirectly or by implication, to any existing or subsequent regulations, including but not limited to the Endangered Species Act, as a consequence of designation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19D268E38F044FDB9F14F3C517378B24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clean air act</header><text>The application of the Prevention of Significant Deterioration provisions of the Federal Clean Air Act relative to mandatory designation of Class I Areas shall not apply.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58839E39F05640578AA8179628561AA8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federally authorized or permitted channels, storm surge protection, flood control devices, oil and gas pipelines and projects</header><text>The designation shall in no way be inconsistent with or impede the construction, maintenance, operation, and use of federally authorized or permitted channels, storm surge protection, flood control devices, oil and gas pipelines and projects and the result of such functions shall not be deemed to be an owned land of a public park, National Recreation Area, or other public resource within the meaning of section 303(c) of title 49, United States Code, and shall not be deemed to have a significant effect on natural, scenic, and recreation assets within the meaning of section 47101(h)(2) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBE78E4D2D76416792735AC89DA9BF04"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Emergency response</header><text>In the event of emergency conditions created by acts of God, including natural disasters, any relevant Federal, State, or local governmental entity may provide expedited emergency relief and assistance where necessary to protect life or real property during the pendency of the emergency, the provision of which shall not be deemed inconsistent with or otherwise subject to any restriction or regulation as a result of this designation. This Act does not preempt or otherwise alter any funding or Federal support for lands and improved property. National hurricane response efforts and Federal grants would still be accessible to all parties within the Network that qualify under the established criteria for these programs. Nothing in this Act affects any jurisdiction or responsibility of FEMA with respect to lands not owned by the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF857D23238D94A7A9FF658C1B20C18BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities within the national recreation area</header> 
<paragraph id="H788AC0B4CB5A47EC94393FA80F43F066"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hunting, fishing, off road vehicles and personal water craft</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), and with the written consent of the immediate prior grantor of fee or less than fee interest in land to the National Park Service, the Secretary shall permit hunting and recreational and commercial fishing, off road vehicle and personal water craft use on lands and waters owned or managed by the National Park Service within the National Recreation Area, in accordance with applicable Federal and State law.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD039EBAAFF2547ED89DB74A654128B54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative exceptions</header><text>The Secretary may temporarily restrict such uses under paragraph (1) only as needed to address public safety and emergency situations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA22E5B8AF88404BA8F394528BC7C16F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Except in public safety and emergency situations, decisions to close locations within the National Recreation Area to such uses shall be made in consultation with, but not limited to, local user groups, including but not limited to, the Texas Parks and Wildlife Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09D264B5859B4404A0D48CA66580400B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Closures</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), decisions to close locations within the National Recreation Area to such uses shall not become effective until the Secretary files public notice providing the justification for the closure, the location or locations being closed and the expected duration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H362D34F120224D35B3FB666A4A4E4E2F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects any jurisdiction or responsibility of the State with respect to fish and wildlife on Federal land and water covered by this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29DBAB1BEC8B4F7BA1806ED2F126E999"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Oil and gas minerals</header><text>When acquiring land, waters, or interests therein, the Secretary shall permit a reservation by the grantor of all or any part of the oil and gas minerals in such land or waters and of other minerals therein which can be removed by similar means, with the right of occupation and use of so much of the surface of the land or waters as may be required for all purposes reasonably incident to the mining or removal of such from beneath the surface of these lands and water and the lands and waters adjacent thereto, under such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary with respect to such mining or removal.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H123987D39029414C9820DB81C414C792"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="H753BC096BFCF4C0AAD93C2F3AAB2EA3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the Secretary to provide technical assistance, interpretation, planning, marketing, cooperative agreement administration, education, and signage in furtherance of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H53951092253D450AAE7D765CBF45E039"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except for costs associated with the establishment and operations of the Partnership, interim planning, and development of the Plan, expenditures shall be consistent with the approved Plan.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52A67E6B7B0C48B4A248C8D9E76F8970"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Land acquisition by condemnation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated pursuant to this Act may not be used for the acquisition of land or any interest in land by condemnation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H532B3DA40B5243DE82EBAC02710DA55D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on Federal ownership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require or authorize the acquisition of land or interests in land except from willing sellers through donation, purchase with donated funds, exchange, or transfer from another Federal agency, consistent with section 4.</text> </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

