<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC59C225A24454662B0505CD2CA763644" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7921 IH: To amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to modify provisions relating to rural decentralized water systems grants.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7921</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to modify provisions relating to rural decentralized water systems grants.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7B4884A9CC8B486A88FF8AB158F11C16" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H343C7028CC194571BD7AAFD7EB601145"><enum>1.</enum><header>Rural decentralized water systems grant program modifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 306E of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926e">7 U.S.C. 1926e</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H400F56EAB2F9499BB82E78BF4542F0D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the section designation and heading and all that follows through the end of subsection (b)(1) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H857D07D90FC64D6689D47E5F08579269"> 
<section id="H0861421B8F79494D8C10B8D43610B12E"><enum>306E.</enum><header>Grants to nonprofit organizations making loans and subgrants for construction, refurbishing, and servicing of individually owned household water well systems and household decentralized wastewater systems in rural areas</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD452C0416DB649439C400F46D50D4CB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants to nonprofit organizations</header><text>The Secretary may provide grants to private nonprofit organizations for the purpose of providing subgrants and loans in accordance with subsection (b) to individuals for the construction, refurbishing, and servicing of individual household water well systems and individually owned household decentralized wastewater systems in rural areas that are or will be owned by the individuals.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H537F55C93F304DFFA83A6DB9FF89C6B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loans and subgrants to individuals</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E58E290AC774007B8CEF9FA1787FA96"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit organization shall use grant amounts received under subsection (a) to provide—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF7899C767B1422C9C3C4C37AF45C5EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subgrants for use in accordance with this section to individuals residing in the service area of the nonprofit organization who are members of a household with a combined income (for the most recent 12-month period for which the information is available) that is less than 60 percent of the median nonmetropolitan household income for the area, according to the most recent decennial census; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA35F1A39133B4D4CAFFA7170C00BA9D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>loans for use in accordance with this section to individuals residing in the service area of the nonprofit organization who are members of a household with a combined income (for the most recent 12-month period for which the information is available) that is 60 percent or more of the median nonmetropolitan household income for the area, according to the most recent decennial census.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4E5B0FBD63146019492068DAC271A15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC70DBCBC1FA84816856EB078595CF9D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>$15,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$20,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B074B36C0814685BF07FEFE46444525"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7EAA4BB8B60429B9AF79BF689D16016"> <paragraph id="H8F7EA41B50774C03ACD2C268F206AF6B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Funding to cover cost of performance warranties</header><text>A subgrant provided to an individual under this subsection for an individually owned household decentralized wastewater system may include sufficient additional funding to cover the cost of a performance warranty with a duration of at least 5 years.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9418087A70548FD99C5B7FD59B49292"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>2023</quote> and inserting <quote>2031</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

