<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6DB277A2990244F78C5C7D3B9A74E5FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9125 IH: Sectoral AI Governance Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9125</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the head of agencies to issue rules related to the uses of algorithmic decision-making systems that are likely to materially contribute to violations of Federal laws that the agency is authorized to enforce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1660153930E94D4C99F9D18B21BB308B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBF61DF58929C4A82847A1F0F8CD1DEB0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sectoral AI Governance Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H16617C2F33E242ABBCF3ABC03444B067"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9EEC070FC6704839BCE00C0A1425A705"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Existing Federal laws may already prohibit certain harmful uses of algorithmic decision-making systems. However, uncertainty regarding the scope and application of existing authorities to such systems, and variation in agency procedures and approaches may impede clear and coordinated regulation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H150B20630BFC419F9E89C7C751BB3DB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Agencies may benefit from clearer authority, consistent with their existing enforcement mandates, to issue prospective rules governing uses of algorithmic decision-making systems that are likely to materially contribute to violations of Federal law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D091524393649BDAEADC176E455DDF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A coordinated framework for consultation, guidance, and reporting may improve transparency, consistency, coordination, and accountability across agencies.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBA5FC9D7B3804FFEA36118EE343E59C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rulemaking authority related to the use of algorithmic decision-making systems</header> <subsection id="H026A530EAFF24A70A601AE908BC8787B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header> <paragraph id="H197C50C8F6D945A890AA3836C93BB5E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency that is authorized to enforce a Federal law is authorized to make rules (in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, notwithstanding any rulemaking procedures that are otherwise applicable to the agency) to regulate the use of algorithmic decision-making systems—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF7D2428E966B4B1FBD6A778B46465FD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the head of the agency determines, based on evidence that is available to the agency, that the use of such a system is likely to materially contribute to violations of the Federal law; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9AD878F56614C57B5BF76DCC15A4D7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the purpose of mitigating such violations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB16C4B99CF834D7C81689642E45D968C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of a rule made under this subsection shall be treated as a violation of the Federal law described in paragraph (1) for purposes of administrative and civil enforcement of such law by the agency.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F6639042EE34810AD21233B506653FF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advanced notice of proposed rulemaking</header> <subparagraph id="HCF0B619392984054991C44FB70323162"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), not later than 60 days prior to issuing a notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to a rulemaking under this subsection, the head of an agency shall publish an advanced notice of proposed rulemaking to solicit public comment on whether the use of the algorithmic decision-making system that the agency proposes to regulate is likely to materially contribute to violations of the Federal law that the agency is authorized to enforce. An advanced notice of proposed rulemaking issued under this subparagraph shall, as appropriate, describe—</text> 
<clause id="H74534879FB854473AD75DD766B2E5451"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the algorithmic decision-making system or category of systems at issue;</text></clause> <clause id="HD9FA9E4A2895487E82598D37CE93435F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the provisions of Federal law implicated; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HECD42749BB3C438484054D9A9B32182A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the types of information, evidence, and public comment sought by the agency.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF422AB7881CE4A849ACF5947FBBA8509"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the head of the agency determines that—</text> 
<clause id="HAF94A39C52C346D4A0AD4C4B62D4B4E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the record of a rulemaking initiated prior to the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></clause> <clause id="H112422A342104118A3478D5555ED41E9"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a prior advanced notice of proposed rulemaking issued pursuant to this Act,</text>
                        </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">is sufficient to support a notice of proposed rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the rulemaking under this section.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6BB3BEA539C2499BAE55D466E84AF2DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination during rulemaking</header> 
<paragraph id="H255ADFD9BA3C4860AF25FF2425910370"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preliminary consultation</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA476DB02E7B2430993A365168322398F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to issuing a notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to a rulemaking under this subsection, the head of an agency shall, as appropriate, consult with the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs on any reasonably foreseeable overlap, inconsistency, or conflict of the proposed rule with any other rule or proposed rule of another agency to regulate an algorithmic decision-making system under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H251E40B8D03E4382A7DC023DB1735DEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Summary</header><text>If the head of the agency proceeds with a rulemaking under this section, the head of the agency shall include a summary of the consultation under this paragraph in the notice of proposed rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D6E7F5A21B845D290EC23EC3925B36A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency that is making a rule under subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3520C5BE9C64409B286B27A6080F5BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult, as appropriate, with the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the National Institute of Standards and Technology on the technical characteristics, evaluation, and governance of an algorithmic decision-making system that the agency seeks to regulate in its rule; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5843AFCC48A4847A995BCD25F9E1DE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include in the rulemaking record a summary of any consultation conducted under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51EC105F8BBF4EED8D0B37905001FCAE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall, to the extent practicable, coordinate with the heads of other agencies to ensure that rules made under subsection (a) do not impose conflicting requirements regarding the use of algorithmic decision-making systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H80C3215BB57A4043B04AD864C1A43C63" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mitigation of disruption of benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency that is making a rule under subsection (a) shall, in making such rule, consider whether the use of the algorithmic decision-making system occurs in connection with the administration of a Government service or public benefit, including by a contractor or service provider, and, where practicable, shall seek to mitigate unnecessary adverse effects of the rule on the delivery, accessibility, timeliness, integrity, or continuity of such service or benefit.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9D8C81F3726A4FC8898F85727C98A37B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, acting through the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs and in consultation with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, shall issue guidance to resolve conflicts and ensure consistency across agencies regarding the rulemaking authority under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2AB06E240874FBD9FD049811CE34768"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Periodic review</header> 
<paragraph id="HD1FBBDA0AB3A44CBA4E39976EF52C6E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after promulgating a rule under subsection (a), and thereafter at intervals determined appropriate by the head of the agency (but not less frequently than once every 5 years), the head of an agency shall review the rule to assess whether, due to technological developments or changes in the use of algorithmic decision-making systems, maintaining the rule is appropriate and that the rule is appropriately tailored to mitigate violations of the Federal law the agency is authorized to enforce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A23B4675CF34AEBA7AE245D28AFD0E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repeal and amendment of rules</header><text>The head of the agency shall repeal or amend any rule that is determined to be inappropriate to maintain or not appropriately tailored to mitigate violations of the Federal law the agency is authorized to enforce.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0BB2ABBD10B4CD0982053958CCD509E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Biennial report</header> 
<paragraph id="H0B933B4A86E94FE1A1F38644567B0FE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agencies that engaged in rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the head of each agency that has engaged in a rulemaking pursuant to the authority under subsection (a) during the 2-year period preceding the submission of the report shall submit to Congress, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and make publicly available, a report on such rulemaking, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HF473B80328224EBDA11B00B46B864350"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the rulemaking;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1106D9F73CFA45B8A299F05A59280445"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of an algorithmic decision-making system the agency determined was likely to materially contribute to violations of the Federal law that the agency was authorized to enforce that the agency sought to mitigate through the rulemaking;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE7A40850EAE43A1B0A57DD69A138482"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hiring and staffing actions undertaken by the agency to support the rulemaking;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E060B0E1F89436BB85D4B47E41C41AE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>challenges encountered by the agency related to such rulemaking;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF8C101DF13642578A71EBD477FBB8D4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>additional personnel and resources needed to support the use of the rulemaking authority under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBB5791ABE874725AF72A225DA9C884D" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of enforcement actions taken by agencies pursuant to a rule made using the authority under subsection (a), including—</text> <clause id="H158D9D89FD64476E925BDC0F177C2182" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the general categories of violations for which enforcement actions were taken; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H33D8A01CA6634291A1B4B5C74B0EA553" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the types and aggregate ranges of penalties or remedies assessed;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A29FD523935482DA6702405AB38FA41" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the rule will regulate an algorithmic decision-making system to prevent violations of the Federal law that the agency is authorized to enforce;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC8DA8C1385A477D9BC45DED5BB5A2A2"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of comments, evidence, or technical assessments received regarding potential disparate impacts or other discriminatory effects associated with the use of the algorithmic decision-making system, and how the agency considered such information in connection with the Federal law the agency is authorized to enforce;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B97A631AAA642E3AF7755EF98D1CA5D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a rule that was repealed or amended pursuant to subsection (e), a summary of the review conducted under such subsection; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80E85CD0D690407A921291985E75FF3B"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of any overlap, inconsistency, or conflict with any other rule or proposed rule of another agency identified during consultation or coordination under subsection (b), and how such overlap, inconsistency, or conflict was addressed or resolved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB04AC687306645F49DD7EA89F81C8436"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain agencies that have not engaged in rulemaking</header> <subparagraph id="H65D8DF90B6A24098B784F5FC172EA350"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the head of each agency described in subparagraph (B) shall submit to Congress, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and make publicly available, a report on—</text> 
<clause id="H480B1E4C0FE0484387731CE71317D4C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the uses of an algorithmic decision-making system that the agency identified are likely to materially contribute to violations of the Federal laws that the agency is authorized to enforce; and</text></clause> <clause id="H503E34A45A824F78B20E3CF297D05AAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the factors the agency considered and information on which the agency relied in making the determination not to engage in a rulemaking pursuant to the authority under subsection (a), including any other available mechanisms used by the agency to mitigate the violations of the Federal laws that the agency is authorized to enforce, and a summary of any technical assessment relied upon by the agency in making such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B1083F7D44647EEACA60EF9121093A1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agency described</header><text>An agency is described in this subparagraph if the agency—</text> <clause id="H7D7B0FC8DB6A435E8F6F49BD6BA9B310"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determined, during the 2-year period preceding the submission of the report, that the use of an algorithmic decision-making system is likely to materially contribute to violations of a Federal law that the agency is authorized to enforce; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F4B91A451C3445CB8375C6A6C29A919"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>did not engage in a rulemaking pursuant to the authority under subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCEFA76F531F740288BBE8E7BB6DE2314" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDAEC9C5183924A469AD00E0C28EB8140" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Algorithmic decision-making system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>algorithmic decision-making system</term> means a computational process integrated into software or hardware, including a process based on statistics, machine learning, artificial intelligence, or any other data processing technique, that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2663290FC784488BB1C4EC16EDCB5E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is used—</text> 
<clause id="HBEE88884CDEA42EF96E59A770CD2C05D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to make or execute a decision; or</text></clause> <clause id="H3A3B42B1E08E44968723D24F699BC8A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist in making or executing a decision, if such process is capable of altering the outcome of the decision; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H243AD712DD9043F7934BEC07EB3B8107"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not passive computing infrastructure.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H552C85D434DE418D836F9EA10F2FB18E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to enforce</header><text>The term <term>authority to enforce</term> means, with respect to an agency—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC2191FDFF226418DB1CCA9B757BF3B1C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authority to issue sanctions (as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code) in response to a violation of Federal law or regulation; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H610C015253204BEB98CEC5B95178E749" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legal authority to bring an action in Federal court to seek a penalty or injunction to remedy a violation of Federal law or regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE05A8204B98403989D81B1523641693" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA96A222FB4A74465AD349D6AA785C7EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Materially contribute</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>materially contribute</term> means, with respect to a violation of Federal law, to play a significant role in bringing about or enabling such violation, including by assisting or facilitating conduct that results in the violation, but not including minimal or incidental support that is unrelated to the violation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H785DCAC81E7F4326B0A391E95067D924"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H135DE0595CF64457AFC1A10962555DA6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Passive computing infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>passive computing infrastructure</term> means any intermediary technology that does not influence or determine the outcome of a decision, make or aid in a decision (including through evaluations, metrics, or scoring), inform policy implementation, or collect data or observations, including web hosting, domain registration, networking, caching, data storage, or cybersecurity.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D568148977143D4A5E7B1A8FE5C20B6" commented="no">
        <enum>(h)</enum>
        <header>Non-Preemption</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt or limit the authority of a State to regulate the use of an algorithmic decision-making system, except to the extent that the regulation of such system by a State is in conflict with this Act or a rule issued under this Act.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

