<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE8A14B244E8048C6BF0CC5D84E7C4B6E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7190 IH: To end detention and electronic monitoring, and redirect funding to community-based wrap-around services.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7190</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To end detention and electronic monitoring, and redirect funding to
            community-based wrap-around services.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H6D370B87419347A78F82B4026374967A" style="OLC">
<section id="H83581BE7A2874DAEB9515181848EE217" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Abolish immigration detention; repeal of detention authority and enforcement</header>
<subsection id="H766496FC6F3A4E6095861812754163B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for release on recognizance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall release on their own recognizance any noncitizen detained by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD67BECE55C464A3B9538EE356E61ED67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of detention authority and enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H00204106B87448E486DC0FC17E24E9B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inspection of applicants for admission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clauses (ii) and (iii)(IV) of section 235(b)(1)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) are repealed.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8E86C613E62A4CDD89663D09D79679A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inspection of other noncitizens</header><text>Subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of section 235(b)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(2)</external-xref>) are repealed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCC6752D06E845FA80DF997CBC09B720"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority relating to inspections</header><text>Section 235(d)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBF85EF6DF1CC423AAC649D6540BB1675"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (A) and (B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D3AE32A4D5D4603808A792BF08E98AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>United States—</quote> and inserting <quote>United States to deliver the noncitizen to an immigration officer for inspection or to a medical officer for examination.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H495E9BB2BB8E49E6BA9F91FACF90FE7E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Apprehension and detention of noncitizens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 236 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC26253382B94D85A794CB4699845A24"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Detention and Removal of noncitizens ordered removed</header><text>Section 241 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H09D4BF3CDB20403CA48700D82296DA2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93A631E68E3C43C9BE52B0A62E07B9BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), and (h) as subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), respectively.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC16554DABADE47CD9E9F44D63722195E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Power of immigration officers and employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D910047C3CB4E6598C8F54FD42BF179"> <subsection id="HFC60248D0A7245688F384440CF37A97D"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any officer or employee of the Service authorized under regulations prescribed by the Attorney General shall have power without warrant to arrest any alien who in his presence or view is entering or attempting to enter the United States in violation of any law or regulation made in pursuance of law regulating the admission, exclusion, expulsion or removal of aliens, or to arrest any alien in the United States, if he has reason to believe that the alien so arrested is in the United States in violation of any such law or regulation and is likely to escape before a warrant can be obtained for his arrest, but the alien arrested shall be taken without unnecessary delay for examination before an officer of the Service having authority to examine aliens as to their right to enter or remain in the United States.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H22408CB990BF407791C3EF402D885EB7"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An alien described in section 101(a)(27)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act who has been battered, abused, neglected, or abandoned, shall not be compelled to contact the alleged abuser (or family member of the alleged abuser) at any stage of applying for special immigrant juvenile status, including after a request for the consent of the Secretary of Homeland Security under section 101(a)(27)(J)(iii)(I) of such Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBA06FB5339C46ECB0D396F345F48FDD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authorizing State and local law enforcement officials to arrest and detain certain noncitizens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 439 of the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1252C">8 U.S.C. 1252C</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2E0C3CBC65E4964AAB7EFA9B948E77E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Communication between State and local government agencies and the Immigration and Naturalization Service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 434 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1644">8 U.S.C. 1644</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD31890F2530D4E8796E538CDC953B1DF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Communication between government agencies and the immigration and naturalization service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE46D7435B1D94AF3BE1D590370D58996" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Public charge; unlawful voters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (5) and (6) of section 237(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H37390CF3C4214257B9621D83C9129D7A" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of contracts for immigration detention</header> <paragraph id="H57EDD84FB3A04B91B243B86A47F70367" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing contracts with respect to physical detention and monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall terminate any contract entered into by the Secretary of Homeland Security on or before the date of the enactment of this Act with respect to immigration detention and monitoring programs, including any contract with any entity that owns or operates a program or facility that provides services related to detention or monitoring.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B66DA11DD6E41B58A780EC9F5B2487F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other contracts with respect to physical detention and monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal funds may be used with respect to immigration detention and monitoring programs, including any contract with any entity that owns or operates a program or facility that provides services related to detention or monitoring.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H83E4F083CAEC4AF2AA57F016739AE77A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of enforcement authorities</header> <subsection id="H4984EAD4D210498EA20A45B65536984F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ankle monitoring system</header> <paragraph id="HCD5BD4456BA7496DAAC7C568B7B16993"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one month after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a plan to remove all ankle monitors from noncitizens being monitored by the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3B7FB962FF544E31889FE74E7934CABB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of ankle monitors</header><text>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall remove each ankle monitor from a noncitizen being monitored by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B6BC45005524ADAA24B484ECC1E0387"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of Federal funds</header><text>Beginning on the date that is six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal funds may be used with respect to ankle monitors or ankle monitoring programs.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD42F1BCFF56D4DB9B3EC5382225D67D0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secure communities program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal funds may be used for information sharing partnerships between the Department of Homeland Security and any State or local law enforcement agency to identify or target noncitizens for the purpose of enforcing the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H28952B919E4944A1BBE095253D1140FB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> may be used—</text>
<paragraph id="HCDA7795898A4466DAED1DF2AD48732C2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to engage in civil immigration enforcement activities, including arrests, detention, removal, or the processing or issuance of charging documents;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H581189FB2AB74AE5B2E72955A24CF162" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enforce, or assist another Federal, State, or local agency to enforce, a criminal offense in which an essential element of the offense is the noncitizen’s immigration status, including State and local offenses and offenses under sections 243, 264, 275, or 276 or subsections (a) or (b) of section 266 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1253">8 U.S.C. 1253</external-xref>; 1304; 1325; 1326; 1306).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HC2C5F702B93E4A6B987DC46941D469E9" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program for wrap-around social services</header>
<subsection id="HEACA27D209AB43828DE9701C987C8FE1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a grant program to award grants to an eligible entity to administer wrap-around social services to any individual affected by the enforcement of the immigration laws (as such term is defined under section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)), including providing—</text> <paragraph id="HDD9F391ED28A4D46AB0B62851A0A8571"><enum>(1)</enum><text>housing assistance;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38E8799BE3034EC1B4E33B84C368D0A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>mental health services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DC69571717D417C8A947C780C4C6174"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assistance accessing healthcare;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H671A7DF976BF4015BA5C78C5DF0F1423"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">financial empowerment and employment assistance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H545B926B784B455E8A3632270ABE3568"><enum>(5)</enum><text>English classes;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H115862E79DDB45D7A709D248872BBE3A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>education assistance; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C6F7DCF7EA9488BBE235FD5A013B557"><enum>(7)</enum><text>immigration legal assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H08E1ED85F3144982A6CB4293CF470AFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section shall be awarded to community-based non-profit organizations that are not involved, and have not previously been involved, in any immigration or law enforcement activity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H70175CA47D204006A89C50CD4E7E6DD8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of services</header><text>Any services provided pursuant to a grant awarded under this section shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H13B3BAE646124275836B49AA38878053"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be provided on an opt-in and voluntary basis and shall not be made contingent on participation in any monitoring or compliance mechanisms; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BF9EAEF894D42B4AE62F0008B929CD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be provided without subjecting individuals to surveillance or monitoring as they access such services, including physical, electronic, or other surveillance or monitoring.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD0F78DD0DE0347638DFBFAF86E4A50CA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions on reporting</header><text>A community-based organization providing services pursuant to a grant awarded under this section may not submit any personal identifying information relating to individuals to any Federal entity.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

