<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77FFC9F909B54C12BBC1B59832352980" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7990 IH: State Department Disability Policy and Accommodations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7990</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for an international disability rights strategy, and for other purposes. provide for an international disability rights strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24A74A062C5B45DE84C107D0E85C7083" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD94CE2F4135B4D14BE09EE27FC069B74"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Department Disability Policy and Accommodations Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEE8F62C435364B41AFCF501C4B3CF4A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disability rights in foreign policy</header><subsection id="H91275BAD7FD24429B28388CFCEEB11C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that international disability rights are foundational to achieving global peace, stability, and prosperity, and should be fully championed as a focus of United States diplomacy and development efforts.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF4C323257D594B1EAA4998E52B9FD3CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Formal policy guidance on disability policy</header><paragraph id="H492BF62965D2485E9F447696BD500011"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, through the Ambassador-at-Large for International Disability Rights and in consultation with relevant foreign affairs agencies, shall develop and adopt a formal policy for advancing disability rights through United States diplomacy and foreign assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE212EFF1191B4819A16C6D70534EDA77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The policy required under paragraph (1) should direct the Department of State’s approach to championing disability rights through the conduct of United States diplomacy and development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56DC5FDC50F14ADEA44944430C44A808"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing and adopting the policy, the Secretary shall consult with—</text><subparagraph id="HAA4FE201DFF84C6D9D2AB353242BD6A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>United States missions and regional and functional bureaus;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF343AEE0C8924BA1AE5CBFF89CA4FD79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities, civil society organizations, international nongovernmental organizations, and international organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDF0083F03FC4892B8911DC87BE43CCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>women, indigenous persons, youth, and survivors of violence living with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7BEF0D15C2F4DDDA1AF4DCAB6FE0737"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>combat-injured persons living with disabilities, including United States security partners and allies, in countries and regions receiving United States security assistance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE15497F85A5C44429C478CCF0D616F10"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Policy implementation</header><text>The Secretary shall update the Foreign Affairs Manual to reflect the policy required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0008EA43CFCD42EBBF06FBD50D7D04E8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall publish such policy on a publicly available website of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2A2A4C97D9E244B1858ABCCEE8761F60"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of International Disability Rights</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C58D640A84744A282C78AC2C3DBADC7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5104 of the Department of State Authorization Act of 2021 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 2345) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF009599F09243158AE910E842AC759F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>should be established</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be established</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H902D3C191D7D44BC93CDDFD42C2653CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) through (d) as subsections (c) through (e), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA30C2906381B45EE821D24B4A78D52D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H4077673020024B1D806C9161DAF1BE22" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="H80DFFCBEB0264F27AEAC4A421601F230"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Office shall coordinate and elevate United States global engagement on disability rights policy, ensuring that the Department of State and relevant Federal agencies promote accessibility, equality of opportunity, and the protection of the rights of persons with disabilities globally.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BF93AE1CCB24B559F681DFC9A4412BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as redesignated by paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EE0BB3D88A1457AA5F4219FA02F92F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>The Office should</quote> and inserting <quote>The Office shall</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AFC7CED719B497A87899E78A47A4A2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), and (8) as paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), and (12), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C7B424DC5C14821B981113EA0BE0213"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2), as redesignated by subparagraph (B), the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2EED8E4BB914EB9934D3F4C3E97BD1F"><paragraph id="H2AB91C8713BE44CEA470544D939A7609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate all international disability policy and international assistance provided by the United States Government, in consultation with relevant and appropriate regional and functional bureaus of the Department and Chiefs of Mission, to support efforts abroad to promote and strengthen respect for the rights of persons with disabilities;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35673C4229574FA5ACC74DFC188107B5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>disabilities; and</quote> and inserting the following: “disabilities;</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8498F5873074827AA25BD324CCF2DE2"><paragraph id="H5649CD84DF054B01A71FC7B57A0438E2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>coordinate disaggregated data collection regarding the United States Government’s foreign assistance and diplomatic activities promoting the rights of persons with disabilities, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, including to the extent feasible—</text><subparagraph id="HBBB3045458664088930E4C1BEB59E34E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed accounting of spending by Federal departments and agencies, including, for each Federal department and agency, the statutory source of spending;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4768F430169D4F45BA61E72F97457C13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amounts spent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D51A87BCDFF4C7B8431BE4FE9976AF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>activities supported to the extent practicable and appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD634EF7B6B6412E9292ED28C8172250"><enum>(10)</enum><text>establish interagency details or rotation opportunities for relevant Federal agencies to be housed within the Office for the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="H7C92F351DAA442F0842D3B40E32AD4D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>augmenting the Office’s ability to share best practices on advancing disability rights policy with United States missions and with international partners; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4712D9776F934E879184B0A7A5B1F900"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strengthening the Office’s United States interagency coordination efforts;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63A84D33108B4261B7C9B46CB0D55EB8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>work with relevant bureaus to promote the use of existing educational and cultural exchanges with international disability policymakers and advocates; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC3310DA91E0482A815A0022DDE990EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5103B151D1F04072877A3C10EF5B278B"><subsection id="H5B5D84179D0D41E382C95B89071B2B47"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Ambassador-at-Large for International Disability Rights</header> <text>The Office shall be headed by an Ambassador-at-Large for International Disability Rights, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to advise the Secretary of State on matters related to disability rights. The Ambassador-at-Large should be a person of recognized distinction in the field of disability rights. The Ambassador-at-Large shall be provided with appropriate funding and staff consistent with the duties of the Office and with Department of State guidance on the status of an Office.</text>
 </subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAC4F9D4C046482F8CEF440A5AA9E064"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sub-section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEE1B723B2684C608F50C65D82869D56"><subsection id="H1FA4BD169BFF44D2BE5882C4B564A175"><enum>(f)</enum><header>International Disability Rights strategy</header><paragraph id="HD254C8C2BD664C9D893F70AA04A83081"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Ambassador-at-Large appointed under subsection (d), and in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies and nongovernmental organizations, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy to—</text><subparagraph id="HDC3DDA7274A34A69A4CF8C3D18059B7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>achieve the purposes described in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BA2B77E02F94066834164057DF93492"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify target countries and regions for prioritization of the Department’s international assistance efforts related to the rights of persons with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAF144E7E1CE4BFDAFD35F003DAA48B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify United States foreign assistance resources to be used to implement the strategy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25DE2DC76D674B16BE1C7F84F515183F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish country action plans to advance the rights of persons with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7AAB5B22D214026B9FA07F4661EAE44"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop partnerships with the private sector, nongovernmental organizations, international organizations, and research and academic institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A5301F8DBF241299627924BFA154D45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><subparagraph id="H6BFE581DE9274A8A82B1875A64931CA1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after submission of the strategy required under paragraph (1), and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Ambassador-at-Large for International Disability Rights and relevant Federal agencies, should provide the appropriate congressional committees with a written description of results achieved, including—</text><clause id="H48BE31FC53D544C89F08FBA1794157D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>progress on implementation of the strategy;</text></clause><clause id="H64F68FC24D9B4B36B776FA99CD6E8DDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of efforts to coordinate United States international disability rights activities and initiatives with foreign governments, international organizations, nongovernmental organizations, and other key stakeholders related to the rights of persons with disabilities;</text></clause><clause id="HA4A89AD98F3E4970822ECC98A3DF7368"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a detailed accounting of spending by the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, and other relevant Federal agencies on United States international disability rights assistance to foreign governments international organizations related to the rights of persons with disabilities; and</text></clause><clause id="H9AAAE3FB69B84FFFACB2B9A6DE0BC5DE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of educational and cultural exchanges focused on advancing international disability rights.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC14CB02ACB33433BB8ABC4003293A928"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disaggregation of data</header><text>The data submitted under subparagraph (A) should, where feasible, be disaggregated by country, gender of recipients of assistance, funding account, funding levels, and fiscal year of funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B180135F5C4BB3AA314344783E0869"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF244A37A15284747B26DC962A6C051A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0809E467A73E4633955E97320071B197"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BB1C2127A2A45B8880250F22A57C078"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, to achieve the purposes described in subsection (b) of section 5104 of the Department of State Authorization Act of 2021, as amended by subsection (a) of this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE0546DDDE06D41BA9A854E8CC7360A6D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Departmental hiring and facilities accessibility</header><subsection id="HC2FF99362FCF4097A1C4896FD071C96B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary of State for Management shall, in consultation with the Office of International Disability Rights, ensure equal access to hiring and recruitment and overseas assignments, for the Civil Service and Foreign Service officers and locally employed staff with disabilities and their family members with chronic medical conditions or disabilities, consistent with the provision of a veterans’ preference in accordance with section 2108 of title 5, United States Code, and related sections and with due consideration for locally employed staff who sustained service-related disabilities while serving as security partners or allies in support of United States military or intelligence operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE878C2180C544FEA9907095E4F85628D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Under Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H287A2A9070DA4977A3A58D35ED02AB55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that United States embassies, consulates, and leased facilities abroad are in compliance with United States Access Board standards, including accessibility to people with disabilities, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H3B36FB5F50DA4F31A34EA14230F5CA23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>making websites and other forms of communication accessible to people with disabilities and providing reasonable accommodations to program participants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H959E99759F0A4718867BD084996B36FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring accessibility of United States Government facilities by contracting with local contractors and subcontractors that meet the requirements of section 503 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/793">29 U.S.C. 793</external-xref>) to affirmatively hire workers with disabilities, including combat-injured persons with disabilities who served alongside United States forces or in United States-backed conflicts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12C4815288474AF5B466FA1D29B4AD7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consulting with the Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contracts Compliance to ensure all Department of State contractors are compliant with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) and section 503 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/793">29 U.S.C. 793</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E335BC9D7A04076805D3939E844DC4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the policies and practices for the recruitment and placement of Foreign Service officers and their families encourage the hiring and placement of people with disabilities in compliance with the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F83B9CB3CC9467692F474ED4827E839"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult with the Disability Rights Section of the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice to ensure that Department of State hiring is compliant with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) and section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/791">29 U.S.C. 791</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C72DAC6A99443038CA48CBF95224AAE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that policies are in place for hiring locally employed staff in embassies and consulates outside the United States to ensure that accommodations are offered, provided, and funded from the Department’s centralized reasonable accommodation fund, including specialized accommodations for injuries sustained in support of United States national security interests.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FA3374BE7634610AF48140FF20AA665"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Facility accessibility</header><text>The Under Secretary for Management shall, in consultation with the Office of International Disability Rights—</text><paragraph id="H9B3B080F15074F56965D8EB046526852"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that embassies and consulates and their services are accessible to people with disabilities, including with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HCD1CD8B31A5F4547A521B8551CEECBFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the physical accessibility of facilities housing embassies and consulates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C50536899AD481DA25CA94E979E915F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>websites of United States embassies and consulates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H481BF4316EA04850A02EA454937E78BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>public internet and telecommunications; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8CC20648AA844E0AA1BDD6C90D0CC3A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other means of communication with United States residents and the general public; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2093AD9007B54147B433DAB056A8506D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure diplomatic residences meet the adaptable standards set by the Director of the Bureau of Overseas Buildings Operations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H372C3A94996242EF89C4E7962DA2C213"><enum>5.</enum><header>Training</header><subsection id="H55FAA6C26A3F41A7A3B32E75D51BDC7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall require online or in-person disability policy training for all civil service and Foreign Service personnel of the Department of State and chiefs of mission, including on—</text><paragraph id="H05DF0EA4AF184EBEBC851F48F2871642"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how to develop policies and programs that reflect United States disability policy priorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E39DD3AEDBF497A8789E64F4BB0D331"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how to help ensure a work environment in compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCBCA95727D747F58F65514B43E7C42D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how to conduct analyses of relevant laws and programming;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF301B4CF82714163B8F89C4A45F304EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how to engage local organizations led by and focused on people with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H765962B6ED5345F6A3409F550678D7D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>how to help remove barriers to seeking and accessing United States foreign assistance for organizations serving people with disabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H127AC7EBA6D048BBA5B2D347060BF34B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensuring United States humanitarian response incorporates and elevates the needs of people with disabilities, in line with established international frameworks, including the Inter-Agency Standing Committee (IASC) guidelines and the Charter on Inclusion of Persons with Disabilities in Humanitarian Action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0C01F7A9ED848A4B0F1F69BE09CA2EE"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Country-Specific and cultural considerations</header> <text>The Secretary shall ensure that training for Foreign Service officers under subsection (a) includes country-specific and cultural considerations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF727F56208AB431A9E4EAB0E066E99DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Foreign Service officers</header><text>Section 708(a)(1) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4028">22 U.S.C. 4028(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H24AA0C2BDAC94AF180F627393CC3B968"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA34CECEBC95140BDA9010840E446BB23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE26B48CC4A184E4581AA033F56923C1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE741DC472A84F1EB638889CD1DB64A6"><subparagraph id="H5EC1E0217A6A44F2BF25D1D249DADDEF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>instruction on recognizing risks and vulnerabilities of individuals with disabilities in specific country contexts, addressing needs of people with disabilities in policymaking and outreach at United States embassies and analysis of disability-inclusive laws and programming in local country contexts; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0BE9813173544636BE00DCEC63D1E8A0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report and briefing requirements</header><subsection id="H9567804F982441C6B25A469D30806F48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall provide to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report and briefing on the steps taken to implement this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFEA60CAE1ACD40CFA6F2C9FE1230CE87"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Matters To be included</header> <text>The report and briefing required under subsection (a) shall include—</text>
        <paragraph id="H0F3F0C287208472E9FDD7863B7D21985">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>an explanation of policies and programs to fulfill—</text> <subparagraph id="H445991C0731541389190293F455E7DB0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the duties of the Office of International Disability Rights established under section 4; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFEB695DDBB6B47FA9FB5B07689DEB33D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the training requirements under section 6;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H944209F18DB841D994590DD8163580F4"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>a description of the status of efforts to mainstream disability policy through the conduct of United States diplomatic outreach and programming without regard to whether such programming is specifically directed toward people with disabilities;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6E9FCF1C3D714DAB97AFAFAFB28A1CA7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>an explanation of disability-specific programming across the Department;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8ACB4876D844EFAB1C184618C26CBA9"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>a description of the status of accessible facilities in all foreign missions, as required under section 5(c);</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3DF824359B92465FBF57D1AC0B4724A7">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>a description of any policy, programming, or human resources gaps to mainstreaming disability rights policy throughout the Department, and plans to address gaps through appropriate mechanisms;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H03E141F82E264BB78D95E5304F392F27">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>a description of progress made on the realization of the rights of people with disabilities as a result of Department policies and programming;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H131FB9704DC0458A83184B0FA306993C">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>an explanation of the current status of the Department’s evidence gathering and improved systematic disability data collection, including the use of disaggregated data, in order to ensure that programming, monitoring, and reporting reflect and address the risks and needs of people with disabilities; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8E9F0C6F14734203BA038DF1ADD2AF58">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>recommendations for legislative actions to fully implement the matters described in paragraphs (1) through (7).</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE2B0D8DE02474793A872DF33E23DE47E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Judy Heumann Foreign and Civil Service Disability Fellowship program</header><subsection id="H1912F440926342CD85B78C4B4FDED370"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HD7A551E3182A49D8A52BAA16CD023500"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disability rights are foundational to human rights, national security, and positive economic growth and development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63E64989ABC840E0BDD4F05B4E485D9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of State shall seek to expand professional development opportunities for civil service and Foreign Service personnel to become better equipped to advance disability rights abroad and to ensure an accessible and inclusive workplace at the Department and United States missions abroad.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF500575C57F34EEBB02E7D5F761D2AAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H7E041463480E4549A3FDCE835662E30F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF89766F191394F92B1819E9F8581D418"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organization of persons with disabilities</header><text>The term <term>organization of persons with disabilities</term> means a nongovernmental civil society organization, including a think tank, nonprofit, nongovernmental organization, academic institution, or other organization, that—</text><subparagraph id="HA324D2CA2A7A419196C2B8D6980C5BB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes staff leadership and a board of directors the majority of which consists of people with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2F6A6BA8E8E426F82B89EFC46C24794"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serves people with disabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC34F657A0AF4878AC063775403A669C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish and administer the Judy Heumann Foreign Service Disability Fellowship (referred in this section as the <quote>Fellowship</quote>) to expand Department expertise on disability rights policy formulation, execution, negotiation, and advocacy. The Secretary shall be responsible for designing, implementing, and operating the Fellowship program, including setting standards for successful completion of each fellowship.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA83E6E49F8A74A7AB05E6FAE21676AF9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of fellows</header><paragraph id="HE23778EE4E0747DE8B0B84AFE59DE8EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish criteria for selecting the fellows and shall play a central role in selecting at least 2 fellows for the Fellowship each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E008C1515CA4494A162B56F2CDD2481"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection and placement</header><text>The Secretary of State shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7F8FD84F033F4FCBAB7E7E30B52F7492"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make efforts to recruit fellowship candidates who reflect the diversity of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B640511D0C44F8EB60D5ACD97D894A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>select fellows from among entry-, mid-, and senior-level Foreign Service and civil service personnel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80AD69F544274402A6184AB279950D94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>approve fellowship placements between 6 months to one year in duration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CACD15018EA4792995BC897F6CA38D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitate fellowship placement with an organization of persons with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1462BD03FA64DA0A54BA1DD7A2B0F45"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for each fellow, establish performance goals and performance indicators as part of fellows’ annual review process; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26EDB1C28FA8422FB690E4C9285C33CC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>reimburse one international trip and one domestic trip per fellow.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1079B19402B4EBEB8148720DB757163"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fellowship activities</header><text>Fellows participating in the Fellowship program shall—</text><paragraph id="H596B9F20F6B646EAAE436EE27873B6D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>study the United Nations Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities, done at New York December 12, 2006;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA51614F3C52C42D08FC196C575485FD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>attend the Conference of States Parties to the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (COSP) along with one member of the hosting organization of persons with disabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2F22F1FF6C46CEB30DA5F94DA16888"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carry out such other activities as the Ambassador-at-Large for International Disability Rights determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C863B54175D443FA073809389BE6411"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the completion of the Fellowship by the initial cohort of fellows selected under subsection (d), and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of the Fellowship, including—</text><paragraph id="HCD46DE65E76C4F8484DD6CC802043E96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the cohort of fellows who completed a fellowship during the preceding one-year period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0736135AF340481D804B2C31912889E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the fellowships and placements, including feedback on implementation and lessons learned; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD479BE141A64BE58BFBCFDB62ED4313"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of trends relating to the diversity of each cohort of fellows since the establishment of the Fellowship program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8610662CB19A40DD8D99755A4D9F2411"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2026 and each subsequent fiscal year to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

