<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06D6579749BB4B21B7785A47C4809A17" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8219 IH: Barring Leverage and Obstruction that Contributes to Kremlin Profits Undermining Transatlantic Interests and NATO Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8219</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage Hungary to end its reliance on Russian energy and prevent Hungary’s efforts to obstruct financial or security assistance to Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B5837EF5A5D44739D1A450BE4AFE892" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5AB9529D1EF94DB490C660253D810D26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Barring Leverage and Obstruction that Contributes to Kremlin Profits Undermining Transatlantic Interests and NATO Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BLOCK PUTIN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8D0253F4498B4798BA5AA8A7988B943E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBC1024CE095A459197B222C5BF654E63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Russian Federation’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022 has demonstrated the strategic risks of Europe’s dependence on the Russian Federation for energy, specifically oil and gas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCCC3201FA4B4D0EA4BD8D036DB773EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Following the Russian Federation’s invasion of Ukraine, the United States, the European Union, and their partners imposed broad, punitive sanctions on the Russian Federation that limited the Russian Federation’s income from energy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52E0CDA636E049FA886D1EB33B263972"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In May 2022, the European Commission launched the REPowerEU initiative to phase out dependence on Russian energy sources before 2028.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2488E968F0CF470AADA55EDCEFB16640"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since February 2022, the European Union has subsequently reduced its dependence on Russian fossil fuels by approximately 90 percent by cutting oil imports by more than 90 percent and reducing pipeline gas deliveries by roughly 80 percent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3892B3865A6B45B585DDC67C7AF0A130"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Most European countries have undertaken significant measures to reduce their Russian energy imports in accordance with the REPowerEU initiative, but Hungary and Slovakia requested exemptions to the timeline.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA68DE2DE7849472B8AFB79A1251DE8EA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Since February 2022, Hungary increased its dependence on Russian energy by an estimated 30 percent, providing approximately $6,700,000,000 in crude oil revenue to the Russian Federation between February 24, 2022, and December 31, 2024.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8686A823CCF744688BD01E36B1BDB6C2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On September 23, 2025, President Donald Trump said member countries of the European Union had <quote>to immediately cease all energy purchases from Russia</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF7EB092433E4CA7A646C0C264051743"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On October 23, 2025, the Council of the European Union adopted the 19th package of restrictive measures against the Russian Federation, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6399EE3096F542989E62EF7E6C633712"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a ban on imports of Russian liquefied natural gas into the European Union;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69ED52D035B3432AA5B2116284FAB108"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a full transaction ban on Rosneft and Gazprom Neft;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16EDC338B35B4926945226AA21BD319D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>measures against third-country operators (which enable the Russian Federation’s revenue streams), 2 Chinese refineries, and a Chinese oil trader; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BFFECB894F346F4962002A821B681A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>strengthened enforcement against maritime circumvention and the <quote>shadow fleet</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42068028DFF244389A7B933A53521FDA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In October 2025, the United States imposed secondary sanctions on Lukoil and Rosneft.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA2313FA986644D688164C33A3462377"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Hungary has shown no sign of reducing its dependence on Russian fossil fuels.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83108536DFF04DE9AA5F0491D823589A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In November 2025, Hungary reportedly received an exemption from sanctions imposed by the United States related to its continued purchase of Russian oil and gas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9051EA5FAA1246D8AD76788E41706964"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In February 2026, Hungary blocked a €90,000,000,000 loan package by the European Union intended for Ukraine’s military and budget support and blocked the proposed 20th European Union sanctions package, demanding in exchange the resumption of Russian oil transit through the Druzhba pipeline.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA274B65320E6421FBE1FDB5AE051C62D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Slovakia has vowed to follow Hungary’s example and block the provision of European Union funds to Ukraine if Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban loses his election.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBCB3DDF60931497AB29CAC23FF72A634"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress; statement of policy</header> <subsection id="HF7F53FBF38624DF09BC2969D369E3F1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that it is in the national security interests of the United States—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD477908CB88A4B14BA5F2CE1E0AACB01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to encourage countries to diversify from Russian energy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FB892B05CF84C4D87E91DC3F042AB35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for European Union member states to finance support for Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB0EB7747AC5146B8AAE8295AC7EA468D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States to hold Hungary accountable for actions that undermine the national security interests of the United States described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5477933ABDB54BEEBC5950B8CBA354BA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header> <subsection id="H278F5D3ADD3D46FDB28366D6AB8DBD73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to the individuals described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CC04522CB514E1383EF40E95BC0726B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text>The individuals described in this subsection are senior officials of the Government of Hungary that, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB9B664B56E3414AAC1C2C1A95E0BCC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take steps to block, delay, or otherwise obstruct additional financial or security assistance to Ukraine through bilateral, European Union, North Atlantic Treaty Organization, or other multilateral mechanisms; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC7B531401754797B8615E866D31107B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>approve or continue to facilitate oil or natural gas imports from the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1CF21ECA5BB5409487C0A0835055E335"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H15F9D3CAC5684C25809952FAE899A5D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of an individual described in subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE9F16F868994BA98DF96D78C7DA1171"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain individuals</header> <subparagraph id="HA1828629E4AB40D3AECC41CD57530CC8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (b) is—</text> 
<clause id="H161BAFC2742C41A08DEF707A8FCA917E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="HDC0C43EE7147416EBBA17329E9F31F47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HECE2490CA2884E89A1DDC7DA57BFFC5B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D9D3CE3DB4344548FC0C596B8B339D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visa revoked</header> <clause id="H5E90780DF4914D6B903B7443D06D5986"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien described in subparagraph (A) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDA7F4D94EC5B41778FD924A88914AE41"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>)—</text> <subclause id="H10E625DC8D364380B469D1B0674F0B8B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2731647AEBB54E3597D6018EAEC1D871"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H77A5B7C8576B4EFB9AAF29D17E7185CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> <paragraph id="HC57CE1A5AA454AC7AD675237E7C53EDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Decreased dependency on Russian oil and gas and allowing assistance to Ukraine</header><text>The President shall not impose sanctions under this section if the Government of Hungary has—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDF9960638014BE49F7656D40EB499F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">formally adopted and begun implementation of a public, time-bound plan to end the dependency of Hungary on oil and natural gas imports from the Russian Federation that includes a binding commitment to achieve substantial diversification of oil and natural gas imports before 2028; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9E7DC4BE61349B98A63178D15D5E5A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a continuous period of not less than 180 days, ceased any official action, to block, delay, or otherwise obstruct additional financial or security assistance to Ukraine through bilateral, European Union, North Atlantic Treaty Organization, or other multilateral mechanisms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1630295E1EC84BA7B229609D04147343"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with international obligations and law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</text> <subparagraph id="HA928060B35AD446A825FFF0B4FEED1C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to comply with United States obligations under—</text> 
<clause id="HFA46F8BEB07A4A368B8CD93571575AE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947;</text></clause> <clause id="HD336104B41A24595A67F188FE9A2DE9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H60D4CCD0DA1146DDAED64DE01374B423"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other international agreement; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1952938866634B728AE86AAD08FB59B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out or assist law enforcement activity in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H732540B62E7B48B59467271B26DE236F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to—</text> <subparagraph id="H27AEAC4B374D458A8BE72755811464AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6287F750B0024714A05ABA21D1BA2663"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H718AC944841140DDB3512AA366BBE966" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEBCC197ED5444C25A155550D1044F4BA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0DC81BB1D11407A868939DD428E09BC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94E0E1D6952148D5A33B374015DCA47B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF573C60A7D184AFBA9629711C57C49C5" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H79A04131072A4B4FA913BDAC31CDAC14"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section for a period not to exceed 180 days if the President determines and certifies to the appropriate committees of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H5188B3895E354442AE4B40974DF7C2D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FA1C1843CA84412973E5DBA89118E8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the individual has committed to refrain from engaging in any action described in subsection (b) for a period of not less than one year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1DDAA405BF314381AC71C02ECCDC2916"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Secretary of State submits to the appropriate committees of Congress a written certification that the Government of Hungary has—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7DF1DD7D049A4FE4909B8D3FF8B739BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>formally adopted and begun implementation of a public, time-bound plan to end the dependency of the country on oil and natural gas imports from the Russian Federation that includes a binding commitment to achieve substantial diversification of oil and natural gas imports by not later than one year from the date of such termination; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H638BB4CC759D43D1845D7F3F957FF0BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for a continuous period of not less than 180 days, ceased any official action to block, delay, or otherwise obstruct additional financial or security assistance to Ukraine through bilateral, European Union, North Atlantic Treaty Organization, or other multilateral mechanisms.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H39C5C5CDC7444AB7BB970E26789CB6C5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE480E88C13E04E01A70166B32B30C9C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien; lawfully admitted for permanent residence</header><text>The terms <term>admission</term>, <term>admitted</term>, <term>alien</term>, and <term>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C1FA44EE8AB478B8B0025A7EA81F937"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E0A0619FA0E4F91AD4A88B7692A781E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E5ABFA69FBE493DB9D47AB45D04889C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A0F52C616CD4298A54B153483FD8EC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H72AFAEEECB5B44CCB6D60B4AE558FF5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5BEEEAFEF24463BB1C39281B13FD3CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02EBC50E840B4AB8915D62F076851E28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HCF264D300A444F47A0BFDC324D1B9A3B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on United States Government facilitation of Hungarian purchases of Russian oil and gas</header> <subsection id="HFF9D07D3C0C04CE583254F19EC17E058"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State shall jointly submit to the committees specified in subsection (c) a report that provides the justification for any United States Government facilitation of purchases of Russian Federation oil and national gas by the Government of Hungary or any related entities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE428439521AD491EA635CBF2251C4A89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H889C10D4EA7F4707AFAD819EF2BFF8B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E0EA2626CE0419AAA4D2BB8CD8B0899"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any license or comfort letter issued on or after October 22, 2025, to, or for the benefit of, the Government of Hungary or Hungarian individuals or entities that were related to oil, petroleum products, or natural gas of Russian Federation origin, including with respect to transactions involving energy companies or financial institutions designated for the imposition of sanctions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1BD9001A623488A96CADBF60AF4DB75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the period of effectiveness of any license or comfort letter described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61BB21EC7954476A8A7A317199624969"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any foreign policy guidance by the Department of State conveyed to the Department of the Treasury related to the issuance of any license or comfort letter described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C26CF2AFCA647C58037F540A23D580C"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>any information communicated to the Government of Hungary regarding the potential renewal or extension of any license or comfort letter described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89FB5181783A410D8D7EA245CF983E16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimate of the total quantity of oil and gas of Russian Federation origin purchased by the Government of Hungary or Hungarian individuals or entities, by volume and dollar value, since the effective date of any license or comfort letter described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF588F4E33B4042769D06E031CA449125"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Committees specified</header><text>The committees specified in this subsection are—</text> 
<paragraph id="H060A531C053A49BDA4DF5088BA330659"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53A1D1EA7DAB4453A22311E048EE5251"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee of Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA627771B617345F6B268AD9F62E9F480"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in an unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

