<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26506-CTG-LX-J8W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 750 ATS: Recognizing “National Public Works Week” and the contributions of public works professionals.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 750</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing <quote>National Public Works Week</quote> and the contributions of public works professionals.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals provide essential services that support public health, safety, and quality of life in communities across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these services include the construction, operation, and maintenance of transportation systems, water and wastewater infrastructure, stormwater systems, solid waste management, and public facilities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public works personnel play an important role in emergency response and recovery efforts, including clearing debris, restoring access, and helping communities rebuild following disasters;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reliable infrastructure is critical to economic growth, environmental stewardship, and community resilience;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public works agencies depend on a skilled and dedicated workforce to deliver these services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Public Works Week will be observed from May 17 through May 23, 2026, with the theme, “Rooted in Service. Powered by Community.”; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Public Works Week highlights the contributions of public works professionals and increases understanding of the infrastructure that serves the public: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ida99a9f4b8ddd4614b07d2e54cc5318eb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes <quote>National Public Works Week</quote> and the contributions of public works professionals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1312eeb3168b4dc487df989520f17565"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends public works professionals for their service to communities across the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82789da327994e73820115bb09679c04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages greater public awareness of the importance of public works and infrastructure.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

