<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL26250-S62-RP-G79"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4575 IS: Supporting Mental Assistance Responder Teams Community Policing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide funding for innovations in community policing, mental health care, and community safety, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Mental Assistance Responder Teams Community Policing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SMART Community Policing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id2900E3B0DCDE478BB1EA6AF8DCB45639"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to strengthen community policing programs to—</text><paragraph id="idEB8A6BE40BEA4A2891EE5AC2CDBF0021"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">de-escalate interactions with law enforcement officers to achieve better outcomes for non-violent individuals experiencing crisis or trauma relating to mental health issues, poverty, homelessness, and substance use disorders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05249C8F0C2C4D9DA6FB9B97AFFA6486"><enum>(2)</enum><text>build collaborative partnerships to connect individuals with mental health services and community resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBF284ED43426489FBEEBC7730A73A9A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>produce better outcomes for communities and law enforcement officers by delivering the appropriate treatment and other support services to individuals in need.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id62AE036453C0493EB1414457C23DBDE5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional authorized uses of COPS funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1701(b) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idc7da9cee56024583ba9108c2e74b59a2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (24), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b243a89db114761835349d8e8bc5188"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (25), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0eba5bbbaece4235bac6119b297a2f4f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e88bfc5ca7b4dd19a2e4265f1eec0a7"><paragraph id="id116524f856374f15af1008840bf6ebe9"><enum>(26)</enum><text>to establish or expand a mobile crisis team program to—</text><subparagraph id="idA2B5480D9EFC4C709DD861E33E9143DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hire skilled mental health professionals and paramedics to—</text><clause id="idFD4FE7E6433B424D9B247F2446B33D4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>respond to—</text><subclause id="id781217B7271D43329B6C1B3B29A20660"><enum>(I)</enum><text>certain 911 dispatch calls at the request of law enforcement officers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4EEA0DB30D244BF09A9B027256649A05"><enum>(II)</enum><text>community members requesting assistance directly;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id1AFC4C3C84724644BF6F2788A90BCF70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>stabilize encounters between law enforcement officers and individuals experiencing a mental or behavioral health crisis; and</text></clause><clause id="id21525408E7CE46F8AF910EE5582F8663"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assume responsibility for securing mental health services for individuals, including individuals in crisis who may need further evaluation and treatment;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id365D9506C6F9488F9EAB0E947B722A7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>train law enforcement officers partnering with mental health professionals and paramedics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE50DEA9AAC8F49EAB7CB33F72FB2D5A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>use a mobile unit to facilitate the response of law enforcement officers and mental health professionals and paramedics to community members experiencing a mental or behavioral health crisis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57EF088587054F649B89B05B9B86DE6C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>hire other personnel;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD6FA8D246E874D42B4B7DE166A33749A"><enum>(27)</enum><text>to establish or expand a co-responder program under which—</text><subparagraph id="idBB1D1EDCEB8843068959C6DE630604F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a trained law enforcement officer is paired with a behavioral health clinician or paramedic to—</text><clause id="id5D76BC0386AC417BB8C21D20A866C57B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>de-escalate situations involving a mental health crisis;</text></clause><clause id="id16D3299903A748E78CBDC3BBF50311E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>connect individuals with mental illness to appropriate services; and</text></clause><clause id="id4306FECE5F094BA2BAFDBCB576C6D782"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide other effective and efficient responses to individuals with mental illness; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAA37A424E0A547419315AFA3C96DD383"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional personnel, including law enforcement officers and case managers, may be hired; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6A67354A4B7F4B79806C0E281DFB51A8"><enum>(28)</enum><text>to establish or expand a case management and outreach team—</text><subparagraph id="idA4F900CFC6794C788DBA858659B95FEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to follow up with individuals experiencing a mental or behavioral health crisis to—</text><clause id="id2E172441FEAF4363931E75FBA6E93EA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>connect those individuals with mental health services and community resources; and</text></clause><clause id="idD6B4FB2D93784950A46A18E7AF2360C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>help those individuals abide by treatment plans and meet other responsibilities, such as work, school, and training;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC16A7D24A8314A76B19CF34DBBCB74D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop specific solutions for, and provide support resources to, individuals who frequently use emergency services to reduce repeat interactions between the individuals described in subparagraph (A) and law enforcement officers or mental health professionals and paramedics; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD56DCE417F104DB19131C842630A7D23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which may be established as a part of a mobile crisis team program under paragraph (26), a co-responder program under paragraph (27), or an independent team.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

