<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HABEEF27E8BE84B69B0F35910F8242FFF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9579 IH: Department of Homeland Security Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9579</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260702">July 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to make certain improvements in the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3DC141FC6760482E99AC9459CB3AFDDE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H72D5A63C63A644F682A76A5DF21C7FCF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2FBE798953F34FAB947D2AD33AA6B5C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties</header> <subsection id="H7395D7FA08524D7790917943EA2D15BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 705 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/345">6 U.S.C. 345</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAA6B934A33454A75A13A6454A06C9C2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Establishment of</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47A20AFC0AEB46CE98554EB79E2B7466"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) and (b) and inserting the following new subsections:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HFE25246B9FB9439F85C24B7F332443ED" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H68D73BF8FDBE45F9BDB86136B8663ED3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="H2EAB647E225B497AB9B3DB28BF181C67" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Department an Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>). The head of the Office is the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties (referred to in this section as the <quote>Officer</quote>), who shall report directly to the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9B09AAC9EFB4A23B8F72129F2C7F921"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Secretary and the head of each component shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H150C3993B3EB459AB94D0CEC37C2B0FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department and the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of such component—</text> <clause id="HDC4A5D03AEAA4611A91C615749ECEB7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have the information, materials, and resources, including appropriate staffing, necessary to carry out the functions of the Office;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE555D2EC0631489CA4187CEAF65EDFDB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are consulted in advance of new or proposed changes to policies, programs, initiatives, or activities impacting civil rights or civil liberties; and</text></clause> <clause id="H34AF024E2AB64EC88540AD94F132310B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are given full and complete access to all materials and personnel necessary to carry out the functions of the Office; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05A5C73A62F9433885BE52145E582DA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider advice and recommendations from the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department in the development and implementation of policies, programs, initiatives, and activities impacting civil rights or civil liberties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H05812199E0E94CEBA4130C796744AE66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Officer shall carry out the following responsibilities:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5AA2B84F3AD34A6AAF7D3347A7CB8D6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Oversee compliance with constitutional, statutory, regulatory, policy, and other requirements relating to the civil rights or civil liberties of individuals affected by the policies, programs, initiatives, or activities of the Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22DAA5063ACF4B2E93CE498EB5717E11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Review and assess information concerning abuses of civil rights or civil liberties, and profiling on the basis of race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability, or other characteristics, by employees or officials of the Department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF706D99934574D22866B47F7B4D4798A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Integrate civil rights and civil liberties protections into all policies, programs, initiatives, and activities of the Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93009505465149448A0D107B18D57619"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Conduct civil rights and civil liberties assessments, as appropriate, prior to the implementation of new Department regulations, policies, programs, initiatives, or activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CCE4D320B5F4C5F8E51512A47983006"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Conduct periodic reviews and assessments of policies, programs, initiatives, and activities of the Department relating to civil rights and civil liberties, including reviews and assessments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA10C3A6614341DDB9F1AFF7994757C5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Provide to the Secretary, the heads of components, and other personnel within the Department policy advice, recommendations, and other technical assistance relating to civil rights and civil liberties.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BED7B0D50734CB58004E4097C76B62A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Investigate complaints and information indicating possible abuses of civil rights or civil liberties by employees or officials of the Department, unless the Inspector General of the Department determines that any such complaint should be investigated by the Inspector General.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00E91CC250C24DCBADE013BCCCB9981C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Initiate reviews and assessments of the administration of the policies, programs, initiatives, and activities of the Department relating to civil rights and civil liberties.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC056BD127C31403DA5C34E6BC91B3FD8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Coordinate with the Privacy Officer appointed under section 222 to ensure the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H4906FAE12A094A69B474B0230564D4FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Policies, programs, initiatives, or activities involving civil rights, civil liberties, or privacy considerations are addressed in an integrated and comprehensive manner.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32B8ACD3B79B452697E0D9BFAC875972"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Congress receives appropriate reports regarding such policies, programs, initiatives, and activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD46A584AF37424C976E8BCF66421721"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Lead the equal employment opportunity programs of the Department, including complaint management and adjudication, workforce diversity, and promotion of merit system principles.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0783C0119404D8DAD328A9A31C18708"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Make publicly available through accessible communications channels, including the website of the Department, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H037203859CDE45FDBD50DB2F4E14DAF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information on the responsibilities and functions of, and how to contact, the Office.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C6B9183083B4D1A97774660A61151D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Summaries of investigations carried out pursuant to paragraph (7) that result in recommendations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83925A0A984545E9BC1CD97E11DA3ED1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Summaries of assessments and reviews carried out pursuant to paragraphs (4), (5), or (8), as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A1B864CB7CD4EED8F1610EB620D6B55"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Engage with individuals, stakeholders, and communities the civil rights and civil liberties of which may be affected by the policies, programs, initiatives, or activities of the Department, including by carrying out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFAC2A0E5E0A74BF4AC685ED9F16D31FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Informing such individuals, stakeholders, and communities concerning such policies, programs, initiatives, or activities, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60DAF1D091094A519C6682DD8028C1B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Providing information regarding how to report and access redress processes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H944BAF7025B14FD2841A7F333F33BD48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Providing Department leadership and other personnel within the Department feedback from such individuals, stakeholders, and communities regarding the civil rights and civil liberties impacts of such policies, programs, initiatives, or activities, and working with State, local, Tribal, and territorial homeland security partners to enhance the Department’s policymaking and program implementation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A4A228CDF0E40C880D0C9626552FF47"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Lead the Department’s language access work to ensure the Department engages effectively with individuals, stakeholders, and communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BA69F4F152E41B8B5DABA99FDA118C8"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Participate in the hiring or designation of a civil rights and civil liberties officer within each component and participate in the performance review process for each such officer.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9279B2BBFF6468E976035E231101555">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Authority To investigate</header>
              <paragraph id="HEE6AB29637854BA993BE785836ABA4B5">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>For the purposes of paragraph (7) of subsection (b), the Officer shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H6415082A6B204CB6AC4306B980ECA7B5"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>have timely access to all materials and personnel necessary to carry out the functions of the Office;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H4786E66ED5E042D2848A866E53AE66F2">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>issue such reports as are necessary or appropriate in accordance with subsection (g);</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HEA0D5883C843435CA5BC40D153C99BD5">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>conduct an investigation in such manner as the Secretary directs; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9FB31012DAB433489AE62E40A308FC8"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>administer to or take from any person an oath, affirmation, or affidavit, whenever necessary to perform the responsibilities of the Officer.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H8420612659314ACE8ABA1FF47F6765D5">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Effect of oaths</header>
 <text>Any oath, affirmation, or affidavit administered or taken pursuant to subparagraph (D) of paragraph (1) by or before an employee of the Office designated for such purpose by the Officer shall have the same force and effect as if administered or taken by or before an officer having a seal of office.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D052B348ACB4FFBBBE50125464304A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text>In the case of a complaint made concerning allegations of an abuse of civil rights or civil liberties under paragraph (7) of subsection (b), the Officer shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="H845B79DA62FF4E92B698763B98416D95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Provide to the individual who made such complaint notice of the receipt of such complaint within 30 days of receiving such complaint.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42ADD175790440A8AFB4C390EDC00239"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Inform the individual of the determination of the Office regarding the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H36C8E6377665463E85B9B9FA3EB7D580"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The initiation of a review, investigation, or assessment, as the case may be, by the Office.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6115B9ABCE3547A9A0F74DC656050CA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A referral to the Inspector General of the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H286A7EA9988E440180C0D942C7C5DFFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any other action taken.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A9688228B634BA69D58E6E075B5EA30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with Inspector General</header> 
<paragraph id="H7ADD3CDFBCA6446CAF065E8A6F4CCDF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB733913322EE4F9B87F26A6F5AE75200"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>Before initiating an investigation initiated by the Officer pursuant to paragraph (7) of subsection (b), the Officer shall refer the matter at issue to the Inspector General of the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF8733293AC74F2B91C37D4747B4CE05"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determinations and notifications by Inspector General</header><text>Not later than seven days after the receipt of a matter at issue under subparagraph (A), the Inspector General shall carry out the following:</text> 
<clause id="HA1095EB8EBC24B6CA82031AA1D90F9F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Determine whether the Inspector General intends to initiate an investigation of such matter.</text></clause> <clause id="H90A87B22280B4CF2AA07F971D3903CE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Notify the Officer of such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD5E62F3C40F4F1F8AB057EB206C95A7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text>The Secretary may authorize the Officer to conduct an investigation pursuant to paragraph (7) of subsection (b) if the Secretary determines that a complaint warrants both the Officer and the Inspector General conducting investigations concurrently or in some other manner.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B97413913B246E6BE4F248AF29B4783"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notification by the officer</header><text>If the Officer does not receive notification of a determination pursuant to subparagraph (B)(ii), the Officer shall notify the Inspector General of whether the Officer intends to initiate an investigation into the matter at issue.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE5B328C859444F8AA7A4C316FDA510E6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recommendations; response</header> 
<paragraph id="H34F86C59537C44ECBFEF9981EDB2B877"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an investigation initiated by the Officer pursuant to paragraph (7) of subsection (b), if such an investigation results in the issuance of recommendations, the Officer shall produce a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDAD15910C0054DEDB300CFAF700AB213"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes the final findings and recommendations of the Officer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15541E879EEC41D9A4C64845329DDA8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is made publicly available in summary form;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC96E45697C2345DEB75184EBDED4217D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include any personally identifiable information; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6687DCC802714C9FA4AC849950AE468F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may include a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B5F63CCB5A345DA977672DEA706D8E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transmission</header><text>The Officer shall transmit to the Secretary and the head of the relevant component a copy of each report under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77B862C5B09244A18F003957306D9348"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Response</header> 
<subparagraph id="H51B152DFCAAA40B58D54D8138DCABA60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date on which the Officer transmits to the head of a component a copy of a report pursuant to paragraph (2), such head shall submit to the Secretary and the Officer a response to such report.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H958B3EF907CF4546A3C13C75ABF6DB4B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>In the response submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A), each recommendation contained in the report transmitted pursuant to paragraph (2) with which the head of the component at issue concurs shall be deemed an accepted recommendation of the Department.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4329C88F77EB452FBF81D587A72B2239"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonconcurrence; appeal</header><text>If the head of a component does not concur with a recommendation contained in the report transmitted pursuant to paragraph (2), or if such head does not respond to a recommendation within 60 days in accordance with subparagraph (A), the Officer may appeal to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98E520B616484B46A15E4A13C8FB2D55"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Result</header><text>If the Officer appeals to the Secretary pursuant to subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall, not later than 60 days after the date on which the Officer appeals—</text> 
<clause id="H263177291F0C42E8A62F89D50106E82E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accept the Officer’s recommendation, which recommendation shall be deemed the accepted recommendation of the Department; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0A73BCBB6C7243E99A1D1B4A0EE77D70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>accept the nonconcurrence of the head of the component at issue if transmitted in accordance with subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H22312377151E41DDAE61EE501FDC2B9D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting</header> 
<paragraph id="H541FFDEB604246E58783CD0D9D3FFCFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an investigation initiated by the Officer pursuant to paragraph (7) subsection (b), if such an investigation resulted in the issuance of recommendations, the Officer shall, on an annual basis, make publicly available through accessible communications channels, including the website of the Department, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H78215F1F6C0E4759852E6427532093ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The accepted recommendations of the Department, if any.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD2B86D5D33F479688FF3CC3FD8BE6BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A summary of investigations that result in final recommendations that are issued by the Officer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E82ADBDCC534E51825E7C84990C7D76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Materials made publicly available pursuant to paragraph (1) may not include any personally identifiable information related to any individual involved in the investigation at issue.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8EDFB98395404AA4ADD037A792AF19BD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Component civil rights and civil liberties officers</header> 
<paragraph id="HAC9AD7DD59DD4291943CE67F669D5694"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any component that has an Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of such component shall ensure that such Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of such component shall coordinate with and provide information to the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department on matters related to civil rights or civil liberties within each such component.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77A37DA52DF24BD5A02BE63278ED8893"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Officers of operational components</header><text>The head of each operational component, in consultation with the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department, shall hire or designate a career appointee (as such term is defined in section 3132 of title 5, United States Code) from such component as the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of such operational component.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27C483AC9349496794BC09425046D8D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>Each Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of each operational component—</text> <subparagraph id="HE038880B025145618DB878D173B0371C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall have access in a timely manner to the information, materials, and information necessary to carry out the functions of such officer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA2D20E17AE24E3FA2F92607CD74E461"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be consulted in advance of new or proposed changes to component policies, programs, initiatives, or activities impacting civil rights or civil liberties;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H016B737D3D064C7097865068D6F2BC8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall be given full and complete access to all component materials and component personnel necessary to carry out the functions of such officer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H81C9F81EEEED4694804F244D6849487B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may, to the extent the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department determines necessary, and subject to the approval of the Secretary, administer to or take from any person an oath, affirmation, or affidavit, whenever necessary in the performance of the responsibilities of each such component Officer under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB27F9AB5A694C1FAB0F273B3E4DC659"><enum>(E)</enum><text>may administer any oath, affirmation, or affidavit, and such oath, affirmation, shall have the same force and effect as if administered or taken by or before an officer having a seal of office.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2D7635FDE1D448B8E8E440E604AD5F5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than June 30 of each year, the Officer shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and any other committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, as the case may be, the Officer determines relevant, a report on the implementation of this section during the immediately preceding fiscal year. Each such annual report shall be prepared and submitted for supervisory review and appropriate comment or amendment by the Secretary prior to submission to such committees, and the Officer shall consider and incorporate any comments or amendments as a result of such review. Each such report shall include, for the year covered by such report, the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1043C2496A764D339DB025BA3DEB851A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of Department regulations, policies, programs, initiatives, and activities for which civil rights or civil liberties assessments were conducted, or policy advice, recommendations, or other technical assistance was provided.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56E13DB18E8A41FF93A094D37838FC9C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the efforts of the Department to effectively communicate with individuals, stakeholders, or communities impacted by policies, programs, initiatives, or activities of the Department, including the individuals, stakeholders, and communities referred to in subsection (b)(12).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA71BB7925644134817DC128D343BCC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A summary of recommendations issued pursuant to subsection (f) regarding investigations under paragraph (7) of subsection (b), together with information on the status of the implementation of such recommendations by the component at issue.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB44A97563144DFBADF8EFAF2150C396"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Information on the diversity and equal employment opportunity activities of the Department, including information on complaint management and adjudication of equal employment opportunity complaints, and efforts to ensure compliance throughout the Department with equal employment opportunity requirements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A2934DC68C541B4880E2F2CD019FEF6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of any efforts, including public meetings, to engage with individuals, stakeholders, and communities the civil rights and civil liberties of which may be affected by policies, programs, initiatives, or activities of the Department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB30B6C63C1F1413391371939ADBD82D0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Information regarding total staffing for the Office, including regarding the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB0F9E08644924B929E5CDE0F8C1F43CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of full-time, part-time, and contract support personnel.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99BED440DA844227BCEE278AAA072B68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information on the number of employees whose primary responsibilities include supporting the Officer in carrying out paragraph (10) of subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13DCCC319D2A41039B757F7BF5165B63"><enum>(7)</enum><text>If required, a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A3E42A9959743C3878C7A1F161B1B21"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>component</quote> means any operational component, non-operational component, directorate, or office of the Department.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H84B51B2965894E1B8EF3925927AB3FE3"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Reporting to Congress</header> <text>Section 1062(f)(1)(A)(i) of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ee-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ee–1(f)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives</quote> and inserting <quote>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives</quote>.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H01D3336721BB4BBE8A99FA1DD27ED56B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller General review</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of subsection (b)(12) of section 705 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/345">6 U.S.C. 345</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEDA48A7550E04F40A3CAEDC08B00E739"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by amending the item relating to section 705 to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H27E177F544CC4365B76B840BFEABFCA2" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 705. Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

