<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F312658BA834F9A853F8806BD063E30" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7443 IH: To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to realign the mission of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7443</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to realign the mission of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H296784631D9744B3832C7468931E9365" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H98DEA758EAC84C17914E99B2BE90DE71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>I&amp;A Mission Reorientation Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H538E3C44DBF24F26B5F3B1FFC14225E7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H5144984C243349F19A00911100F2BB9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA304196F9D24D4FAB457AF4F1B63B40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Office of Intelligence and Analysis (I&amp;A) of the Department of Homeland Security plays a critical role in supporting homeland security by providing actionable intelligence to Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and private sector entities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10C47538B1B442E1ADEB46654D6946B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office’s foundational mission is to serve as an intelligence component that supports such governments and entities by fusing law enforcement and intelligence information.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46462530AFEA4A56BDCF9F64BC202B36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Office’s effectiveness depends on the mutual flow of information, collaboration, and trust between the Department and such governments and entities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6B5B8E0B02F48429EEA6D3BE8D321DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Emerging and evolving threats require a proactive approach to intelligence collection, analysis, and dissemination.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD404BAEF05C48A78FAF4270599A5E4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H3D5F882DDCFB4B66BDFFDD50629957A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security should fully execute its statutory role in supporting State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and private sector entities through actionable, relevant, and timely intelligence;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0CF275933C64067A609A19E502F5E1B">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>consistent with the requirements of section 201(d)(6) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121(d)(6)</external-xref>), the Department should avoid an intelligence posture that promotes a one-directional flow of information from field entities to the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>)), and should actively foster two-way collaboration; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AEC8ABC1F284F2DA5084BA508956F35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>intelligence support to the Secretary of Homeland Security should complement the Office’s broader stakeholder-facing mission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8FC0CDC164984D3985CA897726394562"><enum>3.</enum><header>Realignment of mission of DHS Office of Intelligence and Analysis</header> <subsection id="H58E356A20B5549C990F72824BC6AA986"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 201 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H977F93E546E64D97A7CC335150BA48B8" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H95927CD4CD0C408D821F89475B3399C9"><enum>(24)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To ensure the Office of Intelligence and Analysis’s operational mission of providing timely and efficient intelligence support to State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and private sector entities is equally prioritized and resourced relevant to support provided to elements of the intelligence community by carrying out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H2E13E8D5D2EF4301BDA56425053751B7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Identifying and addressing emerging threats through forward-deployed intelligence capabilities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E8D3B30D378484C948A80B1169B91E5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facilitating two-way information sharing characterized by both the receipt of intelligence from such governments and entities, and the dissemination of actionable intelligence to such governments and entities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3BBDDC5163F54F3C963C2194D081D7BB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Maintaining robust and sustained engagement with fusion centers (as such term is defined in section 210A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4FA8D59EB3F46E8BAA34813EAD72DAB" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ensuring intelligence support from the Office provided to departmental leadership, including the Secretary, does not hinder or deprioritize broader responsibilities of the Office to State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and private sector entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H6EBEC5D819404BE4A09CE95B3601B705"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a report detailing the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H65D9B43B8A394F3C9FEA211AF016A73B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Steps taken to implement the mission realignment of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department in accordance with paragraph (24) of section 201(d) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86449A4B5D0B4E49B8421048E5D0668E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Progress in enhancing two-way information sharing between the Office and State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and private sector entities, in accordance with such paragraph (24).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H914EA6B6B678425EB1B22402A91D8A39"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Metrics used to evaluate the effectiveness of the Office’s intelligence activitiese in support of State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and private sector entities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC3CA67810F343508F589A7517EEED37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any resource or organizational changes to the Office required to sustain such realignment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H63BC6D76A5C541F18E5A3CB77163F97B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to alter or otherwise change the watchlisting functions of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

