<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA4AEBDB0979D46E2B2E953D4147DB527" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7345 IH: Studying Disastrous Impacts of Mass Deportation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7345</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Congressional Budget Office to conduct a study with respect to the long-term economic impact of Trump Administration immigration policies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD361D6BA592E4839B2735E4D9DD292B2" style="OLC"><section id="H6A122113CC784BA8A274EA9AB9F68843" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Studying Disastrous Impacts of Mass Deportation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5B33DE4D6D4E4CD9BBB568F7F146FD45"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional Budget Office study on economic impact of Trump Administration immigration policies</header><subsection id="HA98B0C2359FD4276B2CD055464D6DF25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the earlier of the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act or the last day of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall, in collaboration with the Council of Economic Advisers, conduct and make publicly available a study with respect to the long-term economic impact of the immigration policies implemented and in effect beginning on January 20, 2025.</text></subsection><subsection id="H03ADD25A3BC04B3DAD71133970EEE4DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under <internal-xref idref="HA98B0C2359FD4276B2CD055464D6DF25" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall assess the twenty to forty year economic impact of the immigration policies described in <internal-xref idref="HA98B0C2359FD4276B2CD055464D6DF25" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, which shall include the economic impact as a result of—</text><paragraph id="HFB537EFFA55543638A8E76079E9AEF5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific industry breakdowns (including but not limited to public sector, service workers, farm workers, healthcare workers, and innovation and retention with respect to the academic and professional disciplines of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29A6F716442D47608B722E33AA852232"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impacts on public safety and crime due to pervasive fear;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BBB0ED11DC840C0A5A4FF3E2FB5CCE7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>immigration flows out of the country and overall demographic changes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F9FFF71789C460180B0290F03CA5E24"><enum>(4)</enum><text>effects on productivity and technological innovation, remittances, consumer spending and investment, and GDP contribution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B13DDDC43ED4B8B9554FA3C9F605751"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">effects on small businesses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FAB712CB21341ACA0DD345E0C3FFC9B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>effects on tax revenue due to the net fiscal impact of mass deportation at the Federal, State, and local level.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43B30B3D7C794AB0A8221CCC3CDA0849"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data sharing requirement</header><text>The Department of Homeland Security, the Bureau of Labor Statistics, and the Internal Revenue Service shall, upon request from the Director of the Congressional Budget Office, share such data with the Director as the Director determines necessary and appropriate to conduct the study under <internal-xref idref="HA98B0C2359FD4276B2CD055464D6DF25" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

