<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99AEC9CD8139477F9D2D65201FE1D547" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9631 IH: Bear Poaching Elimination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9631</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To conserve global bear populations by prohibiting the importation, exportation, and interstate trade of bear viscera and bear viscera products, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H69E31123D37A46418E2FC468BB0EAD41" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H258B1F7E5AD6464A8F6947913F4702C6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bear Poaching Elimination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCE39B738147548D0BCCA7032DD19CCFD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H16F3948533024BEFB784A4F2D7C781BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all 8 extant species of bear—Asian black bear, brown bear, polar bear, American black bear, spectacled bear, giant panda, sun bear, and sloth bear—are listed in appendix I or II of CITES;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE65E4B119FEC4B2F9FB148F357360C4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>article XIV of CITES provides that Parties to CITES may adopt stricter domestic measures regarding the conditions for the trade, taking, possession, or transport of species listed in appendix I or II, and the Parties to CITES adopted a resolution in 1997 (Conf. 10.8) urging the Parties to take immediate action to demonstrably reduce the illegal trade in bear parts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82B0C4497AE8449DBD38479BBE150884"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in Asia, thousands of bears are cruelly confined in small cages to be milked for their bile, and bear populations in Asia have declined significantly in recent years as a result of habitat loss and poaching driven by a strong demand for bear viscera for use in traditional medicines and cosmetics;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6965E80A3284A818876F7E03C098E08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal and State undercover operations have revealed that American bears have been poached for their viscera;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F2A9EC979764FD194953F70B2934313"><enum>(5)</enum><text>while most American black bear populations are generally stable or increasing, commercial trade could stimulate poaching and threaten certain populations if the demand for bear viscera increases; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H581808A9C2E1440398EC580AC0D23E5D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>prohibitions against the importation into and exportation from the United States, as well as prohibitions against the interstate trade, of bear viscera and bear viscera products will assist in ensuring that the United States does not contribute to the decline of any bear population as a result of the commercial trade in bear viscera.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBF0B7046235349DEBF6ADAA07D2015D0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure the long-term viability of the 8 extant bear species by—</text> <paragraph id="H558A80382E664F2C9EC1B2A27CD7DE19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibiting interstate and international trade in bear viscera and bear viscera products;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1AACDAB41FCD4BB39713CB8E355646C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encouraging bilateral and multilateral efforts to eliminate such trade; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1061BF3610D34EABB5759451028DB52B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring that adequate Federal legislation exists with respect to domestic trade in bear viscera and bear viscera products.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H66EB034EAC5B4D8B9DE384CC907A7103"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H8965C35C7C6549BBB74A34FF73E8777F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bear viscera</header><text>The term <term>bear viscera</term> means, with respect to a species of bear, body fluids or internal organs—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF67CBB615FB74C5E9AB960C0586446F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>including the gallbladder and its contents; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCBB7409FE41D40A482008734C74DBF0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not including blood or brains.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB67EB84F42AF4186B35F3AFDC311B3A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bear viscera product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>bear viscera product</term> means any item, product, or substance containing, or labeled or advertised as containing, bear viscera.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BE0AC4839794108B87F2FB739042E69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>CITES</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>CITES</term> means the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora (27 UST 1087; TIAS 8249).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82292A0E087D452FA80B29B0EFA5FB9C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Import</header><text>The term <term>import</term> means to land on, bring into, or introduce into any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, whether or not such landing, bringing, or introduction constitutes an importation within the meaning of the customs laws of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAE962FD93554C4BB7184C362F3D77F3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H846326150B21416A9F46621834354A67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual, corporation, partnership, trust, association, or other private entity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB64810E6026640C385932611990527B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an officer, employee, agent, department, or instrumentality of—</text> 
<clause id="H490273CE4B284F6099A8A11F756057D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Government;</text></clause> <clause id="H63941172E2634443A797DA9B34D56260"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a State, municipality, or political subdivision of a State; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF2DDB515D67C4919B30365BD55968AAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a foreign government; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8434D4A10B341D9A2C7F1B8028D1943"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other entity subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2486A6897E1F49B98ED78CDC47F2502A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97C6CBBA5FCC4843B9CA3031E58886BB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory and possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H6DB62D7FD3D5418FAF0414A0C7F92256"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header> 
<subsection id="H86363755BA624A47A84023D59E2983B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), it shall be unlawful for any person to—</text> <paragraph id="H3AC4F204B4DB4934AACA98C49E4E684F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>import into, or export from, the United States bear viscera or any bear viscera product; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71E38D3B830340C69B3C012B569420B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sell or barter, offer to sell or barter, purchase, possess, transport, deliver, or receive, in interstate or foreign commerce, bear viscera or any bear viscera product.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H24216917922C4B0F91E0C192EFE2BAE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for wildlife law enforcement purposes</header><text>A person described in section 4(5)(B) may carry out an activity prohibited under subsection (a) if such activity is—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD818E99245174D059AD7FEA71E1138E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>solely for the purpose of enforcing a law relating to the protection of wildlife; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF43A502D41304AC3BBF21524F21CB6D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>authorized by a valid permit issued under appendix I or II of CITES, in any case in which such a permit is required under CITES.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC36172055C2347D8A9A1E71794CD5A3B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Penalties and enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="HF8C6F9AD799749CEAB2FB949A0475C10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text>A person that knowingly violates section 5(a) shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6C99C516A3B842DEAC54DE5EFE81B97A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header> <paragraph id="HF3EA8B8A7697431D8A8F54AA4C50A487"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>A person that knowingly violates section 5(a) may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary of not more than $25,000 for each violation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA7E13FFCD0447CEA2D9FE9805B7C955"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manner of assessment and collection</header><text>A civil penalty under this subsection shall be assessed and collected in the manner in which a civil penalty under the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> is assessed and collected under section 11(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1540">16 U.S.C. 1540(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE621247870AF47D988B225A572CA97BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Seizure and forfeiture</header><text>Any bear viscera or bear viscera product treated in a manner that violates section 5(a), or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture to the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDFB5A39A7AEA48BCAEFECF9BC20EFF9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the United States Trade Representative, issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFFB8097B966A4B508A8C36BEC6FBC06D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall enforce this Act in the manner in which the Secretaries carry out enforcement activities under section 11(e) of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESA">Endangered Species Act of 1973</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1540">16 U.S.C. 1540(e)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95A500778F934A6BB596E3A537A88087"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of sums received</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sums received as penalties, fines, or forfeiture of property for any violation of section 5(a), or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall be used in accordance with section 6(d) of the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3375">16 U.S.C. 3375(d)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD21EB292ADF146DFA4AE29DFD1B38929"><enum>7.</enum><header>Discussions concerning bear conservation and the bear viscera trade</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In order to establish coordinated efforts to protect bears, the Secretary shall continue discussions concerning trade in bear viscera and bear viscera products with representatives of countries that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3485D3460D3843CA8E3262BB785CC642"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are Parties to CITES; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB768EE8959340C4AF4852734DACDDCE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are not Parties to CITES that are determined by the Secretary and the United States Trade Representative to be leading importers, exporters, or consumers of bear viscera or bear viscera products.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF274A7383B39432C90B9633A2B7B278B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Certain rights not affected</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 5, nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect—</text> <paragraph id="H2ECF2BCDCCC14F4195698E0F8862554F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the regulation by a State of a bear population of that State;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53E950F8BFD24DDBA39736F847E040FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the hunting of bears in a State that is in a manner that is lawful under the laws and regulations of that State; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDD651502CFE4269890210EEB68BC66B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use of bear viscera or any bear viscera product as part of a traditional Native American ritual or ceremony.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

