<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87A4A9857D144BA0BBB27F32C4EB5922" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8300 IH: Stopping Wasteful Allowances for Lawmaker Wrongdoing and Ensuring Legal Liability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8300</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of taxpayer funds for settlements of workplace misconduct claims involving Members of Congress or senior staff of the House of Representatives or the Senate, require personal financial accountability, ensure transparency of past settlements while protecting victims, and mandate referral of criminal allegations to the Department of Justice, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H635051BC20BF4326A0D4C38AEC6EBDCD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDB8485EE94F04463B0C8AEAE44D08AF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Wasteful Allowances for Lawmaker Wrongdoing and Ensuring Legal Liability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Swalwell Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HFEECF8F93A914FB6A629DDAD6873B7BE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of Federal funds in connection with workplace misconduct</header> 
<subsection id="H1A06B587E07C48D9A774D370C27B4966"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds appropriated or otherwise made available from the U.S. Treasury may be used to pay any settlement, award, or judgment arising from a claim of workplace misconduct by a Member of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4381D6C62F7F4EA8A4711FB67AF42BD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Workplace misconduct defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>workplace misconduct</term> includes claims of discrimination, harassment, retaliation, or other violations of employment or civil rights laws.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBDECBB61398C49E49E57D5F60F709577"><enum>3.</enum><header>Personal liability of Members of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate</header> 
<subsection id="H55522AB4F6FC4F55966DE3D379E73F92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Member of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate found liable for, or entering into a settlement resolving, a workplace misconduct claim shall be personally responsible for the full amount of such settlement or award.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H50229D1945CC405BBE3D36C5379E54FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions with respect to reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Member of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate may be reimbursed, directly or indirectly—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC6A8C9162CE74AFCADF6119D5053FACE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with Federal funds for any payment made under <internal-xref idref="H55522AB4F6FC4F55966DE3D379E73F92" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DE354878406484285C5FFE11A533133"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with campaign funds for any payment made under <internal-xref idref="H55522AB4F6FC4F55966DE3D379E73F92" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H093EFA9CBCA04DC489CC1ADC38CB3A86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate shall certify, under penalty of perjury, that no public funds were used in connection with such payments under <internal-xref idref="H55522AB4F6FC4F55966DE3D379E73F92" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H76A7E957EEB34B379E437B9B55460CEA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mandatory disclosure of settlements</header> <subsection id="H851C5FD7D0DE4341853B040D9FAAEFB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate shall maintain and publish a publicly accessible, searchable database containing the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFC1C217F0E9A461D86AFE47F101C8FC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The name of any Member of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate who has settled or been found liable for a workplace misconduct claim.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5DEC29F930840848742BF08534483C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total amount of any settlement or award.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H124EDD42A2F142238DE76EF6A8E66F0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The date of resolution.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4C80928503B4AFFAF53AFB644DEEB62"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The nature of the claim, described in general terms.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H86162CA99B79473AA34E78A77F6ED14A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The database under <internal-xref idref="H851C5FD7D0DE4341853B040D9FAAEFB9" legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall not include any personally identifiable information of victims or complainants.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5137999869754514B684D433CD5FD295"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disclosures shall be made not later than 30 days after the date of the resolution of a claim.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE6A8A8AE01054B3B8D29D7D79E31913C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Retroactive disclosure of past settlements</header> 
<subsection id="H5E72640D5E3C4C0988EFE35EDBC1BC6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Clerk of the House and Secretary of the Senate shall publish all settlements and awards paid using public funds since January 1, 1995, relating to workplace misconduct claims involving Members of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5F3244CACCCB44D59B297D566C588591"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Privacy protection requirement</header><text>Disclosures under subsection (a) shall comply with the privacy protections set forth in section 4(b).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H713913F3B3DE49039F04339F3B04904F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Referral of criminal allegations</header> 
<subsection id="HE1DF1732C04741F29914EEFF84F3DF89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any allegation of conduct by a Member of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate that may constitute a violation of Federal criminal law shall be promptly referred to the Department of Justice for review.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6962E5B204874DA39ADC301B2665D21E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Source of referral</header><text>A referral under <internal-xref idref="HE1DF1732C04741F29914EEFF84F3DF89" legis-path="6.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall be made by the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives, or the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, as applicable.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17A91F08E9264A8BA2E1D3DF34719778"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restrictions on preventing or delaying referral</header> 
<paragraph id="H71113573986E43608A868C943CC85F54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No settlement agreement, nondisclosure agreement, or internal congressional process may prevent or delay a referral under <internal-xref idref="HE1DF1732C04741F29914EEFF84F3DF89" legis-path="6.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H322FACC76AC44D7AB0FEDDF125101DD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>The existence of a referral under this section shall not be contingent upon the consent of the complainant.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H6B13DD8B790C45CB8C1E9A6F98C30B75"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enforcement and penalties</header> 
<subsection id="H1247E2AEAEFD4BC1923FA7D0E6CDA432"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Member of Congress or a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate who violates this Act shall be subject to—</text> <paragraph id="H4457FD747DB34A8C875E059A153AC241"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a civil penalty that equals not less than 200 percent of the amount improperly paid; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE77638E5810B4D109C6A561622303E65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>referral to the appropriate Ethics Committee for further disciplinary action.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H94B7F313AE324FF7A366AA510C4D94FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>The Attorney General is authorized to bring a civil action to enforce compliance with this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H64811841E384454FB105F21F432477DE"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H7C1E070438924F67B61EAAE9A4EAF6AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Member of Congress</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92A3CFF1BFB04D7EA9897490DFCE9F8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate</term> means any individual who, at the time a violation occurred, was required to file a report under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6E90624080CD4FAA8B274089CE5038F4"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6B1AD1BEFD7747F39D4D3154C4A8D9A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit the rights of victims to pursue claims or receive compensation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBF3893F72B740899BD729205C1984D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the disclosure of a victim’s identity, including sex and personally identifiable information, without their express written consent; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3C8CF65684C4597ADA025E7ABB0723A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent the House of Representatives or the Senate from taking such actions as may be necessary to protect the identities of victims.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC7CF4FEA67134B6E9E865B470AD29AE7"><enum>10.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to any claim pending on or after such date.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

