<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN25250-TR3-HH-H5J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 571 ATS: Remembering the December 6, 2019, terrorist attack at Naval Air Station Pensacola and commemorating those who lost their lives, and those who were injured, in the line of duty.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Remembering the December 6, 2019, terrorist attack at Naval Air Station Pensacola and commemorating those who lost their lives, and those who were injured, in the line of duty.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas December 6, 2025, the 6-year anniversary of the terrorist attack at Naval Air Station Pensacola (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>terrorist attack</quote>), is a day of commemoration for those who lost their lives, and those who were injured, during the terrorist attack, including—</text><paragraph id="id7ac2e5d87fcc493ea0209ae879fd84d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ensign Joshua Kaleb Watson of Enterprise, Alabama;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id171b17fb538944edb9fb3c61ce61fd2d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Petty Officer Third Class Mohammed Sameh Haitham of St. Petersburg, Florida; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90e4703f910d402b982b6fb020b1a05a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Petty Officer Third Class Cameron Scott Walters of Richmond Hill, Georgia;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 3 servicemembers who died in the terrorist attack were posthumously awarded the Navy and Marine Corps Medal and the Purple Heart;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the terrorist who committed the terrorist attack was a Saudi Arabian foreign military student who had been radicalized and established contact with Al Qaeda operatives prior to attending flight training at Naval Air Station Pensacola;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Naval Air Station Pensacola security forces and Escambia County, Florida, law enforcement officers took decisive action to end the terrorist attack and have rightly earned the praises and awards bestowed upon them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2 civilians were awarded the Department of the Navy Superior Civilian Medal for Valor for their heroic actions during the terrorist attack;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 8 individuals were awarded the Purple Heart, or the law enforcement equivalent, for injuries sustained during the terrorist attack;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 9 military personnel were awarded the Navy and Marine Corps Medal for their heroic actions during the terrorist attack;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 8 military personnel were awarded the Navy and Marine Corps Commendation Medal for their heroic actions during the terrorist attack;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 8 law enforcement officers were awarded the Medal of Valor for their actions taken during the terrorist attack; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas December 6, 2025, marks 6 years since the lives of 3 military personnel were tragically cut short by the egregious act of terrorism at Naval Air Station Pensacola: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idb819e1e6a509460c957d47ffb8336580"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the December 6, 2019, terrorist attack at Naval Air Station Pensacola (referred to in this resolution as the <quote>terrorist attack</quote>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5B39696655354BF3998A66F144075535"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commemorates in sorrow the servicemembers and civilians who lost their lives, or who were injured, and the harm caused to the surrounding community, as a result of the terrorist attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id627b7eb1273a4907ae015731d5f7b9ce"><enum>(3)</enum><text>remembers Ensign Joshua Kaleb Watson, Petty Officer Third Class Mohammed Sameh Haitham, and Petty Officer Third Class Cameron Scott Walters, who were killed in the terrorist attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecdfd9c868aa49a7af0c0c87009f3a2c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses gratitude for the heroic actions that the civilians, uniformed personnel, and law enforcement performed during and in the aftermath of the terrorist attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida94757a854904aa48823a4b8fe08a614"><enum>(5)</enum><text>lauds the decision to give medals and awards to the law enforcement officers, uniformed servicemembers, and civilians who responded heroically on the morning of December 6, 2019; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id090934DDD29E46DEB0AC01D69D5AB31E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commends the efforts undertaken by the Department of Defense to enhance security at military installations to ensure that the tragedy represented by the terrorist attack is never repeated.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

