<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFA5A36C6E5240BDA018894F59246E11" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9508 IH: Pacific Islands Liaison Initiative Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9508</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require Homeland Security Investigations to establish the Pacific
      Islands Liaison Initiative to strengthen the United States strategic partnerships and ability
      to combat transnational criminal organizations in the Pacific region, and for other
      purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2E3741287B2A4B93B4A1D140090653A4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF5E2D7DE3D7D4AAC80E57A9256FB685C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pacific Islands Liaison Initiative Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5E853DFE21B447EEB1C91533DFE7D3E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Pacific Islands Liaison Initiative</header> <subsection id="H3AAC5233A6EB4ADF8734606B0A78F637"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations shall establish the Pacific Islands Liaison Initiative (in this section referred to as the <quote>Initiative</quote>). The Initiative shall be carried out by Homeland Security Investigations Honolulu, in collaboration with Homeland Security Investigations Guam, Homeland Security Investigations Attaché Canberra, Homeland Security Investigations International Operations, and any other relevant offices of Homeland Security Investigations the Executive Associate Director determines appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9426D2C2ADF243C885C73EEC07ECDA46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Initiative shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="H08603404E86245DEA3BA7E15ED8BFE89"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Strengthen the United States partnerships with Pacific Island countries by enhancing collaboration on law enforcement and security through the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="HDCE5FFE7DCA5466CBF0FA1D7F8AA7B42">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Regular visits by United States law enforcement personnel.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF343375B94847E291C4EF3D71A668BE"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>Conducting joint operations throughout the region.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F3C7B2B0E6444708F88F8390B1F37E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Enhance the capacity of Pacific Island countries to combat transnational criminal organizations, including through the provision of training, technical assistance, and resource sharing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6A1767794AF48F08CE96386BC78CD9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Support the forward deployment of United States law enforcement personnel to a regional hub in the Pacific Islands to enable rapid and frequent access to and engagement with Pacific Island countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D8C2C1263E946DCA422342E840A4F2D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Counter malign influence in the Pacific region by addressing transnational criminal threats and promoting shared values, such as the rule of law, transparency, and good governance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06C781AF0F8B4AD3BAF6AB3ED3DA3598"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Position the United States as the partner of choice for Pacific Island countries by providing sustained support, resources, and expertise to address shared challenges.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBB5F3928F6D4FD497D81AA6CA1828FC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Promote regional stability and economic development by fostering secure and resilient Pacific Island communities through the development of infrastructure, technology, and other resources that support regional security and economic resilience.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB231D141A8F940439513AEC56A37229D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations shall appoint not fewer than four full-time equivalent personnel for the Initiative, to be overseen by an Assistant Special Agent in Charge who is stationed at Homeland Security Investigations Honolulu. Two of such personnel shall be stationed at Homeland Security Investigations Honolulu and two of such personnel shall be stationed at Homeland Security Investigations Guam.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC47397FA11F54F1A8B8FA2C2EB14470F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the establishment of the Initiative and annually thereafter, the Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations shall submit to Congress a report detailing the activities of the Initiative during the immediately preceding year, including the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE46E9FD6E90B4EB49BD2230C529E0CC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed overview of how appropriated funds were obligated and expended.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H213E4BB79D6C4F0EBF8C10928E6B1524"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the impact of the Initiative on countering malign influence in the Pacific region and strengthening regional security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD00A5A8603EB4AF0AE60AD5B48588136"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The effectiveness of the Initiative’s capacity-building efforts in Pacific Island countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BD2288522384BCB8736272B4DEC58B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for additional resources or legislative actions to advance United States strategic objectives in the Pacific.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H189A4EE0648140FEACDC55676F35977D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2027 through 2034 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

