<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25G45-G24-88-049">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3162 IS: To require the Secretary of Defense to carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall develop and implement a comprehensive wastewater surveillance system at certain installations of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3162</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to carry out a pilot program under which
            the Secretary shall develop and implement a comprehensive wastewater surveillance system
            at certain installations of the Department of Defense, and for other
            purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="iddbdedeba454544f3806cbaadbdf55cd1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Pilot program on wastewater surveillance system of Department of
                Defense</header>
            <subsection id="id3ba2ed6c9d104425b7d452b791124766">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Pilot program required</header>
 <text>Commencing not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall develop and implement a comprehensive wastewater surveillance system at not fewer than four installations of a military department at which the Secretary seeks to improve the testing, identification, and analysis of usage of covered drugs and to identify the prevalence of infectious diseases among members of the Armed Forces at the installation (in this section referred to as the <quote>pilot program</quote>).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="ida368afc01aa04f7b9c040044a6cad685">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Technologies and data system used</header>
 <text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall ensure the system developed and implemented under subsection (a) is comprised of appropriate technologies and a uniform data system across the Department of Defense.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id5b6ebe72314a4f8a8a32286693872f03">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Minimum requirements</header>
 <text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall establish, at a minimum—</text>
                <paragraph id="id80e59093458f43608274e6a8ee57802f">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>at least one wastewater surveillance system for monitoring of use of covered drugs at one installation; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id423ee2084dc14948bdc10f0138bc2852">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>at least one wastewater surveillance system for monitoring of infectious diseases at one installation.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id98f2e72612474cb28a01a1e3a007505b">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Duration</header>
 <text>The pilot program shall be carried out during a two-year period beginning on the date of the commencement of the pilot program.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0bb618e116634b83bfa12f1ed5f6d7f5">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
 <text>Not later than 90 days after the termination of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that includes the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="id5354373ca7b842b086a938b1320e7034">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A summary of the findings from the wastewater surveillance system under the pilot program.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id213cf911fae64f48848a2e3898fce1bb">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Recommendations for interventions or policy changes based on trends observed under the pilot program.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idcc286befba8b4f58bb1c32b41ad31c3b">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>An assessment of the effectiveness of the pilot program in enhancing force health protection and readiness.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id1f288d90646c4f06a03591ffde16f4c7">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Use of existing resources and authorities</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall use existing resources and authorities of the Department of Defense, as the Secretary determines appropriate, to implement the pilot program.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id598fd5c0b7ae4690a555a95ce4da7e91">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3437cd3312fe4e9aaf2bf13ab7ec4c94"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Congressional defense committees</header> <text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0778e0eef984936afe5e7638ad6f5e0">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered drug defined</header>
 <text>The term <term>covered drug</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26479a87bdfd4b09afd7207426ca254a"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subparagraph (B), means a drug included on schedule I or schedule II established under section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812</external-xref>); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1bc1630778843f0882c28b93eb676bf">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a drug that—</text>
                        <clause id="id31f975a7c9f342baa3e6dc92078e9af3">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>was newly included on such schedule I or schedule II;</text> </clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9f391f6f8984aed998edafcde059de1"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was previously approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>); and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idecb9c52a499c418ba86f42dcd129e24f">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>received such approval not later than 20 years before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

