<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H527D2B9634CD4682B442C89A9B1B314E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7123 IH: Abolish ICE Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To abolish U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H444A23D7C85A47C09EB56E36F3BD5579" style="OLC"><section id="H9A96FEAFCC704F9C938FF75F95794F2F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abolish ICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA5AE940D4BFF40F8AACE3F6BE2458D3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H895CD590E8F44FDDBA28489D38F5F05F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since its establishment in 2003, legal experts have argued that the mission of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) could be better executed by other Federal agencies and that the design of ICE prioritizes aggressive enforcement rather than compliance with due process rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53633EC1D0854D5EABCDE7A58E2B7659"><enum>(2)</enum><text>One of President Trump’s first Executive Orders, titled <quote>Protecting the American People Against Invasion</quote>, unleashed ICE to carry out mass arrests and deportations of noncriminal immigrants in the United States, with approximately 70 percent of arrests made by immigration agents in 2025 being detainees who had no criminal record.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33C0658C8C25436D93A715A220767A14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On July 10, 2025, ICE carried out an immigration raid on 2 cannabis farms in Camarillo, California, that led to the arrest of 360 individuals and the death of 1 worker.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC41C567D2D1F4129874AF585513028C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On September 12, 2025, ICE agents shot and killed Silverio Villegas Gonzalez after they attempted to detain him during a traffic stop. Prior to being killed, Gonzalez had just dropped his children off at school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08335A6544AD4A178B8B8CD0001D8126"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On September 30, 2025, as part of <quote>Operation Midway Blitz</quote>, members of Federal law enforcement agencies, including ICE, conducted a military-style raid on a South Shore apartment building in Chicago, Illinois, that led to the arrest of 37 people. This raid included the use of flashbang grenades, explosives to breach doors, and unnecessary and unlawful use of force against civilians, with some being forced outside without clothes, zip-tied, and forced into unmarked vans while awaiting processing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0EEA567D5CC42B68E7B1C0AD5821B00"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On December 31, 2025, an off-duty ICE officer shot and killed Keith Porter, Jr., during New Year’s Eve celebrations in Northridge, California. Porter attempted to celebrate the New Year by discharging his firearm into the air when the off-duty ICE officer approached Porter, shooting and killing him.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9556A8B2C92C4F0FBEC77D9EF5F3F4AA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On January 7, 2026, a masked ICE agent shot and killed Renee Nicole Good, a United States citizen, in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Renee Nicole Good was in her car when ICE agents approached her and attempted to remove her from her vehicle. Fearing for her safety, and without reason to suspect why ICE agents were attempting to detain her, Renee Nicole Good attempted to drive away from the agents when she was shot and killed. Bystanders attempted to provide life saving assistance to Good but were forcefully kept away and denied permission by ICE agents to save Good’s life.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61D0633D9FEE4038BD05E77921D8A17A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 2025, 32 inmates died while in ICE detention, the highest number in over 2 decades, linked to the poor conditions faced by inmates that included a lack of medical care and neglect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D367B40BEB7457B83377ABC23CD7330"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 2025, as many as 170 American citizens had been arrested and detained by ICE, a fact which Secretary of Homeland Security Kristi Noem denied during an October 30, 2025, press conference.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAA8EC10DA894F1D888CB908EB1EA863"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since President Donald Trump and Secretary Kristi Noem have taken office, ICE has been weaponized to inflict terror and hysteria amongst American immigrant and non-immigrant communities. ICE has been deployed to major cities across the United States, against the wishes of local government and law enforcement agencies, adopting aggressive enforcement policies that have brought fear to Americans. It is clear that ICE is not an organization bound by the rule of law, is past the point of reform, and must be abolished.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6C05B65ED266485C9F9C3FB9A63D12D7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Abolishment of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement</header><subsection id="H360A0628822F4AA28A3D94D62C2E4BC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, no Federal funds may be made available to carry out any of the functions, duties, or responsibilities assigned or delegated to the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement pursuant to the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/252">6 U.S.C. 252 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other provision of law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB286F7E569824AF1AE5F18633078863E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rescission of funds</header><text>The unobligated balance of each amount made available to the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act is rescinded. Any other assets or liabilities of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement as of such date of enactment shall be transferred to the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1095F05CBD2B4DE7AA065F588D03E24F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Abolishment date</header><text>Effective on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement is abolished.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

