<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61644400DABC496AA0A03AF5C667D685" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9472 IH: The Protecting Homeowners from Squatters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9472</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Community Development Block Grant funding and Federal mortgage support in municipalities that allow squatting.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4331754D9A3447ECA33703E850E7AFA3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD38AF18A683940C797B52C1A17E7FFA8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The Protecting Homeowners from Squatters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0FCB117273C14B39B4120C55DA9A870D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Combatting squatting</header> <subsection id="H0D78AEC0BCD94E609E26B8A2B31814EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text>The Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H190937FE1936415EA5ADCEFB5FE266DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unlawfully entering a property without the permission of the property owner and residing in that property for consecutive days without the permission of the property owner and without the payment of rent or a rental contract agreed to by the property owner can be defined as <quote>squatting</quote> and should not confer any special status as a tenant or lawful occupant of the property;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6730AE5E49F3402FBC2BEEDC35295C44"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local law enforcement should take actions to expeditiously remove from a property any persons or persons engaging in squatting and should prosecute such actions as prescribed by local law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5831FAF5D51043A9907CB3A487299D72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Federal Government benefits, including loans, loan guarantees, subsidies, and tax credits, should not be used to reinforce, condone, or otherwise incentivize squatting; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EBB34FC44C34097B536F4472BCDDFFA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>real estate collateral securing a government or government-sponsored enterprise loan, or subject to a loan guarantee, mortgage insurance or other Federal mortgage support program must be protected from persons engaging in squatting as it creates undue risks for the value of such property.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8009C471137340FEAA3D646A4A4DD122"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on CDBG funding</header><text>Section 104 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5304">42 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H57C0591D5FF64B37AB8540888388A0E7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HA9BBA73667E84B3FA8BB0B12D63DC4F6"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Withholding of funds for jurisdictions that permit squatting</header> <paragraph id="HD277E9F00C8B4B58A28DAF66C6D4A12E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, by regulation—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA82A42E3B79848659FAAB859673EDF49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prohibit the allocation and provision of funds under this title for any unit of general local government that permits squatting or confers special status for rights of tenancy for a person or persons engaging in the practice of squatting; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D703D312110431E88DA433423F8E9D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for—</text> 
<clause id="H8C96F0E8C85C487C99C8E9DD9EC72F1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>units of general local government to take corrective actions to remedy the applicability of the prohibition under subparagraph (A) to such unit of general local government; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB566E149331E46B6B253DE14FC8DB107"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>certification by the Secretary upon a determination that such actions taken by a unit of general local government are sufficient for the unit of general local government to receive funds under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9AB45C975EF6484F880D43BFE3B55658"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text>The Secretary shall make publicly available for each fiscal year a list of all units of general local government that are prohibited by paragraph (1) from receiving funds under this title and the justification for inclusion in the list of each such unit of general local government.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H691EFDB1D5F74814B999B45446D1AADB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Squatting</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>squatting</quote> means the practice of entering a property without the permission of the property owner and residing in that property for 10 or more consecutive days without the permission of the property owner and without the payment of rent or a rental contract agreed to by the property owner.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB125682AB6642338FDCFAAE5B149705"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal mortgage support</header> 
<paragraph id="H4F2713EA2E1E4E988A3CFB8B1AA2E476"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal support may be provided for any loan that is secured by a first or subordinate lien on residential real property (including individual units of condominiums and cooperatives) and designed principally for the occupancy of from 1- to 4-families if the property securing such loan is located in a unit of general local government that is, at such time, prohibited from receiving funds under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 by section 104(n)(1)(A) of such Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3DA2869562C491C92AD78B7D20B437D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heads of the covered agencies shall jointly develop, by regulations issued not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, guidelines for such covered agencies to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13719B96668A4EBAA6F7931D4511126B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <subparagraph id="HA80FBBE733D14576AEA960C154DF1656"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered agency</quote> means—</text> 
<clause id="H702FB4925AB8478AB9DBAF2FCE4D863F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text></clause> <clause id="HB8E5E39A7827458180F201608361D8FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal Housing Finance Agency;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H928E2D01F22B431E88A7E777E44CAB89"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF19C05C015204FEBA981CC630E797E86"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7DBD2922AD6A441BB7983E47126389AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal support</header><text>The term <quote>Federal support</quote> means, with respect to a loan—</text> <clause id="HEC1642B2D7D843A496299B0BDF1DB5CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>insurance of the loan by the Federal Housing Administration under title II of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1707">12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H613DA1778C644C538448D724B5337FC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">insurance of the loan under section 255 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715z-20">12 U.S.C. 1715z–20</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H076E0946825048248D5572DCD7BC71BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guarantee of the loan under section 184 or 184A of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (12 U.S.C. 1715z–13a, 1715z–13b);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H20A4FE39372E44B083620C6977AB1FA1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>guarantee or insurance of the loan by the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></clause> <clause id="HE98F8BE269E54760869C4D6962154608"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guarantee or insurance of the loan by the Department of Agriculture;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HECACF90EFAAB4B9B8C5CFB8DA091F0C9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making of the loan by the Department of Agriculture; or</text></clause> <clause id="HC9BA223FD15644B08AB4636EB2705894"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchase or securitization of the loan by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation or the Federal National Mortgage Association.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31EA9AAD35CD48E9A94EF1E6144027E0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Squatting</header><text>The term <quote>squatting</quote> means the practice of entering a property without the permission of the property owner and residing in that property for 14 or more consecutive days without the permission of the property owner and without the payment of rent or a rental contract agreed to by the property owner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

