<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H895E9877FCE94FE896A33F766A81891A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6265 IH: Safer Guarding of Adolescents from Malicious Interactions on Network Games Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6265</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require online video game providers to provide certain safeguards for minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2FEE00E66E3C47F6B2A3C9A07AE64430" style="OLC"><section id="HE35E4DFC67FB42928DE90C9F4EE573D2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Guarding of Adolescents from Malicious Interactions on Network Games Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Safer GAMING Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDBE1FAFF0476465E80C5A30D7155F433"><enum>2.</enum><header>Safeguard requirements for online video game providers</header><subsection id="HD49DAE8D123C47BDA179667258BF1B9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H713D80B15B6347388538E45393AAEFE3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adult user</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>adult user</quote> means a user of an interactive online video game if the provider of such game knows that such user is not a minor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA52F9F2F30CC4B778A38449D7D2196F1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered user</header><text>The term <quote>covered user</quote> means a user of an interactive online video game if the provider of such game knows that such user is a minor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE75F55AE30C64D398095BC8B2EDB62EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interactive online video game</header><text>The term <quote>interactive online video game</quote> means a video game that—</text><subparagraph id="H22696E7392ED4DE1B8D6A75417DD1C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>connects to the internet; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ADA4767D750415E8C503DA96C48AA8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allows a user of such video game to communicate with other users of such video game.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B66126FF96B4540A0A6931EAE26B9D5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Know; knows</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>know</quote> or <quote>knows</quote> means to have actual knowledge or to have acted in willful disregard.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C6E512657E94B85B681593BDE82A03F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <quote>minor</quote> means an individual under the age of 18 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43B2A42E8D41465484A0AEA06F8420AC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Online video game provider</header><text>The term <quote>online video game provider</quote> means a person that provides an interactive online video game directly to a consumer for the use of the consumer, including through a website, mobile application, or other online means.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9F0804BE10449929F0EEC1C390F8C5A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Parent</header><text>The term <quote>parent</quote> means the legal guardian of a minor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3011AAD2F50F4AB682FA2769D16EB7BC"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Video game</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>video game</quote> means a device or software program that—</text><subparagraph id="HA8B0C38CAF9644598BEE30BEB99A5C2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receives and stores data or instructions generated by the user of such object, device, or software program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8AA96F374ED4AE0B5D6C80AF4707C49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>processes such data or instructions to create an interactive game for such user to play or view on a computer, gaming system, console, mobile device, or other technological means.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD2830C519F246009E60653928761CD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safeguards required</header><paragraph id="H882271B3397843B8A0764A630D3C78B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An online video game provider shall provide safeguards to the parent of a covered user of an interactive online video game of such provider that allow the parent to limit communication between such covered user and any other user (including any adult user) of such online video game.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BBB9DA2C4FD4A59ABFA16B66C439A68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Features</header><text>An online video game provider required to provide safeguards under paragraph (1) shall ensure the following:</text><subparagraph id="H50EC643ADCE64F0EA1BC455E1165FC90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The safeguards—</text><clause id="H70AA6486B28F40BCB2290DEA4214DBCC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are accessible and easy-to use;</text></clause><clause id="H0E3319300EF34D208164458ACD840560"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are enabled by default on the account of a covered user of the interactive online video game of such provider; and</text></clause><clause id="H8944F0E75E5D4C858AE466A753E6870A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">can be disabled only by the parent of the covered user.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF25CE803530848CB872F072559409F19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The most protective level of control offered to a user with respect to privacy and safety settings—</text><clause id="HED36F9A4D6344BB0818049AB21A555EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes such safeguards by default; and</text></clause><clause id="HD4B6F1B3A28A43AD867E4D4FB6F669C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a covered user, can be disabled only by the parent of the covered user.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H957B278605004BF5A1C3D3646EFE1A9A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit an online video game provider from providing the parent of a covered user of an interactive online video game of such provider with the ability to limit or allow communication between the covered user and multiple other users.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H154E9247C5694026AF4495FC32DE8E27"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H731B4C679D1B41D28821B458BA07A672" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph id="H0C57271E657840DDA011548710433B7E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (b) shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4659BA8FE587402DBE012C38D8F950BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce subsection (b) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates subsection (b) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57FD3630B16E4B0D9DB49E4D37A6640D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Federal Trade Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6797908DF48844EA868FDB07497C5D8E" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Actions by States</header><paragraph id="H1C82E351353A4F9B83EA3FEB72A54EC5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of such State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of subsection (b), the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph id="HE02F1E9F0D0A48728226C583A58D7535" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H321ABA1933E742B3BB60027EA41B8180" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EFCDAFAAC774629B377733705DC8572" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC807C6C596B4D24AF37F101533D30EA" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain such other legal and equitable relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9581100DD30C418CA8C7753D974D1D43" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Before filing an action under this subsection, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State involved shall provide to the Federal Trade Commission a written notice of such action and a copy of the complaint for such action. If the attorney general, official, or agency determines that it is not feasible to provide the notice described in this paragraph before the filing of the action, the attorney general, official, or agency shall provide written notice of the action and a copy of the complaint to the Federal Trade Commission immediately upon the filing of the action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DB8D5D8CF884A6E80072B21965C15E7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority of Federal Trade Commission</header><subparagraph id="H48B49A58BDA04036B0E6BC5E22DD2E04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On receiving notice under paragraph (2) of an action under this subsection, the Federal Trade Commission shall have the right—</text><clause id="H5528BF4AF3F24E3AAA3996B6CACDFA57" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to intervene in the action; and</text></clause><clause id="H3BD6B7EACE77424DAB0161A4AA4F5934"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon so intervening—</text><subclause id="HC3BB6BB1FEFA4A62B5E65FD4051AF04F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H28CF9C1CA11645FC998443C95975DD3E" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BC0ADA0EB7740B5833C3FFE75E37919" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Federal Trade Commission or the Attorney General of the United States has instituted a civil action for violation of subsection (b) (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>Federal action</quote>), no State attorney general, official, or agency may bring an action under this subsection during the pendency of the Federal action against any defendant named in the complaint in the Federal action for any violation of such subsection alleged in such complaint.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E36266313064C67BB8892153A453A6B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing a civil action under this subsection, nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent an attorney general, official, or agency of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, official, or agency by the laws of such State to conduct investigations, administer oaths and affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H978BD0BFBFDB4C128ED44C3DDB99C405" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State or political subdivision of a State may prescribe, maintain, or enforce any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law, if such law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision relates to the provisions of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

