<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA3191955303D41A784057C55695BB2C8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7511 IH: Iowa National Guard Heroes Commemoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7511</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Des Moines, Iowa, as the <quote>Staff Sergeant Edgar Torres-Tovar VA Clinic</quote> and to designate the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department in Marshalltown, Iowa, as the <quote>Staff Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard VA Clinic</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9E140E3567F442BCA55563363C0BBE48" style="OLC"><section id="H3756B8D98C3E42ECB7C35B9962E1933D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Iowa National Guard Heroes Commemoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H61C288B7DA38485DB35D659B2A770675"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Staff Sergeant Edgar Torres-Tovar VA Clinic</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB8271191D844A4089152D73C6A554BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6BB1BA2FA13D477F8ECB41143744CEF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar was born in DeKalb, Illinois, on October 17, 2000, and raised in Des Moines, Iowa.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CAB86D6F5F34D0BAF27618792593328"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Torres-Tovar graduated from Dowling Catholic High School in West Des Moines, Iowa, in 2019.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ABF5A81779844448650685A6EC7F939"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On February 21, 2019, Staff Sergeant Torres-Tovar enlisted in the United States Army.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H640CC43261664EE68768E648C60320DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Torres-Tovar was the first in his family to serve in the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47F46B7C87E14BC389BA3302983FC6CB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Staff Sergeant Torres-Tovar deployed to Kosovo in November 2020, supporting United States and allied operations, and deployed to Syria in July 2025 in support of Operation Inherent Resolve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H501267A8CCC840C98D2A6B8C64ACB724"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Torres-Tovar served as a Cavalry Scout with Troop B, 1st Squadron, 113th Cavalry Regiment, 2nd Brigade Combat Team, 34th Infantry Division of the Iowa National Guard.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4689AE3EE6754E90BE9AA611C5852AEF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On December 13, 2025, Staff Sergeant Torres-Tovar was killed in action in Palmyra, Syria, while supporting United States counterterrorism operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3FDF6801386432CA4B03940CDF0C1AE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Torres-Tovar was awarded the Bronze Star Medal with Valor, the Purple Heart, the Combat Action Badge, and the Army Commendation Medal with Combat Device for heroic service during combat operations in support of Operation Inherent Resolve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A57F8C58BE9456A839C4A2AEB8DC236"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs located at 1211 East Army Post Road, Des Moines, Iowa, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Staff Sergeant Edgar Torres-Tovar VA Clinic</quote> or the <quote>Edgar Torres-Tovar VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3B07F2F00E14495B8B901D13EF7C4295" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in subsection (b) shall be considered to be a reference to the Staff Sergeant Edgar Torres-Tovar VA Clinic.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB903E11F8BA441ACA413E2E69C1121AF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of Staff Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard VA Clinic</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CA3D2CD9F9D4C308DC6D1ED482F1023"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H52C3432875354331AF4DD497BC90C64A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant William Nathaniel <quote>Nate</quote> Howard was born on August 14, 1996, in Marshalltown, Iowa.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64B58D8292B043D384FA1FD81EDA8E41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Howard graduated from Marshalltown High School in 2014.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3498477177504D23A42503B6C268CA7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>At the age of 17, while a high school senior, Staff Sergeant Howard enlisted in the Iowa National Guard on November 27, 2013, completing basic combat training and advanced individual training at Fort Benning, Georgia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6AC059DCE4C4A29BA01468F6D3FB48A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Howard deployed to Kosovo from November 2020 to July 2021 in support of United States and allied operations, served on the Texas border from April 2024 to May 2024, and deployed to Syria in July 2025 in support of Operation Inherent Resolve.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C88ECDF9E3D4A2893D5632A09C576BB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Staff Sergeant Howard served as a Cavalry Scout with Troop B, 1st Squadron, 113th Cavalry Regiment, 2nd Brigade Combat Team, 34th Infantry Division of the Iowa National Guard.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28B3B08561D24CF4B2B03CEFEC6B035D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On December 13, 2025, Staff Sergeant Howard was killed in action in Palmyra, Syria, while supporting United States counterterrorism operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DE8EBC53B5844A294D0BC9EEF14AF69"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Staff Sergeant Howard was awarded the Bronze Star Medal with Valor, the Purple Heart, the Combat Action Badge, and the Army Commendation Medal with Combat Device for heroic service in combat.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C2BC679DCEA4E7BACF45B178868C03B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs located at 201 East Merle Hibbs Boulevard, Marshalltown, Iowa, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Staff Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard VA Clinic</quote> or the <quote>Nate Howard VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H90ED19EFD3574E1FB9F9B399C5526BDC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in subsection (b) shall be considered to be a reference to the Staff Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard VA Clinic.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

