<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H290CC4769B074EFDB22B4D7937B2B2AD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1290 IH: Recognizing the significant and often overlooked behavioral health needs experienced by individuals and families affected by rare diseases, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1290</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the significant and often overlooked behavioral health needs experienced by individuals and families affected by rare diseases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas rare diseases affect an estimated 25,000,000 to 30,000,000 Americans, more than half of whom are children, and many of the individuals and families affected by rare diseases experience yearslong diagnostic journeys marked by uncertainty, misdiagnosis, and delayed treatment;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas behavioral health conditions, including anxiety, depression, trauma-related symptoms, and caregiver burnout, are common for rare disease patients and caregivers, and such conditions are the predictable consequences of the structural challenges inherent in rare disease care rather than reflections of a personal weakness;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas access to behavioral health care for rare disease patients and caregivers remains limited due to the shortages of trained clinicians, geographic barriers, low reimbursement rates, and fragmented care models that rarely integrate behavioral health;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas peer support programs have demonstrated significant benefit in reducing isolation, improving coping skills, and strengthening community resilience for rare disease patients and caregivers, yet such programs remain inconsistently available, unstandardized, and insufficiently supported across States and health systems;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas culturally competent and culturally humble behavioral health care for individuals and families affected by rare diseases is essential to ensuring equitable access, reducing disparities, and meeting the needs of diverse communities that are disproportionately affected by delayed diagnoses, stigma, and systemic barriers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the behavioral health workforce faces ongoing shortages, particularly in child and adolescent psychiatry, psychology, social work, and community-based behavioral health roles, limiting the availability of specialized care for rare disease families;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas payor challenges, including low reimbursement rates, administrative burden, and limited coverage for integrated behavioral health, further restrict access to timely, high-quality behavioral health services; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas continuing medical education on rare diseases and their behavioral health implications is limited, and incentivizing such continuing medical education would strengthen clinician preparedness, improve diagnostic accuracy, and enhance whole-person care: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9DDC5A1B1AC148E79EB87475FE8E28ED"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H396FA2FCF92745888E40C6DEE115808B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HBCDC5BF2BF744A7F8E7378DFCAA02CF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the significant and often overlooked behavioral health needs experienced by individuals and families affected by rare diseases;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D185CD2B05A48B0ACD3CA3BE2CCB460"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirms that behavioral health care is an essential component of comprehensive rare disease care and should be integrated into clinical pathways, research agendas, and Federal policies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42ABFC10946146CA82DFA2497B49D595"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls upon Federal agencies, including the Department of Health and Human Services, the National Institutes of Health, and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, to prioritize behavioral health access within rare disease initiatives, research funding, and care delivery models;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE84ECED923C4D8F97639A9BD2DD4F74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the development and expansion of standardized, evidence-informed peer support programs for rare disease patients, caregivers, and families, including support for virtual and community-based models;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC0B6F1F7C5A43CA84D276CBCD159B1C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports efforts to strengthen cultural competency and cultural humility across the behavioral health and rare disease workforce, including training, community partnerships, and equitable access initiatives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56A98EDB91F64A659F43BCE79B6703A3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>urges investment in the behavioral health workforce, particularly child and adolescent providers, to ensure adequate capacity to meet the needs of rare disease families;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA274F44A7C7F4A9BA3056D945F743FC0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recommends that public and private payors evaluate and address reimbursement barriers that limit access to integrated behavioral health services for rare disease patients;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6654EE2C769442FFA75C72A84077D1AA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>encourages the creation of Federal incentives for clinicians to pursue continuing medical education on rare diseases, including their psychiatric and psychosocial dimensions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9D107575FD04F4486D692B98E24F080"><enum>(9)</enum><text>supports ongoing collaboration among Federal agencies, patient advocacy organizations, academic institutions, and community partners to develop comprehensive strategies that address the behavioral health needs of the rare disease community.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

