<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25C70-3TY-VS-04G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 570 IS: Designating November 2025 as “National Lung Cancer Awareness Month” and expressing support for early detection and treatment of lung cancer.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 570</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 2025 as <quote>National Lung Cancer Awareness Month</quote> and expressing support for early detection and treatment of lung cancer.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas lung cancer is the leading cause of cancer-related death among individuals in the United States, accounting for more deaths than colorectal, breast, and prostate cancer combined;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in 2025, an estimated 226,650 individuals in the United States will be diagnosed with lung cancer, and 124,730 individuals (approximately 340 individuals per day) will die from the disease;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas 1 in 16 men and 1 in 17 women in the United States will develop lung cancer during their lifetimes;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas each year more women die from lung cancer than breast, ovarian, and cervical cancer combined;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in 2025, cigarette smoking directly caused approximately 109,100 of the 124,730 lung cancer deaths, and exposure to secondhand smoke causes over 7,300 lung cancer deaths each year in adults who do not smoke;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas approximately 10 to 20 percent of lung cancer diagnoses occur in people who have never smoked, and the proportion of lung cancer diagnoses in individuals who have never smoked is increasing in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas women who never smoked are more likely than men who never smoked to get lung cancer;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Black men have the highest incidence of lung cancer and the highest mortality rate from lung cancer in the United States, and nonwhite individuals are 13 to 18 percent less likely to be diagnosed with lung cancer early in their lives;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas veterans are 25 percent more likely to develop lung cancer compared to the general public, and although approximately 1,000,000 to 2,000,000 veterans have an elevated risk of lung cancer and are eligible for screening, less than 3 percent of veterans get screened;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas lung cancer is the second most commonly diagnosed cancer in veterans;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the 5-year survival rate is 67 percent for those diagnosed with localized lung cancer and 12 percent for those diagnosed at a stage when the cancer has spread to distant parts of the body;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the number of individuals in the United States recommended to receive lung cancer screening was estimated to be 14,500,000 as of 2021;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas only 16 percent of individuals in the United States at high risk for lung cancer undergo lung cancer screening;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas limited geographic availability of facilities and transportation barriers are persistent challenges to lung cancer screening;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas 62 percent of adults are not familiar with lung cancer screening and the low-dose computed tomography scan;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the stigma surrounding lung cancer—</text><paragraph id="id5fcf9241fc06440aa1384f51325a3a27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates barriers to early diagnosis, treatment, and research; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7af241c3492748a09ca2b1ff52024324"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has a detrimental impact on the quality of life of lung cancer patients;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lung cancer research is leading to breakthroughs in biomarker identification and the development of immunotherapies and targeted therapies that are improving survival and quality of life for those with lung cancer;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas access to biomarker testing and cutting-edge diagnostics is challenging across populations and geographic areas; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas educational efforts can increase awareness of lung cancer and lung cancer screening among the general public, patients and their families, and health care workers and increase the early detection of lung cancer: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0e11845ffd184f9dbdf6b519e3bb22fd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates November 2025 as <quote>National Lung Cancer Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4cf3ec1aaf04080b9dfa3c73dcb1515"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designates the first week of November 2025 as <quote>National Women's Lung Cancer Awareness Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id797cea85d3d64a728cf5edcd6278416a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>designates the second Saturday of November 2025 as <quote>National Lung Cancer Screening Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b96cc357cc54a05bf5e880778f6a139"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the purposes and ideals of National Lung Cancer Awareness Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id132413f1dbd6436fb9a80d2313d8c410"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promotes efforts to increase awareness of, education about, and research on—</text><subparagraph id="id29244c0726784ffa87af62eb73e1f094"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mitigation of risk factors for lung cancer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef624bf519264054bad9175fb0142ca0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lung cancer screening;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a383e939d7c46a5a70696b146607e5e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>treatment of lung cancer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3a78a6e20ff40fcbb394eaeeccd4262"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lung cancer affecting minorities and individuals who have never smoked; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id046d63835f40474e9c97c4ce1f4ce598"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe National Lung Cancer Awareness Month with appropriate awareness and educational activities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

