<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EDW26197-MJP-GJ-018"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 S4248 IS: Enhancing Long-Term, Efficient, and Viable Alternatives to Empower Flood-Prone Communities Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4248</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for planning and implementation of nonstructural flood risk management solutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Long-Term, Efficient, and Viable Alternatives to Empower Flood-Prone Communities Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc5840b63ab5c41f18125b088d0b23c52"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id704003fbb6e1489db127f9f8f75edc8d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nonstructural feature</header><subparagraph id="id4926b8a00654419bac21a7b74a3cf9b9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>nonstructural feature</term>, with respect to a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction, means—</text><clause id="id00a707ffe7ec4449a970e340018981bb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>structure elevation;</text></clause><clause id="id3885bb3e074d406aa8c5b040429369bc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>structure floodproofing;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa60617f6a9e46589b3de26046355c74"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">basement filling; and</text></clause><clause id="id5650624b24da4813adb94c2780f4f7f3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>acquisition of floodplain land and structure demolition or relocation, except as provided in subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80c960d89f144ae9b2bddc980aa665da"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>nonstructural feature</term> does not include any property acquisition and structure demolition or relocation required to implement a structural feature or to mitigate for flooding induced by a structural feature.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id12100f820dc146dea0485dfa62f42551"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id5dbfb4f6aabc48be9410015ecd9c82ae"><enum>3.</enum><header>Planning and implementation of nonstructural flood risk management solutions</header><subsection id="id244bce44f89d457d93e73c7691967a1a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="ida0b28b8209a04bf1a1cd5cf0428c44c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nonstructural features are proven methods for reducing both short- and long-term risk and damages from the isolated and compound effects of all flood drivers, including fluvial flooding, coastal storm surge-driven flooding, and flooding from extreme rainfall;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91907c5fd04d490c9c49659b0163e05e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>nonstructural features reduce flood risk and damages while preserving the benefits of natural floodplains, including natural flood and erosion control, fish and wildlife habitat, water quality maintenance, groundwater recharge, and recreation opportunities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7eeda7970a524195b055642e2e1ee891"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nonstructural features require minimal operation, maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, and replacement and, as a result, are often more cost-effective than structural features such as levees and floodwalls;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d1942ce6fac452b8c3388e27cc6694b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>nonstructural features may be the only cost-effective solution to address flood risk and damages in small rural communities and in large, densely populated areas with multiple flood sources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8947f44bf6604edbb8a20510b6e915d3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Congress has required the Corps of Engineers to consider nonstructural features in the formulation of all flood risk management and hurricane and storm damage risk reduction projects since 1974;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2241cf8ec1844714b17de28666f8bf02"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Corps of Engineers reportedly has identified over 88,000 individual structures for elevation in authorized flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction projects or in ongoing feasibility studies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7437e1a798f041c9b2d1aa121a187e92"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the wholesale pausing or termination of participation by the Corps of Engineers in nonstructural flood risk management is contrary to the direction of Congress and will leave flood-prone communities unacceptably vulnerable to increasing flood risk.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id68fab2135b4d4791910741bf4892faed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text>Congress declares that it is the policy of the United States that—</text><paragraph id="id88ecae71c245456095167c5d3bee3b81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nonstructural features shall be given equal consideration to structural features in every feasibility study conducted by the Corps of Engineers for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id117c2e7491064ec1889c1407cb2b492d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementation of nonstructural features determined by the Corps of Engineers to meet the Federal objective for investments in water resources is a fundamental part of the primary mission of the Corps of Engineers for flood risk management and hurricane and storm damage risk reduction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idafd0ede01321424c89e9edb98889d8a0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id195ad8cfff254fa1a981e7ce68b80f4e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reaffirm the role of the Corps of Engineers in the development and implementation of nonstructural features; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40902bd062b4474d9838975edc575f97"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enhance the capability of the Corps of Engineers to plan and implement nonstructural features efficiently and effectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9dbe4f6e1d4144089b0957bd5fae32ff"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation of studies and projects</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcdc0eeb999447e0811e668fe9b4f3a8"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Continuation of studies and projects</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd751a9ec10c4cce974773857f588703"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (5), the Secretary shall not pause, terminate, or otherwise defer the initiation or continuation of any study or project described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id091d2cd530e0435ba47efb8412898256"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Resumption of studies and projects</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall resume any study or project described in paragraph (2) that the Secretary paused, terminated, or otherwise deferred during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act, unless an exception under paragraph (5) applies to the study or project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id04a996eebb0e43489cdce045c9317bea"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study or project described</header><text>A study or project referred to in this subsection is an authorized flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction study or project—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id801f600155b14ba89b3a42009b517753"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that includes a nonstructural feature;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1628d17f1af4382be74471751469ae8"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idd5b73ec6bb764779ac308e3b98f81a8b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for which Congress has specifically appropriated funds; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8952a5ed826149b2a1832c682070b63b" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which funds have been allocated in a work plan submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75a5c08cd1c64beb97f2b6648339e7c9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for which funds are available for obligation and expenditure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idab24d06fb1c64c02b9b0bfc482efb422"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required disclosures to non-Federal interests</header><subparagraph id="idddcac1affa04434999551add22356c0e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The District Engineer responsible for a study or project described in paragraph (2) shall—</text><clause id="idad38dacb5e3d46eda0db772a2001f263"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, notify the non-Federal interest for the study or project, in writing, of the status of the study or project;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc0e6297f5194bc1b4396c9bb95b5754"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>every 45 days thereafter, provide the non-Federal interest for the study or project, in writing—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90032373d08b494cad6ba3429bd9dfcc"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a current schedule for completion of the study or project; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58b2aadc6a9d4c10a5382e2cbadde5db"><enum>(II)</enum><text>documentation of funds expended and work items completed;</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8952fca4bbe47f28ce0d0406ab17045"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>notify the non-Federal interest for the study or project, in writing, by not later than 15 days after the date of any—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a668137a89b4908978b84eb29bf0551"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">change to the schedule that exceeds the programmed float for the study or project; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdb90fda53b64032897ecabca53f6806"><enum>(II)</enum><text>pause, termination, or deferral of the study or project pursuant to an exception described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (5); and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4176eb958bb84f1fbc81acf0e847c57e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>beginning February 15, 2027, and each February 15 thereafter, notify the non-Federal interest for the study or project, in writing, of the capability of the Corps of Engineers for the study or project in the upcoming fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9ec3dd1d30d4e7796662face9b7e6dd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of notification</header><text>The written notification under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) shall include an explanation of the cause of the change to the schedule for the study or project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf14d2ff01f348b99451e367b1d54a49"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a copy of each notification issued to a non-Federal interest under clause (i), (iii), or (iv) of subparagraph (A) to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d742f0f45624c478ce7052b0caceb7e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements for certain studies</header><subparagraph id="ide68aa0f14b9546bfaaf243e46a93731e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a study described in paragraph (2) the purpose of which is to develop a recommendation with respect to a congressional authorization for a project, including a congressional authorization to increase the maximum authorized cost of a project in accordance with section 902 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2280">33 U.S.C. 2280</external-xref>), the Secretary may not—</text><clause id="id8c7320abd6d84983b3c92d4c4feaad85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complete the study without submitting to Congress a Chief’s Report or Director’s Report, as applicable, for the study that includes such a recommendation;</text></clause><clause id="ide84d550ce0604705a80e8d149efa8ddd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>narrow the purpose or geographic scope of the study relative to the authorized purpose and geographic scope of the study, unless requested in writing by the non-Federal interest for the study; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06283afeee12410ba6c7dc8e49b9c6bc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>delay progress of the study toward a schedule milestone by a period exceeding 45 days under subsections (b) and (c) of section 1001 of the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2282c">33 U.S.C. 2282c</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8a713dfc07643a793e9ef2fc3e95db6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Locally preferred alternative</header><text>On the request of the non-Federal interest for a study described in paragraph (2) that requires a Chief’s Report, the Secretary shall include in the Chief’s Report, with a level of detail comparable to the level of detail required by the Secretary to support a recommendation for congressional authorization, the features and costs of the locally preferred alternative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8ecf920e01d4cd782de1219fd8a4910"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a study or project described in paragraph (2) if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e180821968e403e93a9acb542ba2743"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the pausing of construction of the project is required to comply with section 902 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2280">33 U.S.C. 2280</external-xref>), subject to the condition that the pause does not affect the validation study necessary to support an increase in the maximum authorized cost of the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc823aad50dcc44eb9591914235ad5cb8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the pausing or deferral of the study or project is required because the non-Federal interest for the study or project lacks the capability to carry out the non-Federal responsibilities required by, as applicable—</text><clause id="id422bd077a10c405aabd200e572139806"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 101, 102, 103, or 105 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2211">33 U.S.C. 2211</external-xref>, 2212, 2213, 2215);</text></clause><clause id="idf6c0d1f6f5c5447fa7649586cf81d658"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 221 of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1962d-5b">42 U.S.C. 1962d–5b</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="idda4e573a8f464c1985cccf3bdef3fe41"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the authorization for the study or project;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c98b63c145f4be5b5f21b0a647464ab"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the pausing, termination, or deferral of the study or project is required to comply with a court order or condition of a settlement agreement; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc24e3fdc54cb4d2885eae7a5f30ec989"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the pausing, termination, or deferral of the study or project is requested in writing by the non-Federal interest for the study or project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89dda849e5634561858c88392aa7e930"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Presumption</header><text>A study or project described in paragraph (2) to which no exception described in paragraph (5) applies shall be presumed to be paused, terminated, or deferred in violation of paragraph (1) if—</text><subparagraph id="id9086de7ae0474961b8fadbb5e580bd26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>progress of the study or project toward a schedule milestone is delayed by a period exceeding 45 days; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6d5907131a849f9ab7e81ede5946350"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District Engineer fails to provide to the non-Federal interest for the study or project any documentation or notification under paragraph (3)(A) in accordance with the terms of that paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7880c820811740efa59dc321191f239d"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technical competence and capacity building</header><paragraph id="idd21febdf1bc6429096c1077117e0681f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National nonstructural committee</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67bd41c5334a449487e92be79c58f03c"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary shall not terminate the charter for the National Nonstructural Committee of the Corps of Engineers without specific authorization from Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcbffdee2f5941c19a742fccd01b9dfc"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Stakeholder engagement and community outreach policies</header><text>The National Nonstructural Committee shall prioritize the development of guidance and tools to enhance participation in nonstructural features through stakeholder engagement and community outreach.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8995c561e1684f45a43e29b8d1da7465"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonstructural working group</header><subparagraph id="id91e224e22f904dbd85c01b1703ae9301"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the National Nonstructural Committee, shall establish a nonstructural working group composed of subject matter experts from Federal agencies with statutory responsibilities related to flood risk management or flood hazard mitigation, State and local governments, and nationally recognized nonprofit organizations with expertise in nonstructural flood risk management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33d6ab5c57524582bea05ef8438f25ed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the National Nonstructural Committee shall ensure that the nonstructural working group established under subparagraph (A) includes—</text><clause id="idc1a9cc56c6414c0286d4e8a342124b45"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01f605af075f4e36bcdda5df9af0dd62"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from the Department of the Interior;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f75d9cf4dec418492b368dddf2f65cc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from the Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98c60b86404347829fa9071717a9f2a9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from the Department of Agriculture;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8fcf1929e734495bdd5fd0c64cc02b9"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 1 representative of a State or local government with expertise in rural floodplain management;</text></clause><clause id="idec140745bb16486eb873a0ecd2b599c8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative of a State or local government with expertise in urban floodplain management;</text></clause><clause id="id96d93007f0b04441b94159fcff9fd81c"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative of a State or local government with expertise in inland floodplain management;</text></clause><clause id="idab3b5fccb04d45beb5137f0b5d84d990"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative of a State or local government with expertise in coastal floodplain management; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10cea1e947744a60999644e0273bbf95"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>not less than 5 representatives from nationally recognized nonprofit organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d513f44facc4a78bc25bad955dfb08d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Members of the nonstructural working group established under subparagraph (A) may provide—</text><clause id="iddcc49c8aca044e079f64b72f7a5f35a4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information and individual advice to the Corps of Engineers offices and non-Federal interests to further the execution of flood risk management and hurricane and storm damage risk reduction studies and projects that include nonstructural features; and</text></clause><clause id="idc1a416d6da1d4501846976ef227f158d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information and individual advice to the National Nonstructural Committee and to the mandatory nonstructural center of expertise described in paragraph (3) to further the development of technical and policy guidance for the formulation, evaluation, and implementation of nonstructural measures.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id059d8dc46bd448128765327cc0d12a9a"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Access to information</header><text>The National Nonstructural Committee shall provide the members of the nonstructural working group established under subparagraph (A) such access to information related to ongoing flood risk management and hurricane and storm damage risk reduction studies and projects that include nonstructural features and technical and policy guidance as is necessary for the members to carry out the duties described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf71b55d3d7b7404791937fc437773885"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The nonstructural working group established under subparagraph (A) shall convene on not less than a quarterly basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd63dfced56854589b5933c0d666a7623"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mandatory nonstructural center of expertise</header><subparagraph id="id43b3c1987baf431d90e4289531ae2427"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall designate a mandatory nonstructural center of expertise in the Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ba58bc76ae94c4cb21df79c40e7bd32"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the mandatory nonstructural center of expertise designated under subparagraph (A) include—</text><clause id="id18db1a0d084448f9a08478979abc0304"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consolidating existing technical expertise to facilitate efficient and effective delivery of technical and specialized services for flood risk management and hurricane and storm damage risk reduction studies;</text></clause><clause id="id3c104079730b431c9e12d1b9907d468a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reviewing, coordinating, and improving the quality of study products and recommendations;</text></clause><clause id="idafa302ffe9d2416394644d4aa0d9684d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>building capacity and technical competence within the Corps of Engineers with respect to nonstructural flood risk management; and</text></clause><clause id="id65855b882b6f42169ffa13cc1720ed19"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinating with the nonstructural working group established under paragraph (2)(A) to assess needs, review recommendations, and support the development of policy guidance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id644da7616b82477396094b69bcaaf509"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="ida1221f5eeb634ee3a249d4e89129f963"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the activities of the National Nonstructural Committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb5b87c435a043558b2df15614392350"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the contributions of members of the nonstructural working group established under paragraph (2)(A), including an assessment of any recommendations made by individual members of the working group;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6473e48becfa45f9b368820fdf126024"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of the activities of the mandatory nonstructural center of expertise designated under paragraph (3)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81c0c074455c4afc8d6ff924ffec1a16"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the consideration of nonstructural features in ongoing flood risk management and hurricane and storm damage risk reduction studies, including—</text><clause id="id5633e97caf194bc197b4a1f40663f963"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a comparison of the benefits and costs of nonstructural features and alternatives relative to the benefits and costs of structural features and alternatives across studies; and</text></clause><clause id="id03378d3cb1ca4170a2c651e2be1caec2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of any study in which a fully nonstructural alternative was not included in the final array of alternatives and the justification for the decision;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf19544980f284cac9add1d4c7b7ff534"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assessment of the implementation of nonstructural features included in flood risk management and hurricane and storm damage risk reduction projects under construction, including a summary of participation rates and a description of the community outreach strategies implemented during project construction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03cb04f3a9da42a282276713592a8f43"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of actions taken by the Corps of Engineers to address barriers to implementation of nonstructural features.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfd601b933c17483a83203f76d515e1dd"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><paragraph id="idc106fcfb9303451787fc6bc6a445eccb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 103(b) of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2213">33 U.S.C. 2213(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id1f75e4543721463584d66761790c89c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>The non-Federal share</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the non-Federal share</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e548ead18ce4ad78f4792f8e412627c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0588ba16aca04eaab60ba2f0536d3890"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">35 percent</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">the non-Federal share</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idecd33852f3bf4cdbbc7691458fb73dbf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>35 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>the non-Federal share</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf645c646ec914eb9b468685c40f927a2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>65 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>the Federal share</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b5254fee74e454f9f7e43b8f0c32099"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e82590d5ccd4ec7bf47455c6de8d5e7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2cde29c2ab540488a1aa39f5d291161"><paragraph id="idfa51878ea66a442c95b8d3602f36145a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost sharing for certain measures using nonstructural features</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction measure using a nonstructural feature shall be—</text><subparagraph id="id11ba5f3e31134c2fbe36142c7a33c166"><enum>(A)</enum><text>90 percent, if the measure benefits an economically disadvantaged community (as defined pursuant to section 160 of the Water Resources Development Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2201">33 U.S.C. 2201</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7016ef99eb84aeb9edd555ac895e3e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>90 percent, if the measure is for a repetitive loss structure (as defined in section 1370 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4121">42 U.S.C. 4121</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80a312e116a34e2a83f41415398618eb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>100 percent, if the measure is for a severe repetitive loss structure (as defined in section 1366(h) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(h)</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7f9eca5f1be4b3b8e988f1be25cb41c"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">75 percent, in the case of any measure not described in subparagraphs (A) through (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id221e382dacb64720aaec61e4ae38b562"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall apply to—</text><subparagraph id="idd3720a84d56545dea40e702cde0fbf1e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that is authorized after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb45fef976f148819f9f2c20ee746436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that was authorized on or before the date of enactment of this Act, on the request of the non-Federal interest for the project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idacbdd575e2ee4ae4b21de8d36d060dcc"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Phased implementation</header><paragraph id="id75681d77b9494e75a2080aff2168ecba"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On the request of the non-Federal interest for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes nonstructural features at scale, the Secretary shall phase implementation of the nonstructural features by municipality, neighborhood or community group, type of structure, category of nonstructural feature, or other appropriate criterion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id729809bce5d24fa5957d85f43baaf0cb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project partnership agreements</header><text>In carrying out a project described in paragraph (1), the Secretary may enter into a separate project partnership agreement with the non-Federal interest for each phase of construction of the nonstructural features.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd618cbb914ea4d169c652459acb46ffe"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multiple non-Federal interests</header><text>In the case of a project described in paragraph (1) that involves multiple non-Federal interests, the Secretary may enter into separate agreements with each non-Federal interest.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd11ca53cb45f45a88042adb4696638b3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Acquisition and structure demolition or relocation</header><subsection commented="no" id="id2236af5781974803b20dd4d8284ed3cc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Voluntary basis</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a property acquisition and structure demolition or relocation nonstructural feature on a voluntary basis and may not compel the owner of a structure included in the nonstructural feature to participate.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4aef2ee1fc2c4359805524b442518fef"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relocation and temporary housing advisory services</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the costs of land, easements, rights-of-way, dredged material disposal areas, and relocations required for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a property acquisition and structure demolition or relocation nonstructural feature the costs of providing relocation advisory services or temporary housing advisory services, as applicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7fc745cc046846808efbec154045506a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Temporary housing</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the costs of land, easements, rights-of-way, dredged material disposal areas, and relocations required for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a property acquisition and structure relocation nonstructural feature the costs of temporary housing for the owner-occupant of a structure included in the nonstructural feature.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f221ba9d61140618e8bb24b12bab8b6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Moving expenses</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the costs of land, easements, rights-of-way, dredged material disposal areas, and relocations required for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a property acquisition and structure demolition or relocation nonstructural feature the costs of actual, reasonable, and necessary moving expenses.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9a7f92d02d8b4d85abb97fd6fa37bd36"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplemental payment in excess of appraised value</header><text>The Secretary may include in the costs of land, easements, rights-of-way, dredged material disposal areas, and relocations required for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a property acquisition and structure demolition nonstructural feature a supplemental payment to the owner-occupant of a structure included in the nonstructural feature in excess of the appraised value of the structure if—</text><paragraph id="id7bb8fcea1b0a43c3a6db94aa9783e8b6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the cost to purchase a comparable replacement dwelling in a nonhazard-prone location exceeds the appraised value of the structure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f7ad681cfe945e1923a0f323bb6a4a8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the household of the owner-occupant qualifies as low income, as defined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id228631b49e474b5ab688f95c0707971f"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="id7d522e4ffc7a45328c1b96950501db70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall apply to—</text><subparagraph id="idae9ad92efa1640f2b8915b1e46aba9ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any study for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that has not reached the tentatively selected plan milestone on or before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b4f4d6c6f6f473ba8dc039e1d0e84c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any study for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that has reached the tentatively selected plan milestone on or before the date of enactment of this Act, at the request of the non-Federal interest for the study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5837172617334ddbb3836326c1ed52a9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Previously authorized projects</header><text>In the case of a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a property acquisition and structure demolition or relocation nonstructural feature authorized on or before the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, at the request of the non-Federal interest, shall carry out the nonstructural feature in accordance with this section without a general reevaluation study.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5c3bb83312ed4cbba9d445c33276e1a7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Structure elevation</header><subsection commented="no" id="id4c10845089ba4b13bd44e7af0eb171c2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Design flood elevation</header><text>In the case of a structure elevation nonstructural feature included in a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idccf3db5b06a3431cbd488f01e1f4d962"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the target design flood elevation shall be not lower than the elevation required by local ordinance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1e7aa86e37d4da8ba8aa537dbee7d0a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary shall evaluate the costs and benefits of adopting as the target design flood elevation for the feature the design flood elevation determined in accordance with the most recent edition of standard 24 of the American Society of Civil Engineers, entitled <quote>Flood Resistant Design and Construction</quote>, if higher than the elevation required by local ordinance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7d238f90afe44ef7b4702ce267fcd9ce"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain eligible project costs</header><text>In the case of a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a structure elevation nonstructural feature, project costs shared in accordance with the cost share requirements otherwise applicable to the project shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text><paragraph id="id5ce3730760414ced89501e46fdf28234"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Costs to comply with minimum design loads and associated criteria for all hazards applicable to a structure included in the project, including seismic hazards and wind hazards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f37fc9969c440cd8270c3269007c81f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Costs to replace or repair utility service components that are undersized, inadequately designed, or unsafe, if required by State or local requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec6e17247bb24074a54f640a018b5124"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Costs to abate asbestos and lead-based paint.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c5d217f86c94ea290c7c95c59a762e6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Costs to elevate existing decks, porches, or stairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0dc17f85c5424a6a8a351c5291f658a9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Costs to construct a floor system that meets minimum State or local requirements when the existing floor system cannot be elevated or is not appropriate for the new foundation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id17fd358dc9794dd4a8413a068fdab55c"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Costs to construct new stairs, landings, and railings to access the elevated living space in compliance with State or local requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ab3bd5e432e47ec82edc2a9b937128b"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Documented reasonable housing costs incurred by an owner-occupant temporarily displaced during construction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id80ee578dd968442aae82f7d6892fc74a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ownership verification</header><text>The Secretary shall accept as proof of ownership of a structure included in a structure elevation nonstructural feature any of the following documents:</text><paragraph id="idcf3f71aa04b242ac95088aa8c7cfffe3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Deed or official record.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd04759589ecb40e88d94d49f45a940a5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Mortgage document.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6878ffee7c4c47a893291ab737e17612"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Homeowners insurance documentation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba707ab4a3eb4ad4be5ec24a980c8958"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Property tax receipt or bill.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a0c177656334c09bc1d5e657454e7d9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Manufactured home certificate or title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf4cb6069ccb48b9a660fab4589a5801"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Home purchase contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id66e609e83d01436f8d547401f088bad9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Will or affidavit of heirship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0c0853ee41143c7b9b9d909701da388"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Receipts for major repairs or maintenance to the structure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2f936c3b3ac456480ac75dba11c995b"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Court documents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ef3dd2ad6df4ebc9992d959b7a58cd4"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A signed statement from a public official.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id86e8c114079847388d8bc9c7b39affbb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project delivery</header><paragraph id="id7320f950b1c240239dd89ee1821d157a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the request of the non-Federal interest for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a structure elevation nonstructural feature, the Secretary shall enter into a project partnership agreement with the non-Federal interest—</text><subparagraph id="idac42ca78f83f44bdb1ac255f1f2ee3ea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to allow the non-Federal interest to carry out the nonstructural feature; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6020f6b087ad4a66b659d548aabd7ae9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide in advance to the non-Federal interest the Federal share of funds required for construction of the nonstructural feature.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6187438909de4a4aa2fc9dc9d47632ab"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracting</header><text>In carrying out a structure elevation nonstructural feature, the Secretary may permit the owner of a structure included in the nonstructural feature to contract for performance of the work on the structure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd1e670847627412abd909dcc12f1693b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="id6552715efba6434c90b85105e1c14cbf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsections (a) through (c) shall apply to—</text><subparagraph id="idafe373542629442aac3c4660b0b7754a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any study for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that has not reached the tentatively selected plan milestone on or before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc82c2c9b681943d9a3f33f7341348e95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any study for a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that has reached the tentatively selected plan milestone on or before the date of enactment of this Act, at the request of the non-Federal interest for the study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb6aca8e65b149fa82e394b1fae6f6f6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Previously authorized projects</header><text>In the case of a project for flood risk management or hurricane and storm damage risk reduction that includes a structure elevation nonstructural feature authorized on or before the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, at the request of the non-Federal interest, shall carry out the nonstructural feature in accordance with subsections (a) through (c) without a general reevaluation study.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

