<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6B847ED22D2B41CC96F351FA7A4FDF84" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6954 IH: January 6th Truth and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6954</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260106">January 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Congressional Research Service to prepare a report extent of recidivism by individuals pardoned by the President under Presidential Proclamation 10887, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B6527675E264DCAA4409CD44E843EFF" style="OLC"><section id="HF4C4C3EF0CA1434B871F610CD341A33F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>January 6th Truth and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H71996A1728714381889EBF0EEB42BD99"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on recidivism by 1/6 insurrectionists</header><subsection id="H87691F2445BE4A75B2C2FD193C7A4B05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Director of the Congressional Research Service shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and make publicly available on the website of the Library of Congress, a report on the extent of recidivism by individuals pardoned by the President under Presidential Proclamation 10887 entitled <quote>Granting Pardons and Commutation of Sentences for Certain Offenses Relating to the Events at or Near the United States Capitol on January 6, 2021</quote> (January 20, 2025).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1050B86F816F46DD897C60238D771846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall contain—</text><paragraph id="H4757307D6A154922BB67C3437586F774"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of each individual who was pardoned by, had their sentence commuted by, or with respect to whom a pending indictment was dismissed pursuant to the Presidential Proclamation referred to in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H470B470D27E54147BDF1E42F1FB2D9A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of each individual described in paragraph (1) who has been arrested for, charged with, or convicted of a criminal offense under Federal, State, or local law, during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of the report, including a description of each such criminal offense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDE212DD750A4F9296D4397BD50F59A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of each individual described in paragraph (1) who has been involved in an encounter with Federal, State, or local law enforcement, that involved the use of force by a law enforcement officer against the individual; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3517C0E6505482C87485EE91F5B535E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other information the Director of the Congressional Research Service determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42761256722E4E59A9990C930A05BDD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means</text><paragraph id="HD9D5E3C896D64F24B46FA0A02E22B2EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80808142CCC54A78869454DE8D13C416"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFEAA720DAB840AD9A30C7988DDF8EC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

