<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HDBB20D36FF914A73B3DCD1634F901B78" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7305 EH: Energy Threat Analysis Center Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7305</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to reauthorize the Department of Energy’s Energy Sector Operational Support for Cyberresilience Program to provide operational support for energy sector cybersecurity and resilience.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HDDB134294EF24F8A9AF3CDEAF285E912">
<section id="HDC2784E0F9924F6BA7292D5AF3F07A22" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Threat Analysis Center Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H44C03C148430463E9599B34B4ED90B6D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Energy Sector Operational Support for Cyberresilience Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 40125(c) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18724">42 U.S.C. 18724(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HD747BAD5CBCC4CF9A2D06FD27629452C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C80A976B39D4827BD6F8ABC85624286"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (E) as subparagraphs (B) through (F), respectively;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H433C207E244A4140B34EFDB12CEFEF0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before subparagraph (B), as so redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H207EFBED58774407AA05AD9697E87FDA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H7694126453154D7C8E90901F91FBFC72"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to strengthen the collective defense, response, and resilience of the United States energy sector—</text>
<clause id="HB23989293AD745BCB855C0738B339B68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by enhancing collaboration between the government and the energy sector to analyze threats to the energy sector and to deny, disrupt, and mitigate operational impacts to energy systems—</text> <subclause id="H861A883280BE44159DDB7965A1406B64" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by exchanging information at the classified and unclassified level, collectively analyzing potential and realized threats, and providing recommendations to mitigate these threats that benefit the broader energy sector; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE76FDC29CE5E4013B388EBE22CA74AFF" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by increasing operational collaboration through establishing the technical infrastructure necessary to house, access, and perform advanced analytics and experimentation to enable analysis, discovery, alerts, and collaboration activities of intelligence-driven and intelligence-informed technical data and knowledge, threat information and to share actionable insights and threat mitigation;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H525CB14ED37A4DD7BCD4A20B53705346"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by advancing the collective understanding of national security risks and vulnerabilities associated with the energy sector that may be exploited by adversaries; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HE05E1D43FE9C49E0A4D1757AAA47FEEA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by increasing the energy sector’s understanding of threat actor tactics, techniques, procedures, indicators of compromise, capabilities, and activities that present risks to the energy sector;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAECE4674062A4F9B89B49FCD44A61AE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>sector;</quote> and inserting <quote>sector; and</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE36094C6034A47BE93C12DC020540DE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE63E435563847BD8254022822A0F13A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F), as so redesignated;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58B32BCD09704704B6A44CD27E69B885"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (7);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H239124D65BD04BC888BB9ADCFFD79F87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1599EDD8D18549208B5B895F320AA818" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="HD3F0E678263E41088AD54970987CCE4B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy Threat Analysis Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may carry out any activity of the program developed and carried out under paragraph (1) through an Energy Threat Analysis Center, which may be established at one or more physical locations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A6AC4A0626B40AC8BE86B9668925649"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No right or benefit</header> <subparagraph id="HBDA0024C149B4992BE5160F3EAC6961E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretarial authority</header><text>The provision of assistance or information under the program developed and carried out under paragraph (1) to a governmental or private entity shall be at the sole and unreviewable discretion of the Secretary.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6144DBACAE4941A2BD3136BF2E435DF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Provision of assistance or information</header><text>The provision of assistance or information under the program developed and carried out under paragraph (1) to a governmental or private entity shall not create a right or benefit, substantive or procedural, for any other governmental or private entity to similar assistance or information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABB13185A8414A7B9C09B04D85CFF1BB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program developed and carried out under paragraph (1) shall not be considered an advisory committee under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H15FC7E3B61294A78A260C013F773B756"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exemption from disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information shared by or with the Federal Government or a State, Tribal, or local government under the program developed and carried out under paragraph (1) shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA817A9BCF4F4C51A28071D2135AB0BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deemed voluntarily shared information and exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, and any State, Tribal, or local provision of law requiring disclosure of information or records; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFA766A9EF1E74887B45698B39A821E0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withheld, without discretion, from the public under section 552(b)(3)(B) of title 5, United States Code, and any State, Tribal, or local provision of law requiring disclosure of information or records.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74934A5CAD284DE39B4AE3232FEFB4C5" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Transaction authority</header> <subparagraph id="H4C5DB9395B12409EA7084EBB569DDE45"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other authority granted to the Secretary under any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to enter into and perform contracts, cooperative agreements, grants, and other transactions with public agencies, private organizations, and persons to carry out the program developed and carried out under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF02CF29155714EC6A29C1348A03D2710"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimizing delays</header><text>The Secretary may establish and utilize pre-approved national security contracting mechanisms, model partnership agreements, and expedited review procedures for purposes of entering into transactions under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20922C4FBB6048FFAE14886898D85A2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>2022 through 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>2027 through 2031</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260629" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 29, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


