<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H34660C192678441FB18B418214C6C49B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6186 IH: No Antisemitism in Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6186</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require public elementary schools, public secondary schools, and institutions of higher education to treat discrimination motivated by antisemitism in an identical manner to how such school or institution treats discrimination motivated by race, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C5D1BEE780540E28E76064C46AA9D9B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBC6610E75384489F8117789C0FB678B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Antisemitism in Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCDCAC86260554FDE86B40D6CCF52C45D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Discrimination motivated by antisemitism</header> <subsection id="H96117B7B34DE4B81963F24F2F01F9175"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receiving Federal funds, any public elementary school, public secondary school, or institution of higher education that receives Federal funds shall be required to treat discrimination by students or employees, and discrimination resulting from the institutional policies of such school or institution, that is motivated by antisemitism in an identical manner to how such school or institution treats discrimination motivated by race.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7524CE56E66B4BFD8ECA709DFD86C4C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed as—</text> <paragraph id="H6465F53FBC3D448D8F69ADD1224EF6D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>diminishing or infringing upon any right protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7748C517FB9477682B26E6FFC306674"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preempting State antidiscrimination laws. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9A1EF1AA713342DE9705DE27E7B4F29E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H21752CBEDE7E4ECDBBEE4D5D0C5A3E72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antisemitism</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD6F5AEB174704C56BC22A60C0D1A13CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>antisemitism</term> means a certain perception of Jews, which may be expressed as hatred towards Jews. Rhetorical and physical manifestations of antisemitism are directed towards Jewish or non-Jewish individuals or their property or towards Jewish community institutions and religious facilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE7EFA084F7A474FB5CA9216407B2A72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Examples</header><text>The term <term>antisemitism</term> includes the following examples of behavior:</text> 
<clause id="H83D297E2B74C49CDB4E6C0514DEC979A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Calling for, aiding, or justifying the killing or harming of Jews, often in the name of a radical ideology or an extremist view of religion.</text></clause> <clause id="HD022F7BB73B0489BBA3B6E361A7A66F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Making mendacious, dehumanizing, demonizing, or stereotypical allegations about Jews as such or the power of Jews as a collective, especially, but not exclusively, allegations regarding the myth about a world Jewish conspiracy or of Jews controlling the media, economy, government or other societal institutions.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCF79DAB716F04DC39E8274610FBA6AAF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accusing Jews as a people of being responsible for real or imagined wrongdoing committed by a Jewish person or group, Israel, or for acts committed by a non-Jewish individual.</text></clause> <clause id="HDCDA43B210914AE6BC976BA28B1EEC8F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accusing Jews as a people or Israel of inventing or exaggerating the Holocaust.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3BDC615541794AF68958717238751113"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Accusing Jewish citizens of being more loyal to Israel, or the alleged priorities of Jews worldwide, than to the interests of their country of citizenship.</text></clause> <clause id="H5D1FD37512FA4BF3A917EED7BEC3F11F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Demonizing Israel by using the symbols and images associated with classic antisemitism to characterize Israel or Israelis, drawing comparisons of contemporary Israeli policy to that of the Nazis, or blaming Israel for all interreligious or political tensions.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E2ABC1F7E784A0E96949CE10A675748"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applying a double standard to Israel by requiring behavior of Israel that is not expected or demanded of any other democratic country, or focusing peace or human rights investigations only on Israel.</text></clause> <clause id="HBA5C60EB5F144DA79A8E2E534237AFDA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Delegitimizing Israel by denying the Jewish people their right to self-determination and denying Israel the right to exist.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A3743EC1BD04833AB51448F6EAEA109"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>antisemitism</term> does not include criticism of Israel that is similar to criticism towards any other country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE6E67A5935E4D21B4A49AA53DACDB16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA Terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>institution of higher education</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


