<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC783F23CC3354DB8AA207AAB20D81E9C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6801 IH: American Citizenship Healthcare Integrity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6801</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require hospitals to ask the citizenship status of patients as a condition of participation in the Medicare program and to require reports on the cost of furnishing hospital services to noncitizens.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F781C88F6644499B092B3F18A293C1B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDF113B74627E402C9F6F094F1D4A0947" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Citizenship Healthcare Integrity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H07C5DD2319C14363B015C66F1883AEF9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring hospitals to ask the citizenship status of patients as a condition of participation in Medicare</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1866 of the Social Security Act is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF05697AD19B749469014AFA8A554ED48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H23F995EC396F4618BE592343179AEAD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (X), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1FE986CF02EA4BD6937FE4AD774010A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD2489A23A49479BB8AAE21C50095AEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAA826EDBBB59420DA0A68570E94AAFFC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H55828D95D00743DBA772E34F0AEFEE00" indent="up1"><enum>(Z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, in the case of a hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital—</text> <clause id="H2049E637B21B4AE3AB5C519A7F329C68"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each intake form (or its equivalent) provided in connection with items or services furnished by such hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital to an individual, to ask on such form whether such individual is a citizen or national of the United States; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC85E7D7CE5264874998227A85ADF11A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, and annually thereafter, to submit to the Secretary a report including, with respect to the previous year—</text> <subclause id="HF6123722C6D5480E9B67A5F91250AFAC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals who are not citizens or nationals of the United States to whom items or services were furnished by such hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H467EE3C3E4E342EAB2440D5B668A4485"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the dollar amount of any uncompensated care furnished by such hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital to such individuals.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC55BAE75F4FA4551A3FAD24ECCC26501"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE42BFC1B08BA4616A121FC8749119F5B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H74EB44480D1B4B98B1A1BE214AF3F28F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Report on cost of hospital services furnished to noncitizens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall make publicly available a report on, with respect to the previous year—</text> <paragraph id="HB02FACD574274ADDAECA4AA2FAC09434"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the dollar amount of any uncompensated care furnished by hospitals, critical access hospitals, and rural emergency hospitals to individuals who are not citizens or nationals of the United States, as determined based on the findings of reports submitted pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(Z)(ii); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADB952393D754473A8488D668E661420"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of Federal expenditures under this title and title XIX that would not have been made in the absence of such uncompensated care, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

