<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL26084-0JC-HC-KLN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3751 IS: Prescription Drug Supply Chain Pricing Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3751</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study and submit a report on price-related compensation and payment structures in the prescription drug supply chain.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Drug Supply Chain Pricing Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9c3ca83d149b4555b59224b630fccb6f"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study and report on price-related compensation and payment structures in the prescription drug supply chain</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1860D–42 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-152">42 U.S.C. 1395w–152</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD66B9D74D39446AF9188020165FD9F0B"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dff6a0ba87d4890b2be65ba5ba58d29"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO study and report on price-Related compensation and payment structures in the prescription drug supply chain</header><paragraph id="idffeb71fa36ac4789b5253c5740a1e2df"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study on the use of compensation and payment structures related to a prescription drug’s price within the retail prescription drug supply chain. Such study shall include an overview of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id33b2cb292e96474b9564308fc1711805"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The type, magnitude, other features (such as the pricing benchmarks used), and prevalence of compensation and payment structures related to a prescription drug’s price, such as calculating fee amounts as a percentage of a prescription drug’s price, between intermediaries in the prescription drug supply chain, including—</text><clause id="id0aca858c4ab14098aef4d134df78d149"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pharmacy benefit managers;</text></clause><clause id="id38ff49a263114e00bb4fc3354f2a9827"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>part D plan sponsors;</text></clause><clause id="id9625fd4fba694111afc2a70d7fd9e0b0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>drug wholesalers;</text></clause><clause id="id9b6adf035b9849bda469e99ec06cc395"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>pharmacies;</text></clause><clause id="idbc1e636ba1c44d21a5aa1d6ed3387b1d"><enum>(v)</enum><text>manufacturers;</text></clause><clause id="id5a309f8619b34c71a09c1bcdcd6b10e3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>pharmacy services administrative organizations;</text></clause><clause id="id6e11119302d9401abf4396a7930e4772"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>brokers, auditors, consultants, and other entities that advise part D plan sponsors about pharmacy benefits or review part D plan sponsor contracts with pharmacy benefit managers; and</text></clause><clause id="idb442b0d6ec0143edb6122dd88bd84370"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>other service providers that contract with any of the entities described in clauses (i) through (vii), including rebate aggregators (or other entities that negotiate or process price concessions on behalf of pharmacy benefit managers or plan sponsors).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc30438d65bfc4cae9ae467f0cf3438fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The primary business models and compensation structures for each category of intermediary described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45f8dea35c2543d783cdd2d5156c9b70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Variation in price-related compensation structures between affiliated entities (such as entities with common ownership, either full or partial, and subsidiary relationships) and unaffiliated entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c488fb0c8d24cc1a567d4303807c1bd"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Potential conflicts of interest among contracting entities related to the use of prescription drug price-related compensation structures, such as the potential for fees or other payments set as a percentage of a prescription drug’s price to advantage the formulary selection, distribution, or purchasing of prescription drugs with higher prices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id276648da580c463e8eb92bc062ffb267"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Patterns and trends in price-based compensation structures over time and between different market segments, such as under this part and the Medicaid program under title XIX.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9580f23849cf4aca8aa783d9c9202643"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The factors driving the consideration and use of price-related compensation structures in the prescription drug supply chain.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id238665869fc44ca787c39d7fe22cd763"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Other issues determined to be relevant and appropriate by the Comptroller General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id579aa3892b7f4a9aa4ab6fb2a056268a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

