<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H081360B2831E42FD9D9EA9962F593ADD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9486 IH: Health Data Access, Transparency, and Affordability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9486</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to increase transparency of group health plan data, prevent discrimination, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H67E2C9DF07854A92AC0AD91C6538E289" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H022F7D66354B4B93A85432B8CCCC4B8C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Data Access, Transparency, and Affordability Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>Health DATA Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAB6D3104C7774A5F9F8946666219B1F3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing transparency of group health plan data</header> <subsection id="H2D7E464671C94518BE3EEB2F3BDD6A38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Group health plan audit rights</header> <paragraph id="H8C418D6177B944ADBEDFAF66DB52DE9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 408(b)(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HCA13F3EF41E848BB9E37C0AD8ED91912" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H48774E63D18C4C5E8DEE026EF4EE9132"><enum>(D)</enum><text>No contract or arrangement for services, and no extension or renewal of such a contract or arrangement, between a group health plan (as defined in section 733(a)) and any other entity, including a health care provider (including a health care facility), network or association of providers, service provider offering access to a network of providers, third-party administrator, or entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, is reasonable within the meaning of this paragraph unless such contract or arrangement—</text> <clause id="HCDD11874BF8B4D8791B4C625F603448D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allows the group health plan to audit all de-identified claims and encounter information or data described in section 724(a)(1)(B), provided that such information or data has been deidentified in accordance with section 164.514 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to—</text> 
<subclause id="H45841EE60F01472B8FE1D055B90A100B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensure that such entity complies with the terms of the plan, the terms of the contract or arrangement for services, and the requirements of this title; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF853D7ABBD454E6BA28DE4F85FD3A83C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determine the reasonableness of compensation received by such entity; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H105C577A2A5345E898EDBFD8D6F71C69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not—</text> <subclause id="H0BD05411BFBA4F1BBC6EBB8596502295"><enum>(I)</enum><text>unreasonably limit the number of audits permitted during a given period of time;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE2DBADB1F25545D7ABE98349B46019F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>limit the number of de-identified claims and encounter information or data that the group health plan may access during an audit;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBF9850CC1F024FB19816F20151EAD92B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>limit the disclosure of pricing terms for value-based payment arrangements or capitated payment arrangements, including—</text> 
<item id="H7A74BF3F85DF4D538D7717F56B2BEF32"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>payment calculations and formulas;</text></item> <item id="H78BF4E8CCE6A4585A5B64A2C42891E5E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>quality measures;</text></item> 
<item id="H2B11D675A66B45ECAD242700A036964F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>contract terms;</text></item> <item id="H4BE9E03C1EE4409DBBB75F4248BF9915"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>payment amounts;</text></item> 
<item id="H4EDC3F8C09A7467993440A6C38B11568"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>measurement periods for all incentives; and</text></item> <item id="HD546C35B4C9B4DD9ADD907F9EBB920DF"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>other payment methodologies used by an entity, including a health care provider (including a health care facility), network or association of providers, service provider offering access to a network of providers, third-party administrator, or entity providing pharmacy benefit management services;</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H68F212960E194E71A71A837BDF4195E4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>limit the disclosure of overpayments and overpayment recovery terms;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H203D692C4C4A4DFA9CAC8458BFC35EE5"><enum>(V)</enum><text>limit the right of the group health plan to select an auditor;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFF232BEF385C4CC0A3652136DE4C297D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>otherwise limit or unduly delay by greater than 60 calendar days after the date of request the group health plan from auditing any such de-identified claims and encounter information or data; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCAEC2B5EFF044C61A74625630D5DA4FF"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>permit the entity to charge a fee beyond the reasonable direct costs to provide the required information and otherwise comply and assist with an audit request.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBC508391D6B45289667311084A39FFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header> 
<subparagraph id="H531FD11378424D6EA23D8D993F15F7C4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 408(b)(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H70A67E0F6B80489991FBDAEEFFAEB606" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HF7AB164D70904C959B43639A5ECC4B66"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Privacy requirements</header> <clause id="HADDA2723004248D7A315A81EF3010D2E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H95A8AA59D2B143C79340EF9A0F5734EC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide data or information under subparagraph (D) in a manner consistent with—</text> <item id="H0B2CBC332291412AAC0FD9230BEC1C21"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the privacy regulations promulgated under section 13402(a) of the Health Information Technology for Clinical Health Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17932">42 U.S.C. 17932(a)</external-xref>); and</text></item> 
<item id="H607FEF1ACED64635B66075604FB44F86"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the privacy regulations promulgated under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 in part 160 and subparts A and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></item> </subclause> <subclause id="H689FB80FA0AE49ECAE3F0B57D9C6D7C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent such data or information constitutes protected health information, restrict the use and disclosure of such information for purposes of such privacy regulations.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H4D7D53B0425B4A8D9B5ACEB3DB2C6F08"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>A group health plan shall comply with section 164.504(f) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), and a plan sponsor shall act in accordance with the terms of the agreement described in such section.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HA56898E848B3482F8E0263C61EA7D688"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H6F85AC5A79E349EA911F7A047B722C9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 502 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H30C7FC962DC34A49993963B686C06079" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HE455B7263EF043C786A98F0F746E7193"><enum>(14)</enum><text>In the case of an agreement between a group health plan and a health care provider (including a health care facility), network or association of providers, service provider offering access to a network of providers, third-party administrator, entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, or other service provider that violates the provisions of section 724, the Secretary may assess a civil penalty against such provider, network or association of providers, service provider offering access to a network of providers, third-party administrator, entity providing pharmacy benefit management services, or other service provider in the amount of $10,000 for each day during which such violation continues. Such penalty shall be in addition to other penalties as may be prescribed by law.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H662D7201890C45A9B45CB9AA165CC5B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty collection</header><text>Paragraph (6) of section 502(a) of such Act, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H118656DAECB54F91B45315E4BD14BD2A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H9C07126C59A7425C96314E5F6D3ABE9C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the Secretary to collect any civil penalty that the Secretary has imposed or assessed pursuant to this title;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD59E72CE1F20469687A4469D0A8DBFB0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Improving collection of gag clause attestations</header> <paragraph id="H76F278764E304573B7DC1B9DA78E5AAE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 506 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1136">29 U.S.C. 1136</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBEAC3BEAC3254FC89D84B4A2D94F951E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HB8A9816D98AB4899AE0C79841EADF777" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Attestations relating to group health plan data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall collect the attestations required to be submitted under section 724(a)(3). The Secretary shall ensure that any service provider submitting such an attestation on behalf of a group health plan does not have any conflicts of interest with regard to such attestation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11418FB0AB4B42249CAA906B60F4A870" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 506(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1136">29 U.S.C. 1136(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>In order</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsection (d), in order</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4E7AE9E6B22E425398DA537D95994451"><enum>3.</enum><header>Fiduciary duty with respect to plan data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3(21)(A)(iii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(21)(A)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>such plan.</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>such plan, including any authority over the use, management, disposition, or safeguarding of data generated, used, or maintained by the plan or a service provider to the plan in connection with the administration of benefits or management of plan assets.</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H22C2EBA7A62A499A9959315E065E48FE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preventing discrimination based on plan data</header> <subsection id="H69446AF30A7E41739B53D6BC67C5D724"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part 5 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1131">29 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA2657182D3834B0C8A8534C07110D35C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HAD6791979BA6442AB17FCD42C0E58F5F"><enum>524.</enum><header>Preventing discrimination based on plan data</header> 
<subsection id="H9AF98420C4D440B1860B6BB1A934F68E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for a person specified in subsection (c) to discharge, fine, suspend, expel, discipline, or discriminate against, including by failing to meet the requirements of subsection (a) or (b) of section 702 (related to discrimination in eligibility and premiums for participation in group health plans), a participant or beneficiary on the basis of information or data described in section 724.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFFA263F0176147CAA9A80A5D0852BD18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="HB6D17E8EFC9343E283BD9922097DF094"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 502 shall be applicable in the enforcement of this section, except that in any action brought under subsection (a)(1)(B) of such section in relation to data or information described in section 724, a participant or beneficiary may not be required to exhaust administrative remedies prior to bringing such action.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27541121D04542449A57327CC34AA589"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equitable relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying section 502 for the purposes of this section, the term <term>equitable relief</term> shall include any relief necessary to restore a participant or beneficiary to the position they would have occupied but for a violation of subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H683D94763D0C497ABE4C1BB0B7CB84AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civil monetary penalty</header> <subparagraph id="HB16716125AC74FBDB1B80C4026F9C216"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a violation of subsection (a) by a person, the Secretary may assess a civil monetary penalty against such person.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2DC271057B543229DC60195141EC4B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of the civil monetary penalty imposed by subparagraph (A) shall be $100 for each day in the noncompliance period with respect to each participant or beneficiary to whom such violation of subsection (a) relates.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B57A6B36190409B8A7B4094DC9DE17E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Noncompliance period</header><text>For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>noncompliance period</term> means, with respect to any violation of subsection (a), the period—</text> 
<clause id="HCFBC9ACC152745348FC072555DEB5CD4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>beginning on the date such violation occurs; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA4BA68D8F6814224A90C9248E67A1814"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ending on the date such violation is corrected.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7EF768AD596465F8B633E03DFE1EF79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specified person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person specified in this subsection is any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5199E98F83474B779BF530BC74539B8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An employer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDB139E89822484FA3F07DC6EA5DA01F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A plan sponsor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21F97BFD6B3741E183707639E3C03860"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A plan administrator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H558B39D35F4D46DD98325B9DE2CD85AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan fiduciary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H52CF5EA5486C4EFB908AD17E47D9127E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to limit the application of any Federal or State privacy or civil rights law, including the HIPAA privacy regulations, the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/233">Public Law 110–233</external-xref>) (including the amendments made by such Act), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>), title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>), and title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF02441546AD94EA3891B48B087FE3EF8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 523 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE58A54FF381D46ECB33D80AF53171934" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 524. Preventing discrimination based on plan data.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

