<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F5B5F5AF2414FA48450B65243FAF4D2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6502 IH: College Financial Aid Clarity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6502</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to develop requirements for institutions of higher education on formatting financial aid offer forms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCE2329DDF939489E8CE82FE8E49A39D8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H439ADE97EC764CBBBA7893EBC36F79D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>College Financial Aid Clarity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA4E50536F3164D928D6723F49556D814"><enum>2.</enum><header>Financial aid offers</header> <subsection id="H8EE381715E424E16A558805442AD938F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H27368A4B9E4E41A99D5C5CF13F8EF4F1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HFD11453219ED4E8389F74FAE80BF5BE7"><enum>124.</enum><header>Financial aid offers</header> 
<subsection id="H4837B912A157415BAB8EF545A08E8906"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Institutional requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HCD5E3FA2E0B74111922ADDB103A76CC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on July 1, 2029, an institution of higher education that receives Federal financial assistance under this Act—</text> <subparagraph id="H69DC63098D0F4218BAFB2EDF1C61A3D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text> 
<clause id="H5F811A5DCE024A9F8CEF03B66673AD95"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for all financial aid offers (including paper, or mobile-optimized or other electronic offers), include the information (including terminology) listed in subsection (c), and meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d), in compliance with the requirements published pursuant to subsection (b)(2); </text></clause> <clause id="H7B29BF89004347BBBCF03EA282A33CE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the supplemental content and disclosures described in paragraph (2); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC8216C744DBB480BB9F59068ABC6C494"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for all communications from the institution related to financial aid offers (including the supplemental content and disclosures described in paragraph (2)), use the terminology referenced in subsection (c) in a consistent manner; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE1E6C182AFE4718B35A7FEE3AA5A064"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an electronic financial aid offer that includes a requirement that a student confirm receipt of such offer, may not consider such confirmation an acceptance or rejection of such offer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82F1A8E24B764D42988FED45031654AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplemental content and disclosures</header><text>Each institution of higher education described in paragraph (1) shall provide, in supplemental documents or through easily accessible weblinks to the institution’s portal or a website, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H532B3816E6D24F6F9534391CD0A574D2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The renewability requirements and conditions under which the student can expect to receive similar amounts of financial aid that is included in the student’s financial aid offer for each award year the student is enrolled at the institution.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE3B44DECC2B442583E2DEFDAD74A711" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether the financial aid offer may change if aid from outside sources is applied after the student receives the initial financial aid offer, and, if applicable, how that financial aid offer will change.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB1370B37B0054906B724E7EDE45ECADB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If loans made under part D of title IV or other education loans offered through Federal programs are included, a disclosure that the interest rates and fees on such loans are set annually and affect total cost over time, a link to any website that includes current information on interest rates and fees, and a disclosure that such loans have to be repaid and the student can borrow an amount less than the offered loan amount.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76DDAD4CE00143F7A3F46BBD9F764A4B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A link to the College Financing Plan website of the Department (or the successor website).</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9B716FD6BD44BEFAB4DE3C8FDE57035" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Omission of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education may omit information listed in subsection (c) or paragraph (2) of this subsection from a financial aid offer or supplemental document provided to a student, respectively, if the information—<italic></italic></text> 
<subparagraph id="H3DC6ACB2F800479C8E59569F06CBB097" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relates to aid—</text> <clause id="HD325CC8967F2458EA54BC03BA69D018B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for which the student is ineligible; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1D7D9D628B1C4F8385B2D5F289464E19" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is provided through a program with which the institution does not participate; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D0934D42D0A4645819AAB4F71B66655"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is otherwise inapplicable to the student.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA85C346E097747608E4A326F0D10D946"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretarial requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HA9229013A3734BCFBD0AD966252D06C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements for institutions of higher education</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8F9A46AC305645A5880636F1297DCE09"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consumer testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H58FE2F92078F47748A7D7F06674A5323"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>College Financial Aid Clarity Act of 2025</short-title>, establish a process for consumer testing, with the representatives described in subparagraph (B), requirements for institutions of higher education on formatting financial aid offers to include the information (including terminology) listed in subsection (c), and to meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d), in a manner that is simple and understandable for students and the students’ families; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H07B43624168B429C9E68F20B4F9FB880"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 8 months after the process for consumer testing is established pursuant to clause (i), conduct and conclude such consumer testing.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08C254B1B954469EBB06E35E914546CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The representatives described in this subparagraph are representatives of students (including low-income students, first generation college students, adult students, veterans, servicemembers, and prospective students), students’ families (including low-income families, families with first generation college students, and families with prospective students), institutions of higher education, secondary school and postsecondary counselors, nonprofit organizations (including scholarship-granting organizations), private lenders, and States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77265105C57C4326AE1B62BA9E12EB1A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonapplication of paperwork reduction act</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the consumer testing process under this subsection. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14D23EDB955046F1B8B8710DE7E9A638"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication and notice</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2028, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0133919C3C10491D8A6DBD6F8312967F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish the requirements developed pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) on a publicly available website; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B6447636F23433D99713E0177F44EF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify each institution of higher education that receives Federal financial assistance under this Act of such best practices and the requirements of subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H65707C9385F44217A549E7DAC8111FE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>To comply with subsection (a), an institution of higher education shall include the following information in any financial aid offer that is made by the institution: </text> <paragraph id="H7F6719ED861B4C04ACD816E04C21A819"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information for the award year covered by the offer</header> <subparagraph id="H63B6EAA40B01435196B92CCFC30E2367" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Award year information</header><text>The award year covered by the financial aid offer, and an explanation that the amount of financial aid offered may differ—</text> 
<clause id="H7D78BE752FBA40EE82436B62172CDA37" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for academic periods not covered by the financial aid offer, such as a summer term or future award year; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD7EC805610144C98BE071E1AD02F6BE8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by program of study.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D9C9617BD9A4D1EB78F148F3DE73258"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual cost information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the student’s estimated cost of attendance for the award year covered by the financial aid offer, including the following:</text> <clause id="HD1732FFB497145ACA1B0B546A84FB0C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The required costs for such award year, including the academic workload used to determined such required costs.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H176836771A004FC18D1D841E20746DD5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The cost of attendance for such award year.</text></clause> <clause id="H0032B0627F9348C283D9899B57B668B0" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An indication, as applicable, about whether any of the items used to calculate the required costs included in clause (i) which are subject to change are—</text> 
<subclause id="HF5E44B99220B453680FA548FD03E7A95" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>estimated based on the previous year; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4399AA29BF39493AA094543040871D90" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>set for the award year covered by the financial aid offer.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F3567D38DD94B5298FC50499B8739DA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Annual Grants and scholarships</header><text>The amount of grant and scholarship aid for the award year covered by the financial aid offer.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F1FAD14E5AE47EE96FD80BBBDED9738"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Annual net price of attendance</header> <clause id="HCDDF971475134982A4B8A6D3F6CF3F7F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual net price of attendance</header><text>The annual net price of attendance for the award year covered by the financial aid offer.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H07CCDC5E951B458092CEDFF1391AA4D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>A disclosure that the total and annual net price of attendance of the student includes costs that are not required costs and is an estimate.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE2AE49904C244EB84E570AA2AB41FD8" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on each loan for which the student is eligible for the award year covered by the offer (including any loan disbursed by the institution, and any other loan (such as a Federal, State, or private loan)), including—</text> 
<clause id="HD107DA641064432ABA0B17D57DB65A8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total amount of each type of loan offered to the student; </text></clause> <clause id="H5AA8A6077D054FFB8631CD44F71467BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each loan, any applicable interest rate, including any capitalization of interest on the loan, and fees (including origination fees and additional costs);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9B32BEE99AB34AF9921BE4ED62409D0B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, information on any loan repayment plan offered by the institution; and</text></clause> <clause id="H357289922A9845619AD43DD09FDCD88F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a disclosure that the interest rates and fees on such loans can affect total cost over time, and a disclosure that such loans have to be repaid and the student can borrow an amount less than the recommended loan amount.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFAA5EEE784F43D9B2A1C2918555F9A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants and scholarships for the program length</header><text>The amount of grant and scholarship aid for the program length of the student’s program of study.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA52B218A92D043B68274743F17CE8030"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Student employment</header><text>Information on work-study employment opportunities (including work-study programs under part C of title IV, institutional work-study programs, or State work-study programs), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2F27DDCCE9694962901B2C164938ECBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maximum annual amount the student may earn through such an employment opportunity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED592BD2766F49B98ADCCB0781230BCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a disclosure that any amounts received pursuant to such an employment opportunity may be—</text> 
<clause id="H8F24B8105F0548EAAAC45C323D8EB041"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to the availability of qualified employment opportunities upon enrollment; and</text></clause> <clause id="H97CBD0BFD8C841BFBFB18FD8E24D8CC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disbursed over time as earned by the student.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2CF5986DE824057937C99D9BF25315A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Net price calculator</header><text>A link to the universal net price calculator website described in section 132(c)(4).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4BA63F21AF5479E81623278C7CD46DE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cost information for the most recent award year</header> <subparagraph id="H21EB0E5917854F5BAA693F16B7DA788F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Average annual net price required for completion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Average annual net price required for completion for the most recent award year for the program of study.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B57795D9AEB4C02B7FF5879AB545EB2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Total average net price required for completion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average total net price required for completion based on the time to credential for the program of study (as determined based on the most recent award year). </text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDE4A7B6D2CA4227BCE445F8D5D40E9B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Average annual price of attendance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Average annual price of attendance for the most recent award year for the program of study.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA25E6702666E43099695AEED92B3D9C4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Total average annual net price of attendance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average annual net price of attendance based on the time to credential for the program of study (as determined based on the most recent award year)</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8730E5F014940C3A098F075ED5F63C9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A disclosure that the information provided in this paragraph is based on required costs and amounts of grant and scholarship aid for the most recent award year, and such information may not be applicable to the student receiving the financial aid offer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AD60C4C081B4EA0A8A54E44C1A6ED9D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Process for accepting, adjusting, or declining aid and next steps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text> <subparagraph id="H1A0C626FDDD2423885852A12065253C9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>The deadlines and a summary of the process (including the next steps) for—</text> 
<clause id="H3B2641A139A5465E8C4984B0B947D50D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accepting the financial aid offered;</text></clause> <clause id="HEB7C8E7427C24092B22404DFF4D7B60F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjusting the amount of aid offered; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H044324C6ABC04C1388338469426C2209" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>declining the aid offered.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44FEB51B6B9A4042B2B6A277737791E7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>Information on when and how costs described in paragraph (1)(A) must be paid. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA5C91601756A41AFBAB73B7C0A3B183F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>A disclosure that verification of information provided on the Free Application for Federal Student Aid may require the student to submit further documentation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF81431901973403C98B0EB10D44A4246" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Financial aid information</header><text>Information about where a student or the student’s family can seek additional information regarding the financial aid offered, including contact information for the institution’s financial aid office and the Department of Education’s website on financial aid.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H86E6E1223C56457F9D4B790285BD7337" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>College costs and student outcome information</header><text>Information about where a student or a student’s family can seek additional information on college costs and student outcomes, including a link to the Department of Education’s College Scorecard website (or successor website) and how to use such website to compare information from institutions of higher education regarding such costs and outcomes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HBA93E2D8CDAA4B4F8D0F8A666B20385E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Format requirements</header> <paragraph id="H27059FAB82794DE1BC737E93E1635924"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To comply with subsection (a), any financial aid offer made by an institution of higher education shall be titled <quote>Financial Aid Offer</quote>, use plain language wherever possible, and format the information listed in subsection (c) in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27A568E3E91F49D2814FD35318F4CE30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Format of required information</header><text>The information listed in subsection (c) shall be formatted in a financial aid offer made by an institution of higher education as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="HC18A89C3CBB9466F82548C8E753DD94C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The information required in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of subsection (c)(1) is listed in such order, under separate headings, and in the same font.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H599CBF17E7C74A5AB9CDF29CB6939073"><enum>(B)</enum><text>There is a clear distinction between the required costs and any other costs of attendance included in such financial aid offer.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77BB4F1CD8BA4347919753A814DDCDD4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a clear distinction between the aid offered under subparagraphs (C) and (E) of subsection (c)(1), including—</text> 
<clause id="H877FA76D1DF746F8A4117F28894890B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by not combining the different types of aid described in such paragraphs; and</text></clause> <clause id="H13079E1A07244C9DA5B896F14DDF53B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in such subparagraph (E)—</text> 
<subclause id="HCD606C7FA99643AC95D327E9F3298F78"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by using the word <quote>loan</quote> to clearly describe the recommended loan amounts; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H545F9F81D0814973BF31A0E71CA56A94"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by clearly distinguishing between subsidized and unsubsidized loans.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E00EB0FBA44447090639F7AE63CA558" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terminology referenced in subsection (c) is used in a consistent manner.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC95DF76B273A4749B0ECDD1D4E0A70FE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such information is listed—</text> 
<clause id="H0260110CF465439C93D3AE00433CA58E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a manner that ensures none of the information is inappropriately omitted or deemphasized; and</text></clause> <clause id="H16C311C9D8374C30A3ECE6B90458E3EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a consistent format for all financial aid offers made by such institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H12E64790BB23413290F2F2202B2858A2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H9C55EDD22FAC4A6E88ACB219D4B1D30A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required costs</header><text>The term <term>required costs</term> means the sum of all the items listed in section 472(a) that are required by an institution of higher education for a program of study for the program length of a program of study, for the time to credential for a student, or for an award year of a program of study, as applicable, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB1FDFDD8B98B4DC5AC963064DC0AF54B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the tuition and fees normally assessed a student enrolled in such program of study carrying the same academic workload, as determined by the institution; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F78962532914E4AAF0EEC4DFDE3AE3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which the institution requires a student to reside in institutionally owned or operated housing or to use institutionally owned or operated food services, the applicable standard allowance for such housing or food services determined by the institution in accordance with section 472(a)(5).</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E156967E0CE4B26BCAC1815D6D45FB9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of grant and scholarship aid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>amount of grant and scholarship aid</term> means the sum of all of the grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for the program length of a program of study, for the time to credential for a student, or for an award year of a program of study, as applicable, that a student does not have to repay, including need-based, merit-based, or athletic-based, or another type of grant and scholarship aid, that is—</text> <subparagraph id="HC7327F3CFCAB447AB5EAA0B576D680BF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offered under title IV;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDD03AACADC74202B695C3396613825C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offered through other Federal programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4A55053F81D40D482E9292D3F93FAF8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offered by the institution;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31AF0ED87A6245F982CD8738D765E607" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>offered by a State; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB9C3CA64DA546558D161D602EA4652F" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>offered by any other source.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC956B00884844180A11C994060CBA118" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Net price required for completion</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD09A5796CC8C488586BAE85890FB36E2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Net price determinations</header> 
<clause id="H1CD54CBE63274F7A8FA2DAFBFAECFE91"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Total net price required for completion</header><text>The term <term>total net price required for completion</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study—</text> <subclause id="H0A6D6C36B6AC4014BD504A4D1592814B" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the required costs charged to such student for the program of study for the time to credential; minus </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3B2AD22E229C47A68747D9511A1DDFFB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for such program for the time to credential.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE43F862336B74478B73D936D8703AD77"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Annual net price required for completion</header><text>The term <term>annual net price required for completion</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study—</text> 
<subclause id="HC0B41E311C9B40E0AE0CE1C3DC71C4FA" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the required costs charged to such student for the program of study for an award year; minus </text></subclause> <subclause id="HB23F4F5963AF4C9B90D5C88FC928BD81" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for such program for such award year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39153D91D7094EA396E19148164AA119" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Net price required for completion</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFC39D12CE7D5431584A460C26A458849" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Net price determinations</header> 
<clause id="HCF905EA35520450DBC67FB13ECD29BE8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Total net price required for completion</header><text>The term <term>total net price required for completion</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study—</text> <subclause id="H304C555FDDE24BE8BE74B4101EFF05EA" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the required costs charged to such student for the program of study for the time to credential; minus </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H15CE579F0F594ED090EABC64A1A16D94" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for such program for the time to credential.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H80B1CE3E5F1F49E3A3075E7557F8A700"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Annual net price required for completion</header><text>The term <term>annual net price required for completion</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study—</text> 
<subclause id="HF5A33BE729C940DC8A9125360691AE46" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the required costs charged to such student for the program of study for an award year; minus </text></subclause> <subclause id="HBEE3C73ED0004AC48F47875805FF8297" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for such program for such award year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B6E310B7CF24E0B807224CA28C0EF98"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Net price of attendance</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6981F2D8119C4DBAAD9F16A1FD739ED1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Total net price of attendance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>total net price of attendance</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study, the sum of—</text> <clause id="H340E2862794F4ACAAFAE16E174A8E782" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total net price required for completion; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE43E0A8BAEF04610B1EB3A6A9CAD7BFC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sum, for the program length of the program of study, of all the costs listed in section 472(a) that are not required costs.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C4177728689496FBB1015F5C51C90FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual net price of attendance</header><text>The term <term>annual net price of attendance</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study, the net price of attendance for a specific year of the program of study, determined by disaggregating the total net price of attendance for the student by each year of expected enrollment for the program length of the program of study.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86C672A97EDA4B62B9666A97CF67E340"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program of study</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD499AACEF737432BA9B5BBA4AD645A28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>program of study</term>—</text> <clause id="H54937D75DB9B4FADB8166517CCC6C34B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means an eligible program at an institution of higher education that is classified by a combination of—</text> 
<subclause id="H52DD8B5646D7467A9DD4CED678DCF5E1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>one or more CIP codes; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE9F4D5F0F92E47D787C7D1621E695B80"><enum>(II)</enum><text>one credential level, determined by the credential awarded upon completion of the program; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H3129AA6A90394808854A1F75595729A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include a program of study abroad.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB225A8F42F3F4F4EAAE5FFF5DC174482"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cip code</header><text>The term <term>CIP code</term> means the six-digit taxonomic identification code assigned by an institution of higher education to a specific program of study at the institution, determined by the institution of higher education in accordance with the Classification of Instructional Programs published by the National Center for Education Statistics.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19FF19ADE70049379D7ED33D6E856EE4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Credential level</header> 
<clause id="HE2FA40E559304940BBE491621C34FF80"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>credential level</term> means the level of the degree or other credential awarded by an institution of higher education to students who complete a program of study of the institution. Each degree or other credential awarded by an institution shall be categorized by the institution as either undergraduate credential level or graduate credential level.</text></clause> <clause id="H799E8B621CEB446FAFEA2A691BFAC37B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Undergraduate credential</header><text>When used with respect to a credential or credential level, the term <term>undergraduate credential</term> includes credentials such as an undergraduate certificate, an associate degree, a bachelor’s degree, and a post-baccalaureate certificate (including the coursework specified in paragraphs (3)(B) and (4)(B) of section 484(b)).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6918DC326C2A4EE8B7C24A3835A6F25E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Graduate credential</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When used with respect to a credential or credential level, the term <term>graduate credential</term> includes credentials such as a master’s degree, a doctoral degree, a professional degree (as defined under section 668.2 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations), and a postgraduate certificate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H076ED8A6A42C4E6293156B90298505F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program length</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program length</term> means the minimum amount of time in weeks, months, or years that is specified in the catalog, marketing materials, or other official publications of an institution of higher education for a full-time student to complete the requirements to obtain the degree or credential awarded for a specific program of study.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C1127B3391C46EB8F01B9D00C6DD60D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Time to credential</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term ‘time to credential’ means, with respect to a student, the actual amount of time in weeks, months, or years it takes the student to complete the requirements to obtain the degree or credential awarded for a specific program of study.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A1714EFB53F4B5ABD5BDC04D81764F8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Cost of attendance</header><text>The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given such term in section 472. </text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBAA8C809883C491A8439304BC95FD859" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H385C7C16DA4F4B8BB405F9BC02A88FA9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H8BCE4AC3F89D41A0B3065BE4581635E7" commented="no"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will comply with the requirements of section 124(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7AE08EF2F46846BF896E991D917A4DE6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost of attendance of a program of study</header> 
<legis-comment display="no">DDRamey: This amendment is also included in net price.</legis-comment> 
<paragraph id="H611F053AD33E4606BCB76A1356979870"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of cost of attendance of a program of study</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5224D43E657C41B4AD8CA40DD5B9E76F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 472(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="HF92C67393AEA48259000AEF81C98E9C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>carrying the same academic workload</quote> and inserting <quote>enrolled in the same program of study and carrying the same academic workload</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD69818879CEA43609B450E832FCABDB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>same course of study</quote> and inserting <quote>same program of study</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5D8BE4AC53B44ED483AA17A1ECF84E3A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking <quote>program</quote> and inserting <quote>program of study</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E1E1CEB74EE445587AC09B62374A18A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Section 472(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H985B461B20C343D08F2B964D76915347"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>of each program of study at the institution</quote> after <quote>cost of attendance</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H010E3273796D469DAD22A17F123D2FA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of the institution</quote> and inserting <quote>of such programs of study at the institution</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

