<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF18053DC1A848958F3E7F078361B239" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9646 IH: Quantum-Enhanced Critical Minerals Mapping Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9646</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a quantum-enhanced critical minerals survey, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCF5CBF86778C46C1B2BDA605852F49EC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H067B0747ABC24851B93DBDF549E64374" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quantum-Enhanced Critical Minerals Mapping Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H38A306617E594647ADED7342497EC040" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF8F5A4EBD53543679A5760B8B466CAD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term> has the meaning given to that term in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF65B7D753EB4B1787F4B53D322CAF62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Earth MRI</header><text>The term <term>Earth MRI</term> means the Earth Mapping Resources Initiative of the United States Geological Survey.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02E346FD7BB14390A8E5EF7816004EE9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quantum gravity gradiometry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>quantum gravity gradiometry</term> means the use of quantum mechanical systems, including cold-atom interferometry, to measure spatial gradients of gravitational fields for the purpose of detecting subsurface density variations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H941EDD9096C845D4A31B3D0E6AA5EFED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rare earth element</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rare earth element</term> means any of the 17 metallic elements consisting of the 15 lanthanides plus scandium and yttrium, which are a special subset of critical minerals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A5ED16BC4434F108DC0A39F9842364F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC31F0595E2F54E6AB65A2159ACC96089"><enum>3.</enum><header>Quantum-enhanced critical minerals survey</header> <subsection id="H65361A7E41CD4487A0E2B6D145CD7FB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish and carry out a program to conduct original quantum-enhanced geophysical surveys to improve upon existing United States Geological Survey data for the discovery and characterization of critical mineral and rare earth element deposits on or adjacent to Federal lands.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF686870F908847DB9DC37D3DA361C6A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Survey requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA75DFB2B0677430EB1077A9359ED2F54"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct mobile quantum gravity gradiometry surveys over not fewer than 3 priority critical minerals focus areas identified under the Earth MRI program, with priority given to focus areas in the western rare earth element zones;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB00347048E3F4569AA512C2CE9238691"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compare quantum gravity gradiometry data with existing classical geophysical survey data from the same focus areas to quantify detection improvements in resolution, depth penetration, and mineral deposit characterization;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D33150D50964DF2BF766641284406A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrate all survey data into the Earth MRI national minerals database and make such data publicly accessible in a format compatible with existing Earth MRI data platforms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99A6D07156AC40FEBE01C057A3AB54BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with the Secretary of Energy, acting through the directors of relevant Department of Energy national laboratories, including the National Laboratory of the Rockies; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADB22D03657740D7960234D5DEAD9ECE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the maximum extent practicable, carry out surveys under cooperative research and development agreements with private quantum sensing firms to leverage private sector investment and reduce Federal costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H684AB19AA4C14F2699CBB7755AF50AE8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall consult and coordinate with the State Geological Surveys of affected States in selecting survey focus areas and interpreting survey results.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H198EEA5B0EE7420FA5CBFEBA6A824D7B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Industry access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Survey data made publicly available under subsection (b)(3) shall be provided to mining and mineral exploration companies to facilitate private-sector investment in domestic critical mineral development.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H631CDEC6570A4FED9613DF982A4454D0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header> 
<subsection id="H8A25B45AA8E1478ABFC489141F148201"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on the quantum-enhanced geophysical survey program established under section 3.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H59132BDCF28B49F79E3A6C7588C0C459"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC8A71E967CD476CA25D225EAD462BDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of each survey area, the quantum gravity gradiometry instruments deployed, and the survey methodologies used;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CFB2859B0AD431D9ED200E27169633E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of critical minerals and rare earth elements identified or characterized in each survey area, including estimated deposit locations, depths, and potential economic significance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE75F200743B74CF9A9E4C4D4F30BC090"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a quantitative comparison of quantum gravity gradiometry results against classical geophysical survey results from the same areas, including metrics for detection resolution, subsurface depth penetration, and cost per unit area surveyed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8EA16AE3CCA4E90A27F8A5C2AB54629"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the potential for quantum gravity gradiometry to reduce speculative drilling requirements in domestic critical minerals exploration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18659694FB404F229F1E5BA145E3380E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of private sector interest in and investment resulting from publicly released survey data;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12D8850111C5462794318BFAB203FD0A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for scaling quantum-enhanced geophysical survey capabilities across the Earth MRI program nationally;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA78D8E32A84C4D6E8A1500B55D3888D4"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any legislative or regulatory changes the Secretary recommends to accelerate domestic critical mineral permitting in areas identified by the surveys; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3BC12FD23D34707957C2E9D50EF9D55"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a cost-benefit analysis comparing the Federal investment under this Act with the estimated economic value of critical mineral deposits identified.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

