<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26096-56D-8G-XLT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 595 ATS: Congratulating the Indiana University Hoosiers football team for winning the 2026 College Football Playoff National Championship and completing an undefeated 16–0 season.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260130">January 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Indiana University Hoosiers football team for winning the 2026 College Football Playoff National Championship and completing an undefeated 16–0 season.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 19, 2026, the Indiana University Hoosiers football team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Indiana Hoosiers</quote>) won their first national championship with a 27 to 21 victory over the 10-seeded University of Miami Hurricanes in the College Football Playoff National Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach Curt Cignetti led the Indiana Hoosiers to a national championship in his second year as head coach, completing one of the most remarkable program turnarounds in all American sports;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas quarterback Fernando Mendoza completed 16 of 27 passes for 186 yards and scored the game-clinching touchdown on a fourth quarter run, earning the title of Offensive Most Valuable Player;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas defensive lineman Mikail Kamara recorded 4 tackles and blocked a punt that was returned for a touchdown, earning the title of Defensive Most Valuable Player;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this championship follows victories in the Big Ten Conference Championship Game and the historic Rose Bowl and Peach Bowl;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Indiana Hoosiers became the first college football team in modern history to finish a season with a perfect record of 16 wins and 0 losses;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Indiana Hoosiers defeated 4 top 10-ranked opponents en route to the national championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Indiana Hoosiers were recognized as the number 1 team in the country by the Associated Press college football poll for the first time in school history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas quarterback Fernando Mendoza was recognized as a consensus All-American and awarded the 2025 Heisman Trophy, becoming the first Indiana Hoosier to receive college football’s highest honor;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas offensive lineman Carter Smith was named the top offensive lineman in the Big Ten Conference and recognized as a consensus All-American;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Indiana Hoosiers offense led the Nation in scoring;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Indiana Hoosiers defense was among the most dominant in the country, allowing only 56 points across 4 post-season games;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Indiana University Marching Hundred, cheerleaders, students, faculty, alumni, and fans worldwide have supported the football team through a triumphant season; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this self-described team of <quote>misfits</quote> inspired Hoosiers throughout their incredible season and made the entire State of Indiana deeply proud: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id026729048cc84ea4abbe2e2496713ce5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Indiana University Hoosiers football team for winning the 2026 College Football Playoff National Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0692f2f3a6af4b2a9ea7cc1266456408"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the players, coaches, and staff whose hard work led to the championship; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide96d039c6bd14feb93fc46ab7ae9485e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate prepare an official copy of this resolution for presentation to—</text><subparagraph id="id1ad4bcf75de0408bb20e2de7655ca1b3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President of Indiana University, Pamela Whitten;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8cafcfb41b0540449d5d0e9cef5b4ade"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the athletic director of Indiana University, Scott Dolson; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id086dc0bf4c8447dfa0deb231fe28ce76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the head coach of the Indiana University football team, Curt Cignetti. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

