<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00A9CB7E5C3B45D5A4117906CC651E09" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8338 IH: Safeguarding Americans’ Fairly Earned Retirement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8338</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent the premature seizure of an individual’s securities, digital assets, or investment accounts in the custody of a financial institution under State escheatment laws, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F5CA86CEC794C5990DF6D9FC08399F5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFCC8CB3186EE475792D7118F9EE3292C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Americans’ Fairly Earned Retirement Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFER Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC0C8FE52365F4948B1B0DFCB0EF62850"><enum>2.</enum><header>Escheatment of certain securities, digital assets, or investment accounts held by custodians</header> 
<subsection id="H7DD5111A3D2C4B2796DA4443B6836355"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any covered asset that is directly held or beneficially owned by a person or entity and custodied by a financial institution, the financial institution may not yield custody of the covered asset, any proceeds from the sale of the covered asset, or a payment related to the covered asset (such as a dividend, principal payment, fork, or airdrop) pursuant to a State unclaimed property law, regulation, or administrative action or other means of escheatment, unless—</text> <paragraph id="H76D180F70C6D4C52A8C50EB4FAA47D42"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a covered asset directly held or beneficially owned by a natural person—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07159A985E05471E8AB1ACA62410D731"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the financial institution receives confirmation of the natural person’s death at least 3 years before yielding custody;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64710AE579A640B9BCE300F5D12C4015" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no fiduciary appointed to represent the estate of the natural person has made an expression of interest in such asset, proceeds, or payment for at least 3 years before yielding custody; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACB4FB9CD1C0485EB3C827BFFB6262D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an asset, proceeds, or a payment where another natural person has an ownership interest, the financial institution receives confirmation of the other natural persons’s death; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6738A381545A4BEFA61AB9F0DF99E493"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a covered asset directly held or beneficially owned by a person or entity other than a natural person, the financial institution has no record of contact with a representative of the person or entity for at least 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7C4FAC1CF3D14B7AB3EF68309862342B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Checking of certain inactive accounts</header> 
<paragraph id="H0145B7177F6040178C2068AFF5007BC8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a covered asset described in subsection (a) that is directly held or beneficially owned by a natural person who has attained retirement age and custodied by a financial institution, at the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date that the financial institution last has a record of contact with the natural person (or a representative thereof), and every five years thereafter, the financial institution shall conduct a comparison of its records with a State or Federal Government database of deaths to identify whether the natural person is deceased.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F914BC1ABF64871BCC22EFD1A039A66" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retirement age defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection and with respect to a natural person, the term <quote>retirement age</quote> means the applicable age, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">section 401(a)(9)(C)(v)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD802D25E078F4C70A12A79F4E756D170"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Death determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a financial institution may confirm the death of a natural person if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H119E47D64A5F4A989423AC989520D1BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the financial institution obtains a death certificate for the natural person; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7DCABAF508C45228811ACFC76DE66D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the financial institution obtains such other legal documents as the institution determines sufficient to confirm the death of the natural person.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC84D8C9DCE914313845A133D068B2F1E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section preempts any State law, regulation, ordinance, or other provision that requires a financial institution to remit, escheat, yield custody, or otherwise transfer any asset, security, or investment account to a State or local government in any manner that conflicts with this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H348A92400315425992CC4F8C4751553E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H945896B82D5A46C8AA38CBFE5AE28153"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this section does not preempt any State law, regulation, ordinance, or other provision requiring communication between the State and a financial institution or a person or entity that directly holds or beneficially owns a covered asset; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE29C4949A9B74F319285506573D4B353"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">this section does not prevent an owner of a covered asset from seeking remedies through State or Federal law for mishandling or improper escheatment of a covered asset.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2E8050A119B24F399D1DD11795B7AB2F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE57BF92197C54D2B933B25ADDEFB8FEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered asset</quote>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H46E0A8DB7852437CA95D9110305B299A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any—</text> <clause id="H6CBCE84DDC6E4781A435D10243A2B005"><enum>(i)</enum><text>security;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6C4082E329904CE4B02CA939F81EC0D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>digital asset; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEBF0B9C8776C4D849599CE16C77FEA52"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>investment account; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDBF2C76AC0C445B9AE9B05AD30B12B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include an employee benefit plan subject to title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A84BC482B524EC1A1583E0F423250C7"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Digital asset</header> <text>The term <term>digital asset</term> means any digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically-secured distributed ledger or other similar technology.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H991EF0B46CBE4C648C3F07F336C9FD70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employee benefit plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>employee benefit plan</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 3(3) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(3)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H80A7901223DA4B8AB6B6108F3BBBC168"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>financial institution</quote>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H978504D54FB149489099FC874988C594"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given that term under section 5312 of title 31, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E0BD0C038C4455B877DC1DBB68DAFC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any—</text> 
<clause id="HC0BF7DB06BB248D0AC4FC61D3F1AE98D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>national bank;</text></clause> <clause id="HA996170C5B654C4387C4C2C1140E34DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transfer agent; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD765E3E239EC4BB2BA36F5E3DC02A50F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">centralized digital asset exchange.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF910A3F388504A1C9519B1833AF1E41D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Investment account</header><text>The term <quote>investment account</quote> means an account, including a retirement account, that can be used to hold, manage, buy, sell, or trade a digital asset or security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB85186660D3040DD9F4E35017DB4B3D9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>security</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96AAC4EB578C46239652442227CBED50"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20165DAA62B9413E8123D6A3A04F662A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply to a covered asset, proceeds from the sale of a covered asset, and a payment related to a covered asset—</text> <paragraph id="H7A238968E023484C83D69A4B0B622092"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that is held or beneficially owned by a person or entity on or after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H672B922212114D01948CE00BE30A5074"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the custody of which has not been yielded pursuant to a State unclaimed property law, regulation, or administrative action or other means of escheatment as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill> 

