<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25876-W4F-WK-8RX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 435 ATS: Honoring the life of Brian Douglas Wilson as a rock-n-roll and pop icon, a musical genius, and one of the greatest composers, songwriters, and innovators in the history of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 435</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251006">October 6, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life of Brian Douglas Wilson as a rock-n-roll and pop icon, a musical genius, and one of the greatest composers, songwriters, and innovators in the history of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Brian Douglas Wilson was born on June 20, 1942, in Inglewood, California, to Audree and Murry Wilson;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Mr. Wilson grew up in Hawthorne, California, with his brothers Carl and Dennis Wilson and attended Hawthorne High School;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Mr. Wilson was a musical prodigy from a young age, recreating tunes he heard on the radio and teaching himself to play the piano at the age of 12;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson, with little formal training beyond a handful of high school music classes, began experimenting with production elements and writing songs as a teenager;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson, his brothers, their cousin Mike Love, and friend Al Jardine formed the Beach Boys in 1961, pioneering a unique harmonic sound with lyrics embracing California surf culture;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson and the Beach Boys released their first album <italic>Surfin’ Safari</italic> in 1962, and quickly achieved commercial success and widespread popularity;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson, as the group’s bassist and primary songwriter, propelled the Beach Boys to 13 top-ten singles between 1962 and 1967 and 3 number 1 hits: <quote>I Get Around</quote>, <quote>Help Me, Rhonda</quote>, and <quote>Good Vibrations</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson composed, arranged, and produced the Beach Boys’ revolutionary album <italic>Pet Sounds</italic>, which, widely considered among the greatest albums of all time, features some of the band’s most enduring hits, like <quote>Wouldn’t It Be Nice</quote>, <quote>God Only Knows</quote>, and <quote>Sloop John B</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson and the Beach Boys were inducted into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame in 1988 and earned a lifetime achievement award from the Recording Academy in 2001;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson won 2 Grammy Awards as a solo artist and received Kennedy Center honors in 2007;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson openly talked about his struggles with mental health and addiction, helping to decrease stigma, and served as an advocate for those who suffer from similar conditions;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson completed his long-awaited masterpiece <italic>Smile</italic> in 2004, an ambitious and critically acclaimed 17-song rock opera he began producing decades earlier in 1966; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Mr. Wilson passed away on June 11, 2025, and has left an enduring legacy in music, inspiring countless artists and millions of fans with his intricate and emotive musical arrangements, introspective songwriting, and pioneering California surf culture sound: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate honors the life of Brian Douglas Wilson as a rock-n-roll and pop icon, a musical genius, and one of the greatest composers, songwriters, and innovators in the history of the United States.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

