<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H124EE92081274A38A65FE8B35D0B9F63" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6048 IH: NDO Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6048</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to modify delayed notice requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H75BD1D54B55C4A4BB68D6923FD8D5A03" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H984ADF3B8A9E42CD97BEE33738F6A034"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NDO Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9A250080D6EE4BA29AEBB30DA9C339CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preclusion of notice</header><subsection id="H514ED94FFB6A4F159F8022A2641B3170"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2705(b) of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA217898410FD4D3AB1FB44668BA65673"><subsection id="HC73A4BFE5D364496B5235D9FA182D52F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preclusion of Notice</header><paragraph id="H8802133DEF7540F9B2BAE1A7889A349E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67783CC724D84B2F9EB975186BA58BD0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governmental entity that is seeking a warrant, order, or subpoena under section 2703, when it is not required to notify the customer or subscriber, or to the extent that it may delay such notice pursuant to subsection (a), may apply to a court for an order, subject to paragraph (6), directing a provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service to which a warrant, order, or subpoena under section 2703 is directed not to notify any other person of the existence of the warrant, order, or subpoena.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47FD23B9C82A4AD58D1D0F25F386F621"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Length</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An order granted under subparagraph (A) shall be in effect—</text><clause id="HC4127523FE09480AADA9D81E71B39971"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for a period of not more than one year if the governmental entity notifies the court of a material change in circumstances, as set forth in paragraph (4), if the nature of the offense pertains to child pornography, as defined in section 2256, or sexual exploitation of children, as described in section 2251, or any Federal, including military, State, or tribal offense that is the substantial equivalent; or</text></clause><clause id="H45BCAF4334A543DC97ED459E5DE08998"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for a period of not more than 90 days for all other investigations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F12E1372D5C4BE0A4E6E3485DD3D480"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA8AE7DF4B304EABA38227F6699DB5A6"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A application for an order under subparagraph (A) shall state, to the best of the applicant’s knowledge, whether the named customer or subscriber whose information is sought by the warrant, order, or subpoena under section 2703—</text><subclause id="H01F394C3E0C6486E83EFBC7925EB3702"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is aware of the warrant, order, subpoena, or underlying investigation; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE3E6F980C9E460A8501428268C16702"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is suspected of involvement in the commission of the crime under investigation.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE47CB02647ED478C800DF5CE421CBBB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Orders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An order granted under this paragraph may not direct, or otherwise require, a provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service to provide notification of the expiration of order to the court or government entity that sought the order.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2AFE1D32C914B9A80DD84EC542C54EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEB525472D23424EA02BCADC6456262F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court may not grant a request for an order made under paragraph (1), or an extension of such order requested by the governmental entity pursuant to paragraph (3), unless—</text><clause id="HE07481DDAF4F47CBA136063A2590F9CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the court issues a written determination, based on specific and articulable facts, and including written findings of fact and conclusions of law, that it is likely that not granting the request will result in—</text><subclause id="H4F0787B164C34AF88084FA566132BBF2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>endangering the life or physical safety of an individual;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E54BF3021234024B21FAB621E8C44F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>flight from prosecution;</text></subclause><subclause id="H88FC3FAE91AB4104BEB9991CFD66889A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>destruction of or tampering with evidence;</text></subclause><subclause id="H57F88F79574F4F1F9A07D1A4F4696F0E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>intimidation of potential witnesses; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H442C9067145441ABA2E7BB7A69E6A935"><enum>(V)</enum><text>otherwise seriously jeopardizing an investigation or unduly delaying a trial; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H77CE0F805BA344EFA010D1FF41FB3830"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the order is narrowly tailored and there is no less restrictive alternative, including notification to an individual or organization within or providing legal representation to the named customer or subscriber, that is not likely to result in an adverse result as described in subclauses (I) through (V) of subparagraph (A)(i); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D64D4C001724AD58696E490FD125362"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the court has reviewed the individual warrant, order, or subpoena under section 2703 to which the order issued under this paragraph applies.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD298BF48029F498284796D3114B5E493"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nature of the offense</header><clause id="H12A946763C6443A9B546965D203CB6EA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), the court may consider the nature of the offense in issuing a determination under subparagraph (A).</text></clause><clause id="HC57FF8BB060648088614615108F25415"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Presumption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court determines there is a reasonable belief the nature of the offense pertains to child pornography, as defined in section 2256, or sexual exploitation of children, as described in section 2251, or any Federal, including military, State, or tribal offense that is the substantial equivalent, the court may presume that one or more of the adverse results described in subclauses (I) through (V) of subparagraph (A)(i) are met and may issue an order consistent with this subsection without a written decision under subparagraph (A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2664CD2E0E34B21AC63F949C330068F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governmental entity may request one or more extensions of an order granted under paragraph (2) of not more than 90 days for each such extension. The court may only grant such an extension if the court makes a written determination required under paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC6E8750C97E4A6FB7F9375D709CA404"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification of changed circumstances</header><text>If the need for the order issued under paragraph (2) changes materially, the governmental entity that requested the order shall notify the court within a reasonable period of time (not to exceed 14 days) of the changed circumstances, and the court shall reassess the order and modify or vacate as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5599F1C8B4884FA4A24802657455C7B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Opportunity to be heard</header><subparagraph id="HFAE18AC05E0D4EB2ABA2A8DA578519F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon an application, petition, or motion by a provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service or person acting on behalf of the provider to which an order under paragraph (2) (or an extension under paragraph (3)) has been issued, the court may modify or vacate the order if—</text><clause id="HB256EA9CD87D4231A757ABE68B79DDD5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the order does not meet requirements provided in paragraph (2) or (3); or</text></clause><clause id="H3F63FB7FE5FF41E69181A5E81EE1F95C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compliance with the order is unreasonable or otherwise unlawful.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2965413CF14546FD80613B895F367C1F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Stay of disclosure of named customer or subscriber communications or records</header><text>A provider's obligation to disclose the information requested in the warrant, order, or subpoena to which the order in paragraph (1) applies is stayed upon the filing of the application, petition, or motion under this paragraph pending resolution of the application, petition, or motion, unless the court with jurisdiction over the challenge determines based on a showing by the governmental entity that the stay should be lifted in whole or in part prior to resolution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BA92AA58B574F6DACB8CD5E2D83A4AB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Finality of order</header><text>The decision of the court resolving an application, petition, or motion under this paragraph shall constitute a final, appealable order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3417EDED894563A93828FF1399803A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service to which an order under paragraph (2) applies, or an officer, employee, or agent thereof, may disclose information otherwise subject to any applicable nondisclosure requirement to—</text><subparagraph id="H128162D2B8604F3E8982FB9B6C5A6D6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>those persons to whom disclosure is necessary in order to comply with the warrant, order, or subpoena;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE38DCDFCB1FF497E84465C1E4DAC83E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an attorney in order to obtain legal advice or assistance regarding the order issued under paragraph (2) or the warrant, order, or subpoena to which the order applies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H165ED3A71F0A41F8B89B8815B1D6B566"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person the court determines can be notified of the warrant, order, or subpoena.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD219D14D604F05AE4BC226241BE905"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Scope of nondisclosure</header><text>Any person to whom disclosure is made under paragraph (6) (other than the governmental entity) shall be subject to the nondisclosure requirements applicable to the person to whom the order is issued. Any recipient authorized under this subsection to disclose to a person information otherwise subject to a nondisclosure requirement shall notify the person of the applicable nondisclosure requirement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04350699530344A6B8EB47E9B5761134"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Supporting documentation</header><text>Upon serving a provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service with an order granted under paragraph (2), or an extension of such order granted under paragraph (3), the governmental entity shall include a copy of the warrant, order, or subpoena to which the nondisclosure order applies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7452F445CA9349439449BDE086ADD3A0"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Expiration of order precluding notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon expiration of an order issued under paragraph (2) or, if an extension has been granted under paragraph (3), expiration of the extension, the governmental entity shall deliver to the named customer or subscriber, by at least 2 methods, which shall be personal service, registered or first-class mail, electronic mail, or other means approved by the court as reasonably calculated to reach the named customer or subscriber within 5 business days of the expiration of the order—</text><subparagraph id="H88F32B822F7A4A3DB610B8AAFE1F14ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of the warrant, order, or subpoena; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A8161DDFB70445E8CE055F523CA5D87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notice that informs the named customer or subscriber—</text><clause id="H6813D0694D2047A5B4F121C530707EC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of the nature of the law enforcement inquiry with reasonable specificity;</text></clause><clause id="HD105F20E1C1F47CBA121DBE2F6C174EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that information maintained for such customer or subscriber by the provider of electronic communications service or remote computing service to which the warrant, order, or subpoena under section 2703, was directed was supplied to or requested by the government entity;</text></clause><clause id="HF6E307B4BB4540749E1901EB5059CF19"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that notification of such customer or subscriber was precluded by court order;</text></clause><clause id="H072BDA82A3BE47DBAAA5BE9D90DDBA41"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the identity of the court authorizing the preclusion of notice;</text></clause><clause id="HBE2DC2F9B46D417C98DFB5994DC8A869"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the provision of this chapter under which the preclusion of notice was authorized; and</text></clause><clause id="HE49C45868A1C4048884B6957D6232672"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the government will, upon request by the customer or subscriber made within 180 days after receiving notification under this paragraph, provide the named customer or subscriber with a copy of the information that was disclosed in response to the warrant, order, or subpoena, or in the event that no information was disclosed, a written certification that no information was disclosed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32CB8F470677410C88667E7CD4B4B0D3"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Copy of information disclosed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon expiration of the order precluding notice issued under paragraph (2) or (3) of this subsection, and at the request of the named customer or subscriber made within 180 days of receiving notification under paragraph (9), the governmental entity shall promptly provide the named customer or subscriber—</text><subparagraph id="HEF422EDBA233425DBEB82B38F1334616"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with a copy of the information that was disclosed in response to the warrant, order, or subpoena except—</text><clause id="H3F9F3872FA1643DCB3C09EDB91740988"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">illicit records;</text></clause><clause id="HBC49CF1EBFFA42CEBD2A640C6E848BE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>records or materials pertaining to child pornography, as defined in section 2256, or sexual exploitation of children, as described in section 2251, or any Federal, including military, State, or tribal offense that is the substantial equivalent; or</text></clause><clause id="HB6D6593D3FF145D791642810EF93BDF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other illegal material; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48A6CD9DD2C142F68725B29CC93AF48F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the event that no information was disclosed, a written certification that no information was disclosed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D350CA7178D46908003A41B2174EA1E"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Redactions</header><text>Any information disclosed pursuant to paragraphs (9) and (10) may be redacted only if a court finds such redactions necessary to preserve the secrecy or integrity of an investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H12160483E6A6481F90A2C6D18FAA0CC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional provisions regarding delayed notice</header><text>Section 2705 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F8B5A4CBBD043A98D0A591F8AC0E10A"><subsection id="H53A2D16B10A44E5D9D886D7077570AD9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="HE9D20B82688F4571A3101E07C996588E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis, the Attorney General shall provide to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, which the Attorney General shall publish on the website of the Department of Justice, in a manner consistent with protection of national security, a report setting forth with respect to the preceding calendar year, for each Federal judicial district—</text><subparagraph id="H5D43C61AE0C64B909B3FD5FCB58930FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of named customers or subscribers with respect to whom, in that calendar year, a warrant, subpoena, or court order was issued pursuant to section 2703;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H700E5C1475C6424DB98D9047F4394C4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the aggregate number of applications requesting delay of notification pursuant to subsection (a)(1), preclusion of notice pursuant to subsection (b)(1), and extensions pursuant to subsection (b)(3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89CCA1D156B545C1B77B6BCE1BD4715C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the aggregate number of orders under this section either granting, extending, or denying a request for delay of notification or preclusion of notice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H253CC2BCC58D4C9DAAE781E3A43F399F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the aggregate number of orders under this section affecting a member of the news media, including any conduct related to activities protected under the First Amendment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D46B0E6DD3F4E0A99B0FDA272C5AEBB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the aggregate number of arrests, trials, and convictions, resulting from investigations in which orders under this section were obtained, including the offenses for which individuals were arrested, tried, or convicted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA47D61A0B0F14EE6ACC477E5F30AF1A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The Attorney General shall include in the report under this subsection a description of the process and the information used to determine the numbers for each of subparagraphs (A) through (E) or paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

