<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3CFCBBCD65914CE090223500F657430E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9473 IH: Defenders of Bataan and Corregidor Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9473</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000598">Mr. LaLota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to the individuals
      who fought for or with the United States against the Armed Forces of Imperial Japan in the
      Pacific theater and became prisoners of war from December 8, 1941, to August 15,
      1945.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H817FC5D39B2146548C090953A2A7C968" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H5B50B8B0B17C4D019D052AC70A31620E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defenders of Bataan and Corregidor Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H41BDCE260339485EA7E24660C6ECEDAD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA7CB373710CA4B23982E1ABA6BB15A69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hours after the attacks on Pearl Harbor, Hawaii Territory, on December 7,1941, Imperial Japanese forces launched coordinated attacks throughout Asia, striking Malaya, Thailand, Singapore, Shanghai, Hong Kong, the Philippines, and the United States territories of Guam, Midway Island, Wake Island, and Howland Island.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33289A75B3EF4C9CA40F728E9518A708"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the next 7 months, undermanned United States forces in the Pacific fought with outdated weapons, expired ammunition, and without reinforcement or resupply to their besieged island posts.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA13C194823614B7DA087326AB32A8467"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On the first day of United States participation in World War II, December 8, 1941, the <quote>first to fire</quote> in the Philippines at the Imperial Japanese were the New Mexico National Guardsmen from the 200th and 515th Coast Artillery (AA) regiments, the successors to the famed <quote>Rough Riders</quote> of the Spanish-American War, who had only recently arrived in the Philippines where they were stationed at Fort Stotsenburg north of Manila with the mission of defending Clark Field.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0287A841FDC4556A182BEB7ECD0337E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Filipino soldiers and civilians valiantly fought alongside and as part of the United States Armed Forces and were integral to their war efforts.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2EF28F395274085A546AB63A5E7DC23"><enum>(5)</enum><text>By the end of December 1941, all United States forces on Luzon Island in the Philippines withdrew to the Bataan Peninsula of the island, where, for the next 4 months, with neither air nor sea defenses, an estimated 12,000 United States and at least 63,000 Filipino troops and 20,000 Filipino civilians endured siege conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1128BF34447D4E0BB669DCC3173E7ED1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On April 9, 1942, Major General Edward P. King, Jr. surrendered the United States and Filipino forces on the Bataan Peninsula. The Imperial Japanese Army forced thousands of troops and civilians to assemble at the port of Mariveles at the tip of Bataan and other locations along the peninsula for a 65-mile forced march. This forced trek came to be known as the <quote>Bataan Death March</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B96F02BFE784D43B7F99C4D9E62A192"><enum>(7)</enum><text>During the Bataan Death March, approximately 700 people of the United States and 6,000 to 10,000 Filipinos were killed. Survivors were sent to Camp O’Donnell where 26,000 more Filipino prisoners died.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3BCCBDD029946C3932EAA28C3BFD168"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On May 6, 1942, Lieutenant General Jonathan Wainwright surrendered the fortress islands of Corregidor (Fort Mills), Fort Drum, Fort Frank, and Fort Hughes in Manila Bay. The complete surrender of the remaining United States and Filipino forces in the Philippines occurred on June 9, 1942.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H864BC9660B1E4116AA1A8F917B603823"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Included in the surrenders in the Philippines were female nurses of the United States Army and Navy and the Philippine Army and civilian volunteers who became the first large group of United States women in combat and, counted with the Army and Navy nurses surrendered on Guam in December 1941, comprised the first group of United States military women taken captive and imprisoned by an enemy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99DF72AA09EE4E46B499103C0F9679E7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Between January 1942 and August 1945, thousands of prisoners of war from the United States who had survived the surrenders throughout the Pacific were shipped in unmarked freighters and vessels.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H873FF97DA7D04BE98271C33FF8C55F9D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>It is time to recognize the defenders of Bataan, Corregidor, and other places throughout the Pacific who were ordinary men and women who found uncommon courage in extraordinary circumstances.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB9EA0EAEBB544DC4B1ADEC60B730D460"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H085DED00240141109F12A7705E365834"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals who fought for or with the United States</header><text>The term <term>individuals who fought for or with the United States</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F9740DC8FEC4B9BBB4953EFD2ACC59F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any individual who—</text>
<clause id="HE6C3C74E997043A7AF2AE36A4F5B0F06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was in the Pacific theater at any time during the period beginning on December 8, 1941, and ending on August 15, 1945; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC649262DAE9B4AF882802099D7DB6F0A"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8AAB5B3E3C774749ACA90AB1F1A2DCEB"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>served honorably as a member of the United States Armed Forces or at the command of the United States Armed Forces in the defensive battles in the Pacific from December 8, 1941, to June 9, 1942; or</text>
            </subclause>
            <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="H3F25B3AC81804260AFC827C90DA97E28" indent="up1">
              <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">became a prisoner of war of Imperial Japan during World War II until August 15, 1945, including civilians who the Imperial Japanese Armed Forces considered military prisoners of war and received veterans status after the war; and</text>
            </subclause>
          </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H52D8F6FA45604BCEA1FE1FBFC7D77BE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a member of the Pacific Fleet or the Hawaiian Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83DE6B8A790940F0A3C4A774545FE35C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pacific theater</header><text>The term <term>Pacific theater</term> means Shanghai, the Central Pacific Area, and the Southwest Pacific Area.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H06EEA9DDF22F45128E2342AC991FCD48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resistance or battle</header><text>The term <term>resistance or battle</term> includes an action in and around Shanghai, Tientsin, Guam, Wake Island, the Dutch East Indies, Borneo, the Philippines, or Midway Island.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43F31AF90C1C46ED96650577F28FFEEF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H5621F2181C2843118AD0258E1AFF1C12"><enum>4.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header>
<subsection id="HC7F4594DE8C44E42BB6C681FF9A8E8D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the collective award, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to the individuals who fought for or with the United States to defend Bataan, Corregidor, and other places in the Pacific theater, and became prisoners of war, in recognition of their personal sacrifice and service during World War II.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCDA6E1FD15C7495D93ABB44918BB0DFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For purposes of the award under subsection (a), the Secretary shall strike the gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H286B6906FE7B41F6BA76676275D1B2E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian institution</header>
<paragraph id="HAAE97A9C806845DF8D86F1C067BDC96F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the National Museum of American History of the Smithsonian Institution, where it shall be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21ED05ED0454448381FBCC9EBD3B8C91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the National Museum of American History of the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display at other locations, particularly at locations that are associated with—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1174E59199C844E4A88AD8CB1CC9EFDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the defensive battles of World War II in the Pacific theater from December 8, 1941, to August 15, 1945;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76E99EC4ACEC4C3EBD0BA074E54B2D72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the prisoners of war of Imperial Japan; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4DD2BEA4AE4E4585A2C154B197CAE9CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the defense of the Philippines, Guam, Wake Island, Midway Island, and Java.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H147D91E5ECDA4F9D9E8DC19A66C9AA9F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 4, at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medals, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section>
<section id="H08378F4922904E0FA6787B83FFC50859"><enum>6.</enum><header>Status of medals</header>
<subsection id="HDB2A9D04ED2345FB885BD4CB5B007E9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H344B56EA3F514F14881716AC78B8E866"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H12D46DE68E8F4E568D76DDF3601DD564"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header>
<subsection id="H40E15F8D385142459A18A985FEFEB174">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authority To use fund amounts</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HCC396AC3906A48ACBAB6F66308CE4EBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 5 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

