<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE821E55413E44C3C9E68E6749367EE87" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1306 IH: Recognizing “National Public Works Week” and the essential contributions of public works professionals.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1306</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing <quote>National Public Works Week</quote> and the essential contributions of public works professionals.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals plan, design, build, operate, and maintain the infrastructure systems that underpin the Nation’s economy and safeguard public health and safety;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas these professionals are responsible for critical services, including roads and bridges, drinking water and wastewater systems, stormwater infrastructure, solid waste management, and public facilities;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas public works personnel play a vital role in emergency management and are often among the first to respond before, during, and after disasters by clearing debris, restoring access, and reestablishing essential services;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas modern, resilient infrastructure is essential to economic growth, supply chain reliability, environmental sustainability, and community well-being;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the successful delivery of infrastructure projects depends on strong partnerships among Federal, State, and local governments;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas public works agencies across the United States face workforce shortages and increasing demands, underscoring the need to recruit, train, and retain the next generation of skilled professionals;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals demonstrate dedication, innovation, and service in supporting communities every day;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the American Public Works Association works to advance professional excellence, workforce development, and public awareness of the value of public works;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas <quote>National Public Works Week</quote> will be observed from May 17 through May 23, 2026, with the theme <quote>Rooted in Service. Powered by Community</quote>; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas National Public Works Week provides an opportunity to recognize the essential contributions of public works professionals and to promote understanding of the infrastructure systems that communities rely on: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H248C934EC8594335B69E29A097A30D97"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDFDF0B396DAF4F6FBCD33262DEB2D275"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H0CFE9553D7D34CE38E64703378A5381C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes <quote>National Public Works Week</quote> and the essential role public works professionals play in protecting public health, safety, and quality of life;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE37824B6018D4AB783F5C34BAC17358C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends public works professionals for their service and dedication to communities across the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87BC6580E4D645188BC5D34E625B099B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports efforts to strengthen and grow the public works workforce to meet current and future infrastructure needs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H48C7D0F038194810A132C4D4AE1E1157"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages greater public awareness of the importance of infrastructure investment, resilience, and maintenance; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F938965FF8347E2B8392FD3CB7FB4A7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>affirms the importance of strong Federal, State, and local partnerships in delivering infrastructure that benefits all Americans.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

