<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B416E407DEB494D8F211E62DA58DFDE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6001 IH: Veterans with ALS Reporting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6001</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit a report on risk reduction strategies to lower the incidence and prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in veterans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2A3911B654A04DDF853BB1490BDCE47C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8BAEB9B18CF248C89AEEDBD86F955279" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans with ALS Reporting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6BCEE430FBF64C9B95ED81F67F826E89"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis in Veterans</header> 
<subsection id="H2C925A72A827437C991031BAB5EA738C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall submit to Congress a report on the incidence and prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (commonly known as <quote>ALS</quote>). Such report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HA51A75D2253446F3B67459E51EBDC2B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the incidence and prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in veterans (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B50169C172E4462A43BCE8AA7CBB39D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the resources and support that the the Centers for Disease Control and the Department of Veterans Affairs provides to veterans with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H517A0AECF0B94055B20E09A38E1E281C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any deficiencies in the resources and support described in paragraph (2);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6168ED3F57D47FD96B5A27A6E901E34"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a strategy to develop and test risk reduction strategies intended to lower the incidence and prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis among veterans;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F8D59239FE744E391E08337A118CF18"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a strategy to develop a pathway for veterans receiving amyotrophic lateral sclerosis care within Department of Veterans Affairs clinics to participate in clinical trials and research sponsored by the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H468AEA4398784E239FDF249C2509D64E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for the enactment of legislation to address the challenges or needs associated with lowering the incidence and prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis among veterans.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H36A96F3BC6814E708AB98D077DB32133"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tracking of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in members and veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall track the prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis in veterans using the amyotrophic lateral sclerosis registry and biorepository of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA3C8BA4D017D4406AAF5E7093702D128"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every three years thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress an update to the report required under subsection (a) and information on the prevalence of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis tracked under subsection (b).</text> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

