<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9A0511ABFD2E455D9BCACB5E79B89FAA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 980 IH: A resolution observing the 1-year anniversary of the 2025 Southern California wildfires.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 980</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution observing the 1-year anniversary of the 2025 Southern California wildfires.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas a series of wildfires, exacerbated by extreme Santa Ana winds and dry conditions, broke out in Los Angeles County and its adjacent counties on January 7, 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the wildfires burned nearly 60,000 acres across the region, killed 31 people, destroyed over 16,000 structures, and displaced over 200,000 Southern Californians;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2 largest fires, the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades and the Eaton Fire in Altadena, burned a combined 37,000 acres and destroyed over 16,000 structures;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the wildfires devastated homes, schools, businesses, places of worship, and entire neighborhoods;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the wildfires caused losses that make it one of the costliest natural disasters in the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 7,500 firefighting emergency personnel were deployed to fight the unprecedented fires;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas firefighters and first responders from across California, from the United States Navy and the United States Forest Service, from departments in Oregon, Washington, Utah, New Mexico, Arizona, Montana, Texas, Canada, Mexico, and from 12 Tribal nations mobilized to respond to the fires;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the firefighters and first responders risked life and limb to preserve and protect lives and property;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hundreds of volunteers worked tirelessly to tend to those who had lost their homes or loved ones;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals across the United States and around the world expressed their support and sorrow for those affected by the fires;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, 1 year later, the rebuilding process in the Pacific Palisades, Altadena, and other communities across Southern California continues; and</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas continued coordination between Federal, State, and local authorities is required to ensure that those affected by the fires obtain the relief and support they need: Now, therefore, be it</text>
 </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4B4DF63834974EF891049B7236882B19"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H47609892F6284A26AC87751A114CD3FD"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H35AEE8137B164D7D8F1A93218A93F6DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors and remembers those who lost their lives in the wildfires;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEA1AEB8C4654C709641C7A3D1C2464B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and commends the bravery and selflessness of the first responders who risked their lives to respond and extinguish the wildfires; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0758509236B4FADBA58FD676471B581"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms its commitment to helping Southern California communities continue to rebuild.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

