<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEED61C8B8B5E48B98FC3491253A8D37A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9475 IH: National Task Force on Caregiving Youth of Veterans Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the National Task Force on Caregiving Youth.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H37B50136D2554A26823F8825159CC406" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1C1F8179C5AA449D83A3DBF447CDE0B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Task Force on Caregiving Youth of Veterans Act.</short-title></quote></text></section> <section id="H07730A64268B4742B93F35BDEE49358A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H21CA149087A8434AAA4EB23AD52DDC9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Caregiving youths provide unpaid care to veterans and members of the Armed Forces with disabilities, illnesses, or injuries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83A6311F40054B25BBE07D989184E448"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The care provided by youths to veterans and members of the Armed Forces often includes physical assistance, emotional support, household management, and advocacy, which may adversely affect their education, long term mental and physical health, and economic opportunities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3972E2E9BBA147898E021B93AA568E8E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research indicates that millions of caregiving youths across the United States who provide care to members of the Armed Forces and veterans face increased risks of academic disruption, social isolation, and long-term health challenges.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6122FF54787641BE9F7F14A5C70D25C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Caregiving youths who provide care to members of the Armed Forces and veterans contribute significantly to the well-being of members of the Armed Forces and veterans and their families, reducing institutional care needs and strengthening family cohesion.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1208F154F2D94E019BA5AC8089285E1B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Existing Federal programs do not adequately identify or support caregiving youths who provide care for member of the Armed Forces and veterans, and there is no coordinated strategy across agencies to address their needs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H888E8655D6F445C7AE5DC3A205DDEA8F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A national task force is necessary to assess the scope of caregiving youths providing care for members of the Armed Forces and veterans, support ongoing research, and develop policy and programmatic solutions to ensure such youths receive appropriate recognition and assistance.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB36F51EFD7274394AAA2437A9F3DCB38"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of National Task Force on Caregiving Youth</header> 
<subsection id="H18D84A407FBB4FCDA71F100AFD952632"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish the National Task Force on Caregiving Youth (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F2C5E46263C43A8BE37FCF2765B01AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of not fewer than 18 members, as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H33754C8CE1CB4ABDBCDF5B7473BEC31C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs, including a representative of each of the following designated by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs:</text> <subparagraph id="HB981916567424F1184C50D295C062287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Veteran Benefits Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1223E8DA2E84A0DA4AA94D30E7539D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The National Cemetery Administration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03CF727E3A3847FFB244BDCE6E33B7EE"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>The Veteran Health Administration.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC81D877C39B49F6948A9002617CCC3C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Caregiver Support Program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED1EF2DB35B1489FB0EC712DE91E0F60"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Veterans Experience Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B516D9514654BDE9295FDF117D5C167"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Health and Human Services, including a representative of each of the following (or successor office) designated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services:</text> <subparagraph id="H2754276628D24BF5962DBE0EFBCFCA70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H895C1C8C59744BACBF409B17B5702538"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Administration for Community Living.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01C9D0C42B2D427AB44BE5210FC5B864"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Indian Health Service.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6FEA9BF672B4579994350A003DF1CBF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Administration for Children and Families.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BACAF6098D047B8B30C6D93FE9F8177"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Education, including a representative of each of the following (or successor office) designated by the Secretary of Education:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8379CD5BD92C45C5855C2093349F55B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Elementary and Secondary Education Program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H140DF30718A8419C93A01CCFC7C33B18"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Special Education Programs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89D8C50470CA4F73953B8534F2337888"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Office of Student Support and Accountability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB982B017DAF04E6E85353A9CB9165811"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Defense, including a representative of each of the following (or successor office) designated by the Secretary of Defense:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H36DE5F4716C549A8A8BC676102A21311"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Defense Education Activity.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H11EC7B2F8C1240C587156C50B6CE58FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Office of Military Community and Family Policy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27D5900E7C8D4E379AD2F970FAA44ABE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Defense Health Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD41248B7331647ECAED75C0D9C8DEF1F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One representative from each of three non-profit organizations that specialize in military family support, caregiving youth initiatives, mental health advocacy, or educational access for caregivers designated by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA42186C09DC34C57BBE46421E3B06F48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall designate the Under Secretary of Veterans Affairs for Health or designee to serve as Chairperson of the Task Force.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H66CDF6DC5EF74EDF9A4CC2ED18716962"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header> <paragraph id="H435251D6EC0C43DD9697D014B977292C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall meet at least once each calendar year quarter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35891A0B2BCD4539B8CEA90E65EB0A98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Two-thirds of the members of the Task Force shall constitute a quorum.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2A9C9E892F9E47E9A2616EA3EE486E9A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Task Force include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H952D93B81BBE4F95B67EE2515DA06EF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the Task Force, to seek to enter into an agreement with a federally funded research and development center to conduct a national study on caregiving youth. Such study, which shall be completed not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAA096CAE68804364B86B5AC28E80B518"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An analysis of the prevalence, demographics, and socio-economic impacts of caregiving youth.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66C90A5951C54F17B9FDEAE036593FD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short- and long-term effects on the education, employment, safety, and physical and mental health caregiving youth.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33B8B5185FFA4B14A52B13961E6A55E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Geographic disparities in access of caregiving youth to support services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B433F36B1AC4110926D8E0666A83DF7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Barriers to Federal, State, and local assistance programs for caregiving youth.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H605B2387AA1F4F798E6860915A73F655"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An identification of gaps in services available for caregiving youth.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB87B474127FF4F278E0B1518284B6BA3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An identification of the benefits of caregiving for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and caregiving youth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AA4B782B74048A1AEBF2AA4A4B6B39A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the establishment of the Task Force, to consult directly with stakeholders including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H63535BE2BC164205B34E0DCD27E4AC1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>caregivers and survivors of veterans and members of the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF3DBD48CEC94058ADCF82D017DA1584"><enum>(B)</enum><text>representatives of nonprofit organizations that specialize in military family support, caregiving youth initiatives, mental health advocacy, or educational access for caregivers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B49FE1FB6854DF6827E0E84E2DEEF31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>relevant Federal advisory commissions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B5D462F0CC6401F93F120DFDE2BF20E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the Task Force, to develop targeted policy recommendations to Congress, and Federal, State, and local agencies on how the Federal departments represented on the Task Force pursuant to subsection (b) can expand program support, resources, and accommodation for caregiving youths who provide care for members of the Armed Forces and veterans, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE07E347B78584A618F209F5424FB8B7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>school-based resources and scholarship programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74C15410CAB24ADEB093F1A304B6E24C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improved mental health support by integrating trauma-informed care for caregiving youth within frameworks of such departments;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA563C062CFEF4928AB9006A29DF067F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>creating support programs within each such department; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H239DD9247DC2487A93BACF64BE40BDC0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing financial assistance models.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9621B2EA58F4FB88604164E95049E8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To explore the feasibility and advisability of the development of a standardized database to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A0B78FEB1124AF5830FB0D9E9B6E704"><enum>(A)</enum><text>track the demographics and services used by caregiving youths who provide care for members of the Armed Forces and veterans;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5966D6C3B66242918E889CE85528446F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop joint initiatives between relevant Federal agencies to provide comprehensive support; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A37FEE6D5DC431AA800B7B5924C49CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>align Federal programs with State and local resources to ensure no caregiving youth is overlooked.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B7CB82CBE354A2EB84E94FA14EB8AD1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To formalize nonprofit engagement by establishing a Caregiving Youth Advisory Council that—</text> <subparagraph id="H71CBEAF240BF4A528589E5AB02E13B4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is composed of advocates for caregivers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H935A6768DFD2485AAAEB9E1FC44FB541"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hosts quarterly roundtables to incorporate front-line perspectives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H864769EB9AEC460587E8A8CFE1FABBD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides recommendations to relevant Federal agencies regarding the allocation and use of Federal grants to support non-profit organizations by expanding direct service programs for caregiving youth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EDC9ABADD1B4FC4A78801BE86B0E83B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To conduct a survey of all existing efforts of Federal agencies to support caregiving youth, including best practices and past and ongoing efforts to collect data, research, and other relevant information.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCFBBAE77F98C47FAA681B483E483200D"> <enum>(f)</enum> <header>Authority To enter into agreements</header> <text>The Task Force may enter into agreements with entities, including academic institutions, research entities, and nonprofit organizations, to assist in conducting the national study and developing policy recommendations.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7520EE42E3546728F2F10FC3158EEC0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="H23D88610654343F0ABA2B6C35A8A974B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Task Force shall submit to Congress an initial report that includes a description of the research methodology and preliminary findings of the Task Force related to the duties of the Task Force, including stakeholder consultation, national study design, and early policy considerations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43DC15DDCF2F411889747AB26CC5CE0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the submission of the initial report under paragraph (1), and annually thereafter through the termination date specified under subsection (h), the Task Force shall submit to Congress a report that describes the progress of the Task Force on such duties, including updates, policy recommendations, Federal collaboration efforts, nonprofit engagement, and survey results.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA21E936F99B4E42852A6EBE1223CD42"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Task Force shall terminate on the day that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3F1A3B365A1F44B79A5F7B059E83CC39"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Caregiving youth defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>caregiving youth</quote> means an individual under the age of 26—</text> 
<paragraph id="H34A50F40FD354B2FA12BF8A1D3062B0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who provides unpaid care, including physical assistance, emotional support, household management, medication oversight, or advocacy, to a veteran or member of the Armed Forces with a disability, chronic illness, or injury; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52ADD029FCB340EB84461719F1C70DF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">without regard to whether the individual or the parent of the individual qualifies for the Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

