<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25L49-8V4-VC-G95">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3160 IS: To provide for interagency tabletop exercises to assess the impacts of Department of Defense decisions during crises and evaluate United States Government tools available to augment Department of Defense capabilities in competition, crisis, and conflict, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3160</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide for interagency tabletop exercises to assess the impacts of
            Department of Defense decisions during crises and evaluate United States Government
            tools available to augment Department of Defense capabilities in competition, crisis,
            and conflict, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4678f89375a049b6bb430704d1fa5a1c" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Interagency tabletop exercises to assess augment Department of Defense
                capabilities in competition, crisis, and conflict</header>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93f1d19ad404463fb15c22871abb4ac5">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Defense shall invite representatives from Federal departments and agencies focused on economic issues, including the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Transportation, the Office of the United States Trade Representative, the National Economic Council, and representatives from the private sector, as appropriate, to participate in unclassified Department of Defense tabletop exercises for the purposes of—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id975f9b1123d14e54a521a935a9422404">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessing the economic impacts of Department of Defense decisions during crisis and conflict; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23cc1e780bf440a09ca9ac274ca92417">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluating the economic tools available to the United States Government to augment Department of Defense capabilities in competition, crisis, and conflict.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e3103fe2aa846c1a5db763fed0caa94">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Briefing</header>
 <text>Not later than December 31, 2025, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees (as that term is defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code) a briefing on the current and planned efforts of the Department of Defense to include representatives from Federal departments and agencies focused on economic issues and the private sector in unclassified Department of Defense tabletop exercises.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

