<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25C46-7H6-GM-4CF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 575 ATS: Congratulating the Oklahoma State University men’s cross country team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Men’s Division I Cross Country National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260106">January 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Oklahoma State University men’s cross country team for winning the 2025 National Collegiate Athletic Association Men’s Division I Cross Country National Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the 2025 Oklahoma State University men’s cross country team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Cowboys</quote>), under the leadership of head coach Dave Smith, won the team’s sixth National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as <quote>NCAA</quote>) Division I championship title;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys won the national men's cross country title for the second time in the last three years, making it the Oklahoma State University's 55th NCAA team championship overall;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys competed in the 2025 NCAA Midwest Regional Championship 10,000-meter race, where they finished first in points, earning an automatic bid to compete for the national title;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys finished the season by winning the Big 12 Cross Country Championship, NCAA Midwest Regional Championship, and the NCAA Division I Cross Country National Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cowboys 24-man cross country team is comprised of talented distance athletes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Adisu Guadie, Ryan Schoppe, Will Muirhead, Laban Kipkemboi, Brian Musau, Fouad Messaoudi, and Denis Kipngetich all played a key role in securing the Cowboys a sixth national title;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Brian Musau was the first of three Cowboys to cross the finish line in the top 10, finishing fourth and beating his previous 10,000 meter record by three seconds, and earned his third cross country All-America honor;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fouad Messaoudi and Denis Kipngetich followed suit with fifth and sixth-place finishes, and both Cowboys earned their third cross country All-America honors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Adisu Guadie and Ryan Schoppe both earned their first All-American honors; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head coach Dave Smith was named Men’s National Coach of the Year by the U.S. Track &amp; Field and Cross Country Coaches Association: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id3148afdd1b0f4b05aa37082eaba66ddb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the 2025 Oklahoma State University men’s cross country team on its championship season; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a49112b496946aa89e254285bcfbc7c"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the 2025 Oklahoma State University men’s cross country team for its hard work and dedication to the sport and for the excitement it brings to Oklahoma State University, the State of Oklahoma, and to Cowboy fans everywhere.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

