<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9F5C04BB72B8454AB76FA53C95D442BE" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1161 IH: Congressional Quilt Show Resolution of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1161</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the establishment of a Congressional Quilt Show to recognize and honor American quilters and their craftsmanship in the Nation for over 250 years.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H9804F14C3AA241B484F3B9892D073BE8">
        <section id="H1B909779ACB144ACB4111EBCC8E8D588" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Quilt Show Resolution of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="HC3BD3C134F794929910448652EBD9EB0">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Findings</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The House of Representatives finds the following:</text>
            <paragraph id="H7F0CADDEC4AB4DFD9D04937B9983CB71">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The American quilting community are persistent, inter-generational stewards of craft, memory, and skill in our Nation.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H6A779EF4EDFD4413845B3CD4752F30CA">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Since before the Nation’s founding, the rigor and joy of quilting and needlework have ushered Americans, predominantly women and girls, to learn the muscle and union of beauty and function and embody the utility and necessity of visual and mathematical intelligence.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HA08CFAE4AE584812A7E78A6C99C85FD2">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Congressional investment will aid American quilters in their work to uphold high standards of skill and ingenuity, and build community across the country.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HB6488BCE3E3341ADA2986732FBF1F744">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>It is the intent of the House of Representatives to celebrate the important role American quilters play is keeping our Nation warm, sharp, self-sufficient, and generous.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H39BB9A7122B540F4BA012B00C5B01989">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Bringing together Members of Congress and their constituents to participate in activities that will result in a deeper appreciation for quilting will foster cultural pride and affirm the value of craftsmanship as a national asset.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="HAC7FA371F17844BD90220B7484C8AB4E">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Congressional quilt show</header>
            <subsection id="HEACA81033FF144C8A0E7FDE4EEC3D404">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Establishment of showcase</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established a congressional quilting showcase, which shall be administered by lottery and held each year among eligible constituents in each congressional district.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H457E530FAAAC43438B9B0AB445818DCD">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Regulations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The showcase under this resolution shall be carried out in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Committee on House Administration.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HD86AFAC422004BD6BCB6B18ACDA80B3A">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Display</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Architect of the Capitol shall display each quilt outside the respective congressional office in the House of Representatives.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H9432B1F4056A45ADB1780D2D24112643">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Eligible constituent defined</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible constituent</term> means an individual who has won a ribbon from a county fair, or received similar recognition, within their respective congressional district.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </resolution-body></resolution>

