<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E180DACD28E477C920C4B964F09F9F7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5966 IH: Ohio River Restoration Program Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5966</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to establish an Ohio River Basin Restoration Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F68BF8806384101B5889FDC0ADDFAD7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5CC77B87AE2F4851A3A05DC6290C9F37" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ohio River Restoration Program Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H42C0DD6419234322AE8997D482622300"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ohio River Basin Restoration Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0BA2834B087B4CDAB8C9A38B63582DE9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HA57F1AFB3232414B898A2CA11CB08FA4"><enum>127.</enum><header>Ohio River Basin Restoration Program</header> 
<subsection id="HFC6466BEEE59446C8265E547B37CA8E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF4BC0EC3CB18493C9FD4280FB491FBF3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>advisory council</term> means the advisory council established under subsection (b)(5). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F04E734B08741CFB89D8741C57CBDB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>Agency</term> means the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71CE062B4A36460D924BF5E5E474C1E6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ohio River Basin</header><text>The term <term>Ohio River Basin</term> means the portions of each Ohio River State that contain the watershed of the Ohio River.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6807F94B7E82402F8E7AE8F2D33638ED" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ohio River Basin Restoration Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Ohio River Basin Restoration Program</term> means the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program established by this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE63CF7E1264A4E50A900450DEDC491CE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Ohio River State</header><text>The term <term>Ohio River State</term> means Ohio, Kentucky, West Virginia, Pennsylvania, Indiana, Illinois, New York, Virginia, Maryland, North Carolina, Georgia, Alabama, Tennessee, Mississippi, or South Carolina.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H224F96954334470D938262C1206A6316"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program Director</header><text>The term <term>Program Director</term> means the Director of the Program Office.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BD67C3FE29540D6A1F837BE58390CD4"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program Office</header><text>The term <term>Program Office</term> means the Ohio River National Program Office established under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H860A7080021A46508D4EAAA707454CDE"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal Government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal Government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian tribe individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published under section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H0E9E38F7E9FE4EE1856B5C15F30C07B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ohio River National Program Office</header> <paragraph id="H64FDD4D421514856B220C4AA94F20A92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish an Ohio River National Program Office within the Agency to carry out the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H937EC9B2082244699C3744E019F46109"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program Director</header><text>The Program Office shall be headed by a Program Director, appointed by the Administrator, who, by reason of management experience and technical expertise relating to the Ohio River, is highly qualified to direct the development of programs and plans on a variety of issues related to restoration of the Ohio River Basin.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF661284620014BFEAF40C41D0C2B46D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Program Director shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC7C28E072D974C7DB718B89A7024D219"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate actions of the Agency that seek to protect and restore the Ohio River Basin;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA71C8040703E47F48A3E7DB38DF23D27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop, implement, and update the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program and action plan required by this section, in coordination with the advisory council;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABD12EEC5E4F463499B4C5937D1D07D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">document information and updates related to the development and implementation of the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program and action plan required by this section, and make such information and updates available to the public, including on a public website; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF21E3A0F28F149AFB4B9D6258608B991"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitate, in cooperation with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, engagement and consultation with Tribal Governments and Tribal organizations to ensure Tribal needs and priorities are solicited early and throughout the development of the actionable goals and action plan required by this section.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D1FC1D67E30463EAD2A31820FFEE833" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (3), the Program Director may enter into agreements, as applicable, with relevant Federal agencies and non-Federal entities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0BF4C9AA70B44F29F677F241C4861B3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Program Director shall establish an advisory council consisting of relevant Federal entities and non-Federal stakeholders, including representatives from—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H568D3A7522B04B15B23BE8D194A4719B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each State located in whole or in part in the Ohio River Basin;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5C1B2CF98B34DFFB4B788CF6DBC6FE4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each of the lower, middle, and upper basins of the Ohio River;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A39B15E42374E26AA2F4E4F6A9A1CCB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each Tribal Government located in the Ohio River Basin; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACB8AA948BF1417C867635BEE7AC4A7A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9562EF4D59FD4D219300035E22B11E26" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>The Program Director shall submit to Congress, and make available on a public website, the action plan and updates required by this section, and an annual report describing—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B7220373AB44CA3B183C8736DCCC19A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>progress made in implementing the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDE74DB02C074C60B74F01969658709D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordination of the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program with other Federal, State, Tribal, and local programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3470EB839CFB461BB1067C4F929CC8C2" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any funds transferred to relevant Federal agencies under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DF77475B47F40A1BA338BA027DE88CD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any grants awarded under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF329AB21DC9D45AF861809CFCD70C107" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>specific projects and activities carried out pursuant to this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9E2206384AB54AFB8D57783794AAB28C" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>agreements with relevant Federal agencies and non-Federal entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H0903FDAE6AF74442A0C6F686641CD597"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ohio river basin restoration program</header> <paragraph id="H7B7C15554F8F446588643FD68F11A4BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Agency the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program to carry out projects and activities that advance systemic, large-scale restoration and protection of the Ohio River Basin.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A65DB131A9F4C1BAFFB3F40A8A1CBEB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any project or activity carried out pursuant to the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program shall be designed to address at least 1 of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAC140B94D7F149B98D8AAE0AF2536AF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improvement of water quality in the Ohio River Basin and drinking water in the Ohio River States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F9411E3391D44EFB437EF36A286EC01"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increasing community resilience to flood and storm risk, including through restoration of natural systems in the Ohio River Basin.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7E39EB0640D4C27894871C92E00D608"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protection and restoration of fish and wildlife habitat in the Ohio River Basin.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B4F5123D5324FDBA0979DBBB78E75C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prevention and control of the spread of aquatic invasive species in the Ohio River Basin.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51661BBC208F4956A23A7AEF29841514"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Remediation of toxic substances.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3A20C8E82C84A0B95C2D716AEEEAA31"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improvement of opportunities for public access and recreation in the Ohio River Basin consistent with the ecological needs of fish and wildlife habitat.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC1335F80B7A434E8B248E88BA11C37C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Collection, monitoring, and evaluation of data needed to plan, implement, and assess the effectiveness of projects or activities carried out under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H495F787BF67A405C9AB60B0EEF9C354A"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improvement of public outreach, education, and citizen involvement in the development and implementation of projects and activities carried out under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA3EB9F51FE9441B8A1440918B02778C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approaches</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Projects and activities carried out pursuant to the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program shall prioritize use of natural infrastructure, nature-based, and non-structural solutions to the maximum extent practicable, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBA6666A1493B43A7809993156F2E2F85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protecting or restoring naturally occurring hydrologic, geomorphic, and ecological functions and processes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17D42980FA7C42309398CE8680305487"><enum>(B)</enum><text>removing or modifying structures such as culverts, levees, and dams to restore ecological functions and processes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85176CCA9D1B41DDB7382C61E735BE6D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Project and activity implementation</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE69BB64E4B71406D82CF47E4223262AE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available to carry out the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program may be used to plan, design, implement, or construct projects and activities described in paragraph (2) that are carried out by a relevant Federal agency or by a non-Federal entity in accordance with the action plan developed under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A31F5D04A8A4D3B823F04125A8A40E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>The Program Director may make a grant to, or otherwise enter into an agreement with, any non-Federal entity (including any State, interstate, regional, local, or Tribal governmental entity, nonprofit organization, institution of higher education, or individual) that the Program Director determines is qualified to carry out a project or activity described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64BF7DEBA3C748728EB18CE66B3A4DA9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Project and activity selection</header> 
<subparagraph id="HACD11945FE3E4419B54987B0E79E669C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Program Director, in collaboration with the advisory council, shall select projects and activities to be implemented pursuant to the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program using appropriate principles and criteria, including—</text> <clause id="H571D8AD98C204400A3BB4B5D2998401B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the selection of projects and activities that are equitably distributed throughout the Ohio River Basin;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBCA5D75C52704F98A11AED2DEEA17C97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of a project or activity to achieve strategic, measurable, and reportable environmental outcomes in accordance with the action plan developed under subsection (d);</text></clause> <clause id="HDC9C2670DCB243F4AF5ED1E262F9B731"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recognition that projects and activities may provide economic benefits to local or regional communities, or to the entire Ohio River Basin;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE8D2927384A6446BB9259ABC9B7F77D0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the feasibility of prompt implementation, timely achievement of measurable results, and resource leveraging; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC81E033089224016B849592B3D7D19C7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the opportunity to reduce duplication and improve measurable environmental outcomes.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59DF34C8329B4972A9F08089B880D21C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compatibility</header><text>The Program Director shall ensure that projects and activities carried out under this section are compatible with—</text> <clause id="H35A3CD0DCFBB4CA8820FBB7BD94DB95E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ability of the Corps of Engineers to maintain navigation and other Federal projects in the Ohio River; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H09AA49682C3A4A13AFBED7766D2CA2DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the structural integrity or effectiveness of Federal, State, local, or Tribal disaster risk reduction infrastructure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7796D3A2AC7F4FB5A32809BC6761ADFA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Actionable goals and action plan</header> <paragraph id="HF914292AA6AF457F90DC49CC89AEDB5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actionable goals</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Program Director shall develop actionable goals for the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program, which shall be measurable and reportable and shall include criteria for measuring their success in making progress toward restoring the ecological health and resilience of the Ohio River Basin.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96F8FA3321C34AC58B690F00E88E6755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Action plan</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Program Director shall develop an action plan for advancing the actionable goals developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B6282A8E0364D03B023FE4D6BEC2E38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Program Director shall include in the action plan developed under paragraph (2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0DD24BA3699444F883E3B12C89627E78"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of existing Federal, State, Tribal, and regional commissions, and regional plans, programs, and activities affecting the Ohio River Basin, that may be used to advance the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D6896E3917C4CA19E71559B9F2EAFD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for a comprehensive approach, which (where appropriate) leverages existing Federal, State, and Tribal programs, to—</text> 
<clause id="H6A54A3DF5A0A46B5A2903DDF47B4DE1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advancing systemic, large-scale restoration and protection of the Ohio River Basin; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2C723CACAB21427BA6EFA592BF7E5061"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improvements to water quality within the Ohio River and its tributaries;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7379D93C87740D886202C3C531FEE69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a multi-year plan that identifies specific objectives with corresponding commitments for activities, research, and measures for progress; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7D4D39F76D2488FA005C96A602FBDA0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan to maintain and monitor the implementation of any specific projects or activities identified in the action plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5528DCAAED6432F8AD06C3E0A6C135A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Project and activity recommendations</header><text>The action plan may include recommendations for specific projects or activities that advance the action plan objectives, including timelines, anticipated costs, and the identification of entities responsible for carrying out such projects or activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9117EE35F99F4E98BE497C320F7114C7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less often than once every 5 years, the Program Director shall review and update the actionable goals and action plan developed under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06270B29A4F1419CA6A39E17669E14A4" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consultation with advisory council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and updating the actionable goals and action plan under this subsection, the Program Director shall consult with the advisory council.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DB222A1CBFC4BD899F0453A501E5A28"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public engagement</header><text>The Program Director shall provide public notice of, and an opportunity for comment on, the actionable goals and action plan developed under this subsection, including during each update period under paragraph (5).</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0BDD40B75AC345159FDADA4AC05D9C88"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header> 
<paragraph id="H4D3B293F9347452A95CBFB09640DEC18" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $350,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09CC5FBCB714430D99C0C73E3706F7A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of funds to Federal entities</header><text>With funds made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year, the Administrator may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H38634CD67C974085B07B136F33255D5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transfer funds to the head of any relevant Federal agency, with the concurrence of the head of such agency, to carry out activities in accordance with this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7D4D35D20464AEE9F89C8A8D975F1CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into an interagency agreement with the head of any relevant Federal agency to carry out activities in accordance with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H75BB5A1BDB484E148DA77F920EE2B6F4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Budget item</header><text>The Administrator shall, in the Agency’s annual budget submission to Congress, include a funding request for the Ohio River Basin Restoration Program as a separate budget line item.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill> 

