<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25060-S2S-62-GPJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4045 IS: Food and Nutrition Delivery Safety Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4045</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260310">March 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to establish online and delivery standards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Food and Nutrition Delivery Safety Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id951195cd852d4c41b8252cab195575f3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Online and delivery standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2018">7 U.S.C. 2018</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB0D63F81AECE42E390295E6884A6E48A"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e5d17596147455b9fad22357c12cff5"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Online and delivery standards</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a60820d11e2446991934d31e7a64672"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator of the Food and Nutrition Service, in consultation with the Administrator of the Food Safety and Inspection Service, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and relevant stakeholders, shall establish—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided6311bba1db4bf3a46eb1d0d26aa150"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any retail food store or wholesale food concern authorized to accept and redeem benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program that accepts benefits through an online or mobile platform, standards for the safe and secure online use of the online or mobile platforms by participants in the supplemental nutrition assistance program and retail participants, including with respect to digital privacy and cybersecurity of the user; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6959a120e9e64542906780b84a23cafb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for any retail food store or wholesale food concern authorized to accept and redeem benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program that provides delivery services for foods purchased using those benefits, delivery standards that aim—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e914a53b17f4286baf0d76a4f0c62bc"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to promote fair and safe working conditions for the employees of that delivery service, including paying prevailing wages; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f88f1980c7b40b29f60878df6acd474"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to keep food safe and secure during delivery.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd59c8ec2454243d0a37c179d4fdae902"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report requirement</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date on which the Administrator of the Food and Nutrition Service establishes standards under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall promulgate regulations that require a retail food store or wholesale food concern seeking authorization under this section to accept and redeem benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program to submit to the Secretary a report describing compliance with the standards established under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3e9816a3b264c95a942afb2d1eddc62"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effects of noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a retail food store or wholesale food concern does not comply with the standards established under paragraph (1), that retail food store or wholesale food concern—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7a94e3b20b04b39bf9255a6fb1337d6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall lose authorization to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17063b0dd7ad4389b8b79913fb4d1de5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may reapply for that authorization upon demonstrating that the retail food store or wholesale food concern, as applicable, is in compliance with those standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

