<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4449EAF2CBB44253924E6EC427A30C34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6325 IH: To require the Secretary of Defense to report on the use of other transaction authority, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6325</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251128">November 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to report on the use of other transaction authority, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B6AB6A68C204433825709033C824B29" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H38C04626DAB549AF9BF6A88FA2F149CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Report on the use of other transaction authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the use of follow-on production contracts or transactions under section 4022 of title 10, United States Code, during the period beginning on October 1, 2020, and ending on October 1, 2025. Such report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H1A456A1EA6F54DB2A008DED8454C2BF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of transactions for a prototype project awarded under the authority provided by such section 4022;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H111E41C3B67D4275B58064759F90E8E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of such transactions for which an option for a follow-on production contract or transaction was awarded;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00CCF76CAC964F78A07454F3B591F584"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each follow-on production contract or transaction described in paragraph (2), a summary of the status of such contract or transaction, including a description of the overall performance of the contractor in execution of such contract or transaction and the total value of the award;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCDFB8ADBE4D0473284B7004EA33AF6DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of any trends or lessons learned that may limit or prevent the use of follow-on production contracts or transactions under such section 4022; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88B584C3066941BA9EA1402111124C22"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations of the Secretary to improve the use of follow-on production contracts or transactions under such section 4022 and to increase the number of prototype projects that successfully transition to production through such use.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

