<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25A86-N5Y-W1-937"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 474 ATS: Designating October 2025 as “National Country Music Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 474</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251029">October 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating October 2025 as <quote>National Country Music Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas country music, a uniquely American sound, echoes from the backroads of the United States to the streets of Nashville, Tennessee;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Bristol, straddling the Tennessee and Virginia State line, is recognized as the <quote>birthplace of country music</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Grand Ole Opry, the most famous stage in country music, has been called the <quote>home of American music</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Ryman Auditorium, the original home of the Grand Ole Opry, has been described as <quote>the Mother Church of country music</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas country music reminds every American of the importance of faith, family, freedom, hope, opportunity, and patriotism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas country music has influenced numerous other genres of music;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas country music is an incredibly diverse genre, appealing to Americans from all walks of life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas country music has millions of fans all across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the country music industry contributes billions of dollars in revenue each year to the economy of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Country Music Association first celebrated <quote>National Country Music Month</quote> in 1964; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Nixon issued a presidential proclamation in 1970 to acknowledge October as <quote>National Country Music Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id7764a4a6965542a7a53bf3e34982bd87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates October 2025 as <quote>National Country Music Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2abf834e01a490eb9c0f7479dd2cdd5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the contributions of country music to the story and history of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb193dc8fa002488797deae0a84c60804"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the American people to observe <quote>National Country Music Month</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

