<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09A5657AFC454651B2A7E08F455B8961" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5826 IH: Increasing and Developing Entrepreneurship Access Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5826</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251024">October 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to provide minority business enterprises access to entrepreneurship opportunities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA87C2A48AB804E4088697B1F07F9A35B" style="OLC"><section id="HC292D2E7ECAA4BE287629B04B0DC2399" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing and Developing Entrepreneurship Access Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IDEA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDEF55DA5AE2D4E80B8B31E755174F27C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to provide minority business enterprises access to entrepreneurship opportunities</header><subsection id="H4ECC953DBFC3435093D63CC422B9718C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development shall establish a program to provide grants to business accelerator entities to provide entrepreneurship opportunities to minority business enterprises.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AE890D421454FF8AD2912B8CD79A7C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A business accelerator entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Under Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Under Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC81BA06705F141AE9C24CB1BF427CFA7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount and term</header><text>The amount of a grant provided under this section shall be $1,000,000 each year for a period of five consecutive years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H75D4792BA02B4DFEB758A626CF7F2398"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of a grant provided this section to a business accelerator entity may not exceed 75 percent of the total amount of funds provided by the entity to carry out activities using grant funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED42F5BDAAB54BB39A0868C68D6C2DE8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="HBC16EE54D9A4472EA7A3CF1DBC779C24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant provided under this section shall be used by a business accelerator entity to provide—</text><subparagraph id="HD653CBEC521A43B286CED1DEC6C237C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>capital, including direct cash transfers of grant funds, to minority business enterprises in a region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF6CFACC84F4C7FBECDBC04275C5FAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>networking programs that connect minority business enterprises to sources of capital and innovation in a region; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36946D7163484EC9BE9A81BC9686B7D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other assistance that the Under Secretary determines to be appropriate for minority business enterprises in a region.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FCBC93EF96341D2A5472C5B5816957C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Region described</header><text>A region described in this subsection is a region in which not less than 15 minority business enterprises, each with a revenue of not less than $250,000 a year, are located.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF203DB0A646F4692B8BF35A1192EA6ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Under Secretary shall submit to Congress, for each fiscal year in which the Under Secretary provides grants under this section, a report on the program established under this section, including—</text><paragraph id="H3E938F37B87D4B0A8F4618CF93A9E6E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an identification of the number of grants provided in such fiscal year and the total amount of such grants;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02485308287C40CD8B4E4BE609ED9AA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an identification of the number of minority business enterprises that have received assistance from such entities in such fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9312006BDB384884AB52A47D07AABEDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any noncompliance by any business accelerator entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79C02D8B4B524DADBD661279857A2B16"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Misdemeanor</header><text>A business accelerator entity that receives a grant under this section that knowingly uses amounts under the grant for any purpose not otherwise permitted under the program established by this section or who knowingly attempts to do so, shall be fined as provided in title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</text></subsection><subsection id="H63D454649F4D41AE9CEA048BBEAB126C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB7BF08283CD74645AE0CB38E7170333A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business accelerator entity</header><text>The term <term>business accelerator entity</term> means an entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H456596ACDDC54260AE6FC69D249F48A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engages in a partnership with one or more public or private organizations that support minority business enterprises;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H839DDBA6C31948C9AB7BA05CB9EC1A3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides opportunities to expand minority owned business enterprises through seed investment or networking opportunities; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8077112E91504A908672BEA9EAC63EF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offers start-up capital or opportunities to raise capital from investors for minority business enterprises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56BA3E0FC8BC49738744423FC08973DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minority business enterprise</header><text>The term <term>minority business enterprise</term> has the meaning given in section 1108(a) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9007">15 U.S.C. 9007(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9F848E40A4C40F396046ED469F859B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Under secretary</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development of the Minority Business Development Agency (established under section 100002 of the Minority Business Development Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9501">15 U.S.C. 9501</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H104949D253DF4A89AF48A5AFFDE68099"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

