<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85F29CB97EA74FF090D6577D790255C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5954 IH: Beef Origin Labeling Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5954</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the United States Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, to determine a means of reinstating mandatory country of origin labeling for beef that is in compliance with all applicable rules of the World Trade Organization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2BDE8E2EE9654E17B908990989FD5C9D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB8A566E76F1048948928518C395FE557" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Beef Origin Labeling Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7113F0711214428D8B804D71C8504FFE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reinstatement of mandatory country of origin labeling for beef</header> <subsection id="HD0FB8FF981DB42DEA520B5BA34C546D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall determine a means of reinstating mandatory country of origin labeling for beef that is in compliance with all applicable rules of the World Trade Organization.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H96708C1E84574AF081AA2B9D9BCE6668"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter as appropriate, the United States Trade Representative shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HB407BBA4637B41C7A692FC2433B2DF9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of progress in meeting the requirements of subsection (a); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33D08CF78C34489D908EB8C154AEBF97"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for legislation to implement the requirements of subsection (a), including the means of reinstating mandatory country of origin labeling for beef, if necessary, as well as engagements with the Trade Representative’s counterparts in other governments on this matter.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H183C4E032F864DA8B2E7377A09B66243" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultations To resolve WTO dispute settlements</header><text>The United States Trade Representative shall seek to enter into consultations with—</text>
<paragraph id="H295D31E991D7448294B1010D0486362F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Trade Representative’s counterpart in the Government of Canada to resolve the matters involved in the World Trade Organization’s dispute settlement identified as <quote>DS384</quote> and titled <quote>United States–Certain Country of Origin Labeling Requirements</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC273DFC85C4E434DB591E12D1B206632"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Trade Representative’s counterpart in the Government of Mexico to resolve the matters involved in the World Trade Organization’s dispute settlement identified as <quote>DS386</quote> and titled <quote>United States–Certain Country of Origin Labeling Requirements</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H61FA6775C21344FD9206BFA226943A1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H6EB955859160444A8BA834B9D48CFBC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3AEDC6F55B7D4E30BC6358487937B8E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

