<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95858C876ABF48E8B1B23610021A0BE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8724 IH: Providing Resources and Oversight for Tactical Equipment to Communities and Troops Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8724</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 2576a of title 10, United States Code, to improve coordination, training, oversight, and utilization of excess Department of Defense property transferred for law enforcement activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2887CB231AA946A48BA62EF586174B16" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H579C31CA214B4FD7BDA76C8092092992" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Resources and Oversight for Tactical Equipment to Communities and Troops Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA4C3197690804BEFA4457F60422C78D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfer of excess personal property for law enforcement activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2576a of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0A0F7F415FA14FC183504CA21F61B7A2" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H4790887F34EF45C78ADB2A3D7480A62A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Agency-to-State coordination</header> 
<paragraph id="H9228E29701184791974A729891A17D77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish standardized procedures to solicit and consider input from State coordinators and relevant Federal stakeholders regarding program policy and the designation of controlled property.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80792ACF3414492C93390EDE220233B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>Such procedures shall include annual consultations to prioritize transfers that support counterdrug, counterterrorism, disaster-related emergency preparedness, and border security activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H197A3AE99F6D4D51AF151222DDA16A18"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Training standards</header> 
<paragraph id="H0988109F59734704A96AC9259BE5F375"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish minimum annual training standards for State coordinators, including instruction on program compliance, accountability, and property management.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7AE86356C21402AAFA3384C020033C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Such training may be provided through electronic, written, or in-person means, subject to available resources.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3DF8E275F9646829B0A9AB4677E26A8"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Oversight and reporting</header> 
<paragraph id="H53F6A6970AC84A4C87F1F9253939F233"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biennial review</header><text>The Defense Logistics Agency shall conduct a review of the program established under this section not later than one year after the date of enactment of this subsection, and biennially thereafter.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD09BC2C3530460E96D0802D59E5DB87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report containing the findings of the reviews conducted under paragraph (1). Reports shall be publicly posted on the Defense Logistics Agency website within 30 days of submission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85E1B7DF19F6434EB57742D589B3990C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report under paragraph (2) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB2BC5C82D6E43919634EEA4F7B64F04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of compliance with statutory and regulatory requirements;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19FF114B604D4692850BFF56618F9EAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of program effectiveness; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7ACEC096E4A84A34A611E6958758233C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for administrative or legislative action, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

