<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC95661DFA2514BE59ACFC54C786AB403" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7948 IH: To deem certain individuals as parents of Department of Veterans Affairs employees for purposes of determining entitlement to certain family and medical leave for such employees.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To deem certain individuals as parents of Department of Veterans Affairs employees for purposes of determining entitlement to certain family and medical leave for such employees.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC817F6895BCF4327BF259B4A5760E8FE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H80E7396468C748C6AFB5098428B0304A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Treatment of certain family members of Department of Veterans Affairs employees for purposes of family and medical leave</header> 
<subsection id="H687BA10DE4B140EABAF2E0ADCFE4F90C">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7421 of title 38, United States Code, or any other provision of law, a parent of the spouse of a covered employee shall, for the purposes of determining eligibility for the entitlement of the covered employee to leave under section 6382(a)(1)(C) of title 5, United States Code, be deemed as a parent of the covered employee.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF5F8525C6424966A2C86040114E183A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H425D4924DADA4302A39FBF88E4D5D4E0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The term <quote>covered employee</quote> means an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs (including an employee who is appointed in the Veterans Health Administration under any provision of chapter 74 of such title on a full-time basis in a position listed in section 7421(b) of such title).</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE3A625D8A4942D6BCFF45EB584B8484"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <quote>employee</quote> and <quote>parent</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 6381 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

