<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H18CDFDB4DC4B4A55A88703E8C91456C0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9348 IH: Public Access Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9348</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Army to include in any final recommendation for a water resources development project of the Corps of Engineers a plan to maintain equivalent levels of access to existing public recreational amenities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H82C1C0E0DC2045AE957D1B85CDD5EAAF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H18A55CD229DD448FA940A7CE9281C816" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Access Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC7376FC1AE814B8A8B0CFF64BE1635E5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that, during construction of a water resources development project of the Corps of Engineers that affects a public recreational amenity, including a park, a trail, a green space, a recreational waterway, and any other public open space, the Secretary of the Army should—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9EE5A3B9EE2948D6B2623E7703AB8A95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain an equivalent level of recreational access to such public recreational amenity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13E9B75B1F9F4CDBBB4D363E8B55C99B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>minimize temporary disruptions to such access through project planning and coordination with affected communities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD3C6B979C1B47DAAF8BC653D33091CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide alternative public access where necessary to ensure continued recreational opportunities for the duration of such construction.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5D6D72B86C4D4A8CB7EEEAC0A51779D4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recreational access preservation plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, in carrying out a feasibility study for a water resources development project of the Corps of Engineers, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4A3C7BE15B344D53BB3AC66A8511E414"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the potential impact of construction of the project on existing public recreational amenities, including facilities for hiking, biking, walking, and waterborne recreation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77D759E2830D454083CFFC6FBA04D8FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in any final recommendation for such project a plan to maintain an equivalent level of access to such amenities during construction of the project.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

