<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26225-XYK-C4-9NF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4004 IS: Protect Law Enforcement Task Forces Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4004</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Organized Crime Drug Enforcement Task Forces to combat transnational organized crime and to reduce the availability of illicit narcotics in the United States by using a prosecutor-led, multi-agency approach to enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4C0B2EC17078432E9E9A2C6100B2362E"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4869AC78613C4143AF0BA62F160F2D42"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Law Enforcement Task Forces Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H92002350DBBF4E53AA4F50D303F2CC82"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H130455C6B68142D6A790150DEAFC4604"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Established in 1982, the Organized Crime Drug Enforcement Task Forces has been the centerpiece of the strategy of the Attorney General to combat transnational organized crime and to reduce the availability of illicit narcotics in the United States by using a prosecutor-led, multi-agency approach to enforcement through concentrated, coordinated, long-term enterprise investigations of transnational organized crime, money laundering, and major drug trafficking networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE659D46EF2894C6997A1692E76A2A57F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>OCDETF is the largest anti-crime task force in the United States with its own executive office and is accountable for over 500 Federal prosecutors, 1,200 Federal agents, and some 5,000 State and local police. The program has 9 regions and 19 strike forces around the United States to coordinate investigations and prosecutions by bringing together Federal, State, and local law enforcement for multi-jurisdictional operations, while the OCDETF Fusion Center leads on intelligence sharing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6031C5EDE754B568FB189CC1E13B860"><enum>(3)</enum><text>OCDETF implements a nationwide strategy combining priority targeting, coordination, intelligence sharing, and directed resourcing to have the greatest impact disrupting and dismantling command and control elements of criminal organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3692CB40E6C74FB589910AAE5D5208D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>OCDETF has one of the best returns on investment in Federal law enforcement, as demonstrated by the following:</text><subparagraph id="H3306E5C50FA04A2E838681A834D6B885"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In fiscal year 2022, OCDETF brought in $524,000,000 in cash and property seizures and forfeitures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF2409817FE646ABA9573D2D0FB2E2F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In fiscal year 2023, OCDETF brought in $423,000,000, almost offsetting its funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF472BB45DD8641FA9D7DBAC42BEDF1D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Since the inception of OCDETF, tens of thousands of arrests have been made, and hundreds of tons of narcotics and billions in currency, real property, and conveyances have all been seized proving how, in its current structure, OCDETF is a legitimate and effective initiative that has successfully lowered crime in cities across the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f315e9f2d0846d28957f590bc4c3108"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id6ded4a355b9a4bceae02d98cbe312160"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <term>covered agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HCA0F9E12F5AE420E804617F01B6CC1C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30B1AE517F184E8EA2D9993992ED7149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79B0901934044A3B87003A295E79E5E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Postal Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC6B9EB7996D4BBDB59CAF345F2BB7E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Labor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A03FF1307B141AA8323A06E80CA3FAA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87152b6160c541baa547f429c6a1a36c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>OCDETF</header><text>The term <term>OCDETF</term> means the Organized Crime Drug Enforcement Task Forces established by and under the direction of the Attorney General and announced on October 14, 1982, in the Remarks Announcing Federal Initiatives Against Drug Trafficking and Organized Crime.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf53614e0da2840fc9868db30d312eb34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>OFC</header><text>The term <term>OFC</term> means the OCDETF Fusion Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2aed808adbb24932ad08df576bc27dd4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Task Forces</header><text>The term <term>Task Forces</term> means the interagency task force established under section 4.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H521F1ADC6DF34987BFD057768BABE0DA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Interagency task force</header><subsection id="H47D53F94B60B45CCB3FF7AB2412E16F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the OCDETF, and in coordination with other agencies of the Department of Justice, including the Drug Enforcement Administration, and covered agencies shall structure the OCDETF to combat transnational organized crime and to reduce the availability of illicit narcotics in the United States by using a prosecutor-led, multi-agency approach to enforcement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B4A6333BF494D9AADBBC79050224F69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H66C5BB95B3A04675A0349F6B9317618E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the OCDETF, in conjunction with the head of each covered agency, shall submit a joint report on the successes of the Task Forces to—</text><subparagraph id="H11633C80C938497385F76AB5D175DBF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF37D741E69A94C8197436E0A1AFE7FAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34BAC1BC4C6344CCAB64BB41116619F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H026A8F08A79F4D3B8A0C528612C26144"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA5414F8AEFC4F44A38A9479391B07CA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C8ECCE607C24F589C3892B6DE6F4958"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H124277DD710B41088100D48C390D5346"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classification and public release</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H68074833F53944DB99EC4EE8DE5EF667"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submitted in unclassified form, to the greatest extent possible, with a classified annex only if necessary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73153CB98F0D46E79CCFACDCE6CF061F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of the unclassified portion of the report, posted on the public website of the Department of Justice and each covered agency included in the Task Forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H544319E6B51F4BA78FBF7C59B881D9FE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall have no force or effect after January 20, 2029.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

