<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H29DBA4DDD19D4FF1A79B6F1EF12750F2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7935 IH: Shall Not Be Infringed Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7935</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a cause of action enabling recovery of any person harmed by the limitation on ability to carry a firearm in a different jurisdiction.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEE067FD06CE141A3972FB04BADF9C6BB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE6E0AF2042D44345A3A04E3F2F09BC19" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shall Not Be Infringed Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5C9B13A3CD4A4170A720F9D22DB62466"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gun free zone policy requirement pertaining to eligibility for Byrne-JAG funding</header> <subsection id="H4BD926A8ECEA4AF589BC4FA5C43455B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gun free zone policy requirement</header><text>For each fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in subsection (b) in which a State or unit of local government receives a grant under part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), the State or unit of local government shall conform its laws and policies to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H017C95592FB943C08CD1FD9372D43C97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the State or unit of local government has in effect any law providing for a gun free zone, then in the case of any person—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6E701A3D97044BB8B6F235A52B76AC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is harmed by the use of a firearm by another,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A7737BA93F945F9AC4A1B7DA6E8E626"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such harm occurs in a gun free zone,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5173E33044A3408E8A84B0DBBC802722"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who is authorized to carry a firearm in that person’s State of residence, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF6325B656F44DB6B8638311C916DB47"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the person harmed could, if allowed to carry a firearm, have averted or mitigated such harm,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">such person may recover, in a civil action against the State or unit of local government, compensatory damages and damages for pain and suffering.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99B3072A67FB44ACA337A927C0663DC3"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gun free zone</term> means any geographical area where the carrying of a firearm is prohibited under Federal, State, or local law by a member of the public.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E7C62F6F4304C6E836673D07E60B06B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance and ineligibility</header> 
<paragraph id="H17E4D606F53C4BE19E13ECB7145F0123"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period specified in this subsection is the period beginning on the first full fiscal year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5388755BCBE14E63BF5B5777C506B639"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in paragraph (1), a State or unit of local government that fails to comply with subsection (a), shall be subject to a reduction of not more than 99 percent of the funds that would otherwise be allocated for that fiscal year to the State or unit of local government under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), whether characterized as the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, the Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants Program, the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program, or otherwise.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE5293FFDB8DB4A9899288BDEE0C181A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>Amounts not allocated under a program referred to in subsection (b)(2) to a State for failure to fully comply with subsection (a) shall be reallocated under that program to States that have not failed to comply with such subsection.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HD1916E4D60B44879A2C33F16E3F59CD5" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Gun free zone policy requirement pertaining to eligibility for COPS funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For each fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in section 2(b) in which a State or unit of local government receives a grant under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), the State or unit of local government shall conform its laws and policies to the requirement in section 2(a). For any fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in section 2(b)(1), a State or unit of local government that fails to comply with this section, shall be subject to a reduction of not more than 99 percent of the funds that would otherwise be allocated for that fiscal year to the State or unit of local government.</text></section> 
<section id="H879B3BF70A134D83A182415618999763" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Terms used in this Act have the meanings given such terms in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

