<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H61D86F6F26C34D8BBA4E3D2EF5C7CDA2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2675 RH: Protecting Our Courts from Foreign Manipulation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 608</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2675</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–700]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250407">April 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on April 7, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, to increase transparency and oversight of third-party funding by foreign persons, to prohibit third-party funding by foreign states and sovereign wealth funds, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HA79F8CCEAD2A49A7AF6189A1288C97FE"><section id="HA8E55282501E4D1B8F596524D8EB9F8E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Courts from Foreign Manipulation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF7B0053DE64A49E6BFC79F379E88AB24"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transparency and limitations on foreign third-party litigation funding</header><subsection id="H84A6AB0A19A24361896ECB36B5CC0A8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAC04CBFC3F148AF92B3E970D49E6F78" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><section id="HFD6559BB74AA4B3280CA78790BC946ED"><enum>1660.</enum><header>Transparency and limitations on foreign third-party litigation funding</header><subsection id="HE91567BEBFB5464CAF68A473FBE05BBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on third-Party funding litigation by foreign states and sovereign wealth funds</header><paragraph id="H1063F5F952CD4BC1BF269EFA6E527D0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Funding prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful—</text><subparagraph id="HA8DA9A74984A41348DE27543489D3B5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any foreign state or sovereign wealth fund to provide any monetary support either directly or indirectly for initiating or litigating a civil action in which it is not a named party; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H970E9571F64945239ADEE9D3BCEBFC90"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any party or counsel to receive from a foreign state or sovereign wealth fund any monetary support either directly or indirectly for initiating or litigating a civil action in which the foreign state or sovereign wealth fund is not a named party. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30D48523F244427F98ABFD3E4F0093A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sourcing prohibition</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any party or counsel to enter into an agreement creating a right for anyone, other than the named parties or counsel of record, to receive any payment that is contingent, in any respect, on proceeds from the action or from any matter within a portfolio of civil actions that includes the civil action and involves the same counsel of record or affiliated counsel, the terms of which are to be satisfied by money that has been or will be directly or indirectly sourced, in whole or in part, from a foreign state or a sovereign wealth fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F1A195856EC49C88007474AA203C059"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H5CCE758C8C5E44D594E38DBF6176CB4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Null and void</header><text>Any obligation to provide monetary support or agreement in violation of subsection (a) shall be null and void.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8C87F1AB9F741A6AE626EF763788BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dismissal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any civil action in which monetary support in violation of subsection (a) has been or is being used by a plaintiff to litigate the civil action shall be dismissed with prejudice and subject to terms the court considers proper. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36981456ED344A5B8FDE40187866542A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relief on motion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any final judgment entered in a civil action in which monetary support in violation of subsection (a) was used may be subject to being relieved on motion made pursuant to Rule 60(b)(3) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H444B936C99F24249BFBD790F43EC2DD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure of third-Party litigation funding and foreign source certification by foreign persons, foreign states, and sovereign wealth funds</header><paragraph id="H63F6858A4D5B4885862CF3C370796496"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any civil action, each party or the counsel of record for the party shall—</text><subparagraph id="HA60AABDDF33E4DED9D7D29F9C6D7432D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disclose in writing to the court, to all other named parties to the civil action, to the Attorney General, and to the Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General for National Security—</text><clause id="H985EA1DF6FA743F7832E9EEE366CA659"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, the address and, if applicable, the citizenship or the country of incorporation or registration of any foreign person, foreign state, or sovereign wealth fund, other than the named parties or counsel of record, that—</text><subclause id="H0DE3E2607BE64348BE6D3A68F703797C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has provided or has agreed to provide direct or indirect monetary support for initiating or litigating the civil action; </text></subclause><subclause id="H1CB0BA0E36694960B61861D73965B029"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has a right to receive any payment that is contingent, in any respect, on proceeds from the civil action pursuant to a settlement, judgment, award of attorney’s fees, or pursuant to any other outcome of the civil action; or </text></subclause><subclause id="H33D551CC90CB444FBE52028511AA7F02"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has a right to receive any payment that is contingent, in any respect, on proceeds from any matter within a portfolio of civil actions that includes the civil action by settlement, judgement, award of attorney’s fees, or pursuant to any other outcome of the civil action, and involves the same counsel of record or affiliated counsel; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDDA20F12CEC64C01A624C317B100F135"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the party or the counsel of record for the party submits a certification described in subparagraph (C)(i), the name, the address, and, if applicable, the citizenship or the country of incorporation or registration of the foreign person, foreign state, or sovereign wealth fund that is the source of the money; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36C9E87BF087401C93D45E15784A8ACE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>produce to the court, to all other named parties to the civil action, to the Attorney General, and to the Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General for National Security, except as otherwise stipulated or ordered by the court, a copy of any documentation concerning monetary support described in subparagraph (A)(i)(I) or any agreement creating a contingent right described in subclause (II) or (III) of subparagraph (A)(i); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H796CF125321C4A5783EE94CB792C69D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a civil action in which direct or indirect monetary support for initiating or litigating the civil action has been or will be provided or in which there is an agreement creating a right to receive any payment by anyone, other than the named parties or counsel of record, that is contingent, in any respect, on proceeds from of the civil action by settlement, judgment, award of attorney’s fees, or pursuant to any other outcome of the civil action, or on proceeds from any matter within a portfolio that includes the civil action and involves the same counsel or affiliated counsel, submit to the court a certification that—</text><clause id="HD2BC4F003B1A4528B46FDB6A81A5BCC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the money that has been or will be used to provide monetary support or satisfy any term of the agreement has been or will be directly or indirectly sourced, in whole or in part, from a foreign person, foreign state, or sovereign wealth fund, including the monetary amounts that have been or will be used to satisfy the agreement; or</text></clause><clause id="HD55EF5D9EB71414DB9229D0A565F0517"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the disclosure and certification criteria set forth in subparagraph (A)(ii) and clause (i) of this subparagraph do not apply to the civil action. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02F0F76DB8084F21A4C93ABBBA63FC6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA53F95B494FC4691A18FCA5EDEB9EA75"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any disclosure and certification required under paragraph (1) for a civil action described in such paragraph shall be made not later than the later of—</text><clause id="H2B62A15C2664426A94CCB927E69FF95F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>30 days after the date on which any monetary support that is required to be disclosed pursuant to paragraph (1)(A)(i)(I), or any portion thereof, is initially provided, or any agreement described in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of paragraph (1)(A)(i) is executed; or</text></clause><clause id="HDEFA72AB6C524C46914C5BB5CD36A2AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the civil action is filed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09017A1DDE5249E6A03DD5BD203A25D5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Parties served or joined later</header><text>A party that has disclosure and certification obligations under paragraph (1) that is first joined in the civil action after the date on which the civil action is filed shall make any disclosure and certification required under paragraph (1) not later than 30 days after being joined, unless a different time is set by stipulation or court order. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C64326666F42E580B3C3D92C17E11E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign source disclosure and certification format</header><subparagraph id="HF2508321BE94489FB29D8FF146488858"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any disclosure required under paragraph (1)(A) and a certification required under paragraph (1)(C) shall—</text><clause id="HE7EDCC7D9DE0413481A19AC21C130ADB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be made in the form of a declaration under penalty of perjury pursuant to section 1746 and shall be made to the best knowledge, information, and belief of the declarant formed after reasonable inquiry; and</text></clause><clause id="H9725B0F8186A489E8AE4D7AE8F71502D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be provided to all other named parties to the civil action, to the Attorney General, and to the Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General for National Security by the party or counsel of record for the party making the disclosure and certification, except as otherwise stipulated or ordered by the court.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2FB6D731A334C14BEFAA65562C9E0F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supplementation and correction</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a party or counsel of record for the party knew or should have known that a disclosure made under paragraph (1)(A) or a certification made under paragraph (1)(C) is incomplete or inaccurate in any material respect, the party or counsel of record shall supplement or correct the disclosure or certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF7CE8F4383341A89B2C45D1BB66B3D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Failure To disclose, To supplement; sanctions</header><text>A disclosure, production, or certification under subsection (b) is deemed to be information required by Rule 26(a) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure and subject to the sanctions provisions of Rule 37 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text></subsection><subsection id="H34B0901EF5D742FC8AA0F583645B1D18"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H30F3B728F21342C1BB09FC840CF81C55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>foreign person</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HD461FD46B6144925B4B48DEC38657494"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any person or entity that is not a United States person, as defined in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF698B79E844A4294A9230C5738170349"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a foreign state or a sovereign wealth fund;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6536011205EA474BA3D8D5712234856E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>foreign state</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1603; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D0EA71094EE462ABABC29F82A662FD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>sovereign wealth fund</term> means an investment fund owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state (as defined in section 1603).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9631A2D989AD4D279DE3C4C95C9F5171"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HCEC0D44A707541E48B66C909CE249FD8" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><toc changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00"><toc-entry level="section" idref="HFD6559BB74AA4B3280CA78790BC946ED">1660. Transparency and limitations on foreign third-party litigation funding.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H686D1C47BB784BB4BF2A48E5D336BA97"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the activities involving foreign third-party litigation funding in Federal courts, including, if applicable—</text><paragraph id="HEB524D0B88CF4789BC63FDC116292FAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the identities of foreign third-party litigation funders in Federal courts, including names, addresses, and citizenship or country of incorporation or registration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB08416742A844CEBD6D873AF60DACF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the identities of foreign persons, foreign states, or sovereign wealth funds (as such terms are defined in section 1660 of title 28, United States Code, as added by section 2 of this Act) that have been the sources of money for third-party litigation funding in Federal courts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15D19071FC8E489E8ABD2B14642C7E43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the judicial districts in which foreign third-party litigation funding has occurred;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F679767CCDF437998EA3398C3086902"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an estimate of the total amount of foreign-sourced money used for third-party litigation funding in Federal courts, including an estimate of the amount of such money sourced from each country; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F273843FD244D78B080F533E02C0CBD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a summary of the subject matters of the civil actions in Federal courts for which foreign sourced money has been used for third-party litigation funding. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H8B3D56450E58446CA044ABFBF99123EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply to any civil action pending on or commenced on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

