<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B8FC3048F8945D48460273C766B6309" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7362 IH: Form 5500 Filing Simplification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7362</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employment Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to simplify the filing of Form 5500 for employee benefit plan administrators.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC44B0D27D48F4342868DFE9DADE96E97" style="OLC"><section id="H4C6F49A615C04DCF98B9542F45C2BC75" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Form 5500 Filing Simplification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H24C2402195254B069E649A46DDBF2C73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Form 5500 filing simplification</header><subsection id="HD7B03D5B96B54B448283E0274EE13110"><enum>(a)</enum><header>ERISA filing</header><paragraph id="H9739295406A24B9AB4033534E818A657"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Filing with Secretary and furnishing information to participants and certain employers</header><text>Section 104(a)(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1024">29 U.S.C. 1024(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>within 210 days after the close of such year (or within such time as may be required by regulations promulgated by the Secretary in order to reduce duplicative filing)</quote> and inserting <quote>not later than the date that is 15 days after the end of the 9th calendar month that begins after the close of such year (or, if the Secretary determines that the employee benefit plan, or any sponsor, administrator, participant, beneficiary, or other person with respect to such plan, has been affected by a disaster, fire, or action as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7508A">section 7508A(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, a later time determined appropriate by the Secretary)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82C1CDF9133746A8A9FAB93BC7E79D8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report of plan administrators</header><text>Section 4065 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1365">29 U.S.C. 1365</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter following paragraph (3), by striking <quote>within 6 months after the close of the plan year</quote> and inserting <quote>not later than the date that is 15 days after the end of the 9th calendar month that begins after the close of the plan year</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13E18431912D45E2AAADDEBB19433D32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treasury</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall conform Treasury Regulations and other guidance to the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC4441E80075B4FA7B87F488ADAACA9F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modernization of filing statements</header><paragraph id="H8A6D4AE1FAF34E1F993A7CECABCEB3CE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, and the Director of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, as appropriate, shall modify the returns required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6058">section 6058</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the reports required under sections 104 and 4065 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1024">29 U.S.C. 1024</external-xref>, 1365) to permit such return or report, and any additional information required to be submitted with such return or report, to be signed through electronic means.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H002D1459969C41D1A099103E796F2FB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Good-faith reliance</header><text>A plan shall be treated as satisfying the requirements of this section if it complies in good faith with the provisions of this section until the date on which the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, and the Director of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation implement the modifications required under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8BDDFC3781449609D937996A630A1CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC0084DD9CA724311892751341AF67439"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply to plan years ending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

