<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEF2F1197B17D4D01B8F364E0211DD53C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6932 IH: Individuals with Disabilities Education And Legacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6932</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251226">December 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To rescind unobligated amounts made available to the Department of Education for fiscal year 2026, and transfer such amounts to States in accordance with section 611 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC67D2826BAEB4DC4BAD4143E1A0D7130" style="OLC"><section id="HD04F85F8DB5F4EFD90612AC4BDBC4043" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Individuals with Disabilities Education And Legacy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IDEAL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2D6F9A0D025443EEBA71820496214FA3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H0621383210AA4FD78898C8172AD8556E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On November 29, 2025, the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) will honor its 50th anniversary since President Gerald Ford signed the Education for All Handicapped Children Act into law in 1975.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H043E4FCA6B2C4C7EA5C6C5E78EB0AEAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>IDEA stated, clearly and unequivocally, that every child, regardless of disability, has the right to a free appropriate public education in the least restrictive setting possible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD61CDD5A1E60412886C01D5A67566CED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>50 years of progress, 50 years of possibilities, IDEA opened classroom doors, expanded opportunities, and transformed education for millions of students with disabilities, let us keep moving forward, not backward.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H743B2F186BC24DF18FBDC77F8763F6CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Before 1975, more than 1,000,000 children with disabilities were excluded from public schools, often relegated to specialized private schools sponsored by charities and psychiatric hospitals, or left without an education altogether.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDD050204AF44145913B702E98D9767A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>IDEA changed that, paving the way for individualized education plans that addressed the individual needs of students classified under IDEA.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D76B38204B34E7A929C719D9B55957E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Today, IDEA governs the education of nearly 8,000,000 students nationwide, or approximately 15 percent of all public school students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3BA190B0D46449998CC938D06FD5CE1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>According to the law, public schools must identify and assess all students to ascertain if they require services under IDEA.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H379C496C188A4605A1E13F331F8D070A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Children who are experiencing homelessness or attending private schools must also be afforded these services if required.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9DA6FB1F99F41A5BA0530E5B41A1F4C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>For 50 years, IDEA has been the cornerstone of special education in the United States, ensuring access, accountability, and equality for millions of students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21D7035FCE7D4B7E9D468ADBF0999B43"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The history of IDEA is one of progress hard-won and progress worth protecting.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1478BCADAD645CFB662828257D61017"><enum>(11)</enum><text>When IDEA became law, only 1 in 5 children with disabilities had access to public education, and today, millions learn, grow, and thrive because of its protections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C2B937C4BC6452DBDD3F1D10D3B905F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>50 years later, that impact can’t be forgotten, or undone.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H374790A7A63048E8BFB90AB29A2874C2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transferring unobligated amounts to the IDEA</header><subsection id="H2EBCBC2A13F84846BC61BB87BCA8DA5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unobligated balance of each amount made available under the heading <quote>Department of Education</quote> by any Act providing appropriations for fiscal year 2026, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, are permanently rescinded.</text></subsection><subsection id="H17BCC88B49274880A0CB807AAB441CC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that amounts otherwise made available to carry out section 611 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1411">20 U.S.C. 1411</external-xref>) for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 are equivalent, accounting for inflation, to the amounts made available to carry out such section 611 in fiscal year 2025, there is hereby appropriated, out of any amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to be allocated to States for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 in accordance with such section 611, an amount equal to the amounts rescinded by subsection (a), to be merged with amounts otherwise made available for such purposes. Amounts allocated to States pursuant to this subsection for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 shall supplement, not supplant, amounts otherwise made available to make allocations to States under section 611 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1411">20 U.S.C. 1411</external-xref>) for each such fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H438F61D53824428B82C90BB03BAAF718"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after amounts are rescinded by subsection (a), the Secretary of Education shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report identifying—</text><paragraph id="H7455F66571E149B79D911C520B520922"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amounts rescinded by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD745A5BA774834AEA128F499CBEC45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amounts allocated to each State pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

