<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H08601150894A48708A897B8A2F5839FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7953 IH: Fast-tracking Approval for Innovative Rare disease therapies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7953</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To accelerate patient access to innovative medicines and clinical trials for life-threatening diseases by establishing a reciprocal approval mechanism with trusted international regulatory authorities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB82FAA04C366484CB36D9FD2C8C02082" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H81CC791703B6427A92CA372944F498AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fast-tracking Approval for Innovative Rare disease therapies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAIR ACT</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7E2297C3AC39475C8270A8B3BB5B6141"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H528F9B14A3E346C991CA12547C350E6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Patients in the United States often face significant delays in accessing innovative medicines compared to patients in other trusted nations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D89131C7DEE4FEEB7FE20DDEB00AE58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The lengthy regulatory process at the Food and Drug Administration contributes to the movement of clinical trials abroad, leading to fewer opportunities for United States patients to participate in cutting-edge research.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H773DF321B8004F5289C67EB0A924DB90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>China and other nations are rapidly expanding their clinical trial and biopharmaceutical development capacity, threatening United States leadership in biomedical innovation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84B97613ED184CC9929F88B114ACA960"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>A reciprocal approval mechanism with trusted international regulatory authorities will accelerate access for United States patients to life-saving therapies and preserve the United States competitive position in biomedical research and innovation.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H84F6D5321D1B4E1181DC3F787E5C95C4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reciprocal marketing approval for certain drugs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 524B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360n-2">21 U.S.C. 360n–2</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4C57EFF05994AA28A31112E200CD223"> 
<section id="H70DBC454222D480DA668E06BA2E804A5"><enum>524C.</enum><header>Reciprocal marketing approval for certain drugs</header> 
<subsection id="H67A03B3475EA41F1BA485893FC10199E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered product with reciprocal marketing approval in effect under this section is deemed to be subject to an application or premarket notification for which an approval is in effect under section 505(c) or 510(k) of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H816F4FBF83F746349E8FFB141E52C9A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, with respect to a covered product, grant reciprocal marketing approval if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56638C01ED0A487C99FF44E1A192D251"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sponsor of the covered product submits a request for reciprocal marketing approval; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAE82E95B9F343F7A62CC22414A36875"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the request demonstrates to the Secretary’s satisfaction that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H922236982B7B48B49C04744106D95EA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered product is lawfully marketed in a foreign country pursuant to an authorization from a trusted international regulatory authority of that country;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04C44EDBC3FE4C77BF2D6400FA6C35C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>absent reciprocal marketing approval, the covered product is not approved for marketing, as described in subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8C1D27B33694B62A77F874CC43E7187"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary has not, because of any concern relating to the safety or effectiveness of the covered product, rescinded or withdrawn any such approval;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H445A4030EEBF494FAE0AEE128CE4F93F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authorization to market the covered product in a foreign country pursuant to an authorization from a trusted international regulatory authority of that country has not, because of any concern relating to the safety or effectiveness of the covered product, been rescinded or withdrawn; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5755977E589A4C76AE5781F8B5A6BCBD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the covered product is intended for use in the diagnosis, treatment, or mitigation of an immediately life-threatening disease or condition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H68D315CC46BD446CAD2FCD156D524DD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Request</header><text>A request for reciprocal marketing approval shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBC7C93F505254F81A73E4461D970595E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be in such form, be submitted in such manner, and contain such information as the Secretary determines necessary to determine whether the criteria listed in subsection (b)(2) are met; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA8B2FA09F7144F49858A340C8A38789F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include, with respect to each trusted international regulatory authority that authorized a covered product to be lawfully marketed in the foreign country involved, as described in subsection (b)(2)(A), an English translation (if necessary) of the dossier issued by such regulatory authority to authorize such marketing.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC26B4044F514E3C92A52D09280BAC9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue an order granting, or declining to grant, reciprocal marketing approval with respect to a covered product not later than 30 days after the Secretary’s receipt of a request under subsection (b)(1) for the product.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H11811D8193D7408AB61CCDEABE6986D9"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Labeling; post-Market requirements</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 30-day period described in subsection (d), the Secretary shall finalize—</text>
            <paragraph id="HF058F634285E455B936208017B79513D">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the form and content of the labeling for a covered product for which reciprocal marketing approval is to be granted; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H8118725538FC4B27855289292EBA0C83">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>any postmarket studies the Secretary determines necessary to ensure the safety and effectiveness of such product.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4DEC3C25466549749C2D6BA8A7A61650"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability of relevant provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this Act shall apply with respect to a covered product for which reciprocal marketing approval is in effect to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a product for which approval of an application or premarket notification under section 505(c) or 510(k) of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable, is in effect.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC09524620A4A4DC99DE4235F89EBFBF3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Withdrawal of reciprocal marketing approval</header> <paragraph id="HF429FF8783E94F3F8CFC1A2B88A4CC3F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, at any time, withdraw or suspend reciprocal marketing approval with respect to a covered product granted under this section if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H416E0E2CD0A840E798842F29ED2B2712"><enum>(A)</enum><text>new clinical or real-world evidence demonstrates that the product presents an unreasonable risk of serious adverse events or mortality; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D2987BCEE3D47498B97138A3088BD66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the trusted international regulatory authority that originally authorized the covered product has rescinded or suspended its approval in the applicable foreign country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF42673F8223F4DD89649DCD6B4DE3BD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of withdrawal or suspension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the withdrawal or suspension under paragraph (1) is based on adverse event reports occurring within the first 30 days after reciprocal marketing approval, the Secretary shall provide public notice and may require immediate cessation of marketing and distribution.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96CAF00C32E54CF18197D4BF384AA8D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Phase-out option</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may implement a phase-out plan for withdrawal under paragraph (1), including patient transition measures, to protect public health while minimizing disruption to ongoing treatment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA396AF5AC164F5D89BA1A15C1E4BD31">
                        <enum>(h)</enum>
                        <header>Fees for request</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of imposing fees under chapter VII, a request for reciprocal marketing approval under this section shall be treated as an application or premarket notification for approval under section 505(c) or 510(k) or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable.</text>
                    </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE679CB5D38CD4C0B9A84FC36E7BF7A46"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a comprehensive report on—</text> <paragraph id="H5E474CB2FED04EFDB47A44F3323626F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the reciprocal marketing approval program under this section in accelerating access to innovative medicines in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA04AB3467CF04567A6BFF74B01D6EEB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of reciprocal marketing approvals of covered products granted or denied under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50FFE1E1B1EA4840878FCB977F75A8B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the reciprocal marketing approval program under this section on patient safety and adverse event reporting; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA1121533FD34AF1AADB71AE30207B03"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for the continuation, modification, or termination of the reciprocal marketing approval program under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3717AB5F61C84CD08427A28383FCCDC2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBDB2753B58A3494CBB7A5E2FAB7E1591"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered product</header><text>The term <term>covered product</term> means a drug, including a biological product (as defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(i)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CDCF96567DB4804988DC56FB2DD75C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediately life-threatening disease or condition</header><text>The term <term>immediately life-threatening disease or condition</term> has the meaning given such term in section 312.300(b)(1) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB09D8DCCE2F34F6695D78D64C481524E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Trusted international regulatory authority</header><text>The term <term>trusted international regulatory authority</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7DC3240F3564EF2B63D46236F850222"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the European Medicines Agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD0E464A8EC44B69B4E0DB536F9BF9DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency of the United Kingdom;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED3ADEE0E97A48EF80223283AC79748D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Health Canada; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB65B3468962405E83160635DABEB4C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other international regulatory authority designated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HC69C1A83EF5D4E749FF1F13CA49628FB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reciprocal allowance of clinical investigations authorized by trusted international regulatory authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/351">21 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 569B (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-8b">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–8b</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H49A4924F3BE44B04BE6B33129BF1971D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HA62BF11A30A94171BA9C9BA7B9B3CAAD"><enum>569B–1.</enum><header>Reciprocal allowance of clinical investigations authorized by trusted international regulatory authorities</header> 
<subsection id="H271A507084D54F9185841FA0D1F30E90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer may seek reciprocal allowance to conduct a clinical trial under section 505(i) of this Act or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act with respect to a qualified product by submitting an application for such allowance to the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDED6C29C24AD47BCA1714BD2FE7E4DB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A manufacturer seeking reciprocal allowance under subsection (a) to conduct a clinical investigation as described in subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary an application containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H516E631FB8944513872BAD6DF10467C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the authorization by a trusted international regulatory authority to conduct the same clinical investigation with respect to a qualified product in the applicable foreign country; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA38D73FA6544D8980A1163F78168E5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any supporting documentation for such authorization.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF2EC64BBD8EB48F8883CF36EC37DA782"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, for purposes of applying section 505(i) of this Act or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act—</text> <paragraph id="H0B906C72E2BF4DFFB58829E715B3D48F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>treat an application for reciprocal allowance with respect to a qualified product under this section as meeting the criteria applicable to a submission under section 505(i)(2) of this Act (or pursuant to section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act) with respect to beginning a clinical investigation of a new drug (or biological product); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAB6378180F04746AB331978149E96A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursuant to that treatment, issue an order allowing, or declining to allow, a reciprocal allowance with respect to such qualified product not later than 30 days after the Secretary’s receipt of a request under subsection (b) for the product.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H181720F6E6A0498C8B4D3A4E2603E709"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability of provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 505(i) of this Act and section 351(a)(3) shall apply with respect to an application for reciprocal allowance under this section to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply to an investigational new drug application under section 505(i) of this Act or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD70ACEAC71E74B4CB93432811AD1D162">
                        <enum>(e)</enum>
                        <header>Protocol modifications</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may request, before the end of the 30-day period specified in subsection (c)(2), that the manufacturer requesting a reciprocal allowance with respect to a clinical investigation under this section modify the protocols for such clinical investigation. The Secretary shall, notwithstanding a request for modification of protocols under this subsection, grant, or decline to grant such reciprocal allowance within such 30-day period.</text>
                    </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA78756330BC143A78346F6820F9F7231"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualified product defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>qualified product</term> means a covered product (as defined in section 524B) that is intended for use in the diagnosis, treatment, or mitigation of an immediately life-threatening disease or condition.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

