<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9CCC11B223374BACA368B255F8B7B8A7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8791 IH: Institutional Grants for New Infrastructure, Technology, and Education for HBCU Excellence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8791</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260513">May 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the long-term improvement of Historically Black Colleges and Universities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H72876D79945B4680BDAC1F8067F7C69B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8245F6F227944689871DF790EA291BCE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Institutional Grants for New Infrastructure, Technology, and Education for HBCU Excellence Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IGNITE HBCU Excellence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6F40A1F273BA43FFA9D8B36559438B8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for the long-term improvement of hbcus</header> <subsection id="HCD38616846074175BF4C566C97B25CD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H8CC1F77A6C2C4C11A90DAFCB6A790A7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities, on a competitive basis, to support long-term improvements to the facilities of such entities in accordance with this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H49E12DE87CF04212B942287BD2388B6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each eligible entity that is awarded a grant under this section, such grant shall be for a period determined appropriate by the Secretary based on the information submitted by such entity under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H688589FAB40D4AA9801BA42B0A832CC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multiple grants permitted</header><text>An eligible entity may apply for, and be awarded, more than 1 grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6598F17CEB844FEB8DD81CFB36381806"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be considered for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H59B40FF026674E998341337FEF1FAC16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent possible, the information necessary for the Secretary to make the determinations under subsection (c);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H639C3E1B273445649B9941B924AE7297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the projects that such eligible entity plans to carry out with the grant and how such projects will advance the long-term goals of the entity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65CE9BCA91574A35B92A101A0EE7D9F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an explanation of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6239E5F4D94945E0A6D498E070E83C64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such projects will reduce risks to the health, welfare, and safety of students, staff, administrators, faculty, researchers, and guests at such eligible entity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7047EFC63FE486C9D7C27B1328F9E31"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the anticipated number of years that any facilities constructed, improved, or replaced under such projects may be used before presenting a risk described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8D8C208DD854490688627BE817D8BDAB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the median age of the facilities that such entity plans to improve or replace under such projects; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C53DB9893744A81BDCB50B6DA44F826"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible entity seeking to carry out facility repairs described in section 3(a)(3), a preventative maintenance plan for such repairs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0980ADFA75A24464AF6BA39ECBEA2787"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="HED4239982DAC412CB25331C7B9525C22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall give priority to an eligible entity that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB5CADC41C6C847C4A60FCB1F75289D12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrates the greatest need to improve campus facilities, as determined by a comparison of factors identified by the Secretary, which may include—</text> <clause id="HAD84261C464E4FB6816F1DCCE325D843"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consideration of threats posed by the proximity of such facilities to toxic sites;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H054994CE671543DB8F4558C5E5FF2D11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the vulnerability of such facilities to natural disasters and environmental risks;</text></clause> <clause id="HCA284ECDC8B74260916F357F9C50855B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the median age of the facilities that such entity will use grant funds to improve;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE3033D1E444E4E0D9BD4D2C4C8393BCE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the extent to which student enrollment exceeds physical and instructional capacity;</text></clause> <clause id="H8AFAD8A669B7483BA35F5218DB48EDB7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the condition of major systems in such facilities such as heating, ventilation, air conditioning, electrical, water, and sewer systems;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE7D28A8D7764F2F935BE72944DD8857"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the condition of roofs, windows, and doors of such facilities;</text></clause> <clause id="HC48AA9EEAF2140669EDE8277676E1083"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other critical health and safety conditions;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5BCC64A9A4BF4BAC94355187193C5E5B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the number and condition of facilities in significant disrepair; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDFD365DD19FB4071ABE267E1CFD49DB8"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the total amount of deferred maintenance of such facilities;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE33E3DB56593402A8A6B6F4297DA4683"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates the most limited capacity to raise funds for the long-term improvement of campus facilities, as determined by an assessment of—</text> <clause id="H32B9E7CA417E4E63BF8C0AADE5F50A70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the current and historic ability of the eligible entity to raise funds for construction, renovation, modernization, and major repair projects for campus;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H26D6BE17877744F2BDE4FAE6E3BE97A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the eligible entity has been able to issue bonds or receive other funds to support school construction projects;</text></clause> <clause id="H04DD7106CD5B41F2917000610564C1BF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the bond rating of the eligible entity;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H09DFA9D3E6974CA1A2D9789856404401"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of students enrolled as of the date on which the application is submitted;</text></clause> <clause id="H3F980614C86E47A290B8381F0085D43F"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total value of the endowment of the eligible entity as of the date on which the application is submitted;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3328184EB82E4261B593211550EB7BE9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of deferred maintenance of such facilities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1CFE2AF4EF4548D5BF46D5C9046CC63B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the amount and sources of institutional revenue;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3217D36FEDCF43209F4F0D5EB8C1D4EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enrolls the highest percentages of students who are eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>), and whose families qualify for other Federal need-based aid;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10695995AE964819BA8E381B1B4915B5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is a public institution that—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H75159CBF47DC461B8167506C65216D26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>faces declining State support or investment; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H3AC1ACBE537D4190A34DF247DD723810"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates limited ability to generate revenue, as determined by assessing—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HDE52CBB8F31C4430ACB25D352FBC53D2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total value of the endowment of the institution as of the date on which the application is submitted; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H17B2604DB8A44B95856AA11021433932"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the costs of the deferred maintenance of the institution relative to the total revenue of the institution; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0970484CDFF74833B3C7FDA1ACAB65A2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>demonstrates an effort to seek support from public and private entities for projects carried out with a grant awarded under this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBF5FEE8C482407888C3729842C8ABC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may give priority to an eligible entity—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H644D53329BB7477B8206C150D5A95CF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that lacks access to high-speed broadband and will use the grant funds to improve access to high-speed broadband sufficient to support digital and technology-based learning in accordance with section 3(a)(6);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FC155977CC244DEB917BC1286D9E0C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF61D813B6CC342E1AA30BED3A6366C91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that did not receive a grant under this Act in the preceding fiscal year; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H26B23722A34E4D0A9683A82EBBB11842"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that proposes projects aligned with long-term infrastructure priorities that—</text> 
<clause id="HDAF517EE201940539181112689CC09B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serve as regional models, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H88AAFC8004BE43ACA3C0FB456EDC113B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>address multiple needs on the campus of the entity;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HE80C631F97374F3392AD1C1195F4A016"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address the needs of at least 1 eligible entity in addition to the entity receiving the grant; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HE85F64C1D1E44152985DF7D629854D14"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>encourage efforts described in section 3(d).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF21C39594DB3443C86986AE9669166F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that grants under this section are awarded to eligible entities in a manner that reflects the geographic distribution of such entities in the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H95F9661F6B82471C98DFD3A6A9EE19FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary, directly or by grant or contract, may provide technical assistance to eligible entities to prepare the entities to qualify, apply for, and maintain a grant, under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC016DCFC8349498EA8053A78CB016C29"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Relationship to HBCU capital financing program</header> 
<paragraph id="H60E9D9AF04EC40ACAE689A223AD6FA05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take into consideration whether an eligible entity has received a loan under a loan agreement made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>) when—</text> <subparagraph id="HC041CC5CA8FA4AB2A6170E33D5B20BEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviewing grant applications under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA09939D175FA44F7B8DE68DE0DEA52A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determining priority under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08440C603D154B139E0520699D03FBCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determining the amount awarded for a grant under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DD35A27F457488CA0087F3202BB9FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>With respect to paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary may—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DBA5B44B80246BDB3F14FF12BD920FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine that an eligible entity should not receive priority under subsection (c) if such entity has received a loan under a loan agreement made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE42B130D5054959B36F728EEB37C2BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine that an eligible entity should receive higher priority under subsection (c) if such entity has not received a loan under a loan agreement made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8617E5221A4D4895AF6270E17E107E95"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant uses</header> <subsection id="H2C55A995737147289F57DFEE7419C16B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permitted uses</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), an eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall use such grant funds to carry out at least one of the following activities:</text> 
<paragraph id="H26870F5AC45C4B7BAAC6B3270A54F130"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Construct, modernize, renovate, or retrofit the campus facilities of such entity, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H440BB28A638B4725A5539996C600D415"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving existing, or establishing new, instructional laboratories or workforce-aligned (as determined by the Secretary) research facilities relating to fields of health, science, technology, engineering, the arts, agriculture, education, and other disciplines as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H145DA33BAA9242CE9F6642A465BB2739"><enum>(B)</enum><text>constructing or improving roads or other transportation infrastructure on campus, for which the eligible entity is responsible;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F5D09A7173B47EBA0017FBE412BCFC0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>preserving facilities with historic significance and facilities that house historic or cultural artifacts;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2E4AE83AB1E545418D0DCFAF68F72FAE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constructing, modernizing, renovating, and retrofitting any campus facility or dormitory (including dining facilities) or other facility customarily used for housing students;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAED3F3382C1A4754B2621FAA699431AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improving security and safety for students, faculty, and staff;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA6CDBEDD05A04AF89E6AB4851D45AFB8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>installing or upgrading water, wastewater, power, and underground infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H31845B18C82549B385EA770BAF2799A0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>developing facilities or infrastructure that support job creation, entrepreneurship, and community-based opportunities, including establishing workforce development hubs that—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H222C325CAA1C40199181A6E20FC4420D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are aligned with regional labor market needs;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D68C7E2CC8D4D888F62948AF522968C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">focus on fields such as artificial intelligence; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA1CF1ED97AE4C5F819BE6447A03CAEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support education, training, and career placement for students.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8220E191D61C4533BF6D6BF21D7E4F1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Purchase, manufacture, or modernize vehicle fleets owned and operated by such entity that are used primarily for the purpose of facilitating campus accessibility and student academic activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HEFA436925BBD4FD5B828DBB229F62026"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Carry out repairs, including with respect to deferred maintenance, to the facilities of such eligible entity in accordance with the preventative maintenance plan submitted under section 2(b)(5).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3045FA54A9694C90A8E48CB7F4FD10D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Acquire and install research-related equipment and technology in the campus facilities of such entity, including specialty equipment with respect to emerging fields (as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the head of the eligible entity), such as artificial intelligence, data science, machine learning, cybersecurity, biotechnology, chemistry, pharmaceutical sciences, robotics, and advanced manufacturing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6C2D0D072A8E44E38D43DD6310041072"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For the purpose of facilitating the construction of new campus facilities that are not primarily used for classroom instruction or academic activities—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF6F89B42EF794B94853777C1992AF729"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase or otherwise acquire title to land to serve as a permanent site for such facilities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H905996ECC1A440F491920910C1FCD03E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent that other public or private funds are insufficient—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H1B6FC762F8A94FC0B1D0CF59EB3E4AEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prepare land for the construction of such facilities; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HCC1488F8C0494C72BFB23238C86B9D57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pay other preconstruction costs relating to the development of such facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB852FC5D5244FE5BBF3F68E8E025FA1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Install or extend the life of basic systems and components of campus facilities, which may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6D6E07250DA14B4194FFA01FE99D798A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high-speed broadband internet infrastructure sufficient to support digital and technology-based learning;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6169FBE5C56E47DEAB70F61B7D0B1144"><enum>(B)</enum><text>high-capacity, middle-mile broadband networks, and campus-wide broadband networks, including 5G and future network generations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD63A06996B34804AD351E03BB1398E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>fiber, cyber, and telecommunications infrastructure, including small cells;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1D60D46486645FDB63B0E9BB01015EF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) or other indoor air quality systems;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB7DA60DBDEF4FE5AE1A8370D2945868"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support for last-mile service for rural campuses when other means of providing this support is unavailable; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC637BD9118E84D14B30BC103FEB4DA09"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other infrastructure to support the success of operations and other digital and technology needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H437541F1813748828BEC1400608F1819"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Strengthen the safety and security of the campus of such entity by improving or utilizing design elements, principles, and technology that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A3C58F66EEA4882842E8271136DACE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>guarantee layers of security throughout such campus; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DBC509846294557B6F6D1150D01CFC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uphold the function of such campus as a learning and teaching environment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCF30172764694D4BB9B8171396DF643A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Strengthen institutional planning and governance to support long-term infrastructure goals by—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4CFBD1EF2DDB4934A276840EA374DA80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing or updating campus infrastructure master plans, facility condition assessments, deferred maintenance strategies, or long-term capital project timeliness;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H15EC953C7FA244C5BF4566704309B69E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aligning campus infrastructure master plans with academic and workforce priorities, including with respect to the facilities used by programs in high-demand fields (as determined by the Secretary) in order to address the needs of such facilities and support the growth of such programs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC8C88550934745A98C844029029A899C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>modernizing auxiliary services to improve financial sustainability, service quality, or institutional competitiveness;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE086DCBDA5E6470F8C861B1AF301DB92"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supporting high-quality research and development efforts, including planning and expanding partnerships with manufacturers, employers, or innovation stakeholders that strengthen infrastructure and innovation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H343731ED32864654A2851D86E6FB8536"><enum>(E)</enum><text>establishing or expanding offices or initiatives for the recruitment and retention of faculty in fields of research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H73C46448BA7B4601A308856F7C1F9E62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act may not use such grant funds for—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBE2B31A3665F4991BF5FF8D5F7A3CF28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>payment of routine and predictable maintenance costs, minor repairs, or utility bills;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94A17D7A652745FFB5E2CBAE40F92199"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any facility that is primarily used for athletic contests or exhibitions or other events for which admission is charged to the general public;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CC0CC3D496D4907869DE764EBB6F7A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the purchase or support of any communications equipment or service (as defined in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>)) that poses a risk to national security; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F8AA3043EE64D558F8767E81743CD3F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities that are funded, in whole or in part, under part B of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1060">20 U.S.C. 1060 et seq.</external-xref>), unless the Secretary approves such use.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF202FAC218E4CF5A7D7366D71877594"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>An eligible entity shall use a grant received under this Act only to supplement the level of Federal, State, and local public funds that would, in the absence of such grant, be made available for the activities supported by the grant, and not to supplant such funds.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1B1461FE7AB74B828495D375C2D8867C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Encouraging partnerships</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage partnerships between eligible entities and public and private entities to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA1B591A85F914AE3AB17AEBB148E1D62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide additional funding; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E9F9C3B38054D57A5A5D77F7C06F21B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist in carrying out the activities under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H70C7899CCCD240798B459837CD23DB2C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Use of small business concerns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out projects funded with a grant under this Act, an eligible entity shall seek to procure contracts from—</text> <paragraph id="HC604435AD3984E1FB37FF903533548C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans (including service-disabled veterans); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB804DC676954756A9E4CCC5DA0DBBED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>qualified HUBZone small business concerns.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H80DF09E103874BC9A127D828E603993D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reservation for administrative and other activities</header> <subsection id="HBC474E4C3906496FBB6308D61D44C5EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act may reserve a total of not more than 5 percent of the amount of such grant to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8B0CC49EEC8F44729638107498B2EFD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop the facilities master plan required under subsection (b);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9706304875CA40A9B1E100F7FCAE8050"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carry out activities to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H978FE006796246F1AC4E516E2BCC09FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protect the health of students, staff, administrators, faculty, researchers, and guests during the construction or modernization of the campus facilities of such entity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43906682D1BB464FA77FEDBFF02E15FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mitigate excessive noise caused by activities carried out under this Act;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48975CCFC7B343CFBFC5D4B98BEDC342"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pay personnel to carry out administrative work relating to the grant program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C26EA603B3840DEA79F40720D2B3DF1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>pay other reasonable administrative costs associated with the grant program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2011451E4DF4BE281DA31D76A40AA54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Facilities master plan</header> 
<paragraph id="H2F3313EEA32149D3AE1AB8A75109E4F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a grant under this Act, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary a comprehensive facilities master plan that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBA9B5895F1934A6993B765ED89DCD92C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes how the entity will carry out the activities identified in the application submitted under section 2(b) with the grant funds received under this Act; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H16431012C4664F34B13B8A29F91EE55C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies the anticipated benefits and outcomes of such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA26C3D0F954B499791F19E84580DCB07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The facilities master plan required under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the eligible entity submitting such plan, a description of, as of the date on which such plan is submitted—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB7682800860D47918F3600A01227CB8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the campus facilities—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HDF9DADCB4A4C426B884B037CD4828E41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meet the educational needs of students; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H62AEF394FD75450E9F95F259ABFED9DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>support the educational mission and vision of such entity;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE47FA846DE194755ADF6F2C043858F1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the physical condition of the campus facilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H26059B29AC4D49E28277B8A82EC40C08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the current health, safety, and environmental conditions of the campus facilities, including—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE298D77483C94E9295F434F998396CBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indoor air quality;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H5BFEC2F927BB47519A701BAB965BFD5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the presence of hazardous and toxic substances and chemicals on or near such facilities;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H083D97232E4E4A6A88B7E8BB03B63136"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the safety of drinking water at the tap and water used for meal preparation, including the level of lead and other contaminants in such water;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H5DFB6FF140514BA6938DFEF1B4FB4D6B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>energy and water efficiency;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H1043C23B03B84AB890D0CA674E923820"><enum>(v)</enum><text>excessive noise in academic spaces; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HF0270280D8A24850B0547E48B350119A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other health, safety, and environmental conditions that would impact the health, safety, and learning ability of students;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4394134C3894124B38753E4A577357A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the actual and anticipated impact of current and future student enrollment levels (as of the date of application) on the design of current and future campus facilities, as well as the financial implications of such enrollment levels;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H143B631967B34409B2BCF6651D346B9D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the dollar amount and percentage of funds such entity will dedicate to capital construction projects, including—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H547C170BB17B4A96B98E7024A4327B1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any funds in the budget of such entity that will be dedicated to such projects; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H2B10239C6A72433AA1B3B9BB4DAEFCED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any funds not in such budget that will be dedicated to such projects, including any funds available to the eligibility entity as the result of a bond issue or the Historically Black College and University Capital Financing Program under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE919909E207E4541987086BB7074491F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the dollar amount and percentage of funds such entity will dedicate to the maintenance and operation of campus facilities, including—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H2F1B8888D85942009DA9DA955C5780FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any funds in the budget of such entity that will be dedicated to the maintenance and operation of such facilities; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8C91BD4BCA73421DBED92BC34A292CF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any funds not in the budget of such entity that will be dedicated to the maintenance and operation of such facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EABD00987264AF59D38917E183C2926"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the facilities master plan, the eligible entity shall demonstrate that it conducted meaningful consultation with diverse stakeholders, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H25AE297BC74947DE96ED3DDE6D737060"><enum>(A)</enum><text>staff and other institutional leaders;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H587FCAA952734F779FB31D5D167A690A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>custodial and maintenance staff;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB43585A1206547C886230934717EB518"><enum>(C)</enum><text>emergency first responders;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB4FFDBA0C2B4940BC93F6EE5A227DFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>campus facilities directors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A8DBD75ACF94246B058FC199E6E1A26"><enum>(E)</enum><text>students and families;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25AE35EBCE0F4AAE9AA622E9F920C43D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>community residents, including those directly affected by actions undertaken as a result of utilizing grant funds;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39ED71B0754E4870AB074E5CDD4EF294"><enum>(G)</enum><text>government entities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H30F4A226C12046109C034DCCF64CD982"><enum>(H)</enum><text>local charitable foundations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB002BC1A40C464498E4D96E39B6A715"><enum>(I)</enum><text>local employers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AF4B68E5D1D4AFBB6519958C1C3E2F5"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Indian Tribes, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC565050760949F994018FAEDBB2199C"><enum>(K)</enum><text>other such individuals and entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H652B44D05ACD44ECAC640B36769B7D87"><enum>6.</enum><header>HBCU capital financing loan disbursement and forgiveness</header> 
<subsection id="H6DD756EE4513453CA47827305B5B351D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each time an institution of higher education receives a disbursement of a loan amount under a covered closed loan agreement, the Secretary shall repay—</text> <paragraph id="HF8360A7EE69D47CF8EA2738A629427C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the outstanding balance of principal, interest, fees, and costs on such loan amount (as of the date of such disbursement) under the covered closed loan agreement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41B852CA493B4D54A890975E6A979196"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reimbursement (including reimbursements of escrow and return of fees and deposits) relating to the covered closed loan agreement that are usual and customary when the loan is paid off by the institution.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H253E8AD27FB2432E90205264E1EC4522"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered closed loan agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered closed loan agreement</term> means a closed loan agreement—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE6BCC4CFA66E4F3F8B0DD3B035167405"><enum>(1)</enum><text>executed before the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H776E730BB73F4FD4A05CC926BABFCD6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H9A860260C3DD410A93CA06C31EF5BDE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that provides for loan amounts that have not been disbursed as of the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF228B1A181CE4EFB996DBCF4EA0012D3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reports</header> <subsection id="HFFD6A22A04264C0F9578D590B5BC662A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of education report</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0C167F83CCAF4F129F65EE9B74688C3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the projects carried out with grant funds awarded under this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48B22A70815B42D0AA45FBBBDA97DD5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HE011A7FCC2B74461B96604B49CADB1D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to projects carried out by eligible entities with grant funds awarded under this Act, an assessment of—</text> 
<clause id="H66C73880CF734156A810BB1EE674A3CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the types of such projects;</text></clause> <clause id="HADA4447B79C44EC09F6721BC3FC406B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the square footage of the improvements made by such projects, disaggregated by—</text> 
<subclause id="HE7B01D555481496995766B712DE47484"><enum>(I)</enum><text>total square footage; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF4BBCBE4FFE145E18DE6967977F1CDE1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>square footage per each eligible entity;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HF61A47FA1FA04F6BA74B10FF32A25559"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total cost of each such project;</text></clause> <clause id="HCC5D1C9613D647D588F7810C8E3CFCB7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the cost described in clause (iii), disaggregated by the cost of—</text> 
<subclause id="HED20A438C74F400C9C1763CE68563AA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>planning;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFBAECFAC702945E3A05987E4201EE3E3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>design;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H05B4F50AA67C4DFFAFA1463D72E48D66"><enum>(III)</enum><text>construction;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCC3C9CD72A0D48A19888F4C96FDCB6FC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>site purchase; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7CE84733226347B2A95AB688023471C4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>improvements;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6E046E515177407DBA7AC44897FD3B7F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the geographic distribution of such projects; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H526122D494904D20A538C932ECAEA24E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the demographic composition of the student population served by such projects, disaggregated by—</text> <subclause id="H77B70EE7D046425D8B7A750BBFDB2623"><enum>(I)</enum><text>race and ethnicity; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8CB76AFB05E34A51B6B319D081CE9528"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number and percentage of students enrolled at such entities who are eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D137FFEBBF64B44BF50AA30CA595B0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of a sample of grant recipients, selected by the Secretary taking into account size and geographic location of each grantee, to determine how such recipients are using the grant and the effectiveness of the activities carried out with the grant; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C6031E548FC4CD79920D58A9AB3C43C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of compliance with the requirement in section 3(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H54362B11B9B1465EBC193B1F33E6F036"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller General appropriations report</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H31A98E4C4C8A46E889B4C9299ADCE28D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the amount of appropriations necessary to continue implementing the grant program under this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H40ADF1E4133040FFA91914217A0E29B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFD31732B0F8A40939EEEBA769A4CE8F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the approximate total cost of deferred maintenance across eligible entities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B459737C6594DD5BEBAD1CF42228FE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an overview of sources of funding for addressing such needs other than the grant program under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7F7396B2323343E4B2864A9BE8AE86FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>After the completion of the study under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the study.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA98B397852114743B75CDE032F67605C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Results</header><text>The results of the study shall be used to inform the appropriation of funds to carry out this Act for the fiscal years following the submission of the report under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H00C591C79FDD4A089A6BC75A815D4171"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller General implementation report</header> <paragraph id="HD995665E132847EB91558447C0CF781E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the implementation of the grant program under this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D220B0CC9E346399A4AFCF66B7F2DB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H9DEB5521E63C401CA706484B27F5BD8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an examination of program implementation challenges; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B305883D92E4E77898793FF21F06FC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of whether any changes are needed to make grants under this Act more accessible to eligible entities with fiscal challenges to help them raise capital for infrastructure projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E24245D508D4FAF89B4F7C7EDB36B71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>After the completion of the study under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the results of the study, including any recommendations to the Secretary for improvements to the implementation of the grant program under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8990BD46FB334701AF3108B3F4957264"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HFFD3135953524F94BF79FEBC711C22DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7AFB72BA905748C19F527B7A574066E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a part B institution, as such term is defined in section 322(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061(2)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9521662DF86149F998F26357794CD1A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an institution or program listed under section 326(e)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1063b">20 U.S.C. 1063b(e)(1)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB40802016AF4905A580231A87112C10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BD1CF09E80D4C01AFC7A73F7F41DC39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD2CD1711465244BDADB2ABC3A75CCBDF"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

