<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C5BF5B87E3C416491EF624474A58A32" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6378 IH: FERC Greenhouse Gas and Environmental Justice Policy Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6378</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To confirm and clarify the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission’s obligation to assess and mitigate the impacts to climate change and environmental justice communities from projects approved pursuant to the Natural Gas Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCF09B3DB34B0471497CAF9CAC72CFB1B" style="OLC"><section id="HA6BB4CD4A22F4DF68E1F28599FE9FBA9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FERC Greenhouse Gas and Environmental Justice Policy Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEDD421C3EBE1498295ACBA1AFAEB549D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Greenhouse gas and environmental justice policy</header><subsection id="H0D58855B59B34837B20A16068594B29A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mitigation proposal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(d) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717f">15 U.S.C. 717f(d)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including a mitigation proposal described in subsection (i)(3),</quote> after <quote>contain such information</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H614D9146EE524FDE893E13F4A9387BE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Present or future public convenience and necessity determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717f">15 U.S.C. 717f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HCEBAB5857D334ADEBA39FC88D2892950" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7556C4CCA556499BBB12B9777ADB9FE0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Present or future public convenience and necessity determination</header><paragraph id="HFFC9907AC5BD4D13A90FB0D296E16FE0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In finding whether a proposed action, to the extent that may be authorized by a certificate, is or will be required by the present or future public convenience and necessity under subsection (e), the Commission shall determine whether—</text><subparagraph id="HE002B651F68E445A8C29B424C9885DC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the environmental effects of such proposed action, including any effects relating to the environment of such proposed action on environmental justice communities, are significant, and if such significant environmental effects, if any, can be mitigated pursuant to a mitigation proposal required under subsection (d);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34EDEB9E8C5E4D7B8E2944E3D0FDC687"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the significant environmental effects of the proposed action outweigh the benefits of the proposed action under paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57302458509A4036B81758D3FF1509BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proposed action is necessary to ensure energy reliability and affordability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H438904868E5343D2B249D85635FB6701"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Significant environmental effects</header><subparagraph id="H6612E22EF2F4483EB325E9373204A1AE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining whether the environmental effects of a proposed action are significant under paragraph (1)(A), the Commission shall, with respect to such proposed action—</text><clause id="HA5732AEA2E324406872C496720B02567"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluate such environmental effects on environmental justice communities under subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="H8FEC3F2D68A54D1B9CAA7E806BF04608"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>quantify reasonably foreseeable greenhouse gas emissions resulting from such proposed action under subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C690707F76046159DB3CF0474ECE8FE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Environmental justice communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall evaluate the effects of a proposed action on environmental justice communities based on all evidence in the record, including—</text><clause id="H2E51C0B6ADBE4DD880F353CE71B3FFD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>existing environmental and public health stressors;</text></clause><clause id="H6ED56AF0DA7C4BAC836C94CD786D9C9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any adverse environmental and public health stressors resulting from the proposed action;</text></clause><clause id="HCE807814A5A744DDA3943BFB99EFE06D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the presence or absence of adverse cumulative stressors;</text></clause><clause id="H492A3FBE697F411FB21C1DC0D11B339F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>potential environmental and public health stressors associated with the proposed action; and</text></clause><clause id="H6DB12B706C504175A9C3C9C19844FF57"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other factors, as identified by the Commission and the affected environmental justice communities following a meaningful opportunity for public engagement by those communities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7F522857A504ED08DE8F4CB7C4B51AF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Quantification of greenhouse gas emissions</header><text>The Commission shall quantify reasonably foreseeable greenhouse gas emissions resulting from a proposed action based on all evidence in the record, including—</text><clause id="H8DBF900BCF37479BA8B05BE0C9F380BB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the projected capacity of the relevant pipelines to transport natural gas;</text></clause><clause id="HF0BB910EE69A4985B60EBBA679AAA25B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the projected utilization rate of the relevant pipelines;</text></clause><clause id="H98063FAB4EE14598968F5C4BB76FDACE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the construction and operation of the proposed action;</text></clause><clause id="H0171B686246F4934BCC8C7642C742F9C" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the projected downstream greenhouse gas emissions and effects, including cumulative effects, including on environmental justice communities, resulting from the proposed action, including those resulting from the combustion of the natural gas;</text></clause><clause id="HABAB41BCFDFB487A996FFAB1BBAD4C4E" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the projected upstream greenhouse gas emissions and effects, including cumulative effects, including on environmental justice communities, resulting from the proposed action, including those resulting from leakage or other release of the natural gas; and</text></clause><clause id="H7E7CC6E89D134EB89828A2EFAC005844" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other factors, as identified by the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H012045DA2B87410BAAA6BD04E91236F4" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Threshold</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining whether the environmental effects of a proposed action are significant under this paragraph, the Commission shall—</text><clause id="H12883076501F4434A07A96293AC123AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to environmental effects described in subparagraph (B), consider that—</text><subclause id="HC04D9BD15D484C5BB2AEB4C390FD4C15"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no community should bear a disproportionate share of the adverse environmental and public health consequences that results from the Commission approving an application for a certificate of public convenience or necessity; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1FBF5C007218489B81029FA9531EC5ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>it is in the public interest for the Commission, where appropriate, to limit the future placement and expansion of a proposed action in environmental justice communities; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD4643F1F5E254D08B55BEFDFE11AA488"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to quantifying greenhouse gas emissions under subparagraph (C), presume—</text><subclause id="H9613743961194A9A96B7C5B051C56858"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a proposed action that has reasonably foreseeable emissions of at least 100,000 metric tons per year of carbon dioxide equivalent to have a significant effect on climate change; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC42FF52F47314206B9B370B9CF3DA839"><enum>(II)</enum><text>greenhouse gases other that carbon dioxide shall be converted to carbon dioxide equivalent using the 20-year global warming potentials from the most recent assessment report published by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5E55F24C6984E1E85F24083D0F71852"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mitigation</header><subparagraph id="H1451D2C3E372459F9F08E51D216BFD83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under subsection (d), the Commission shall require an applicant for a certificate to submit a proposal with the applicable application that details how the applicant will mitigate all or a portion of the environmental effects of the proposed action, including on climate change and environmental justice communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84FC4B4226BA4FA7A13835A7645F0E45" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon reviewing the mitigation proposal under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall, to the extent practicable, attach to the issuance of a certificate, and to the exercise of the rights granted thereunder, conditions that require the holder of such certificate to address any potential adverse effects of any action authorized under such certificate on climate change and environmental justice communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE61E7B2D5B4372A67990A169780853"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>For any proposed action the Commission approves for which it does not require conditions that mitigate or offset the significant environmental effects of the proposed action to below the significance threshold described in paragraph (2)(D), the Commission shall provide a detailed explanation as to why such mitigation is not practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55AC66701E2947D2AF0F5247FD450FC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Weighing</header><subparagraph id="H2B48BDA28E3D419BB29062A6A753718D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under paragraph (1)(B), the Commission shall weigh all environmental effects, including significant environmental effects, to the extent any significant environmental effects can be practicably mitigated under the threshold described in paragraph (2)(D) and determine whether the benefits of the proposed action outweigh such environmental effects.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9443CD491C3D4FD1BBB584FD3D01BDA6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event the Commission finds that the proposed action is or will be required by the present or future public convenience and necessity under subsection (e) despite any significant environmental effects that cannot be practicably mitigated, the Commission shall provide a detailed explanation as to why the Commission finds the proposed action to be nevertheless required by the present or future public convenience and necessity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E784DF7EB234213A00AC5C9B8D4CCF8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HD11EA9EECB9E4FB3A0D04F04E919238B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Certificate</header><text>The term <term>certificate</term> means a certificate of public convenience and necessity described in subsection (c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA178A011B0204D06A2962C0EFEB2FBE5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Environmental effect</header><text>The term <term>environmental effect</term> means an effect caused by a proposed action on the environment and climate change.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD929787233A94B4C9412A337C3CE1AC4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means any population of color, community of color, indigenous community, or low-income community that experiences a disproportionate burden of the negative human health and environmental impacts of pollution or other environmental hazards.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2459DCC20BF74D36B467C2E07FB388C3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Proposed action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>proposed action</term> means a proposed service, sale, operation, construction, extension, or acquisition, as described in subsection (e), in an application for a certificate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

