<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6CD41C35047F417582AB9A503A8C4485" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1134 IH: Celebrating the 100th anniversary of the American Shore and Beach Preservation Association.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1134</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating the 100th anniversary of the American Shore and Beach Preservation Association.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the year 2026 marks the centennial of the American Shore and Beach Preservation Association (ASBPA), which has, for a century, advanced a science-guided commitment to coastal restoration and protection;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1926, in Asbury Park, New Jersey, the ASBPA’s visionary leaders sought to establish a forum <quote>where the novice and he who has long wrestled with these problems can seek more light; where the man of science and the statesman can exchange ideas and collaborate together; where idealist and lover of nature and the economist can arrive at a mutual understanding; where landscape artist and philanthropist can find an outlet for their activities,</quote> thereby fostering collaboration and innovation for coastal stewardship;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the critical issues of shore and beach preservation—promoting community protection, a strong economy, ecological health, and recreation—remain as vital in 2026 as they were at the ASBPA’s founding;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas United States coastal communities and natural resources have benefitted from the ASBPA’s work in translating coastal science and engineering, guiding policy, and advocating for resilient shores and beaches over the past century; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, the ASBPA is celebrating its 100th anniversary: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H31CAFAFEAE164D3EAA5742FE6B5F5476"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H825EF4E9DFA7407E869CCFF61D529A51"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8E3143DE4F95465DB182390EDC45C59A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and celebrates the 100th anniversary of the ASBPA;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2325FB5D7A6E4EF891A341541BCAC295"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commemorates the centennial of the ASBPA, honoring a century of shore and beach preservation and progress; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EDD718475D04D70A5FE4014D3DEE553"><enum>(3)</enum><text>congratulates the leaders and members of the ASBPA on a century of dedication to our Nation’s shores and beaches and recognizes the enduring importance of its mission.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

