<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25A63-CHM-HG-RHD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3378 IS: Helping Undergraduate Students Thrive with Long-Term Earnings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3378</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish name, image, and likeness investment accounts for student-athletes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Undergraduate Students Thrive with Long-Term Earnings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HUSTLE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id87ed23cb8bf14a7dbb4ed5aa8ebf3436"><enum>2.</enum><header>NIL investment accounts</header><subsection id="idf5ea95e938424ea296af8a177827c317"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter F of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 70204 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>, is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8fa07d9974c4494af25db26d041d598"><part id="id4bae98d2716e42faa489e4ff895dd63a" style="OLC"><enum>X</enum><header>NIL Investment Accounts</header><section id="idcb371abcbed84354add69b70d64b0782"><enum>530B.<?LEXA-Enum 530B.?></enum><header>NIL investment accounts</header><subsection id="id80681cc327d0480d91341236369ba748"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>An NIL investment account shall be exempt from taxation under this subtitle. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the NIL investment account shall be subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable organizations).</text></subsection><subsection id="id58632492b3164bb88e45acd40f090e09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="id993e35cf5e004bc49e7bc444b3bee61e" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designated beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>designated beneficiary</term> means the eligible athlete who established the NIL investment account and is the owner of such account.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0bda68d8d8a45adb534536108b50024"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible athlete</header><subparagraph id="idd426da8a1fca41719c0da77c88d6caa6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible athlete</term> means an individual who—</text><clause id="idb57e3c18be4d44b79726729ea2086e31" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is enrolled as a student at a participating institution of higher education, and</text></clause><clause id="id7b5ce0fd07134cf89564e6026c39f559" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>participates in an amateur or collegiate athletic program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59e1c2efb24448f4bec3c9a9b2eb9c69" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Secretarial authority</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall have the authority to—</text><clause id="idd7ba829fea364e63be5b6d3e8c6ee9f2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>further define the criteria for participation in an amateur or collegiate athletic program for purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii),</text></clause><clause id="id99f8ccc482e14a2bb46874159eb31ea8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish procedures for verifying an individual's status as an eligible athlete, and</text></clause><clause id="iddae2cc6872cd4dfba8167424a3298b23" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>issue guidance regarding the application of the requirements described in subparagraph (A) in cases where an individual's enrollment or athletic participation status changes during a taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54a26348052346d7b5d637e2801f79d3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participating institution of higher education</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb271082b842d4b0db26632ab0696bbf2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>participating institution of higher education</term> means an institution of higher education which elects (pursuant to subparagraph (B)) to participate under this section and to comply with any requirements applicable to such institution of higher education under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd83a9885ba804050a5886c1ecb40823c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Election and revocation</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb091eb1e3c63408ea3ff7d51fa8a6dd0"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Election</header><text>Any election made by an institution of higher education to participate under this section shall be effective for the academic year with respect to which it is made and for all subsequent academic years and, once made, may be revoked only pursuant to clause (ii).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa93adac7a4949f69788657ce8b05509"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text>A revocation of an election described in clause (i) may be made by an institution of higher education only if—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb00413c1f16c4725b37a27ecb4a57f00"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such institution of higher education provides notice of such revocation to all eligible athletes enrolled at such institution of higher education, and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fe1a0ea27454f3db3cdd199a5cdeafb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such revocation takes effect no earlier than the first academic year beginning after the date which is 12 months after the date on which the notice described in subclause (I) has been provided.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0dc5081b140440599f98c857c5ffc3c"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Institution of higher education</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the same meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f7661bdda904238854daf3012927804"><enum>(4)</enum><header>NIL investment account</header><text>The term <term>NIL investment account</term> means a trust created or organized in the United States exclusively for the purpose of receiving contributions of qualified NIL income and providing distributions to the individual who is the designated beneficiary of the trust (and designated as an NIL investment account at the time created or organized), but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="id87af01a288ec4e0e93f0f03959eab244"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No contribution will be accepted—</text><clause id="idd1aef6d9cb174ab3b59d4c8af5e37153"><enum>(i)</enum><text>unless it is in cash and is made by an eligible athlete from qualified NIL income, or</text></clause><clause id="id4d70c51646134256baf2dcd6ef56c0b9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except in the case of rollover contributions, if such contribution would not be permitted under paragraph (6).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id587193bbcf6744ba92ab401501bb14ce"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The trustee is a bank (as defined in section 408(n)) or another person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which that person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a860a4d9bc7421f9e2b763a2749b7e3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>No part of the trust assets will be invested in life insurance contracts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45783d886b234a329e0769266b3833e0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The assets of the trust shall not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8d00447d005455088ff2d32efb2aeea"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified NIL income</header><text>The term <term>qualified NIL income</term> means any income received by an eligible athlete that is derived from the use of such athlete's name, image, or likeness, including endorsements, appearances, social media content creation, and licensing arrangements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0997d765e8e45bc841e731e12e3b927"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Contribution limitations</header><text>No contribution will be accepted to an NIL investment account for any eligible athlete—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd66a159e87804c8da6fb2a4d82738105"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which, for any taxable year, is in excess of the dollar amount determined under section 2503(b) for the calendar year in which such taxable year began, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e586f7081dd462682c3afe003ad7b05"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after the end of the fifth taxable year in which such athlete—</text><clause id="idef510eecf5b041c5a20104b379d633a7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has received qualified NIL income, and</text></clause><clause id="id3ebb8309d9bb44128600ead36013d438"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was enrolled at a participating institution of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd642ff4ebc0845c6a9dbda7fc1aeec11"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Treatment of contributions</header><text>With respect to any qualified NIL income received by an eligible athlete which is contributed to an NIL investment account, at the election of such eligible athlete, gross income shall not include such qualified NIL income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c035d99ed81447fa8986f567400697a"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Treatment of self-employment taxes</header><subparagraph id="id33cbd744e36f4071aa75edbe3380f228"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of chapter 2 (relating to tax on self-employment income), any qualified NIL income contributed to an NIL investment account for which an election has been made pursuant to paragraph (7) shall not be taken into account as net earnings from self-employment (within the meaning of section 1402(a)) for the taxable year of contribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id987f19b79a0e46d29439d36d04b411d9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Distributions</header><text>Any distribution from an NIL investment account that is includible in gross income under subsection (c)(1) shall be treated as net earnings from self-employment (within the meaning of section 1402(a)) for purposes of chapter 2 in the taxable year of distribution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5f3dfba11b64bb19bf9d4ccd7d93812"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 529(b) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7ff36bfd21bb4ede9354703d89aedfc0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tax treatment of distributions</header><paragraph id="id718a6be435bd4450b1977b4ef7420003"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any distribution from an NIL investment account shall be includible in the gross income of the distributee in the manner as provided under section 72 to the extent not excluded from gross income under any other provision of this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id507eaf3cf29b4f51b5b30accc3c4367a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tax treatment of distributions</header><subparagraph id="ide68f6abad6464d1c8123272cc51c1aea"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of applying paragraph (1), a distribution shall be treated as—</text><clause id="id32cae05f55ca4b16b35d9e088cbbe3de"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includible in gross income and taxed as ordinary income if made before the date on which the designated beneficiary—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd56c184028dc44c0bb579f642821a60a"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">graduates from a participating institution of higher education (as provided in subparagraph (D)), or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d4f30a3b19149278fabf3dc30ce39d3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transfers from a participating institution of higher education to a non-participating institution of higher education (as provided in subparagraph (E)), and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6eecb0a01221432d8c4b3f0c3fe77651"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includible in gross income and taxed at the rate applicable to long-term capital gains under section 1(h) if made on or after the date on which the designated beneficiary—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4cc7ae7f8c24786ae818dd55fd9f781"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">graduates from a participating institution of higher education (as provided in subparagraph (D)), or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf91c4bd99f1b4f2782d121f5c604ebb8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transfers from a participating institution of higher education to a non-participating institution of higher education (as provided in subparagraph (E)),</text></subclause></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">but, for purposes of clause (ii), only to the extent that such distribution does not exceed the limitation described in subparagraph (B) for the taxable year.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44abb939d26342d3a8371d11c21e21c0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on preferential tax treatment</header><clause id="id0d1849cba71e490dbcc22bf809aa0d6f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of distributions from an NIL investment account that may be taxed at the rate applicable to long-term capital gain under subparagraph (A)(ii) during any taxable year shall not exceed the amount described under section 1(h)(1)(B)(i) for an individual described in section 1(c).</text></clause><clause id="id6cca1d1d59c54750b30e0848edb603d1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Excess amounts</header><text>Any distribution exceeding the limitation under clause (i) shall be includible in gross income, taxed as ordinary income, and (except in the case of a qualified distribution described in paragraph (3)(B)) subject to the additional tax under paragraph (3)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57bd3cfa93754e8f851f5686d1f117bb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Student transfers between institutions</header><clause id="idcda82330dc5b4db59361be31476c8eab"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a designated beneficiary who transfers from one participating institution of higher education to another participating institution of higher education (referred to in this subparagraph as the <term>subsequent institution</term>), the graduation date for purposes of this section shall be the date on which the designated beneficiary graduates from the subsequent institution.</text></clause><clause id="idf1dc4bbc5a5041e8894d9bffd92728e5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text>A designated beneficiary who transfers to a subsequent institution shall notify the trustee of the NIL investment account of such transfer within 60 days of enrollment at the subsequent institution. The subsequent institution shall, upon the request of the designated beneficiary, confirm such enrollment to the trustee of the NIL investment account.</text></clause><clause id="idc9be8ee0583546aeb533ed32034fa0dd"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Multiple transfers</header><text>The rules of this paragraph shall apply to designated beneficiaries who transfer between multiple participating institutions of higher education, with each subsequent institution being treated as the relevant institution for purposes of determining the graduation date.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id312c26faaee84e79a973bcf4730cfc9b" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Certification of graduation</header><text>The participating institution of higher education from which the designated beneficiary graduates shall transmit documentation of the designated beneficiary's graduation directly to the trustee of the NIL investment account. The Secretary shall prescribe the form and manner of such certification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida33661b04c90481091e38369e3c9a6cd"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Transfer to non-participating institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a designated beneficiary who transfers from a participating institution of higher education to a non-participating institution of higher education, the participating institution of higher education shall notify the trustee of the NIL investment account of such transfer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc3491da594b4850a6c071ae664c7f83"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional tax for distributions not used for qualified expenses</header><subparagraph id="id2baca8763a1c451492dfd391f98d7fbe"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The tax imposed by this chapter for any taxable year on any taxpayer who receives a distribution from an NIL investment account—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09f7f43441784acea1cf9f411021e9d2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before the date on which the designated beneficiary graduates from an institution of higher education (as provided in paragraph (2)(D)), or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0634518929884aa29a94c163ac15fec2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a distribution described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii), which is in excess of the limitation under paragraph (2)(B)(i),</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall be increased by 10 percent of the amount which is includible in gross income, unless such distribution is a qualified distribution.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9559ec402d174df8bd5c94790a5d543d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified distributions</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a distribution shall be treated as a qualified distribution if—</text><clause id="idf7986683adb843659daabb7f74842626"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the distribution is made to a beneficiary (or to the estate of the designated beneficiary) on or after the death of the designated beneficiary,</text></clause><clause id="id2298594e1188470db31f4a4ab5389532"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the distribution is attributable to the designated beneficiary's being disabled (within the meaning of section 72(m)(7)),</text></clause><clause id="id5fbfe7b3e87e4bc2b318849f3251e4aa"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the distribution is used for qualified expenses of the designated beneficiary, or</text></clause><clause id="idf92810210201435e8eea27dbf50622b1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the distribution is part of a rollover contribution described in paragraph (4).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf9c35611db34760a4290b1826fd91e3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified expenses</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B)(iii), the term <term>qualified expenses</term> means expenses incurred by the designated beneficiary for any of the following:</text><clause id="idbb4c8c4d556147ae872d9d196a17865c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Career transition costs, including—</text><subclause id="id53551ebd43824183ac3233d8aa990384"><enum>(I)</enum><text>professional training, certification, or education costs,</text></subclause><subclause id="id0c0a7b5b6c3243c8baf65548423f5ec9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>moving expenses (as defined in section 217(b)) related to post-athletic career opportunities, or</text></subclause><subclause id="idcc164cb0b1c14d5795c4520842c5d03f"><enum>(III)</enum><text>professional services related to career planning and development.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6b3b4fabeff6405997eead2af5c76c02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Qualified higher education expenses (as defined in section 529(e)(3)) of the designated beneficiary.</text></clause><clause id="id4a88fcdabc3e4049bcc1c7697cc6e3f7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Qualified medical expenses (as defined in section 213(d)) of the designated beneficiary to the extent such expenses exceed 7.5 percent of the designated beneficiary's adjusted gross income for the taxable year in which such expenses are incurred.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id960fdfcf984a40de8d22ccff776572af"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Such other purposes as are determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54696c7962f2433aa830632966eea760"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Contributions returned before certain date</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the distribution of any contribution made during a taxable year if—</text><clause id="idc07a62b7d27649dc9caba7ceba82b3c5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such distribution is received on or before the day prescribed by law (including extensions of time) for filing such designated beneficiary's return for such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="id97670f029b2a44a8b4070251ba2fd41e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such distribution is accompanied by the amount of net income attributable to such excess contribution.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">In the case of such a distribution, for purposes of section 61, any net income described in clause (ii) shall be included in gross income for the taxable year in which such excess contribution was made.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ad0b6124efd4323885a1181f6486978"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Change in beneficiaries or programs</header><subparagraph id="ide302df341d8b4b04822b81c0b1d1ff1e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Rollovers</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to that portion of any distribution from an NIL investment account which, within 60 days of such distribution, is transferred into another NIL investment account for the benefit of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id25a35876e10c43a18df0e58791fd19a1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the designated beneficiary, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id590d674cc2764a58a0b575daf69e2723"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an eligible athlete who is a member of the family of such beneficiary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbdda3368a76463495306e00d2f58050"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Change in designated beneficiaries</header><text>Any change in the designated beneficiary of an NIL investment account shall not be treated as a distribution for purposes of paragraph (1) if the new beneficiary is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7871c14c0f78417089f7a48f09b95e44"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an eligible athlete for such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b034e11010f4d799021da24c0892fe6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a member of the family of the former beneficiary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7635c6c3d53645478207874346ca5bdb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on certain rollovers</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any transfer if such transfer occurs within 12 months from the date of a previous transfer to any NIL investment account for the benefit of the designated beneficiary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idab039f0ccc33445280f9f2c71a65f2f0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special rules for applying estate and gift taxes with respect to account</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2), (4), and (5) of section 529(c) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd89d081dcb804dc1a67efb16d201fecb"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Member of the family</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>member of the family</term> means, with respect to any designated beneficiary, an individual who bears a relationship to such beneficiary which is described in section 529(e)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf9eb2c632f34f4ebb6e05462294b85b"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Loss of NIL investment account treatment</header><text>If an NIL investment account is established for a designated beneficiary, no account subsequently established for such beneficiary shall be treated as an NIL investment account. The preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of an account established for purposes of a transfer described in paragraph (4)(A) if the transferor account is closed as of the end of the 60-day period referred to in such paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcae51fdc5d99433c93dd6a37e4688d31"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transition to retirement accounts</header><subparagraph id="id5df41700c9a5452eb161f7aeee0573d0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), an individual who has ceased to be an eligible athlete for at least 1 year may elect to convert their NIL investment account, in whole or in part, to—</text><clause id="idc3b45ee0e2d84eb4bdbfdffe81a852a1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual retirement account (as defined in section 408(a)),</text></clause><clause id="id7a2aebea10ae44499a86c3aa61e6806b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Roth IRA (as defined in section 408A(b)), or</text></clause><clause id="ide6ae985e6e5b4d78b41796f7f0296599"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other retirement arrangements as the Secretary may specify in regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd0caee7b2764b99a958799f2693dc16"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tax treatment</header><text>A conversion under subparagraph (A) shall be treated as a rollover contribution for purposes of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9eb51287e9924f82885959dce6520ae8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Lifetime limitation</header><text>With respect to any individual described in subparagraph (A), the amount of any conversion of any NIL investment account to any other account or arrangement described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of such subparagraph during any taxable year shall not exceed the excess (if any) of $35,000 over the aggregate amount of any prior conversions under this paragraph with respect to such individual for all prior taxable years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id14e857ad00a74986b9711e178d2f3c0d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of accounts</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2) and (4) of section 408(e) shall apply to any NIL investment account.</text></subsection><subsection id="id60df15500416409587019e09703712f4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Education requirements</header><paragraph id="id9caa41e483ff42c8bcd69115eab0bb91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The trustee of an NIL investment account shall make available to the designated beneficiary educational materials regarding—</text><subparagraph id="id8ef2627919784e7f9648b5ba94db9cc3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the benefits and rules of the NIL investment account,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd757ebb55aba4c5f9ad123855c32ec28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>basic principles of investing and financial planning,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e7e8e348e684edca4f7be96e9c23958"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the importance of long-term financial security, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id574f3cfc021e442eaf885f2de2eecd6a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other topics as the Secretary may specify in regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b8d39fff7c74d13b0273b52dae40c42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delivery of materials</header><text>The educational materials required under paragraph (1) shall be provided to a designated beneficiary—</text><subparagraph id="id224eef292abc4bd4a29fceac6b0bbdfd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>upon the establishment of an NIL investment account, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7896d8a877304d40a93c1a3d157f46b1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on an annual basis thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcb320d5d322a4a98a87a5087ebf3e2f8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations—</text><paragraph id="ida0ceba2e28bf4b79855caf1707cc1720"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to enforce the limitation described in subsection (c)(7),</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf464a44d8184b4ebeb88e6a2107d375"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing for the information required to be presented to establish an NIL investment account,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idead3064699c043f7a91a49f3bfa04de4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to identify additional qualified expenses pursuant to subsection (c)(3)(C)(iv),</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d244a6db9e94977a8530e30fa2ec9b2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to prevent fraud and abuse with respect to amounts claimed as qualified expenses,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8a8c6ad4aa24d70a24e92db774a690b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to ensure proper reporting and verification of NIL income sources,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d9addd998a046c1bdcb1f4b0aa1d9a7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to establish procedures for tracking the number of taxable years in which an eligible athlete makes contributions to an NIL investment account,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4870717e0fef42cbbdac7c2b050c4380"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to establish procedures for determining the annual limit on preferential capital gains treatment under subsection (c)(2)(B),</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id589b15528f9e4ccfba1626b0326711ea"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to establish procedures for the transition of NIL investment accounts to retirement accounts under subsection (c)(8), and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb79656020e6b4de3acc018ce9acac47a"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to allow for transfers described in subsection (c)(4).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idfbe516eedc3c42eb97053314a0bbac1a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of parts for subchapter F of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55ec2678a6774b4bb15de695cd963f83"><toc><toc-entry level="part" bold="off">Part X—NIL Investment Accounts</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideba474a128914be19f51255a8a0e6d27"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="idf14efc4201ea4adb94b53f262a59fae9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Student athlete sports agent reform</header><subsection id="id92cc3ac364684da3a7ee87980969e5b9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7801">15 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idfb4c054d859f4a758e66fea7bc2671ec"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7801">15 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb12e383822fd43618ddcec02b9b7f57e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d607bde80ec4951b7a24f296b66748a"><paragraph id="id9459761d0e9f4e27bed9315311bdb264"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency contract</header><text>The term <term>agency contract</term> means a written agreement—</text><subparagraph id="id23dacf43442c46979508e6af1f7ed95a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which a student athlete authorizes a person to negotiate or solicit on behalf of the student athlete a professional sports contract or an endorsement contract; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide38edfc43f5b413984c7e0e5e718d5de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="id96d32ea17c0240b6b12cd98bf81cf597"><enum>(i)</enum><text>states the name of each party to the agreement;</text></clause><clause id="id9d926ec41e934801a09d60b137cfb0e3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>states the term of the agreement;</text></clause><clause id="idd5cb2d121bed4e50922ef4a85b9fb97a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>states the registration information for the athlete agent; and</text></clause><clause id="id5b2bd759dcf84d9cab605124472ff423"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>states the fee or commission charged by the athlete agent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb02840fa62345dfa52b2a1574f0f2eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (9) as paragraphs (5), (7), (9), (11), (12), (13), and (14), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51002ec51dba4b39a5c5260e108e3612"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd217038f88840c6a5180e564260d1d1"><paragraph id="id822d76bb5683474abec5ed6c4ba0c157"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Athletic association</header><subparagraph id="idf4df8bf1cf80455fbf0accfc1fb79ee3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>athletic association</term> means any organization or other group organized in the United States that—</text><clause id="idab12295b74964cefb6bf24d13a5742ab"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has multiple conferences and institutions as members;</text></clause><clause id="id2019db8f82e54b5aa30544144d0c5f80"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sponsors or arranges college athletic competitions between those institutions;</text></clause><clause id="idff417a876b294daaa728d357465b9e11"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sets common rules, standards, procedures, or guidelines for the administration of college athletic competition; and</text></clause><clause id="id5bb7dc1357374ecf96df5d03764bdaad"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is not a conference.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bf8970cc3bb464888ce7827396385f9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>athletic association</term> includes—</text><clause id="ide7f52c7b2da5489e8765930eb4bdf036"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Collegiate Athletic Association; and</text></clause><clause id="idb891bf06d5de40e3a8af7ca0a65abc80" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other national intercollegiate athletic association.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida323cec748594b86aa766bf49a514130"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Athletic department</header><text>The term <term>athletic department</term> means a department at, or a component of, an institution responsible for managing one or more varsity intercollegiate sport programs.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14055a00ccb04c65b2f83e53707ed30f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5), as redesignated by subparagraph (B), the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2e00a4a7d22459997115c7021e5d445"><paragraph id="idfd7f3940ca2a46a2ab2c81d9e3c3bb08" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>College athletic competition</header><text>The term <term>college athletic competition</term> means any varsity game, meet, or other competition between or among athletic teams sponsored by institutions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb77b84f70fb49b3a79935578526ffe0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ca46a3ea6144f3a8524964d22c4b337"><paragraph id="id913d3f4cfc9f43f995b9c1fb851e5d8c"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Conference</header><text>The term <term>conference</term> means any organization that is not an athletic association and that—</text><subparagraph id="idfafc6a0f1f5545eda3be6600e3dd4725"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has 2 or more institutions of higher education as members; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b9b99268b204b5f9a756f0620b85054" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arranges championships for college athletic competition or sets rules for college athletic competition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c8a13398394479eb96f2249de155e43"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b9dcf4a8c854367870276c2ad96a73d"><paragraph id="id641d88e043334b938d11d1359b445ce9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>The term <term>institution</term> has the meaning given the term <term>institution of higher education</term> in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb84ac41e4cbb43339c2f4d4dc3dd3705"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id755c01008d72432d94561554f503e019"><paragraph id="id0bb60a74202941e0bdfbe595c2cc5486" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Varsity intercollegiate sport</header><text>The term <term>varsity intercollegiate sport</term> means a sport played at the intercollegiate level, administered by an athletic department, for which eligibility requirements for participation by student athletes are established by an athletic association.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2f9ce7a29c0432ab48f35b3c050628a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 3 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7802">15 U.S.C. 7802</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="idde6e096fc8dc482bb3bd76dffcf956b6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id627a7b3839e043feb129cc4725fe93d4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="id2a4a55ac744641129548b29dfbbab7d5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></clause><clause id="idec90c649b305494dadbcf9e0885aaa90"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9b4072b20534a1e9eaac2fdfa19d717"><paragraph id="id5b4db14d1ed043c1a4489fb611aba65c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>represent a student athlete for an endorsement contract without first entering into an agency contract;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f8f1aeec41a4299bd4a33269f7e9559"><enum>(5)</enum><text>represent a student athlete for an endorsement contract without the athlete agent first registering as an agent with a State and certifying to an athletic association governing the intercollegiate sport the student athlete participates in that the athlete agent is registered with a State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d63fc70dc294a51a2923776995fd98f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>charge a student athlete a fee in connection with an endorsement contract that exceeds 5 percent of the value of the endorsement contract;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31b78ec6a4794f3ba058d504d83409d2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>enter into an agency contract with an athlete for a term that extends beyond the eligibility of the student athlete to participate in intercollegiate sport;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c7810033ec940d995dcbb469fcbd8a4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>entice a student athlete to enroll at an institution, transfer to or from an institution, or declare an intent to transfer from an institution by misrepresenting the existence, nature, or value of a name, image, or likeness opportunity the athlete agent can arrange on behalf of the student athlete; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fb127c7e05b4b1da31b9a7e64f6d38d"><enum>(9)</enum><text>make a materially false, misleading, deceptive, or fraudulent representation as an athlete agent or in the application for registration as an athlete agent.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e9f8c143510463ebe1cb22ff8142891"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>Warning to Student Athlete: If you agree orally or in writing to be represented by an agent now or in the future you may lose your eligibility to compete as a student athlete in your sport.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idca79b0126d8c4c6eb25fc3d962fc23a4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 3 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47862340bcf34290ab09360ee3fc449a"><section id="ida63332e58aa44bae9ff892518181aad3"><enum>3A.</enum><header>Registration and other requirements of athlete agents and athletic associations</header><subsection id="id51664f2623184d16a1c33030cb2bd490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Registration requirement</header><text>Prior to representing a student athlete for an endorsement contract, a prospective athlete agent must register with a State.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide34386ba6ae0438496c398440335ad74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Registration established</header><text>An individual is deemed to be registered with a State for purposes of this section if the individual is—</text><paragraph id="id4a2ff25e2b254e3990c54a1101fce7e5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a registered professional sports agent with a professional sports league or players association, in good standing; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd51d9ef2d77c439d9e1b2879eb1c27ad"><enum>(2)</enum><text>registered and certified under the All State Uniform Agent Acts in the State in which the agent operates, in good standing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idad2250dc19324b3eabde9bd285cbec48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agent fee cap</header><text>Fees charged by an athlete agent in connection with an endorsement contract entered into by a student athlete shall not exceed 5 percent of the value of the endorsement contract.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide29dc35c09804a23bd34096ca29992f3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification to athletic associations</header><paragraph id="id42f922a8d3b0424ca9f641ee581fd454"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>An athlete agent that represents a student athlete participating in an intercollegiate sport governed by an athletic association must certify to the athletic association that the athlete agent is registered with a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4b975337e4a492686163fd79253e96d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>It is unlawful for an individual to certify to an athletic association that the individual is an athlete agent if the individual is not registered with a State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2b078a759d0a4a7d8c43b6ec92965cef"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements of athletic associations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf21e7ac4a4a479a9778d75bfbb60198"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Searchable registry</header><text>It is unlawful for an athletic association to operate without maintaining a publicly available website that includes a searchable database of athlete agents registered under subsection (a) and certified under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ad55f876b36415eae673a9089690ece"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Website</header><text>An athletic association shall include on a publicly available website a working link to, or information on how to locate, the website of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7509db055fb64dfbbab11f1ee628bad3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="ida996b9d2-cb1a-4b52-b765-4aa3e598f663"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida63332e58aa44bae9ff892518181aad3">Sec. 3A. Registration and other requirements of athlete agents and athletic associations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id7c1808a70af14378a15150fb608c1abe"><enum>4.</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subsection id="idb6ef5fc27e7b44ffa3b421fee2135e37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7801">15 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 5 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62f21f474e2d48d3ad940d38b385f163"><section id="id21bfe6d786e84be1a3174607b3fbea2e"><enum>5A.</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subsection id="ide2b900994d284f17a36c5645c6587530"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any current or former student athlete alleging a violation of this Act by an athlete agent (other than a violation of section 6(a)) may bring a civil action against such athlete agent in an appropriate district court of the United States or in an appropriate State court.</text></subsection><subsection id="id13cfa588ef534ba8bbc755d776ef92ac"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action brought under subsection (a) in which the plaintiff prevails, the court may award—</text><paragraph id="idd49382540c1f475a81b25308afbab2be"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actual damages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3fdb36ae4994503a1fa37908e60fc01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reasonable attorney’s fees and litigation costs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95b84fd40fd1407a9597ec2a614a41c3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>injunctive, equitable, or declaratory relief, that the court determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id777f6c23c5304c64b8b0dc1542d4d6a7"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Invalidity of pre-Dispute arbitration agreements and pre-Dispute joint action waivers</header> <paragraph id="ida8ea40d5354148e9bd35d49d0ec65a96"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no pre-dispute arbitration agreement or pre-dispute joint action waiver shall be valid or enforceable against a student athlete with respect to a dispute arising under this Act.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id08c43b13795045f59b490cf6329bfd0e">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Applicability</header>
 <text>Any determination as to whether or how paragraph (1) applies to any dispute shall be made by a court, rather than an arbitrator, without regard to whether the agreement or waiver that is the subject of the dispute purports to delegate such determination to an arbitrator.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="id5acebe150c294c1c8bee4aae7c693955">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
                                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="id3070ccece43947e29dc80ee50e392489"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Pre-dispute arbitration agreement</header> <text>The term <term>pre-dispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="id34f52b432b9740bd83e3b9819eef0ee0">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                                    <header>Pre-dispute joint-action waiver</header>
 <text>The term <term>pre-dispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement, whether or not part of a pre-dispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id8709ac5de2da4602811985c66501f922"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idc8e05e21-be92-4d1d-8424-1acd8bb504ba"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id21bfe6d786e84be1a3174607b3fbea2e">Sec. 5A. Private right of action.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

