<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR26004-29X-TS-C0V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3614 IS: Internet Application Integrity and Disclosure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3614</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260112">January 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require any person that maintains an internet website or that sells or distributes a mobile application that is owned, wholly or partially, by a foreign adversary country, by a foreign adversary country-owned-entity, or by a non-state-owned entity located in a foreign adversary country, or that stores and maintains information collected from such website or application in a foreign adversary country, to disclose that fact to any individual who downloads or otherwise uses such website or application.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HAC66DE5ADCE94105AB9F20171A8CD011"><section section-type="section-one" id="HBCD6222AB3DD432AAF0E30FBD29C06A2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Internet Application Integrity and Disclosure Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Internet Application I.D. Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC636F47F88EF4B738A1A22A65534626D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure requirements relating to ownership, storage, and maintenance of information in a foreign adversary country</header><subsection id="H2BA291D402DA4E928C1843ED178092DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure requirements</header><text>Beginning 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, any person who owns, controls, or distributes access to a covered service shall clearly and conspicuously disclose to any individual who downloads or otherwise uses the covered service the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddfd1bdace3d64849aa3c7801f747e672"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whether the covered service is owned, wholly or partially, by a foreign adversary country, by a foreign adversary country-owned entity, or by a non-state-owned entity located in a foreign adversary country.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id943221a1920b4f3b9b0aafe211db7260"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether information collected from the covered service is stored and maintained in a foreign adversary country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0dae9a537eec4b979f224f7cf9314dbf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Whether a foreign adversary country or a foreign adversary country-owned entity has access to such information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb13d3658c424fc0bae9f0eaf4a9859c"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">False information</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly disclose false information under this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a752f7faaec43478c6f4ea6aa0f1017"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id139CD7D17F8648198AE32C8A28471255"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered service defined</header><text>The term <term>covered service</term> means an internet website or a mobile application that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2AA3968D3EC542A69D9ED7B82EF3AC84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is owned, wholly or partially, by a foreign adversary country, by a foreign adversary country-owned entity, or by a non-state-owned entity located in a foreign adversary country; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id971D28172A224E018DADAD3AE23587D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stores and maintains information collected from such website or application in a foreign adversary country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id09889aa7b0b846e888006ba7dfe3e2ad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign adversary country</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary country</term> means a country specified in section 4872(f)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28A6A293DEB64F11BFECB40FD42BBB74"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individual</header><text>The term <term>individual</term> means a natural person residing in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3FF6BF0B08BB42B78866440798C7DAF8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-state-owned entity located in a foreign adversary country</header><text>The term <term>non-state-owned entity located in a foreign adversary country</term> means an entity that is—</text><subparagraph id="idC6751A8B5A3A4A98BEB71343EAD0B4FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>controlled (as such term is defined in section 800.208 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation) by any governmental organization of a foreign adversary country; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA8A5E29FE0914EDF8D54F99F15C1A99C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>organized under the laws of a foreign adversary country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4B2073138AA0415D97AAAC40E710BDFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="HAC285CB3A7B247188B704C65CE9EE13C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of this Act is a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H714D7A7153F44DF49FC8E56253F25509"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of the Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph id="H9D33EC4B0E1C49B38DD4AF68466FA0E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7453997EE21414393AD76DA12CE206F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person that violates this Act shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecff4c02f83c406a85f38d70f286caf3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Federal Trade Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

