<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAB04FB4F4AC54436A65EC927B73A0B93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8637 IH: Release Your Taxes Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8637</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require incumbent and aspiring Members of Congress to disclose their income tax returns, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD3C3B4A4D645457483413B8404B977B5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2AE4E8400C004B7599A77590FC654A99" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Release Your Taxes Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HCF479BDB940B424FB420A07AF4AC29BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure of Federal income tax return</header> 
<subsection id="H82ECE56ECFD54C2E9D96B293E5353D15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HCBC1D8A453924EDBAA363C4949A9934F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional officials</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional officials</quote> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H62C12E1611F64C15886ED1947AD546D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Clerk of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE85CA4430E24FD7914BB71AAFF32221"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93B050D6DA144A8E836D080BA99820FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional candidate</header><text>The term <quote>congressional candidate</quote> means a candidate, as such term is defined under section 301 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, who seeks nomination for election, or election, to the office of Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H632F95A2F4EA4811B469C3ACB86DD402"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>The term <quote>Member of Congress</quote> means a Senator or Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60B621E29F424253A3EF0CD4B7365955"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tax return filing</header><text>The term <quote>tax return filing</quote> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H1E7088C31444488E9497349634DD9624"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Form 1040 and Schedule A filed with a return of tax under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or the equivalent successor forms or schedules.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF22FD8AE6F174F7AAB065FD33D58A36A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An application or request for extension of the due date for return of tax under such Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H524279CA330A44A387B9D4FAAFA3E637"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The statement referred to in subsection (d)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD4D62F325D2424493466FDE52F471BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of tax return database</header><text>The appropriate congressional officials shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9D668C586D494E749C23CDB329D2145E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a database containing every tax return filing submitted to the appropriate congressional officials pursuant to this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF425CC1C02CA4A4297F60CB74263ED42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prescribe from time to time such rules necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEE9DAA63C1744024B388C8A4F81D0EC7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication of database</header><text>The appropriate congressional officials shall publish—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9D8D6516C37412491109045BA9E28D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the database established under subsection (b) on a website available to the general public under the authority of appropriate congressional officials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93DBB2DBB184487D86EFD3A2A848B4BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each tax return filing received by the appropriate congressional officials through the database within 5 business days after the date on which the appropriate congressional officials received the filing.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8CF213E43E0418FAD42A9E679FC0BD9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disclosure requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="H214FCC5467EF44B281BDB0ECA0ED44BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual shall submit to the appropriate congressional officials a tax return filing pertaining to the individual not later than 2 business days after the date of the filing of the tax return filing pursuant to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 if any of the following apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H51B5CDFBDCFA44CA9251AC18485D01D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The individual is a Member of Congress or a congressional candidate for any part of the tax year with respect to which the tax return filing pertains.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD80AC497C7874A81A3A1947B707BEEA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The individual is a Member of Congress or a congressional candidate for any part of the calendar year in which the individual files the tax return filing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35AFE1CCFB004EED9CDCB484CA601ADE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Change in office status after filing</header><text>An individual who is not a Member of Congress or a congressional candidate on the date that the individual files a tax return filing pertaining to the individual and becomes a Member of Congress or congressional candidate after such date in the same calendar year shall submit the tax return filing to the appropriate congressional officials not later than 30 days after the individual becomes a Member of Congress or congressional candidate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB7BB8CC0B9A4A609B2E44741B27DA4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Absence of tax return</header><text>An individual who would be subject to the requirements under paragraph (1) or (2) if the individual were to be required to file a return of tax under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to a tax year but is not actually required to file such a return for such tax year shall submit to the appropriate congressional officials a statement explaining that the individual is not required to file the return not later than the due date that would apply for filing the return.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCBC883850024DA484D101821519CE59"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Failure of compliance</header><text>The appropriate congressional officials—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF9CA982AC83D4AB7B910222C5D1B3896"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include promptly in the website referred to in subsection (c)(1) the name of any individual who does not comply with a requirement under subsection (d) notwithstanding a duty to comply with the requirement; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89D29620257F454DBD4D783DE0B8C418"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not remove the name of such individual from the website unless and until—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D75E7DC79F644C2B6034A3CE32CFBE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual complies with the requirement; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D9D79A059CE40649AF68C3F8972A6C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>more than 6 years have elapsed after the date on which the individual is no longer a Member of Congress or a congressional candidate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA7388D11F95C4261AB79E923FA50C0D8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transition provisions</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this section, an individual who is a Member of Congress or a congressional candidate on such date shall submit to the appropriate congressional officials any tax return filing that was filed in the calendar year of the date of the enactment that would have been required to be submitted to the appropriate congressional officials under subsection (d) if this section were in effect from the start of the calendar year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H44574C0DB7724D8296B8F8105C51D5BF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to a return of tax under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for a tax year that begins in 2025 or each succeeding year.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

