<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26571-Y5W-KF-TP5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 777 ATS: Designating May 1, 2026, as “United States Foreign Service Day” in recognition of the men and women who have served, or are presently serving, in the Foreign Service of the United States, and honoring the members of the Foreign Service who have given their lives in the line of duty.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 777</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260617">June 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating May 1, 2026, as <quote>United States Foreign Service Day</quote> in recognition of the men and women who have served, or are presently serving, in the Foreign Service of the United States, and honoring the members of the Foreign Service who have given their lives in the line of duty.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Foreign Service of the United States (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Foreign Service</quote>) was established through the enactment of the Act entitled <quote>An Act for the reorganization and improvement of the Foreign Service of the United States, and for other purposes</quote>, approved May 24, 1924 (43 Stat. 140, chapter 182) (commonly known as the <quote>Rogers Act of 1924</quote>), and is now celebrating its 102nd anniversary; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Rogers Act of 1924 established a career organization based on competitive examination and merit promotion;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the diplomatic, consular, communications, trade, development, security, public diplomacy, and commercial diplomacy that Foreign Service personnel perform constitute the first and most cost-effective instrument of the United States to protect and promote United States interests abroad, making America safer, stronger, and more prosperous;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the men and women of the Foreign Service and their families are increasingly exposed to risks and danger, even in times of peace, and many have died in the service of the United States; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas employees of the Foreign Service work daily—</text><paragraph id="id5098ef47263245bba025eeb113100dcd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure the national security of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fd82602ccaa4e31ad08c419b38bd506"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide assistance to United States citizens overseas;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd847f09838344369a525d71430bcd3a8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to preserve peace, freedom, and economic prosperity around the world;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaff8626084b74d518f9b6571a08cab86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote internationally recognized human rights and democracy and their positive relationship to United States security interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id237831e611074b25a90b24cd387818d0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to promote transparency and provide accurate information on international developments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id81c06dd143bb4a51814b7f30d427591a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to cultivate new markets for United States products and services, including energy exports, and develop new investment opportunities that create jobs in the United States and promote prosperity;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48fb9ca4efb54989b1b47fae8652e722"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to combat illegal trade in goods and services, including illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing, illicit financial flows, trafficking in persons, and illegal drugs;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b64a7a910974fcdb521477a38e99686"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to promote economic development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide67d45bba6134d6d89245908475531b8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to provide emergency and humanitarian assistance to respond to crises around the world and to fight disease;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the foreign affairs agencies and the American Foreign Service Association have observed Foreign Service Day in May for many years; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is both appropriate and just for the United States as a whole to recognize the dedication of the men and women of the Foreign Service and to honor the members of the Foreign Service who have given their lives in the loyal pursuit of their duties and responsibilities representing the interests of the United States and of its citizens: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id8a0e3123ad22483cb82de76c4149bb26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the men and women who have served, or are presently serving, in the Foreign Service of the United States for their dedicated and important service to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8c705cdd48a41d4829587d959c71e7f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the people of the United States to reflect on the service and sacrifice of past, present, and future employees of the Foreign Service of the United States, wherever they serve, with appropriate ceremonies and activities; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa408870d216473898191f3cc4671dd7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designates May 1, 2026, as <quote>United States Foreign Service Day</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

