<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H432E9081ACB14A7D9FC0B69F795D4D42" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7928 IH: Thermal Runaway Reduction Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7928</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue certain regulations with respect to the safe transportation of lithium-ion cells or batteries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA6F0CF49A764FE6B0725422C6E34C87" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1FEAD53E94964134B26B42E35CE3E4B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Thermal Runaway Reduction Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8A97B14868A84FDA9DD4CB4E097B2FF0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBF63F390C9D94CD9BA90D84B28CBAA90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lithium-ion cell or battery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lithium-ion cell or battery</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H302640D0F6D14670953D15D2812284F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a rechargeable electrochemical cell or battery in which the positive and negative electrodes are both intercalation compounds constructed with no metallic lithium in either electrode; but</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD1AA4BC09FC4A009F55AA56734A2444"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a cell or battery described in subsections (c) and (g)(2) of section 173.185 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBB37D6655AB46598C6BD65C4CB64344"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Thermal runaway</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>thermal runaway</term> means an uncontrolled increase of cell temperature caused by exothermic reactions inside cells and batteries, including lithium-ion cells or batteries.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE6E615698020497488C5BDEDAEBE8BB1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements for safe transport of lithium-ion batteries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall—</text> <paragraph id="H12F2BD45CCDD42B1B13E4104D1E11691"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with the United Nations Subcommittee of Experts on the Transportation of Dangerous Goods to revise the design tests in subsection 38.3 of the UN Manual of Tests and Criteria to develop an impact test for lithium-ion cells or batteries installed in transport units and transported under UN 3536 to allow improved ability to withstand forces experienced in transport accidents without going into thermal runaway;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70F5BBB20DED4FD78269B48AA1C3EFA3">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue such regulations as are necessary to amend section 173.185 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to require lithium-ion cells or batteries to be offered for commercial transport at a state of charge not exceeding 30 percent of the rated capacity of such cells or batteries (determined through the guidance and methodology under section 38.3.2.3 of the Manual of Tests and Criteria of the United Nations) and authorize the transportation of lithium-ion cells or batteries at a state of charge greater than 30 percent of the rated capacity of such cells or batteries only under conditions approved by the Associate Administrator for Hazardous Materials of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration in accordance with the requirements in subpart H of part 107 of such title;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA45A57AF24A4CBA8F5AA976699A1DD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue such regulations as are necessary or promulgate final guidance on the safe transportation of damaged, defective, or recalled lithium-ion cells or batteries, and such regulations or guidance shall include guidance on the packaging, movement, and disposal of damaged, defective, or recalled lithium-ion cells or batteries; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24C730AF72914CA8923945004745FA7E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">every five years review the regulations and guidelines under this section and update them, as appropriate, to account for other emerging batteries or cells that pose a risk of thermal runaway as a result from a fire during commercial transport.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDE01516E74C643F2BF941DE7C956EB7C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant program for innovative thermal runaway suppression strategies</header> 
<subsection id="H0141B796EB764D159502BE10953311F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Pipelines and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration shall conduct a program to provide grants to eligible entities to test and study—</text> <paragraph id="H74605CEC15474B449616B631B2194CB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of innovative technologies and methods to suppress thermal runaway in lithium-ion cells or batteries transported under UN 3536 in commercial transport units;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC407BC5165F748CB9384D4E2D73D6533"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the state of charge of a battery or cell being transported under UN 3536 on methods to suppress thermal runaway in lithium-ion cells or batteries; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65FFB02076034C38B4D256DC8DCEA0D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods for emergency responders to verify the state of charge of a battery or cell being transported under UN 3536 experiencing thermal runaway as a result of a fire or crash during commercial transport.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48A55E7532AA4B928072DB147A862457"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Facilities that specialize in fire suppression testing shall be eligible to receive grants under this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H41844AB5E54D4C2EB9FA6B2781D5E321"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>In issuing grants under this section, the Administrator shall prioritize projects that test suppression technologies that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC0A02E371A994C84B1F2736E6BB9A18B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>do not contain perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8234A9182264D0895E426EB31992E07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are cost effective.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9DC577FD6AFB4936959EFE1AA09E31BC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing</header> 
<paragraph id="HAAA79F4EC9DD410CB174AFB14FAA34CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application period</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HFEA1D44D3DE14BD8A7E5DE1D8FD633E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>finalize grant eligibility requirements and begin soliciting applications not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H812149158E834F0BA856FD1F55D5A8DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide 90 days for entities to submit to the Administrator applications for such a grant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA68A583D4B31478A9B4E0C5ECF7DDDC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>select recipients of grants under this section not later than 180 days after the date on which solicitation begins under subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8D5DDBD8E6F46C2A5D4111B5EDD331C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in any case in which a deadline under subparagraph (A) or (C) is not met, submit to Congress a report containing any reasons either such deadline was not met.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9D328B192974D569D1F30E79BD6AD54"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Grant completion</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grant recipient shall conclude the project for which a grant is awarded not later than 18 months after funds are provided to such recipient.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE474474E9846420BA51F2E8809930849"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>In carrying out the program under this section, the Administrator shall ensure that each grant recipient, upon conclusion of an activity funded by a grant under this section, submits to the Administrator a report on the findings of any tests conducted pursuant to such grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7C0AE8AC80834A2AA4D7618508AD0E2A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the receipt of all reports required under subsection (e), the Administrator shall review the findings submitted by grant awardees and submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H10B67CC038C449F29FFF2DDEE27B201A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any findings related to the grant program under this section, including which fire suppression tools and techniques were found to be most effective at suppressing thermal runaway resulting from a lithium-ion cell or battery fire;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B987A7CFD7442C584FE0E4FE6FF5BF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the state of charge of a battery on the techniques and tools studied under the grant program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B85E6EA858F4AF39C41A9700E2DD21D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the best methods to verify the state of charge of a lithium-ion battery or cell after a nonconsumptive event and how that information can inform decisions about how to safely mitigate thermal runaway; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0F026C230B04D0295F1097C87089ECD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations on whether, based on such review, updated guidance or training of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration is necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2F1FDEC390A943DB8F7470A13B8419DA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAFC02166044F440DA9172A9A1CEA5012"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increasing access to thermal runaway suppression tools</header> <subsection id="H8C1E82850D4E40BF892ABDD2C462BF34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Lithium fire safety grants</header><text>Section 5107 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9B4A9792B3834C71876BFDFD8BB4E391" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H65BACF4532F040C1A0469D3C654B07A7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Lithium fire safety grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program making grants available to volunteer or career fire departments, or combination of such fire departments, for—</text> <paragraph id="H0852D34E160E469E9BBD2B84DFABEF10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>equipment, including blankets to suppress thermal runaway, portable fire suppression agents, and other equipment that the Secretary determines is appropriate, to support the suppression of thermal runaway resulting from the transportation of lithium-ion cells or batteries;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24450042B27C459AA9F772A72070BA08"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">field-deployed residual-energy assessment and cell-integrity diagnostics;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC4C4BFEB6314D009F576A6BDA1B85B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">environmental monitoring suites and runoff control to assist with cleanup after a thermal runaway event; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09D42E1AEC2F4558A4D7C2E90AFF67C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access and containment tools, over-pack systems, and packaging for damaged, defective, or recalled lithium-ion batteries or cells.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H192D4F48CF7E498CAF0B63BDBECFC8CD"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Timing of grant process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the process for each grant awarded under this section provides for the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB2D0EDCCBD2F4883936AEBCFD71C16B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A period of 90 days for entities to submit to the Administrator applications for such a grant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAB9F3605E8D4EC7A90809004AE89EDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Selection of the recipients of grants not later than 180 days after the date on which solicitation of such grants is initiated.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B390DBBE3A3414E9226AC0E8A438100"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall finalize grant eligibility requirements and begin soliciting applications for the grant program established under section 5107(j) of title 49, United States Code, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

