<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H382DC5D974D04DCEAC18AB9CE7C9D168" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8821 IH: No Bailouts for Cashless Bail Jurisdictions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8821</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Federal funds from being made available to a jurisdiction that substantially eliminates cash bail.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H09FD32871CDA493394C548BC89834F27" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H614619C314D740CCAA38F67D83A2BAB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Bailouts for Cashless Bail Jurisdictions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8B1949194B7141959779BC0E0123FA88"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal funds for jurisdictions with cashless bail policies</header> <subsection id="H05BF24567C944D709C5B862FE59968B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No Federal funds may be made available to a jurisdiction that the Attorney General determines has substantially eliminated cash bail as a potential condition of pretrial release from custody for a covered offense.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7525BBE563EB4C2390609DDC90F1B570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attorney general determinations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less than quarterly thereafter, the Attorney General shall make determinations on which jurisdictions have substantially eliminated cash bail for a covered offense and shall make such determinations, and an explanation of each determination, publicly available.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8D7330D046BF443084ED56A21CBD4E86"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Reinstatement of federal funds</header> <text>A jurisdiction that the Attorney General determines has substantially eliminated cash bail for a covered offense may begin receiving Federal funds on the later of—</text>
        <paragraph id="H20C16599D751444F91C85C2C0EEEB416">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>180 days after the date on which the Attorney General first determines the jurisdiction has substantially eliminated cash bail for a covered offense; or</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC4CCDB75D80646AAB1B29A43CF233E2D">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the date on which the Attorney General determines that the jurisdiction no longer substantially eliminated cash bail for a covered offense.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H4601D5435D7149A0BE773AC9318CE7BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD6659C44EF9D4BD1B2ECB68D13D2D715"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cash bail</header><text>The term <quote>cash bail</quote> means any secured monetary conditions of release, including cash payments, secured bonds, or sureties, required by a court to guarantee a defendant’s appearance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B89E71C3E824435870CE56563EC7159"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered offense</header><text>The term <quote>covered offense</quote> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H3DF13A7F0E25485FBE4CE2C4E80DB2D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a crime of violence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB4BF406EDC8F4241B67E0D2ECDB3275F">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a sex offense;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C61BF2728954178907AC65F10E2AD2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an indecent act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DB5BED95E0549BDAE7D37A290C69B5A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a crime involving moral turpitude;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB22D9FE0C22D463EA589CF4D5FE46E19"><enum>(E)</enum><text>burglary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08D2B86B9F224051B60B412AD147A58B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>vandalism;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C64E0BAADE04BB884F0A2EAE65F0C18"><enum>(G)</enum><text>looting; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47E4528951304F8298475BDC4FA7E3E6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other criminal offense under Federal, State, or local law the Attorney General determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA4F801FAB4B4D6192913C5CBAFB2894"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Crime of violence</header><text>The term <quote>crime of violence</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 16(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC50189673F6148178D422CBF96065438"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sex offense</header><text>The term <quote>sex offense</quote> has the meaning given to that term in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20911">34 U.S.C. 20911</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94067496DBE94BFBBA50E41A0D7D7DAA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indecent act</header><text>The term <quote>indecent act</quote> means a criminal act under Federal, State, or local law involving sexually explicit conduct (as such term is defined in section 2256(2)(A) of title 18, United States Code).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EDCB884EA5C497D82EE7241E32A1047"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Burglary</header><text>The term <quote>burglary</quote> means a criminal act under Federal, State, or local law involving breaking and entering the dwelling of another person with the intent to commit larceny.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFFC05695ECF4171BBBF9D74FE9E3717"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Vandalism</header><text>The term <quote>vandalism</quote> means a criminal act under Federal, State, or local law involving the intentional defacing, damaging, injuring, or destroying property or real property.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H831F7A2FCDB24F31B419FA587992687B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Looting</header><text>The term <quote>looting</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H803F28A5C42747F783320933335DE645"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a criminal act under Federal, State, or local law involving participation in a riot (as such term is defined in section 2102 of title 18, United States Code); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA66F92E45784478C9241291A6BE11020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a criminal act under Federal, State, or local law involving knowingly or intentionally taking, destroying, or appropriating property belonging to another without the owner’s consent by force, threat, stealth, breaking and entering, or other means during a riot, civil unrest, or a natural disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

