<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09E50D1D6C724FCA8198A731DAE81F54" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7712 IH: Reforestation, Nurseries, and Genetic Resources Support Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7712</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to collaborate with various entities, and to establish a grant program, as a means of supporting nurseries and seed orchards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF6C276CFC680435C88FF1A709FA4378F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0AA28D4EF9DE4677ACF10B969E6224B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reforestation, Nurseries, and Genetic Resources Support Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RNGR Support Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA01900ECAD3346D3BE326FCF62125F42"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nursery and seed orchard support</header> <subsection id="H9D7E8D222C6B44F0925BA852F7B52321"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Partnerships, collaboration, and other assistance in support of nurseries and seed orchards</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF7D4EFCC538F492E8618B9D5CB71FB55"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partner with Federal and State agencies, Indian Tribes, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, and private nurseries to provide training, technical assistance, and research to nursery and tree establishment programs that support natural regeneration, reforestation, agroforestry, and afforestation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A4BAE5A3C504EAF81D2A3092E93F7B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote information sharing to improve technical knowledge and practices, and to better understand reforestation needs, relating to seeds or seedlings, effects of climate change, tree genetics for resistance to pathogens and drought, and other issues necessary to address all facets of the reforestation supply chain;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9A9B90445284C35B56DC91D784F2544"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical and financial assistance to international nursery and tree establishment programs through the Forest Service International Programs, the Institute of Pacific Islands Forestry, and the International Institute of Tropical Forestry;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02F598D26280453CBBD408720FF42ABC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate with other relevant Federal departments and agencies, including the Foreign Agricultural Service of the Department of Agriculture, the United States Agency for International Development, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and international organizations, including the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, to provide technical and financial assistance related to nurseries and reforestation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84CDD2E7C73544DE8126ED4D0768F490"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate the efforts of the Department of Agriculture—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC7EBF87E1DB49B8944D3205A2F7D469"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address the challenges associated with the reforestation supply chain, including workforce development; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49682B7CAA544F6B8D59F42309E85258"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to leverage economic development assistance for work with private nurseries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AAD89350B7A4713AB3887910D51D0F9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand reforestation supply chains through science and research, seed collection and storage, workforce development, and nursery infrastructure and operations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81B3E7B6821B4E7587B651A205CB631B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shorten the timeline for approval of permits to collect seeds on National Forest System lands.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H022F030615474409A347BEC6EFF79590"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nursery and seed orchard grant program</header> <paragraph id="H3FCE5CE307C44FF0B729E5BC44F54882"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible recipients to support nurseries and seed orchards.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF611060F94341E7BEDAFEFDFB57E440"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowable uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of grant funds under paragraph (1) may use such funds to carry out a project comprised of 1 or more of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7373031A55024EE6BD99CDDF74164A81"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development, expansion, enhancement, or improvement of nursery production capacity or other infrastructure—</text> 
<clause id="H8B1540ADE0A04F1E807D480165DD123E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to improve seed collection and storage;</text></clause> <clause id="H12FB19C19AB94DC4BA865EA164B430D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to increase seedling production, storage, and distribution; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0C92FC1EB2674D5FA09F6A812E1A37D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to enhance seedling survival and properly manage tree genetic resources.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H445915A2B2AD4B10A40C69D17D02FFAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment or expansion of a nursery or seed orchard, including by acquiring equipment for a nursery or seed orchard.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H154C74EDAFE8405795AD324220B95B20"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development or implementation of quality control measures at nurseries or seed orchards.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5DA618AA0DF4BF7B6C92894E033941D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The promotion of workforce development within any facet of the reforestation supply chain.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6DB49780D8F430D85A514135807839F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other activity determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD9D7CE2C38B44C52940B77734EB062FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reforestation Trust Fund</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of section 303 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/451">Public Law 96–451</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1606a">16 U.S.C. 1606a</external-xref>), of amounts in the Reforestation Trust Fund established by subsection (a) of that section that are not otherwise obligated, the Secretary may obligate not more than $5,000,000 for each fiscal year to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0D827717DF248009454F546925B09B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H32452DFE2BA940A1BE5544DB1052E66F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text>The term <term>eligible recipient</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE35AD21D3895455A913516ADF9B52C27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State forestry agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0B0BD283B4E46EE847D2548741C01E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H07F1288B620D4DBFB91DF110E846BDED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a private nursery that has experience growing high-quality native trees of appropriate genetic sources in bareroot or container stocktypes specific for reforestation, restoration, or conservation, including native plants and seeds that are of cultural significance to Indian Tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A537F6398B541C8897203D60D99FA8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Forest System</header><text>The term <term>National Forest System</term> has the meaning given the term in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27ED7079D53642E6B19A619AFC14E90F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nursery</header><text>The term <term>nursery</term> means a tree or native plant nursery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB727CB7D16C24EFC843B748E5E8FFABE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Seed orchard</header><text>The term <term>seed orchard</term> means a tree or native plant seed orchard.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE082449799CF4DA5A96759400DC171F9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

