<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF797727702444EB4A6FB07B834528C46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>106 HR 6354 IH: Cut the Burden, Keep the Benefits Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6354</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration to establish a hotline to receive notifications of burdensome Government actions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8036D65025744B20B64F9BE7D07BB17A" style="OLC"><section id="H8266277180904385A0A25007FC894278" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cut the Burden, Keep the Benefits Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H411D6D8F0CF54212924664A22F5C4133"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of hotline</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/305">Public Law 94–305</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/634c">15 U.S.C. 634c</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H316E32923DF2498293C7DE72E06306A0" style="OLC"><subsection id="H6127F2DB0479437F9B4899FE3C45F850"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hotline</header><paragraph id="H7C228D866F8642BEADE8F858C9A64D80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief Counsel for Advocacy shall—</text><subparagraph id="H77A3BF6F8932485E8A3FC03F407EE246"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operate and maintain an email address to be known as the <quote>Cut the Burden, Keep the Benefits Hotline</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Hotline</quote>) to receive notifications from small businesses, small organizations, and small governmental jurisdictions relating to Government actions affecting such small businesses, small organizations, or small governmental jurisdictions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51FA2758CF5148F9BFA1F6E8C266F2C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a website providing the email address or including a submission form or phone number in a manner that is easily accessible; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H753FE767D1E74ECB9B3304AD2D617304"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit information from small businesses, small organizations, and small governmental jurisdictions related to Government actions, and when there is a notification related to a rule that will have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small businesses, small organizations, or small governmental jurisdictions, or any combination thereof, consider regulatory alternatives that will achieve the goal of the agency with respect to such action while minimizing the burden on such entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09ED49AE7F0B462AAEFBE5F709BD3442"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Chief Counsel for Advocacy shall submit to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and Congress a report on the Hotline that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H38784605BD2847BF80883E9F3296CE8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Government actions for which Hotline notifications are most frequently received, including the affected industry sectors for such Government actions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0E8F73D08144710B8A9594FD17EBBA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each such Government action that is a rule—</text><clause id="HCDA0D5D040814248888B5F759312FDEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the dollar amount of the regulatory benefits of such rule as determined by—</text><subclause id="HAA63FB9F82CB416989E5B2D3BEE054AB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Management and Budget in the most recent report containing an analysis of such rule submitted by the Director under section 624 of the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1105">31 U.S.C. 1105</external-xref> note); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H0798A13C6494476DBE9A4E5FCF79F153"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the agency that issued such rule; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6DF7B8D05F4A41C0871DEE18C67229BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the dollar amount described in clause (i) is determined by the agency that issued such rule, a description by the agency of the regulatory benefits of such rule in qualitative or monetized terms;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7458B6FC34F748C7A0932A2A9B00444F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each such Government action that is related to an Executive order or Presidential proclamation that is related to tariffs—</text><clause id="H999CBB466C364F78A5BC304280DD0AAD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the specific number of Hotline notifications;</text></clause><clause id="H2F30B29EF64E474F9FDD0FC7E8B605DE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the costs imposted on small businesses, small organizations, and small governmental jurisdictions, including paperwork burdens and fees; and</text></clause><clause id="HF7E06B4B0A1049C294DD1419FF3208E3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the actions taken by the Chief Counsel to address each such Government action;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CA6F9AE5B064D759E0B2AA4B37E76C5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a summary of all the Hotline notifications received, including, for each such Hotline notification, whether the notification is related to a rule or other Government action and the geographic area and the type of organization or affected industry from which the Hotline notification was sent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF76B83DDCA4AF28B9ACC83188243CE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of—</text><clause id="HC0727E4003F44F789201174EC1983991"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each type of entity, disaggregated by small businesses, small organizations, small governmental jurisdictions, and representatives of such entities, that submitted a Hotline notification, and the rule for which each entity submitted such notification; and</text></clause><clause id="H5AE5DABAF8A44E9EA94234D8CFB87A47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each Government action for which such entity submitted a Hotline notification;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E9EB1D69364D9AAFA5F568ACACB496"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for Government actions that minimize of such Government actions the burden on small businesses, small organizations, and small governmental jurisdictions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6E8DA50297E48389356E2333F92E0CC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a summary of actions taken by the Chief Counsel to address the Government actions described in subparagraph (A) and the Hotline notifications described in subparagraph (D), including any such Government actions or notifications for which the Chief Counsel submitted comments or analyses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B1657FEE84D4AB6B2291D2E7F129CB0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H8B1EC867A1EE42D7AA11A30933AC606B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Government action</term> means an action by the Federal Government, including rules, Executive orders, statutes, regulations, and Presidential proclamations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA18B95E1A8204C33BE1BF683124BA7C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terms <term>rule</term>, <term>small business</term>, <term>small organization</term>, and <term>small governmental jurisdiction</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 601 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

