<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A1AF98E5D84470D806FA5BA5086A5B5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6969 IH: Rural Investment for Producers and the Environment (RIPE) Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6969</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to establish a program that provides payments to producers for carrying out conservation practices in selected eligible watersheds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1BEE8BD7F07F4B28A01A03E3AE0F1477" style="OLC"><section id="HEF65C70ED3714D2B9668E0EB9D27278C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Investment for Producers and the Environment (RIPE) Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD097A596CCF34D3EBB50B965E5FF1A7A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 5 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3839bb">16 U.S.C. 3839bb et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1240M the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H110FEC6F2F3C463A92FB18AF44CB87C9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H5CF3548298EB4419878B7F415BD74733"><enum>1240N.</enum><header>Demonstration program</header><subsection id="H8D9B75EC35AF48759936933DC2D105EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCA5DAC28F2C248AFAC4DCF43C1694960"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible watershed</header><text>The term <quote>eligible watershed</quote> means a watershed with significant agricultural production, as determined by the Secretary, that is located in a State or a United States Territory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD67C1313B1F4626B6AC718CB96CA7C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <quote>program</quote> means the program established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8915F4253F6455CAC8FAA4F6023AEAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selected practice</header><text>The term <quote>selected practice</quote> means a practice that has one or more environmental benefit, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7C2A643AB8344672B7556E6E6E4D0C8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improved water quality and quantity, soil health, air quality, climate resiliency, and biodiversity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B7BB026B5204236A8DE731A4CC33DDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased agricultural yields;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CE8AAD37B6F4EE891B2EED6AB96ED4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>restored or enhanced wildlife habitat; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABD37902CAB64D60BA13832EA20DAC57"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other environmental benefit, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D8FD8549F3B4D5184E84937216B874B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Demonstration program</header><paragraph id="H5D9CAD3E7ADA49D3906E982C7F064E84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary enters into a contract with a producer to implement a selected practice on an eligible watershed, selected in accordance with paragraph (2), for the purpose of demonstrating the effects of implementing such selected practice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66BF8765F9A94D49BD31C935CFA071F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible watershed</header><subparagraph id="H7E45E7D2164846629B0FD1329A6D749C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, in carrying out the program, select—</text><clause id="HA909CEA18D76401EACFDB0A32F5FC1BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not more than 2 eligible watersheds in a State or territory; and</text></clause><clause id="H230AA81469014DD8B3E425F7243ACB21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not more than 30 eligible watersheds total.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H180874B3E5C24E28B4438BA95107D452"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Watersheds for Tribal lands</header><text>In selecting an eligible watershed under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall not include an eligible watershed that serves Tribal lands towards the limitation described in clause (i) of such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA21FD88C0394F7197D6BFB281EACB1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contract terms</header><paragraph id="HFA4B295C6932450D8380136427EC2397"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In entering into a contract with a producer under the program, the Secretary shall provide direct payments to the producer for adopting and implementing a selected practice on an eligible watershed selected under subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3937257DE90A43C6A07DC8E7C547EEA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term</header><text>A contract under this subsection shall be for a term of not less than 3 years and not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21F8BAC3F4B94A1EA89B5BBCA383CEC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Under a contract entered into under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H59FBE04DB19B448093DF5C29BF8F6D78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide to program participants the opportunity to enhance or adopt additional existing conservation practices to improve environmental outcomes given the best available and accessible technology and practices, as appropriate for the size and type of operation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDB7B34E7E6C47A4902CE843A2A180D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not prohibit a producer under the program from participating in, and receiving compensation from, an environmental services market; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C338B9DBA1C4EC0A4B79CDB4DD3B505"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent practical, use performance-based metrics and tools to—</text><clause id="H62299C7770144C8F8565D68D11765F9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assess outcomes of implementing selected practices; and</text></clause><clause id="H1B3EAE73CF9D4E20AAFCF4DA8559F08D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the payment amounts that are determined pursuant to subsection (d).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30D1703A818D4429B77BEF6E9318ADC2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payments to producers</header><paragraph id="H93D4F7AA0125404B9938ECE41ABD63E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining amounts for payments pursuant to subsection (c), the Secretary shall establish an amount on a per acre and per animal unit basis each year that reflects—</text><subparagraph id="HB955BDDE5A08429C9485494C7F011C0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cost of adopting, installing, completing, managing, and improving a selected practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB41D18E32FC048FC8E049EE3CC2FCAE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>income foregone by the producer, if applicable, to address—</text><clause id="H33D22DEB8CF24B219CB3AB1E9CA67725"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increased economic risk;</text></clause><clause id="H6416BE07E7A14556AC59E9FDF8342A79"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>loss in revenue due to reductions in yield; and</text></clause><clause id="H743909FE0AB14F32A41655FFAD939ACB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>economic losses during transition to new practices;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62CCD57743DC4000A278B58565C655C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>compensation to ensure long-term continued management, maintenance, and improvement of the selected practice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4778E9CE75CC44E6819B196A5EFD4930"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the environmental benefit, any greenhouse gas emissions reductions, and carbon sequestration derived from implementing the selected practice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CB315BC6DB340F0B6B62BE1FC230CA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of payment amount</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Rural Investment for Producers and the Environment (RIPE) Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall, after a producer adopts selected practices pursuant to the contract entered into under subsection (b), review, and adjust if determined necessary, payment amounts provided under subsection (c) with respect to accounting for agricultural producer costs, associated technology, and any other factors as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC78EBA23392E4396ADAD3C6AA9F67594"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rate for certain farmers and ranchers</header><text>In the case of a producer that is a limited resource or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher, the Secretary shall increase the amount that would otherwise be provided to a producer under this subsection to 15 percent above the otherwise applicable rate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E5623AD06C64515838B428C076C7D84"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties of Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Rural Investment for Producers and the Environment (RIPE) Act, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practical—</text><paragraph id="H31112FDD8CA14EF4929162EF8764C03E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implement a simple application and acceptance process, administered by the Natural Resources Conservation Service, to approve applications, subject to the availability of funding, submitted by producers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0342D9D7CBFF41FBBA02DD6ED3AF595F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure 10 percent of funds are reserved for contracts with producers who are limited resource or socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers through targeted outreach and education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEAA04F1E1BB42E2BDF8D83763AB8D44" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a minimum contract payment for contracts entered into with producers as an incentive to increase accessibility to the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC86B868C6715461D949D751E4478BAC9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to the applicable producer, that has entered into a contract under this section, for implementing and developing a comprehensive conservation plan for any acres of land or animal units related to the eligible watershed selected by the Secretary under subsection (b)(2) that takes effect between the second year of the applicable contract and the end date of such contract; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E72C83616E14A848637BED6A0460DCE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>authorize technical assistance to be provided by—</text><subparagraph id="HE19CF79897F540FCA3BA7EBA0D5AC6F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State or local government, including conservation districts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58D2EC9176A648E8A66478F69BB82450"><enum>(B)</enum><text>third-party providers, including agricultural producer associations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC54E0733BAEC4C16BEC1136D4F54D69C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>commercial entities, including farmer cooperatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD844B39765CF4EF49F71B2DFD1497D14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>nonprofit entities with technical expertise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F4A245CDC3447819382B8C9AE2D84D1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than December 30, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives summarizing the accomplishments of the program, including the number of operations, acres and animal units enrolled, the accrued environmental benefits, the additional and net greenhouse gas benefits accrued, participant demographics, and limitations to adoption, especially within the animal feeding industry.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB6B9C3AA7C63489AA570CDFE38789808"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Of the funds from the Commodity Credit Corporation, the following funds shall be made available until expended:</text><paragraph id="H0288C0C44268408BAD91462BEE9E907F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, for the purpose of establishing program regulations, policy, and administrative procedures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA91C79A0FDB54BCDB971B87020271B7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$150,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2029.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

