<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25C39-81G-T2-17R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3085 IS: Firearm Access During Shutdowns Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3085</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251030">October 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure that certain operations, functions, and services of the Federal
            Government relating to enforcement of firearms laws and firearm export licensing
 continue during a lapse in appropriations.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id2a8aa98352da4bbfab8ba45d48612c54" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Firearm Access During Shutdowns Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="S1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuation of certain firearm-related operations during Government
 shutdowns</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb16fa069f4894f49b46fe290069e8d87"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The operations, functions, and services described in subsection (b) shall be deemed to relate to an emergency involving the safety of human life or the protection of property for purposes of section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, and the employees carrying out those operations, functions, and services shall be deemed to be excepted employees, as defined in section 1341(c) of that title.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9202285b2d74612bf3fcee06c90701f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operations, functions, and services</header><text>The operations, functions, and services described in this subsection are the operations, functions, and services of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1870a60482b440978c89539d5886123b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Instant Criminal Background Check System of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, including the processing of background checks in support of the operations of the Directorate of Enforcement Programs and Services of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12c7ae24b9414a77a67cbee872cbf06c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Directorate of Enforcement Programs and Services of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a98c320961d4f3bad5f8ad55336c6b1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce relating to firearms and firearm-related products, including activities related to processing of applications for export licenses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a77db118a1e47109af7a8efc566311b" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls of the Department of State relating to firearms and firearm-related products, including activities related to processing of applications for export licenses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


