<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDAD635FD87B74B0EB451102271EAEEA5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7549 IH: National Council on African American History and Culture Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7549</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a National Council on African American History and
      Culture within the National Endowment for the Humanities, and for other
      purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDE5C8AD4CF5C46678CF8CED573945D54" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD31D7677F31B42AEB2533CEFC252DF2F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Council on African American History and Culture Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H7B1CB50AA4C04E7A83EE4DA1EA4F5D04">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Council on African American History and Culture</header>
      <subsection id="H5E48EC1EF17A415EB5E1A3E1E0DEE54B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Establishment</header>
 <text>There is established in the National Endowment for the Humanities a National Council on African American History and Culture (referred to in this section as the <quote>Council</quote>).</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HFD5719065F6543E8BA906AF3655C1032">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Membership</header>
        <paragraph id="HCE721122804A4578902C851054E35E4E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Number and appointment</header>
 <text>The Council shall be composed of 12 members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H362390CFFE3A42B6ACBA762244CFAE09">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Qualifications</header>
 <text>The members of the Council shall be individuals who—</text> <subparagraph id="H0AC9C7E1803C4B7E928E4EDE247195A0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>are selected from among private citizens of the United States who are recognized for their broad knowledge of, expertise in, or commitment to the preservation and celebration of African American history and culture;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H2C235D9CC4ED4D3FB7165AE5231740A2">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>are not currently employees of the Federal Government; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19CB590933F948DBAD951A598386AC89"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>have established records of distinguished service, scholarship, or creativity.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD4C99D43962145F0992E958F898A628A">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Considerations</header>
 <text>In appointing members to the Council under paragraph (1), the President—</text> <subparagraph id="H1DF881B6EFF24957958D14221A722B42"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>shall give due regard to equitable representation of women, people of color, and individuals with disabilities who are involved in the humanities;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8DA156FEB13D4168A8F1E85A6D9ED868">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>shall select such members in a manner that ensures a comprehensive representation of the views of scholars and professional practitioners in the humanities and of the public throughout the United States; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H98E0ECE765F4454E90FC58B41A938150" commented="no">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>shall ensure that six members are individuals affiliated with the Democratic party and six members are individuals affiliated with the Republican party.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H9E91A087B65D46B5A91FE1E5E5C6B141">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Chairperson; vice chairperson</header>
          <subparagraph id="H9586C919F22B4ADCB5D6BDE6E35B3F71">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Chairperson and Vice Chairperson of the Council shall be designated by the President from among the members of the Council. The Vice Chairperson shall act as Chairperson in the absence of the Chairperson.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC009AA96E8164B478FECB63D39C8EA40" commented="no">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Party affiliation</header>
 <text>The Chairperson and Vice Chairperson may not be affiliated with the same political party.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H1B150798818B4FADB35A68D6CABB5295">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Term of office; vacancies; reappointment</header>
          <subparagraph id="H5C5E9E64632E46EA935A4D24D3157D42">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text>Each member shall be appointed for a term of five years, except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7917DF6D7DE444DAB3B60EC33DB43300">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Terms of initial appointees</header>
 <text>As designated by the President at the time of the appointment, of the members first appointed to the Council under paragraph (1)—</text>
            <clause id="H914145AB1E6B4FC0988212BBBC0B4C85">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>six shall be appointed for terms of three years, three of whom shall be individuals affiliated with the Democratic party and three of whom shall be individuals affiliated with the Republican party; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HF6BAAA362A2D4EA3901FF3899B903004">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">six shall be appointed for terms of five years, three of whom shall be individuals affiliated with the Democratic party and three of whom shall be individuals affiliated with the Republican party.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8910BA3D5F2843489BB957BD4ED17CBC">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Vacancies</header>
 <text>Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term. A member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H823E6C678BFE44D391B5CC506EE9268B">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>Reappointment</header>
 <text>No member shall be eligible for reappointment during the two-year period following the expiration of such member’s term.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H110C15EB290640BA81A93D7D8BAC36E7">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
          <header>Basic pay</header>
          <subparagraph id="HB07FF5B2D6D84B5EADB91F12991AD516">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Rates of pay</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members shall receive compensation at a rate of 50 percent of the daily rate of the highest rate of basic pay payable for the senior-level positions classified above GS–15 pursuant to section 5108 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which they are engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Council.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3B7A632CE5334AE3A79F9FD04E10E5E1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Travel expenses</header>
 <text>Each member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter 1 of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB23BAC522DFA438799A5531B5A2A53BE">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
          <header>Quorum</header>
 <text>Nine members of the Council shall constitute a quorum. The Council cannot hold hearings without a full quorum.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE89503F5CE794CF18D012521A8AB38CE">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
          <header>Meetings</header>
 <text>The Council shall meet at the call of the Chairperson but not less frequently than twice during each calendar year.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H09359DC6FCA443FDA5BA2A9ADA4803F5">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Duties</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Council shall be—</text> <paragraph id="HEB3590ECECEE48CE8E6328D52EA7825E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prepare an annual report to be submitted to the Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Humanities on the work of the National Endowment to preserve and celebrate African American history and culture;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H615336C92DE54DAD87D1CB051867EDD6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to gather timely and authoritative information concerning historical developments and cultural trends in African American history and culture, as well as to monitor the work of museums and organizations dedicated to the preservation of African American history and culture, and to analyze and interpret such information for the purpose of determining whether national policy is necessary to further support those efforts;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD08E49C6ED7F4460AFD0A6607DB0D79F">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>to evaluate the various programs and activities of the National Endowment for the Humanities for the purpose of determining the extent to which such programs and activities are contributing, and the extent to which they are not contributing, to the successful preservation and celebration of African American history and culture, and to make recommendations to the President with respect to such programs and activities;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE95E3D53C979461E92FAC1386EDF9570">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>to develop and recommend to the Chairperson national policies to foster and promote the understanding of African American history, the preservation of African American culture, and the celebration of African Americans as contributors to the country’s economic, cultural, and political success; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HCD3CC4FDCF5140FA8A99EC238E29BD7E">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>to make and furnish such studies, reports thereon, and recommendations with respect to matters of cultural preservation and African American history as the Chairperson may request.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2BEB4ABE36924190B28EBD46C4D7800B">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Applicability of FACA</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1013(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code (relating to the termination of advisory committees), shall not apply to the Council.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6E4F99F9E6484E5FA356FEC40C920E65" commented="no">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Termination</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall terminate 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

