<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H9612B78928834ACCA295A84204BD440D" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5254 : Gateway Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5254</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc> Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Gateway Arch Park Foundation to host private events in Gateway Arch National Park buildings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HBD70296A65004A748C0963374B4D4235"><section id="H84AAAE3BF414406AA45F8E573A46BC5E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gateway Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA22968A0809D4A7C8246ACA8681B1B78"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H979534F32F6049E38D6FD1A7DAE0BD7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the Gateway Arch Park Foundation, a nonprofit organization that serves as the official philanthropic partner of the Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14500A9604F047FBB13D0472333C8993"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Park</header><text>The term <term>Park</term> means Gateway Arch National Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF00BA4C5BED7423296B65BC0B796286F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Park building</header><text>The term <term>Park building</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H7A82E4600B4143E490E08BE7BAC1BB00" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Arch Visitor Center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0F0D1B321D9473B921175F4B2755AD4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Old Courthouse; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E8E0DB5194341BE87377EF8A87BC060" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other building administered or managed by the Secretary as part of the Park that is open to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4C6B8E05D3C4F1AABF87BD0A439E3AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H97A64DF5B351446E91DFC960314F303B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Gateway Arch National Park Partner Agreement Pilot Project</header><subsection id="H2AB4C1DA209C44638967F7BB465CC4FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in accordance with subsection (b), may enter into a one-time agreement for a period not to exceed five years with the Foundation to host private events at the Park, which may include the use of Park buildings.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE128C6B6DC7A41C8AB3D4223592F1B7E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall include terms and conditions to protect the resources and values of the Park, including—</text><paragraph id="HE313587ACF564B3FBF6643FFF405B3ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>dates and times during which the Foundation may be the exclusive organization that holds a special event in specified Park buildings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBD3514E1E6C4AE6A70762A9870BB0B4"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC95C507E627544E2921E38BB819F06D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maximum number of events that can be held per month; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD272B0AE6558432EA70B8440B960B96A" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriate National Park Service staffing levels necessary to ensure public safety and resource protection during such events;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9DE44253E8D4F73BC1857E2FA69BD5E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>liability insurance in an amount sufficient to protect the interests of the United States that lists the United States as additionally insured;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54FD44F0931F496CBA9A809AA20149DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a provision stating that the Federal Government and agents and employees of the Federal Government will not be held liable for claims for damages or suits for any injuries or deaths from any cause resulting from the occupancy and use of specified Park buildings by the Foundation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EB583DF22B249A1BC34DC0233001299"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a provision allowing for the modification or cancellation of the terms and conditions of the agreement, except that any modified agreement shall still comply with the terms and conditions described in subparagraphs (1) through (4); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAFF24200C2E4B79B80712137A792A4E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36AD9B34D8B14F159AAB339F471A2839"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Private events hosted at the Park or in Park buildings through an agreement entered into under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="HEB0F60C3A6374CB9AC1B2D9EC8528DDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be limited to activities—</text><subparagraph id="H7F7BC4AB7B524435AAC628EFEE4D8CC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with the purposes of the Park; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC536EB448333447E922521E4988D361C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compatible with National Park Service programs; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93446BC930594F8FB3A3DB5E703589DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not include activities that degrade the integrity, appearance, or purposes of the Park; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EE637846FD7439CA007754A7C9B2E7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall not take place during times or in locations that prevent or disrupt public use or access to the Park or Park buildings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CED79E75FF14A33BE0CE88D74C5EA87"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recovery of costs</header><text>In entering into an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="HC6DC975F269547A1AD8977D7A2C85013"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall charge a fee to cover the cost of maintaining the Park and Park buildings with respect to wear and tear resulting from the private events; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7915FD12D20641338D78F1A20F0477B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notwithstanding any other provision of law, may recover all costs incurred as a result of the private events and use of the Park and Park buildings, including maintenance, utilities, administrative expenses, security, and personnel costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7002B7E19FEF4ACC8AE852D2C2CF67A6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>National Park Service-Sponsored events</header><text>Nothing in this Act prevents the National Park Service from hosting events or issuing permits to other individuals or entities for special events or otherwise, as appropriate, in the Park or Park buildings.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFFBA852ACB354487BD23C42C874AD47C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><paragraph id="HC56C1181531D41758604938E9A437960"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authority to enter into and carry out an agreement with the Foundation pursuant to this Act shall sunset on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H566C7B2697AB4488B0FFB5659EC9A854"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect on existing agreement</header><text>Any existing agreement entered into under this section shall terminate, notwithstanding any terms within such agreement, on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B27BA3D2AFB4511B54A863983E4A5A1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Saving clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects any other authority of the Secretary to issue special use permits or agreements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9133F3DEE413411B930C3AC68D2241FD"><enum>(h)</enum><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report evaluating the implementation of this Act, including the—</text><paragraph id="HF547C64E6BD7482CA6E73DBFEDF6C9E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operational impacts of the agreement on visitor access, security, staffing, and facilities management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3C16A3AA6845E5B13D286F1586B04F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>financial implications of the agreement, including fees collected and costs recovered.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260316" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 16, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

