<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB4E06D463FC6446EB251ABCC57DA5C22" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5885 IH: Guaranteeing Access and Innovation for National Artificial Intelligence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5885</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require entities seeking a license to export advanced artificial intelligence chips to countries of concern to certify that United States persons have priority in acquiring those chips.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB3F3F4A18ED74B699AC8E5DBCAD57AC4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7BA0E09DC4E9471F9645E97D8878BCCD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteeing Access and Innovation for National Artificial Intelligence Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GAIN AI Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDB0AB3E7680B4C15A599AD452C05E80F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on prioritizing countries of concern over united states persons for exports of advanced integrated circuits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part I of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4811">50 U.S.C. 4811 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1758 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA7DDADCF949043A981F09A2B6D53D588" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H35020DFCF30E403FB02A8D63EA3D0D81"><enum>1758A.</enum><header>Control of exports of certain advanced integrated circuits</header> 
<subsection id="H6819A323B16F40AC8B094652FBE185A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>License requirement</header><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall require a license for the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of a covered advanced circuit or product to an entity located or headquartered in, or whose ultimate parent company is headquartered in, a country of concern.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H693D074CA10941FCB64F7990022E231A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification of priority for United States customers for certain advanced integrated circuits</header> <paragraph id="HAE9052870AA042E38D91285866766804"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall require a person submitting an application for a license under subsection (a) to certify in the application that such person provided a right of first refusal to United States persons.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE795454CA0F24AC5B66F9E8C0BDC1B21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of applications without certification</header><text>Such Under Secretary shall deny each application for a license under subsection (a) that does not include a certification described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D3B117FA3B147E98D0F8E56FBD13089"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, such Under Secretary shall consult with the public and prescribe regulations providing guidance, based on such consultation, for complying with the certification requirement under paragraph (1), which shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H49E82119B7234A91BD29F99245ADE16D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information that the person submitting an application for a license under subsection (a) is required to make available about transactions with entities described in subsection (a), and the form the public notice of such information must take, to ensure that United States persons can exercise a right of first refusal under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H12AFFE6528E343669ABDC3F1D7F10FD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>procedures for United States persons to exercise a right of first refusal under paragraph (1), including—</text> 
<clause id="HC0C2C9802E464A8EA5C4E02774514C24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how public notice of the right of first refusal shall be provided; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6E7DDA532DB04DBCAF86B2611E2ED102"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>guidance on when a United States person should inform such Under Secretary that they are seeking to exercise a right of first refusal;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H24B3A8ADC047439784A9152E244614A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conditions upon which a person submitting an application for a license under subsection (a) may proceed with the transaction that such license is required for if a request to exercise a right of first refusal is not made in good faith or completed in the required timeframe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC85947C41A674C89BCBF6B7067CDDAD6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recordkeeping requirements;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBBD443F202E046F6BF4EA1A2E5C4EB6D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>penalties for misrepresentation and concealment of material facts; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D8F26E597584F21A7B57FC2A7B51CFF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>guidance with respect to determining whether—</text> 
<clause id="H4DFE0F769EB04FCEB457253BDF743FE9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a United States person exercising a right of first refusal has taken a material step to complete a transaction within the required timeframe; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC57A4CA2AABD49EDA078A03586AD5725"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of a covered advanced circuit or product would create—</text> 
<subclause id="HC714F9879DA94DA78B8AB409F9ACE389"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">backlog of requests from United States persons for the covered advanced circuit or product with respect to which an application for a license is submitted under subsection (a) or a comparable covered advanced circuit or product; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAE1F677E2F424A7799CD5E62B4B1588A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reduction in the capacity of production lines for the production, for United States persons, of the covered advanced circuit or product with respect to which an application for a license is submitted under subsection (a) or a comparable covered advanced circuit or product; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H585E42E7EA79415293F953523CF21B04"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person submitting an application for a license under subsection (a) provides advantageous pricing or terms for the covered advanced circuit or product with respect to which such application is submitted for to foreign persons that are not provided to United States persons.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B11AAA22CA84C14A498BFBBDD7911EC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of more than one United States person requesting to exercise a right of first refusal, nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, or any other Federal official, to allocate, prioritize, or otherwise select one United States person over any other United States person submitting such a request.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA54ED3658724419083951F3A6A9A8EBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption from certain license requirement for trusted united states persons</header> 
<paragraph id="HC28C130E2AFA4154AF074DC1BCC65DB4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirement for a license under sections 742.6 and 744.23 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations shall not apply to the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of a covered advanced circuit or product if the covered advanced circuit or product—</text> <subparagraph id="H31A3EEE5B87A47DEBFA1C2CA43F0B101"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is destined for a country that is not a country of concern; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EBE99365D3F4A5DA19280376EAC176A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>once in operation, remains under the ownership and control of a trusted United States person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3857190DC53A41A8ACC6A5FA64AEFEC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall consult with the public and, based on such consultation, prescribe regulations—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H99315C3569DA4BD2BEE869E831ADCF2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing the standards and requirements a United States person is required to meet to obtain a designation as a trusted United States person, which shall include—</text> <clause id="H9C29A0C97E104759BE74A917154D19A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establishment by the United States person of physical security, cybersecurity, and other measures designed to prevent the illicit transfer or diversion of covered circuits and products, or other violations of United States export control regulations;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6578A6C23A2F495B9A2764F804EF813A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a requirement that the United States person may not transfer or install a majority of its aggregate total processing performance of covered circuits or products outside the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="HCA592F1FF45644C8A9E9B74D71A56E4F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a requirement that not more than 10 percent of the ultimate beneficial ownership of the United States person may be held, directly or indirectly, by any entity that primarily resides, is domiciled, or conducts the majority of its business in a country of concern; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1C82FDC9D06245C29E33A754F865543A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>annual audit or attestation requirement to ensure compliance with this subparagraph; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H233741B24B0F4061AF58018A0337EA03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describing the process by which such Under Secretary shall approve such a designation under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCA9224419EC144ABB59DB52A0C507028"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8B407F28C61246C28534233B7E6B3BA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced integrated circuit</header> <subparagraph id="HCEE39FA8EF264E8E986569C490178EE5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <quote>advanced integrated circuit</quote> means—</text> 
<clause id="HEE95A10777DB496C9FD4A740DA2B00E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an integrated circuit, computer, or other product—</text> <subclause id="H3B6AE56ADD1F498DB0373FB8A789DF23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>classified under Export Control Classification Number 3A090 or 4A090 or related Export Control Classification Numbers; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA823D5D1B7CF4BE5AB09CED371D93DE9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that is functionally equivalent or substantially similar to a circuit, computer, or product described in subclause (I); or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HBB6ADE4144884175AE784D8354D9F701"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an integrated circuit that has one or more digital processing units with—</text> 
<subclause id="H51F11C86BFC146C49D46BBBC251FA519"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a total processing performance of 4,800 or more;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5CDA76AEF5CD42FF8B436A70DFBF7561"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a total processing performance of 2,400 or more and a performance density of 1.6 or more;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H26D7BF0E88404205AFFD593B901B46C8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a total processing performance of 1,600 or more and a performance density of 3.2 or more; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0300AAFF36754D5C94821623990B8402"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a total DRAM bandwidth of 1,400 gigabytes per second or more, interconnect bandwidth of 1,100 gigabytes per second or more, or a sum of DRAM bandwidth and interconnect bandwidth of 1,700 gigabytes per second or more.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3576C781BBB495DB9F7550E9BC9B03A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority to update technical parameters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 24 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security may add new technical parameters for the definition of <quote>advanced integrated circuit</quote> following publication of such parameters and a notice and comment period in the Federal Register.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7A0283BB1604EFCAC49232248CADA30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commerce control list</header><text>The term <quote>Commerce Control List</quote> means the list set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C7276674AF345ADA3A7B89677F730EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <quote>country of concern</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFDF79B9119744540BD1E1374E8EF0E4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a country listed in Country Group D:5 or E in Supplement No. 1 to part 740 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H458DDB5D845E4A44995CC94F1ED39034"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Macau Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2686EBA5309C41F3896F1B501429F8DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2AA69CA00C241ACBF91E7B1454EF3FB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered advanced circuit or product</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4DDD23B3AA884D498EDBCC7CB10C4E46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by subparagraph (B), the term <quote>covered advanced circuit or product</quote> means—</text> <clause id="HFBE5882E629C44DBB87750A72E272DDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an advanced integrated circuit; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB1730B16F7B747F9B431BDB7E51A67B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a product containing such a circuit.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2E2E112732A42E08145582428FEC491"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <quote>covered advanced circuit or product</quote> does not include an advanced integrated circuit or a product containing such a circuit that is not designed or marketed for data centers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF97865E2ABD94D7A8DDB8AB3385B8729"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Performance density; total processing performance</header><text>The terms <quote>performance density</quote> and <quote>total processing performance</quote> have the meanings given those terms in, and are calculated as provided for under, Export Control Classification Number 3A090 in the Commerce Control List set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFC3F5F8A51741428CC48A2EE63BB04A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Right of first refusal</header> <subparagraph id="H39DDF7205F2B402989161558BED6BE3B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>right of first refusal</quote> means the person applying for a license under subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="H5AA5FBBD63DC427785CF34BE0CBECC96"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides, through public notice, not less than a 15-day period for United States persons to inquire about purchasing a covered advanced circuit or product that would otherwise be sold to an entity located or headquartered in, or whose ultimate parent company is headquartered in, a country of concern;</text></clause> <clause id="H4C5DD40C483F4E918F95E729FBEB9D9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides preference to a United States person submitting an inquiry under clause (i), if such United States person—</text> 
<subclause id="H363D99A8789D485E81B2C39A0174A571"><enum>(I)</enum><text>requests to purchase any quantity of the covered advanced circuit or product with respect to which such application is submitted for on the terms such covered advanced circuit or product is offered for; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA6D0982CDDD24E3BBAB358E07D838DE4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>takes material steps to complete such purchase within 15 business days of requesting to make such purchase;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H2EA15D9D78D84A10BDBF2D6CB0638176" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has no current backlog of requests from United States persons for the covered advanced circuit or product with respect to which such application is submitted for or a comparable covered advanced circuit or product;</text></clause> <clause id="H0B737E1179C346A6B55DA9C0CAD069FE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cannot reasonably foresee, based on material information known to such person, that the production and export, reexport, or in-country transfer of the covered advanced circuit or product with respect to which such application is submitted for will result, during the 12-month period following such export, reexport, or in-country transfer, in—</text> 
<subclause id="H9B5D80C6CDD44204AC7014EA0598F95D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a backlog of requests described under clause (iii); or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H147A2171A68E45EB8114DC157A41E4EB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reduction in production line capacity for the production of a covered advanced circuit or product or a substantially similar covered advanced circuit or product, for United States persons; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1773E14E831642C2A2E617D55A3D2C5A"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not providing advantageous pricing or terms for the covered advanced circuit or product with respect to which such application is submitted for to foreign persons that are not provided to United States persons.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDD74AA150C943CA87BD6D4CA5D34464"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> 
<clause id="H1ABFC2FE332A4E2D898CC95F7567D548"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Backlog of requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>backlog of requests</quote> means a request from any United States person for a covered advanced circuit or product that—</text> <subclause id="HD4A9BB496944413A8D41E1340DED1441" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is formally documented through—</text> 
<item id="HA4C9CB96478B4B21BDA4541DFFD8806A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a purchase order or enforceable contract; or</text></item> <item id="H1DD5CED4195C48A3BC45819136AB9C1C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a formal request for supply consistent with ordinary commercial practice that specifies quantity, price, and timeframe of delivery; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2730D2C615284DC596DE9AEB324BEFBD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not fulfilled or will not be able to fulfill within a timeframe consistent with commercially standard production and delivery lead times.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF6DDC60E397947B9A2779E2B3DDA70CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Material information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <quote>material information</quote> includes information disclosed to investors, shareholders, or in public filings.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC51A92D699E24FB4AA8A9377F4EEC087"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Trusted United States person</header><text>The term <quote>trusted United States person</quote> means any United States person designated as a trusted United States person pursuant to subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

