<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F60C6BED34348B185EE50694BCF2D08" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7201 IH: Rural Service and Workforce Corps Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7201</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a program to fill critical rural workforce shortages through an education assistance and loan repayment in exchange for service in designated rural areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C3CABFE3128452DA67DF468238768E7" style="OLC"><section id="H237733EE1C01411F8038B0EAAA0596BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Service and Workforce Corps Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7EEC12E9E2AE491089DA223475B755AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rural Service and Workforce Corps Program</header><subsection id="H93E38C2F23EF44A8A4DEBBCD6EAD4650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Design</header><paragraph id="H145E0CFA339E409CB712F2D440D74117"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall design a program to be known as the <quote>Rural Service and Workforce Corps Program</quote>, modeled after the service-for-benefits framework of the National Health Service Corps, to fill critical workforce shortages in targeted rural areas, through the provision of scholarships, tuition assistance, student loan repayment, stipends or wage support during service, and relocation and retention incentives in exchange for 3 years of service in a rural area designated by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC2EE932A7CB4F8981D8102BBAF69AC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority employment sectors</header><subparagraph id="H0949B78891A44A9BB8F8D4B5470F690D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The program shall be designed to prioritize filling workforce shortages in the following employment sectors, subject to subparagraph (B):</text><clause id="H1DF691185D2248979568203E15CA7A60"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care, including primary care, behavioral health, dental, and emergency services.</text></clause><clause id="H21A64CB24CC84521804A8266816F8F88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Skilled trades, such as electricians, plumbers, heating, ventilation, and air conditioning, welding, and construction.</text></clause><clause id="H422C4B1D450847D1BA5DEAF62AEC5ED9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Energy infrastructure, such as lineworkers, renewable energy technicians, grid operators.</text></clause><clause id="H5E652B62686F40308027FFB540C416DD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Utilities and public works, such as water and wastewater operators and broadband technicians.</text></clause><clause id="HB0AEED7E05D846B1862243A1B3FF5BDE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Other sectors with aging workforces, as determined by the Secretary of Labor.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA418AD377DB41B4A66B2919FC4A2515"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updating</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall, from time to time, update the employment sectors to be prioritized under subparagraph (A), as necessary to ensure that the program prioritizes any sector facing an aging workforce and a limited recruitment pipeline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB136AAE848434737A67F6B11610AB326"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Targeted rural areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program shall be designed to target any rural area—</text><subparagraph id="HCE62604112EB42D4B7EB16B3BC0D5728"><enum>(A)</enum><text>categorized by the Economic Research Service of the Department of Agriculture as a persistent poverty county;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89FCFBA9D26C4C37BD34C077EFB155D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>designated by the Health Resources and Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services as a health professional shortage area; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B541022AC954092952680E74F768D93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in which an Indian tribal, an Alaska Native, or a Native Hawaiian community resides.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B268569398A408BAF53F00F5619B716"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employer participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program shall be designed to allow public, nonprofit, cooperative, tribal, and private employers that meet such wage and training standards as the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, to participate in the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BE66992D07D474BB59C976879818129"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall carry out the program in consultation with—</text><paragraph id="HF5635C4901004B89A2948125CCF669C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Education, with respect to the provision of scholarships, tuition assistance, and student loan repayment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EE19DD976EB4C2381E675844A1D5AAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Labor, with respect to the provision of stipends or wage support during service, and relocation and retention incentives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70125BE84F464F36960BB6139EB2C5F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Health and Human Services, with respect to the health care employment sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3310D20EDA7A493E8EA9C07A235CEF65"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Energy, with respect to the energy infrastructure and utilities employment sectors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6326668D2472437EA0AC6046A190EBE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, with respect to any matter calling for the expertise of the relevant department or agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1193D7789AA444FB60F3A99C0B72732"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall prepare and submit to the Congress a written report on the implementation and effectiveness of the program provided for in this Act, which shall—</text><paragraph id="H484F517C7D224545BAFB9FED8BCD208D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include information, with respect to the 1st cohort subject to the 3-year service requirement under the program, on—</text><subparagraph id="H22A3A1E4017F4DECA85EB755B4883BBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of persons in the cohort;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H922FA9E0E710403BA36A8C8583DB85C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the employment sectors in which a member of the cohort has been placed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ED1DC51E47F4A669648AC461F159E43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the geographical spread of the placements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98D39C642A23475A90B04AD92A3F002C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the types of employers referred to in subsection (a)(4) with whom a member of the cohort has been placed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24A6045E7200446E8FEEE5E6B1577CF1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of the placements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BDAB444D9034776BD002DA94FE8DDF0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the percentage of the cohort who remain in the geographic area in which placed;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE09679C198164E3F898B38F282FEBFC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>address any challenges arising from interagency coordination; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE878EC1CC1F84508BD33F81E4027BF28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include recommendations for improvements in the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2C56179A06449C883BB509DFDBA6043"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of rural area</header><text>In this section, the term <term>rural area</term> has the meaning given the term in subparagraph (A) of section 343(a)(13) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, subject to subparagraphs (D) and (F) of such section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H00CBA7B69BDE4A1AA16BBF344C56351E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

