<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEC13DF8C73104E288FCC816599D1279F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7755 IH: Housing for Our Hometown Heroes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7755</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to submit a
            report to the Congress with respect to exempting any downpayment requirement for
            mortgage insurance offered by the Federal Housing Administration for first-time
            homebuyers who are first responders or school teachers, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H35BBCE8183E3402780C20DDAC7981717" style="OLC"><section id="H199C414B24D84348A6C0BF8FA0229F19" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing for Our Hometown Heroes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H02A1F6CD0DEA4C13AAEC778E522ED40A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on zero-downpayment for FHA mortgage insurance</header><subsection id="HC007DEE3EA3247CA8A6BAFDE4A28D0CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, acting through the Assistance Secretary for Housing and Federal Housing Commissioner, shall submit to the Congress a report that describes the feasability of a program that exempts first-time homebuyers who are first responders or school teachers from any cash investment required as described in section 203(b)(9) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1709">12 U.S.C. 1709(b)(9)</external-xref>) for mortgage insurance under such Act, including—</text><paragraph id="H118390C6DF7E4B95A192A07FB50FE6BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the benefits and detriments of such a program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24C6484027F5479080DB7BCC81C1359F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost of such a program and impact on the mutual mortgage insurance fund;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78FD64CA28244015AC7C299E2C9BA08F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how such a program can remain solvent using—</text><subparagraph id="H0DB231558CBA4C249FC209195091716B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>upfront fees; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C3DA12D85AF44728CB96C6BF163B7D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a combination of upfront and annual fees;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84CFA395391B4EF99FEBA296EB7EB173"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis on how such a program would affect the ability of first responders or school teachers to buy a house;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4C15BDE0C614D059324024A6FAE73FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the expected premiums that would be needed for the program to have a negative credit subsidy rate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF230B002A0F04E02AD53919D380F8F4B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that the Secretary determines that such a program is not feasible, recommendations that describe similar solutions or alternative program designs to support first-time homebuyers that are first responders or school teachers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1D60E3182BE42CAABBA6A0C669A7368"><enum>(b)</enum><header>VA consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall consult with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with respect to the report required under subsection (a), including whether elements of the VA Home Loan Program could be incorporated into the program described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H361A086373004F24AD84C53D3409AA60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H67924925D0AA41FCB76CDAB8143DAF46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First responder</header><text>The term <quote>first responder</quote> means an individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="HEC1691A1ACF849068FE8980C76300579"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1581E227B80242D49C1A6E0B2406441D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employed full-time by a law enforcement agency of the Federal Government, a State, a Tribal government, or a unit of general local government; and</text></clause><clause id="H992F6DFC74974652926608C68BFDA6BF" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in carrying out such full-time employment, sworn to uphold, and make arrests for violations of, Federal, State, county, township, municipal, or Tribal laws, or authorized by law to supervise sentenced criminal offenders or individuals with pending criminal charges; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18F510E9E14844DD9A3F5024C18A5F82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employed full-time as a firefighter, paramedic, or emergency medical technician by a fire department or emergency medical services responder unit of the Federal Government, a State, a Tribal government, or a unit of general local government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H320A4B722F144B2CA619598C4D40FD33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>School teacher</header><text>The term <quote>school teacher</quote> means an individual who is employed as a full-time teacher by a State-accredited school that provides direct services to students in grades pre-kindergarten through 12.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

