<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25C52-6G9-HG-FST"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3435 IS: Future Advancement of Academic Nursing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3435</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants to support schools of nursing in increasing the number of nursing students and faculty and in program enhancement and infrastructure modernization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4FD83EEAEAC14F39B9BEA106C3858646"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1F9CA24CD02C4A6C8260810E26E0851E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Future Advancement of Academic Nursing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAAN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD7709BF33DFD41CD845EA7133366D451"><enum>2.</enum><header>Support for nursing education and the future nursing workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title VIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/296p">42 U.S.C. 296p et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H245F5BB58631467EB62BD7792DF66D54"><section id="H1891DF006FE6450E9D93DEC506FFB558"><enum>832.</enum><header>Nursing education enhancement and modernization grants in underserved areas</header><subsection id="H991781D8AAE54A9CAC39EF136AF0BA34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may award grants to schools of nursing for—</text><paragraph id="H5DB2C6AB2CF14ADCA0FD6A4527B6B773"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing the number of faculty and students at such schools in order to address nursing workforce shortages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H549C1AEACA3442B4AAB632050E2FBF1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding the capacity of such schools to enhance the preparedness of the United States for, and the ability of the United States to address and quickly respond to, public health emergencies declared under section 319 and pandemics that are not otherwise declared as such emergencies; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57CB4FF8339B41E4818036D8801E9C0E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the enhancement and modernization of nursing education programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H000912483A3340AFA29F1DFB3D6B3FCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting grant recipients under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to schools of nursing that—</text><paragraph id="HAB6176640ED6499C990520FC60FAC654"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are located in, or prepare students to practice in, a medically underserved area (as defined in section 330I(a));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EF32A3B18D04513BD9D5BA7046F659A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are located in, or prepare students to practice in, a health professional shortage area as defined under section 332(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3ABEA3FAADB413FA62A22ACDC6B0447"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are institutions of higher education listed under section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94CC5DC2B91349748837EEDE23E9BB27"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are located in, or prepare students to practice in, a rural area or a noncontiguous State or territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE2E95E408FF4283A04C014274345027"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary, to the extent practicable, may ensure equitable distribution of awards among the geographic regions of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D196C6A702043E8A379E521D277FE59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A school of nursing that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds awarded through such grant for activities that include—</text><paragraph id="HBB894A79E2EF447EA74A6F2B6B56651F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhancing enrollment and retention of students at such school, with a priority for students from disadvantaged backgrounds (including racial or ethnic groups underrepresented in the nursing workforce), individuals from rural and underserved areas, low-income individuals, and first generation college students (as defined in section 402A(h)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965), including through mentorship programs, providing tools and programming for underrepresented students, and addressing other student needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D44F7C6BF1D466D94F57B581B4C88C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>retaining current faculty, and hiring new faculty, with an emphasis on faculty from racial or ethnic groups who are underrepresented in the nursing workforce;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F316D153F464F9AB0E6E8C1298B21C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>partnering with a health care facility, nurse-managed health clinic, community health center, or other facility that provides health care in order to provide educational opportunities for the purpose of establishing or expanding clinical education, including through preceptors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFFC8277CB86488FBC68584C31CA386E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>modernizing infrastructure at such school, including audiovisual or other equipment, simulation and augmented reality resources, telehealth technologies, and virtual and physical laboratories;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H552CC7E83B794760B208ACA137DD943D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>creating, supporting, or modernizing educational programs and curriculum at such school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69F5B41E9EA24417B8FEB9FB25A81F69"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enhancing and expanding nursing programs that prepare nurse researchers and scientists;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FBDEAF19CEB47E48780BB17C1EB30C9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>establishing nurse-led intradisciplinary and interprofessional educational partnerships; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FEFDC1BB5A34AE98975087721F5BF94"><enum>(8)</enum><text>other activities that the Secretary determines further the development, improvement, and expansion of schools of nursing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C0F4DE573D64BD697D82096C5C54846"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports from entities</header><text>Each school of nursing awarded a grant under this section shall submit an annual report to the Secretary on the activities conducted under such grant, and other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC7202895E8074BADA36605DCE0615F50"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a report that provides a summary of the activities and outcomes associated with grants made under this section. Such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HABA360C457B343B295E93792720D83E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of schools of nursing receiving grants under this section, including the primary geographic location of any school of nursing that was improved or expanded through such a grant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H746799E477E04DB4925AEE9E8C575903"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total number of students who are enrolled at or who have graduated from any school of nursing that was improved or expanded through a grant under this section, which such statistic shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7BAC9DDB1BC24EF9BEB18657D831258F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent such information is available, be deidentified and disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, sex, geographic region, disability status, and other relevant factors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08FF980A13564E63BB3F6EB83E62C8C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include an indication of the number of such students who are from racial or ethnic groups underrepresented in the nursing workforce, such students who are from rural or underserved areas, such students who are low-income students, and such students who are first generation college students (as defined in section 402A(h)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4C61867B9A0482F9B006AAE3C3CDF65"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent such information is available—</text><subparagraph id="HB0A814DA90834BBD858DC83102427C71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effects of the grants awarded under this section on—</text><clause id="HE5678BA2A6214D7A907751A09FD0172D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>retaining and hiring of faculty, including any increase in diverse faculty;</text></clause><clause id="H707682DCBED94DA880BA2F372B667618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of clinical education partnerships; and</text></clause><clause id="H4662E4C827AB4086B64C3A23A46D9C51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the modernization of nursing education infrastructure; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H575D7BCF18774C6AB344249A5888E233"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other ways this section helps to address nursing workforce shortages and quickly respond to public health emergencies declared under section 319 and pandemics that are not otherwise declared as such emergencies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96FADF098C864FEF9672DF15C234CBC3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the grants awarded under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4152EF91ACC44DEAFC7C30637C205DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other considerations as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A99142821F6424C92C66EB2EDF2287C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000,000 to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HC7208FF9C4F7449A93AC0F6DA5B93E71"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strengthening nurse education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The heading of part D of title VIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/296p">42 U.S.C. 296p et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="part" style="OLC">Basic</header-in-text></quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

