<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3837115B0C38458BA05FF56F70092769" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8384 IH: To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Utah National Guard located in Lehi, Utah, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8384</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Utah National Guard located in Lehi, Utah, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H18F0598B4F084715A5C4CEEBEB2DE66C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H88223A889C164719BBAC61328D0680E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Land conveyance, State Armory Board, Utah National Guard, Camp Williams State Military Reservation, Lehi, Utah</header> 
<subsection id="HCE50E546B5D0438A80151FBFE3944019"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance authorized</header> 
<paragraph id="HD5E4F0A015124C85B2C4050861C6A961"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Army (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) may convey to the Utah National Guard, Lehi, Utah, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property, including any improvements thereon, consisting of three parcels described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D060987424249DCA5E722BB333B27B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation of existing easements, restrictions, and covenants</header><text>The conveyance of the property under paragraph (1) shall be subject to any easement, restriction, or covenant of record applicable to the property and in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB14BD90681004BB9892021074946E95C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of property</header> 
<paragraph id="H54D07029A363428E9EBD243CA37ED45A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The property, including all land, improvements, and appurtenances, described in this subsection is the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H26DE19D7600C4C9C85DC26E26DDB086A"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>First parcel</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A strip of land of varying width situated in Section 35, Township 4 South, Range 1 West, Salt Lake Base and Meridian. Such strip of land extending 25 feet each side and parallel with the following described center line: Beginning at a point in the East line of section 35, 1298 feet East and 1808 feet North 44° 59′′ West from the Southwest corner of Section 36, Township 4 South, Range 1 West, Salt Lake Base and Meridian; thence North 45° 9′′ West 1999 feet, describing a 75 foot strip of land extending 25 feet Eastwardly and 50 feet Westwardly and Parallel with such center line; thence continuing on same bearing 1368.1 feet to the PC of a 5° spiralled curve to the right. Describing a 100 foot strip of land extending 50 feet each side and parallel with said center line, thence Northwesterly along said 5° curve to the right 507.9 feet more or less to a point in the South line of the Northeast quarter of the Northwest quarter of said Section 35, describing a 100 foot strip of land extending 50 feet each side and parallel with such center line.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H364EE3AF2B8E4DDD834C4CF3D8C0C883">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Second parcel</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An irregular shaped parcel of land situated in the Northeast quarter of the Northwest quarter of Section 35, Township 4 South Range 1 West, Salt Lake Base and Meridian. Beginning at the Northwest corner of the herein described land, said point bears West 194 feet from the North quarter corner of Section 35, thence South 5° 47′′ West 587 feet more or less, thence along the line of the 5° spiralled curve to the left a distance of 767.4 feet to a point in the South line of the Northeast quarter of the Northwest quarter of said Section 35; thence East 50 feet to the west right of way line of the Utah Lake Irrigation Company’s canal, thence North 1° 24′′ East along said West right of way line in distance of 1180 feet more or less; thence North 3° 2′′ West 128 feet; thence West 115 feet to the point of beginning.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED26CDD015464703BC9106734EF91BBB">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
                        <header>Third parcel</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A parcel of land situated in Southwest quarter of Section 26, Township 4 South, Range 1 West, Salt Lake Base and Meridian: Commencing 144 feet West from South quarter corner of Section 26; a strip of land 200 feet wide extending 100 feet each side and parallel with the following described center line: Commencing from said point of beginning North 5° 47′′ East 861.1 feet more or less, along the line of a 7° spiral cure to left a distance of 464.4 feet more of less to a point in North line of Southeast, quarter of Southwest quarter of Section 26, extending 100 feet each side and parallel with side center line.</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF06B120E344346D6973C1A51F0CBA5A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>The exact acreage and legal description of the parcels described in paragraph (1) shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B32D3A845A74BD7AC45BDD36A47AE63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reversionary interest</header> <paragraph id="H62A58E9CC877427E9DE7012312FA3380"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines at any time that the property conveyed under subsection (a) is not being used for activities of the Utah National Guard relating to training and readiness, all right, title, and interest in and to the property, including any improvements thereto, may, at the option of the Secretary, revert to and become the property of the United States, and the United States may have the right of immediate entry onto such property.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7660ED706C2C409D912D9FC2926B25A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>A determination by the Secretary under paragraph (1) may be made on the record after an opportunity for a hearing.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2BAF4735332040619ECD817382A5E4B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment of costs of conveyance</header> <paragraph id="HE89C94E5144942EC89C8703F29713EE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment required</header><text>The Secretary may require the State of Utah to cover all costs (except costs for environmental remediation of the property) to be incurred by the Secretary, or to reimburse the Secretary for costs incurred by the Secretary, to carry out the conveyance under subsection (a), including costs for environmental and real estate due diligence and any other administrative costs related to the conveyance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56ED3171060A4A1485C6682B2354D758"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Refund of excess amounts</header><text>If amounts are collected from the State under paragraph (1) in advance of the Secretary incurring the actual costs, and the amount collected exceeds the costs actually incurred by the Secretary to carry out the conveyance under subsection (a), the Secretary shall refund the excess amount to the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2D0E97E9598B40038E7695C57BCDC955"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on source of funds</header><text>The State may not use Federal funds to cover any portion of the costs required to be paid by the State under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H56F22CE0508243CE83B5B10FA1BE69C0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text>The Secretary may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyance under subsection (a) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

