<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H60865E74DC2C4365995DF6F68C8E954D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6017 IH: Veterans Bill of Rights Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6017</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to issue to a veteran a Veterans Bill of Rights, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7324BF14D1AE49D6AA66E767C1670220" style="OLC"><section id="HF63741DD15A445B8B92255C91593BE40" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Bill of Rights Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE7B2029F6FD140B88A0A4D7BBB61137F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans Bill of Rights</header><subsection id="H506D2F230F15443792CA00FA952E09FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended accordingly):</text><quoted-block id="H9D261B2D4B1249A887FC34C6CDCEF644" style="USC"><section id="H69AD4E5551154CE3AC60E943B7B19619"><enum>6321.</enum><header>Veterans Bill of Rights</header><subsection id="H652B9A9D3B4845E6BE5940B3D6805F3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision; publication</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCA2C7D940D3249719378EE90EFC89272"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide to each veteran a physical copy and an electronic copy of the Veterans Bill of Rights described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EB5150E92264F7095B6A0B4514BCE12" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish and maintain, on a publicly accessible website of the Department, an electronic copy of such Veterans Bill of Rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44E8D2C104344C19836A3972C3B733F6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall keep a copy of the most recent version of such Veterans Bill of Rights in each facility of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48EFC573616F481484DF80C5BBD52E1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, the Department, or any officer or employee thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="H510C797DAB014B46A58F6BEE3E880F42"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Veterans Bill of Rights described</header><text>The Veterans Bill of Rights described in this subsection shall inform a veteran of rights and benefits to which the veteran may be entitled under laws administered by the Secretary. Such rights and benefits include the following:</text><paragraph id="H354C8EECA12D4942B5AFD9B451647C44"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans have the right to fair treatment. Veterans shall be treated equally and with respect, regardless of rank, position, or any protected class, in every interaction with the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and affiliated service providers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE33E21EB0D1241E0A7BF5B768453F30D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to be informed of all eligible programs and benefits upon discharge, including healthcare options with non-VA providers.</text><subparagraph id="HB70C1A813BD540C2B8C01699A129746F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon discharge, the VA shall provide each veteran with a comprehensive handbook detailing all eligible benefits and programs, including access to Community Care when VA healthcare is not available within reasonable timeframes or distances.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C6BEC6DBF13407CB7287DA8ED2FDD9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>This information shall be accessible in print and online, updated annually, and cover healthcare, disability, education, and housing benefits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EBB8F1C6CEB4DD6A33920CA80A75ACD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to privacy.</text><subparagraph id="H83523283DAAE4FA1B891ED28D1BD06E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans' personal information and records shall be strictly protected.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26ACDFC11B5243CFAF363DEFC6754D88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The VA must adhere to the highest standards of data privacy and clearly inform veterans about how their data is used, shared, and protected.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63CE54759B904BC5B3BA2B5192543CAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Veterans shall have assurance that all their interactions and records with the VA are handled confidentially and securely.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16BF62C08CB9488F9D27B3EFB92F7EE9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to access quality healthcare.</text><subparagraph id="H481939CADA8D4A6F92421113E750B929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans shall have timely access to high-quality healthcare through VA facilities or Community Care providers when necessary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72E2E975EFB84E5B82B62D14074B1EE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>This includes access to physical and mental health services tailored to veterans’ unique needs, ensuring they receive the best possible care regardless of location or circumstance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60BF74E7991241629D095D9DE232EB10"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to mental health and family support services.</text><subparagraph id="H3DCCA2F402C14E38BFBA7B7FEAA17218"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In recognition of the unique psychological impacts of military service, veterans shall have access to tailored mental health resources, including therapy, counseling, and group support, both in-person and via telehealth.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H468DBDA3AF96437A9723476DAC6025EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Additionally, support services for veterans' families shall be available to foster stability and wellness within the family unit, especially for those experiencing post-service challenges.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18012A10267E447C8D47700FB36F2484"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to employment and housing assistance.</text><subparagraph id="H409BFC95AF3142A695803F39D467C7A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans transitioning to civilian life shall have access to robust employment services, including job training, career counseling, and resume workshops.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7284B6D3EDC94BA0BF8A6054122AF5D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The VA shall also provide resources for housing stability, such as assistance in securing affordable housing and support for homelessness prevention for veterans in need.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8FB445B854E4E449918F782E8736B4A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to accessibility in services and facilities.</text><subparagraph id="HE5A822FA0F294A828EF7D31B212791C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans shall access VA services without physical, geographical, or logistical barriers, with reasonable accommodations provided for disabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2B5F2A64AAB46598D67CCB90396620C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The VA shall also expand telehealth options and partnerships with local providers, particularly to serve veterans in remote or underserved areas, ensuring equitable service access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0719FC4B746C41BAB5C0BBE0FC68CA00"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to involvement in decisions affecting their care and benefits.</text><subparagraph id="H13E758D1E6DC409FB98F5677C2E9CA63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans shall be included in decisions about their care plans, treatment options, and benefits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDFE12DDD59E4A0A85CD0F07EA113E6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The VA shall involve veterans in discussions about their treatment and benefits eligibility, ensuring that veterans’ preferences and needs are considered and respected in every decision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A2DC658D4BB43598E0B0F2CB9948A45"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to transparency in benefits adjudication.</text><subparagraph id="H36A26450D60A4C939308B48FC5334F32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans shall be provided with a transparent process for adjudicating claims, including clear information on application requirements, expected timelines, and necessary documentation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H871D81CE64804E329858AB505D70E1CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The VA shall issue written decisions on claims within a specified timeframe, including explanations for any denials and information on appeal options.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H992830FB31C644A4987F69BA090769EF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to a fair and timely appeals process.</text><subparagraph id="HE75E922463504774B1E48C73C6B57DEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Veterans may appeal denied claims through a fair and efficient process, receiving guidance from the VA on each step.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DB0FA0C166142EF927B0E7F12E34093"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The VA shall aim, to the extent practicable, to resolve appeals within 120 days of filing, with progress updates provided throughout the process to ensure veterans are informed of the status of their cases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA4120BF2CFB4546B098A23BD69C56E8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Veterans have the right to consistent and proactive communication.</text><subparagraph id="H1DC60B968D504AA2B7404FAB7312BDEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The VA shall proactively communicate with veterans regarding any updates or changes to their benefits and eligibility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAABD2DB8F4B94B6E90CE35AFFBE0E839"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Veterans should receive timely information about new or modified services they qualify for, ensuring they have a clear understanding of all available resources throughout their lives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0723F49C35C4157B9E508574CB9EAF9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hotline and portal</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H57B78FF1C448435895B1E4172840EBD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall maintain a toll-free hotline and a publicly accessible website of the Department through which a veteran may report a complaint regarding compliance by the Secretary with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2EB833B356945FCBCD6FD9B209960D0" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall respond to a veteran not later than 30 days after the Secretary receives such a complaint.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFD7BE83147841EBA1C4DD18CD226490"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not less than once each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report regarding compliance of the Secretary with this section. Each such report shall include the following elements with regards to the year preceding the date of such report:</text><paragraph id="HEE6395F903264C08AFE320B1D07C1CAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of complaints pursuant to subsection (c), disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="H5EDC03167B584FCEB68B545DD3A89C77"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">category of issue (such as access to care, claims processing, appeals, communication, privacy, or other); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBC6F7FFD27646CBBD01CEB156AFCF46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facility of the Department;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1920A6D106FA490CB29E878EF86B1F35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The median and average response times for complaints.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC252AE6B6BEF4ECF810C7DE2E421A405"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The percentage of complaints resolved within 30 days.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6790664C1627494EB2E790209BFBD06E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of corrective actions taken or policy changes made by the Secretary as a result of complaints or identified noncompliance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H340FCAD9295C42D0968F4C1B47B99432"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Data on average and median processing times for benefit claims and appeals, compared to the target timelines under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA932F5A32244C0EAE1E3A8112EA48F0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number of veterans provided information or referrals for community care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D680BC42ED49A6A18B236099AB898E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Recommendations of the Secretary for legislative or administrative action to further the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8F93BA2A484A478DA2B6BBD112FE5427"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out section 6321 of such title, as added by this section, not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

