<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26680-XNT-Y2-7K6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S5020 IS: Improving Housing Performance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 5020</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a study on manufactured homes in areas at high risk of natural hazards and weather extremes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id9847c6e97b364b4ead894be0205e052e" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd66ea6b5d1341d1ba76dbaa853f13c6"><enum/><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Housing Performance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72241e50be194c1aa3a5a5268e487fed" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on manufactured homes in areas at high-risk of natural hazards and weather extremes</header><subsection id="id8eb43aa0d466445ea56bfbae1cda1d22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id266f6c19dd5a444ea7284d0b3425c977"><enum>(1)</enum><header>High risk areas</header><text>The term <term>high risk areas</term> means geographic locations that are susceptible to heightened frequency of natural hazards and extreme weather events, including floods, wildfires, tropical storms and hurricanes, tornadoes, earthquakes, and extreme heat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e68ff42295e4333b84c274c432475ea"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manufactured home</header><text>The term <term>manufactured home</term> has the meaning given the term in section 603 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1833b233d1d34430b70e8f2b985a9927"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Performance</header><text>The term <term>performance</term>, with respect to a manufactured home, means the ability of a manufactured home to keep individuals safe and to reasonably withstand natural hazards and weather events, including floods, wildfires, tropical storms and hurricanes, tornadoes, earthquakes, and extreme heat, over time.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6556228c24ab4bdc896f2f1471f1c4bd"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc41d63603f884d0dbd27dd71d369d5f6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The term <term>Standards</term> means the Federal Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards established under section 604 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5403">42 U.S.C. 5403</external-xref>), as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idec47d335b1774573ad80744e45a7a78f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall commission an independent, third-party study in accordance with subsection (d)(2) that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88320520901e47499510404c683789de"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be made available in accordance with subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf2e2245cb064d78bfb2105591203b64"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluates data and other evidence about the performance of manufactured homes that are—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21a0a0090d38485da9b4834ab1577d6a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">built and installed in accordance with the Standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd14e0e0974404dbd8cf0d0c0b1856a95"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">located in high risk areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5b840ed1a4b1451786bf22f4e2f2c8fe"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Research objectives</header><text>The study required under subsection (b), and the report required under subsection (d), shall—</text><paragraph id="id20eca60fba8a4d0cbe47cb67815ce14c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make recommendations on how to improve the Standards that shall inform future updates to the Standards considered by the Manufactured Housing Consensus Committee established under section 604(a)(3) of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5403">42 U.S.C. 5403(a)(3)</external-xref>) and adopted by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7496feead78e48689edd6375b10f74b9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include substantive sections relating to—</text><subparagraph id="idc1d89ca77c1842b19130c17ec0e1e494"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing clear, data-driven criteria for identifying high risk areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc875560f38574980bff9bca4f8ee3fd5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of the best available data and other evidence about the performance of modern manufactured homes in high risk areas, and the identification of improvements to the Standards, building materials, and design, construction, and safety standards that could improve manufactured home performance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06f100cb5bd14a27b7281784968e8e5b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of the best available data and other evidence about the performance of manufactured homes in high risk areas based on the requirements of the Standards regarding installation of such homes, and the identification of potential updates to installation-related Standards that could improve performance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bde0003cc444bc8bb609e71654a31ea"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the effects that improved building materials and design, construction, and safety standards, respectively, are expected to have on the cost and affordability of developing and living in manufactured homes in high risk areas, to the extent that industry is already developing manufactured homes with such improvements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72c7c4f20c4847e6bb0ed73e872b7c76"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which the manufactured home industry is already developing manufactured homes to performance standards that exceed—</text><clause id="id6e17d781d4b844269c4f9289f82f5435"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Standards; and</text></clause><clause id="idd5eed130fd5b4095a29c0209654d04f5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the improvements recommended under subparagraph (B); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5464d860b724dbf97ba9ae72d4685af"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the identification of deficiencies in data available as of the date of the report regarding the performance of manufactured homes in high risk areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idedc606f5baa640cab286dcf40eccb7c9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><paragraph id="id00ec074b2b044eef8edb6c77632d9a67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and make publicly and permanently available on the website of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="iddad237f598a0418398533ea3d4c1fbab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>findings from the study required under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd462baec70634c8f9dfca7c2a16890b7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or regulatory changes to improve the performance of manufactured homes, including estimated implementation timeframes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9ab36d1d72f4c1888e2064d95d7e4b5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of the effects of implementing the recommendations described in subparagraph (B) on the overall performance and affordability, respectively, of manufactured homes, including the upfront costs to produce and install the manufactured homes, as well as the long-term costs of owning, renting, or operating the manufactured homes in high risk areas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1cc68623fb564ccd83cbb017c6e66508"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a strategy for improving data collection on manufactured home performance during and after natural hazards and extreme weather events.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id11a89eb4cd884b1a9fe8bdcd0c50bd33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission and preparation of report</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be prepared by not less than 1 independent and non-partisan research organization with expertise in the performance of manufactured homes and the Standards relating to natural hazards and extreme weather events.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

