<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2CA2D6E372345C893B9ED4FE8C485AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7756 IH: First-time Homebuyer Savings Account Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7756</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish tax-advantaged homeowner savings accounts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F4758ACFE174229B83307FE3545A538" style="OLC"><section id="H472D158D68CC44EE89B2C7C8ABB3E593" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First-time Homebuyer Savings Account Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H769EDA9B295A4BCA983C130014ED4C8C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Homeowner savings account</header><subsection id="HB46730920B5A482B94AF478548328DAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 225 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAE256BC817E84C439AAEACDAB014B14F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H8E5A94515EBD4E85944E685FD4BB1768"><enum>225A.</enum><header>Homeowner savings account</header><subsection id="H5783A920543D42529547B4452F2BF74F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deduction allowed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year an amount equal to the aggregate amount paid in cash during such taxable year by or on behalf of such individual to a homeowner savings account of such individual.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E000E6496C345F69A264AA25BC0DFED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H5C1985D3C387411985953B9B4207B473"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Homeowner savings account</header><text>The term <quote>homeowner savings account</quote> means a trust created or organized in the United States as a homeowner savings account exclusively for the purpose of paying qualified homeowner expenses of the account beneficiary, but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H1CBB2B64A8284388961B7F5E51B2AD02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except in the case of a rollover contribution, no contribution will be accepted—</text><clause id="H16BFEA80B18A4A01A8FB75AD9E9A2E43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>unless it is in cash,</text></clause><clause id="H0EC19CEC88554A728E76B8B961C99658"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent such contribution, when added to previous contributions to the trust for the calendar year, exceeds the amount in effect for the calendar year under subparagraph (A) of section 219(b)(5) (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) thereof), and</text></clause><clause id="HCF5F2DE3EA75480E9935F4468BDA6AB9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the extent that after such contribution the amount held in the account would exceed an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount published under paragraph (6) for the year in which the contribution is made.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF917E69818DF48CA8811EBCEE6479092"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The trustee is a bank (as defined in section 408(n)), an insurance company (as defined in section 816), or another person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which such person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H247F434A7B864838A54D51CEAF2AF467"><enum>(C)</enum><text>No part of the trust assets will be invested in life insurance contracts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37A247C77D6146DFBD107C411F74DFA3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The assets of the trust will not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2151CAFD8B9243A3B4AAF682BB4E7A32"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The interest of an individual in the balance in his account is nonforfeitable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D6AD44ED04C4FDCB6B6CE158AC7CEC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible individual</quote> means an individual if such individual (and, if married, such individual’s spouse) had no present ownership interest in a principal residence during the 3-year period ending on the present date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EFC26B12DC642E78776761B4FEF8EA5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified homeowner expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified homeowner expenses</quote> means amounts paid or incurred to—</text><subparagraph id="H802DEA50B89848BF860F91C8C0EF8144"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase or construct the principal residence of the individual if such individual had no present ownership interest in a principal residence during the 3-year period ending on the date of the purchase or beginning of construction of the principal residence, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AAAD876B6584709BDD9C299E15DF552"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make alterations, repairs, or improvements which meet the requirements of section 143(k)(4) (determined without regard to the dollar limitation provided in such section) to such principal residence so purchased or constructed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB45AD973D2CA43CDA62B935367F561A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Account beneficiary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>account beneficiary</quote> means the individual on whose behalf the homeowner savings account was established.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE640430BC844DFB85D1247DFCDA6668"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>The term <quote>principle residence</quote> has the same meaning as when used in section 121.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77E50EF7EF4E4737B7A534E61E812DEB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Publication of national average single family home price</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall, not later than December 31 of each calendar year, publish the estimated national average price of a single family home for the following calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D33391682946ADB48F00BF4F207A02"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rollover contribution</header><text>The term <quote>rollover contribution</quote> means an amount paid or distributed from a homeowner savings account to the account beneficiary to the extent that—</text><subparagraph id="HD639821EE6254E4B960F5E025814C0A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount received is paid into a homeowner savings account for the benefit of such beneficiary not later than the 60th day after the day on which the beneficiary receives the payment or distribution, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAB2B33438144A6D8FDAF39D5B4A49F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such account beneficiary did not receive any other amount described in subparagraph (A) from a homeowner savings account which was not includible in the individual’s gross income because of subsection (d)(2)(B) during the 1-year period ending on the date of such receipt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H848AB1F6808C4163A9933F25B531BA5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of contributions</header><paragraph id="H7EB49148025F4782B15248819A27CBB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contribution limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount of contributions for any taxable year to all homeowner savings accounts maintained for the benefit of an individual shall not exceed the lesser of—</text><subparagraph id="H7981DFBD27CF49E0B85460DE48EBA7E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount in effect for the taxable year in which such contributions are made under subparagraph (A) of section 219(b)(5) (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) thereof),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC70F3024344C4879B5DB51E3F6C9BD28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amount equal to the compensation includible in the individual’s gross income for such taxable year, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EEF28782A97478F9825FD84C22830B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount that would result in the amount held in the account exceeding an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount published under subsection (b)(6) for the year in which the contribution is made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBE756EEA2FC4C2C9BA984E3AD461536"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation based on modified adjusted gross income</header><text>The amount determined under paragraph (1)(A) for any taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount which bears the same ratio to such amount as—</text><subparagraph id="H192551D8407740418964CA5B354C51E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the excess of—</text><clause id="H43E5B278922949649937C2F4083876A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over</text></clause><clause id="HC4BA65A31C964745A808583D92DFF425"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable dollar amount (as defined in section 219(g)(3)(B), determined after the application of section 219(g)(8)), bears to</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CF587EDD6DD4C96B8B7BEAE45DCB96C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$10,000 ($20,000 in the case of a joint return or a married individual filing a separate return).</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The rules of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 219(g)(2) shall apply to any reduction under this paragraph.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99A20EF915E04366AEAD007DD51796C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Spousal contribution</header><subparagraph id="H281807B2E30F40B986B98C182B5B6E1E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual to whom this paragraph applies for the taxable year, the limitation of paragraph (1) shall be equal to the lesser of—</text><clause id="HD407C040786643508E91326EB3FCED74"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the compensation includible in such individual's gross income for the taxable year, plus</text></clause><clause id="H75866826E04D41AD96D76B6674EC0AC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the compensation includible in the gross income of such individual's spouse for the taxable year reduced by the amount allowed as a deduction under subsection (a) to such spouse for such taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7561231A0B2C41AFA7E7E1F05E60608B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Individual to whom subparagraph (A) applies</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall apply to any individual if—</text><clause id="H9F6A643624A4464F87F41BD7F051B621"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such individual files a joint return for the taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="H83522DFF22034FEDBA6BFC2B446DD2A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of compensation (if any) includible in such individual's gross income for the taxable year is less than the compensation includible in the gross income of such individual's spouse for the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F2D86AAEF0E45519978B3B48953CBC1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of distributions</header><paragraph id="HEB2C12D81D7A4D2E87293A5892EC0582"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts used for qualified homeowner expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount paid or distributed out of a homeowner savings account which is used exclusively to pay qualified homeowner expenses shall not be includible in gross income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H112073D5764B4823AFF9E597EC0D5733"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of amounts not used for qualified homeowner expenses</header><text>Any amount paid or distributed out of a homeowner savings account which is not—</text><subparagraph id="H5B04C940559948BC8293902A97379CF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used exclusively to pay the qualified homeowner expenses of the account beneficiary,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H170B87870C9C46738B2F6AA11C921AD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an exempted distribution, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAAFBF0FD39245A3877A341DF03629D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a rollover contribution,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall be included in the gross income of such beneficiary and the amount of any tax imposed by this chapter shall be increased by 10 percent on any amount so includible.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56830DD3C902415AB98F795140CBB947"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exempted distribution</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>exempted distribution</quote> means an amount paid or distributed out of a homeowner savings account by reason of—</text><subparagraph id="H5ED6162C691C4CD1B0F610EB212A0C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an emergency, including—</text><clause id="H62F526169D5E4528B61C30ECCAD7F708"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the loss of a job or major source of income, or</text></clause><clause id="H2BF4B7C73A8B4D2FB290307F8C967B7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a major health event leading to substantial medical expenses,</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06DC4F9C145F4410BA24B30A7404E17F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a life event, including—</text><clause id="H3ED6220A23744B9FA11942733A68FEA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>acquiring a present ownership interest in a principal residence by reason of marriage,</text></clause><clause id="H3864033DA1A44FACB29FE33F24F51565"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>death of the account beneficiary, or</text></clause><clause id="H743A027576A24BA8A1D802FD18D38A24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the account beneficiary residing outside the United States, or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H512D82A01D6041FB9B33F479A70A1805"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other circumstances as the Secretary determines appropriate by regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A6089F66674582939C69A1E9C7842A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Excess contributions returns before due date of return</header><subparagraph id="HC53EC65EA42943FAAD28996DD709434C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any excess contribution is contributed for a taxable year to any homeowner savings account of an individual, paragraph (2) shall not apply to distributions from the homeowner savings accounts of such individual (to the extent such distributions do not exceed the aggregate excess contributions to all such accounts of such individual for such year) if—</text><clause id="H1842521D50394CBB80BA86C15721514F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such distribution is received by the individual on or before the last day prescribed by law (including extensions of time) for filing such individual's return for such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="HCBE5C08EC38D43D4A57ADEEE23882C7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such distribution is accompanied by the amount of net income attributable to such excess contribution.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any net income described in clause (ii) shall be included in the gross income of the individual for the taxable year in which it is received.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C7359C3EC19467F9A22D90CF957272D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess contribution defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>excess contribution</quote> means any contribution (other than a rollover contribution) which is not excludable from gross income under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36216F376CAC404BB26C5BFE705A1CBC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tax treatment of accounts</header><paragraph id="HE65406DB345241D6A863D434F054994F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A homeowner savings account is exempt from taxation under this subtitle unless such account has ceased to be a homeowner savings account. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any such account is subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable, etc. organizations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF42E150F6A9D4873935A0AEAEED9D63C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Account termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2) and (4) of section 408(e) shall apply to homeowner savings accounts, and any amount treated as distributed under such rules shall be treated as not used to pay qualified homeowner expenses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61E2AB53DCE741AE95A379C040CC716A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Custodial account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a custodial account shall be treated as a trust if the assets of such account are held by a bank (as defined in section 408(n)) or another person who demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that the manner in which he will administer the account will be consistent with the requirements of this section, and if the custodial account would, except for the fact that it is not a trust, constitute an account described in subsection (b)(1). For purposes of this title, in the case of a custodial account treated as a trust by reason of the preceding sentence, the custodian of such account shall be treated as the trustee thereof.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC57659B9B27E46CE9ED0B0BCC1555555"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tax on excess contributions</header><paragraph id="HCC90B4353BA844E893EACC29009692EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4973(a) of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA186B062EF224E2AAB65151078B1527B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>or</quote>,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BD71031383340848EEAE65D0D79406A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the comma, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23DF7263F0C34688947691AF00AFFE32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE116426EBE5D4AF1B271CD5C3EFE70CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HA23C4B06398D48B595538F590270A509"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a homeowner savings account (within the meaning of section 225A(b)(1)),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD0E082D1BAA4D4DAE6ADE82ACDFC2DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of excess contribution in 4973</header><text>Section 4973 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H066365147A7C45B6B74EF0B030A823AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H40A27FBFA2DB4042830ED2D4C8BDBBAE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Excess contributions to homeowner savings account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, in the case of a homeowner savings account (within the meaning of section 225A(b)(1)), the term <quote>excess contribution</quote> means the amount by which the amount contributed for the taxable year to such account exceeds the contribution limit under 225A(c)(1).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D01E6D8130440FEB1A15D451EBAB3C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle A of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 225 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8E498D1980EB4BD8A1616F3E4A5B4729" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="H8E5A94515EBD4E85944E685FD4BB1768" level="section">Sec. 225A. Homeowner savings account.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H81452CF1DD854DDDBCD9D67E9E6465F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

