<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H05C2AB4DDDE44B589CC7D95B2EA1CF0D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6552 RH: Bank-Fintech Partnership Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 456</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6552</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–531]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on December 10, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation to study how partnerships between fintechs and banking organizations can support new banking organization formation and community bank health, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HE5EC628418DA45308DBA56492BC04FFC"><section id="H3BB0E759F2004541ADBC2A64C0223621" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bank-Fintech Partnership Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HD0CFDF208B4948E288CB9CBA493CA2C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on bank-fintech partnerships</header><subsection id="HF2C369AB51C649C29944DD5D9418FDF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall carry out a study of—</text><paragraph id="HEEC0ABDF499249E6AC17BE7ADD0DF240"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of partnerships between banking organizations, on the one hand, and financial technology companies, on the other hand, on the banking sector, competition, innovation, consumer protection, and the availability of financial products and services, including the extent to which these partnerships support the formation of new banking organizations, reduce time to market for products and services, lower compliance burdens, boost customer acquisition, improve technological capabilities, and provide access to more diverse funding sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9DD449C461245479F47989F75401166"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">what changes to Federal laws governing banking organizations, or to rules or guidance adopted by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, may help promote effective partnerships between banking organizations, on the one hand, and financial technology companies, on the other hand.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H161BE42E6A2E4F1DA20D7F93E1F06F71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall issue a report to Congress containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBA3982BA5F8442B48A894B4CCF664101"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Banking organization defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>banking organization</quote> means a depository institution holding company or an insured depository institution, as such terms are defined, respectively, under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H6B8D389CD6EB4E36A9B75017D04F36F8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on credit union-fintech partnerships</header><subsection id="H4C7AE76C0F7048E8BC9D4898FD6FB219"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Credit Union Administration shall carry out a study of—</text><paragraph id="H2029E87B5B594CCE9D37124D07EE76CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the impact of partnerships between credit unions, on the one hand, and financial technology companies, on the other hand, on the credit union sector, competition, innovation, consumer protection, and the availability of financial products and services, including the extent to which these partnerships support the formation of new credit unions, reduce time to market for products and services, lower compliance burdens, boost customer acquisition, improve technological capabilities, and provide access to more diverse funding sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A3594186AB749DC95FCEF525F4A65CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>what changes to Federal laws governing credit unions, or to rules or guidance adopted by the National Credit Union Administration, may help promote effective partnerships between credit unions, on the one hand, and financial technology companies, on the other hand.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE15E74ADF2DA4D4BA7287E73FEDD01F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the National Credit Union Administration shall issue a report to Congress containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

