<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H0A883C56A10540BD8BDB3DCA6315B2BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7529 RH: Fresh Starts for Foster Youth Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 557</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7529</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–640]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 12, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require States to consider legal issues affecting youth as part of case planning and to provide States with the option to use funds from the John H. Chafee Foster Care Program for Successful Transition to Adulthood to support access to legal services and counseling.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HWM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H50328DD73A1544F9A053F1DCA0B1B6F1"><section id="H0E57E6FDFE8B4B7884A9B432607360EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fresh Starts for Foster Youth Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3A927C1A170647CD987F1BE1F5988BE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Legal consulting and access under the John H. Chafee Foster Care Program for Successful Transition to Adulthood</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 477 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8AE53CE99B03436197B2213B725559BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(4), by inserting <quote>legal counseling access,</quote> after <quote>education,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70360CCBA90A42DABDE9D4A9F9AFF034"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC378252A81FE41D99629936E6A2A2826" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HWM00"><subparagraph id="H8E0D46FB1D3C4D4CB9F609333D175889"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A certification by the chief executive officer of the State that the relevant case planning and other processes employed by the State take into consideration certain legal issues affecting housing, education, entry into employment, and family connections of current and former foster youth and the efforts required to address the issues, including with respect to State court records, legal recognition of family relationships, and matters relating to custody and permanency.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HA2F9E7A1661C42D08896A9713B9B8A55"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><subsection id="HA39140EF3BD3421D9918C7AEAA3AB28C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to payments under section 477 of the Social Security Act pursuant to plans approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services on or after such date.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D46D376ACB04053AD363122B1FCA208"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delay permitted if State legislation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines that State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) is required in order for a State plan developed pursuant to section 477 of the Social Security Act to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act, the plan shall not be regarded as failing to meet any of the additional requirements before the 1st day of the 1st calendar quarter beginning after the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the preceding sentence, if the State has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

