<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H007E66DAC586477DB7A86746ED46224E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7226 IH: Leveraging Artificial Intelligence to Streamline the Code of Federal Regulations Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7226</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the use of artificial intelligence to review agency regulations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H697410E82065490EA88702F9853E0670" style="OLC"><section id="H13994224E4F1493EAC6CD005E6500472" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leveraging Artificial Intelligence to Streamline the Code of Federal Regulations Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAF2777D8DAFF48A9A551FC3C65C3ABDB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HFAC7ED0FB22944149D2AB5758E45DFE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B8AD6548734FECA16DB23C09FEC06E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence system</term> means a machine-based system that, for an explicit or implicit objective, infers how to generate outputs, such as predictions, content, recommendations, or decisions that can influence physical or virtual environments, from the input the system receives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26D283E73C464F17BE596337A8FFDDB0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Redundant</header><text>The term <term>redundant</term> means a regulation that duplicates, overlaps with, or serves the same purpose as another regulation, such that the elimination of the regulation would not result in a loss of essential information or regulatory function.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4793D2177454ED0828C912EAB10A0E3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulation</header><text>The term <term>regulation</term> has the meaning given the term <term>rule</term> in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09D8BED26C6C4BAFBAF22B70941E18F6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outdated</header><text>The term <term>outdated</term> means a regulation that has been superseded by more recent legislation, technological advances, or regulatory developments, rendering the regulation inapplicable or unenforceable.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H75CEC2FCE55846209B303BA5E3135FE7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual artificial intelligence review of the Code of Federal Regulations</header><subsection id="H2D8EBB410D084E6CBB6EE16FA91431BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall implement a process for identifying redundant or outdated regulations in the Code of Federal Regulations using an artificial intelligence system.</text></subsection><subsection id="H50202A2E755842F3AA5CD20649BDF1FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The process established under subsection (a) shall employ an artificial intelligence system that meets strict standards, as set out by the National Institute of Standards and Technology, for accuracy, transparency, accountability, and national security risk.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6070203122A41EE8DA00CD2DDBFE8E0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of process and artificial intelligence system</header><text>Not less frequently than once per fiscal year, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in coordination with the head of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall review and, as appropriate, revise the process established under subsection (a) to ensure that—</text><paragraph id="H2FCF8064238A4090A744898562790383"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the process is functioning properly and efficiently; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B6B4BC24CC04CCA8DDF820BFBD1F719"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the underlying artificial intelligence system involved in such process still meets the criteria under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28E85C3580BE40CC9E3695E6E5692028"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of regulations</header><paragraph id="HDCA5A280B38F4E43968E0F8833B3AD85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Referral and review</header><text>A regulation that is identified as redundant or outdated using the process established under subsection (a) shall be immediately referred to the agency responsible for promulgating the regulation for review by that agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC873FB6CD36A4DD9A396A2A7F6EAD4D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><subparagraph id="H34DE144991B54050B190FF65B4608B0D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after a regulation is referred to an agency under paragraph (1), personnel at that agency shall make a determination as to whether the regulation is outdated or redundant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0307F5B23D5144D8BA29B4D2A8F37898"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Finality of determination</header><text>Any determination made under subparagraph (A) shall be final.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C4C9D5BB014420E9BD7C84FA12B90E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rescission of regulations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a regulation has been determined to be redundant under subsection (d), the agency that promulgated the regulation shall rescind or remove such regulation from the Code of Federal Regulations, notwithstanding the requirements under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC058F02461114F60BED234D1D3A79340"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Amendment of regulations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a regulation has been determined to be outdated under subsection (d), the agency that promulgated the regulation shall—</text><paragraph id="H6B819EFDA22A45FCA7A9A894FF153942"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amend the regulation, notwithstanding the requirements under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, for the purposes of bringing the outdated substance up to date; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC3178DCEF8942A39149FA65E158ED6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>rescind or remove such regulation from the Code of Federal Regulations, notwithstanding the requirements under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C306D4B742F47038028737756D66994"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Written determination</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B8D7EDFF1544B26B4A6BC7A0DA8758B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any determination made under subsection (d) shall be immediately published on the website of the relevant agency, including a brief written explanation of the determination, which shall be made publicly available.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBA0EDD9755244C988E8FE6E60B3467F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classified annex</header><text>The head of the agency may, as necessary, submit a classified annex to Congress to supplement the explanation published under subsection (g).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H85DB4F274BC843A08986165D7D6E96DB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expedited rescission and amendment of redundant and outdated regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended in the flush text at the end—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8F4FBC55CAF473A9BC9064B82B9988D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63EBD9772CA14ACAA1E9D5C99AE96D86"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H416C2D09FEFF4B2989AF77F14ED3DB8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A7C71D9D6CD45B7A7CC1244906BC825"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6581F5D7ABDC4D40BA74620E3F0C16E3" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a regulation determined to be redundant or outdated as part of the annual review of the Code of Federal Regulations under the <short-title>Leveraging Artificial Intelligence to Streamline the Code of Federal Regulations Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

