<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H482A7C39464F45D49FCBBCC9F34AE756" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6060 IH: Safe and Fair Elimination of Taps with Lead Service Lines Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6060</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to provide grants to units of local governments, drinking water systems, and federally recognized Indian Tribes for the replacement of lead, galvanized steel, and iron service lines and lead drinking water mains, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE6103B4DF8004A2380283C339BAB9502" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF6FC71723F1643BC8F254CCA5AE708B2" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe and Fair Elimination of Taps with Lead Service Lines Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Taps Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HA3D6C92EFFCC4C9D8D2522DCDA83072A" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2E545A0D733A456D8CEEBE5643D9D512" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The presence of lead in drinking water poses a grave and ongoing threat to public health in the United States. The Environmental Protection Agency and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention agree that there is no known safe level of lead exposure, which causes irreversible neurological damage in children and serious health conditions in adults.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H239D94D896874E49A8327D3B3D783A3D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Lead service lines, which connect drinking water mains to millions of homes, schools, and childcare facilities, are the most significant source of lead contamination in drinking water. The Environmental Protection Agency estimates that 9.2 million lead service lines serve water to buildings in communities across the United States.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18C8C40586B242DC86BAE0991BC0E7D5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency, through subpart I of part 141 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, has mandated the full replacement of most lead service lines within a 10-year period, placing a significant legal and financial obligation on units of local governments and public water systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4CE8F812C9C4F4BAFF02FFE07133F11" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While State revolving loan funds established under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300j-12">42 U.S.C. 300j–12</external-xref>) are a critical tool to finance water infrastructure, the primary structure of such funds as a loan program is inadequate to meet the needs of many communities facing the lead service line replacement mandate under subpart I of part 141 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations. Financially distressed and disadvantaged communities often lack the debt capacity to accept loans or the technical capacity to navigate the complex application process under a State revolving loan fund.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA347554B749A46A3B3407A70049B89E5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The funds made available for lead service line replacement projects and associated activities by the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) provided a historic and vital down payment for lead service line replacement, but the overwhelming demand for these funds demonstrated that a substantial funding gap remains and that a loan-based system presents significant barriers to the most vulnerable communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FFBC729C4274BCAAF740217E5674A05" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In many older communities, lead service lines are connected to aging drinking water mains that are also at or near the end of their useful life. Forcing municipalities to replace lead service lines without addressing these deteriorating drinking water mains is fiscally inefficient and fails to ensure the long-term integrity of the water system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A8E8C072E854AC1AF0829D7E8386581" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A dedicated Federal grant program is therefore necessary to ensure the equitable, efficient, and timely replacement of all lead service lines and drinking water mains that are not lead free to protect public health, to achieve compliance with subpart I of part 141 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, and to advance environmental justice for all Americans.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HE2F0C36CBBBC4054A87C6FCB838C6496"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program for the replacement of lead, galvanized steel, and iron service lines and lead drinking water mains</header> <subsection id="H00FFD35932C44A909047ED8A9A647228" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish a program to provide grants, subject to the availability of appropriations, to eligible recipients to pay for eligible project costs.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA935E16158C74052833F1DFC376530BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Labor standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of construction, alteration, or repair work financed in whole or in part with a grant provided under the program shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar work in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>).</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H8682ADE13FB845A1B286C352B5786099"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H76332D5F148943749214679494DB65B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80CAC5CF5935413498544A522D345A87" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible project costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible project costs</term> means costs to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H98D2AA9966234091BCB3E0B1E2EA9916" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">replace a lead service line;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F97D4038E0148D5BEFCBFD977D5883E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">replace galvanized steel or iron service lines that are or were downstream of lead components;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AD37237AF1544BBAEE7E0CF54A5EBDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>replace a drinking water main that is not lead free;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA98F0CFD594F410A9609604E22F22B42" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">plan for or otherwise design the replacement of a lead service line, galvanized steel or iron service line, or drinking water main using a grant provided under the program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AA116D186594B88B63EC9BC464A08B2" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop or update any inventory of lead service lines; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6EEB000398FF492295D5A842056B0C94" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>restore the site at which a service line or drinking water main is replaced using a grant provided under the program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C5ED07C74C441B1A22685FE3619BE4B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text>The term <term>eligible recipient</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H912C8F81F2FF4D809E509BAE73B76529"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of local government;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H965FCF0D205748F59CD2BECE7A814818"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public water system; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0EC497361D645A685EEC646EC0E0294"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36E12DE98DAC4AD8B42DE861BC653C2F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Lead free</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lead free</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1417(d)(1) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300g-6">42 U.S.C. 300g–6(d)(1)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H734B8825D8C44322906C21E656B1C60D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lead service line</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lead service line</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1459B(a) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (42 U.S.C. 300j–19b(a)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB65C0389BACD4A5DBBB0C398130D0A62"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program</term> means the program established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9717DE00A5C646EDAD97E73E26A808E0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public water system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public water system</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1401(4) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

