<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDCD7861A09EA47399AC9136B8ADC6727" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7237 IH: Chemical Abortion Risk Awareness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7237</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260123">January 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure that a woman seeking a chemical abortion is made aware of the risks involved, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H673E81C7741C419680F918D9EE01CECF" style="OLC"><section id="H4C45B57988CB478F9BFD359B4C613512" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chemical Abortion Risk Awareness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD07CB960B227490C96CC932010B3448A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chemical abortion risk awareness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9DC96791018843F8A22181E6747CE85A" style="OLC"><title id="H1A22D68B571E49F99519094B36248E24"><enum>XXXIV</enum><header>Chemical abortion risk awareness</header><section id="HB482B27787E741D9BDC15AE22EB78A6C"><enum>3401.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="HD65AB8B0943048D492BD1C84CB5550E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chemical abortion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>chemical abortion</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H735D32FB68F840BC89AE05D2494684AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the use or prescription of an abortion-inducing drug dispensed with the intent to cause the death of the unborn child; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23ECF0D0719A41FF90AB2260A2370EE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="HAFB1CDAC66574770A5FA97964EA26A5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separation of the mother and her embryo or fetus to prevent the mother’s death or immediate irreversible bodily harm if such death or harm cannot be mitigated in any other way;</text></clause><clause id="HEFEC38C1796C419D9010D4B1238734FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>treatment of ectopic or molar pregnancy; and</text></clause><clause id="HC8FCA46B373F4C31969908245748CB7F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>treatment of miscarriage.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC21AB136A52471683FC4061E46ADDD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chemical abortion provider</header><text>The term <term>chemical abortion provider</term> means any person licensed to perform a chemical abortion under applicable Federal and State laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0330225464AD4EF481C6A3E08A8A765C" commented="no"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Unborn child</header> <text>The term <term>unborn child</term> means a member of the species Homo sapiens, at any stage of development prior to birth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE0DAE59800FE4F3583B4C5DFC2265F03"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Woman</header><text>The term <term>woman</term> means a human being with XX chromosomes.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF1CC7E33CBC84FE8942E3CD27A1FD807"><enum>3402.</enum><header>Chemical abortion risk awareness</header><subsection id="H4316ADD2FB4A43E499B6A03D4112D80A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement of compliance by providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective 30 days after the date of enactment of this title, any chemical abortion provider receiving Federal funds, or working in, for, or on behalf of a medical practice or company that receives Federal funds, who knowingly performs or induces, or attempts to perform or induce, any chemical abortion, shall comply with the requirements of this title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H35AF8D502E5042BD8EC0647431592986"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Informed consent</header><text>A chemical abortion shall not knowingly be performed or induced, or be attempted to be performed or induced, by a chemical abortion provider referred to in subsection (a) unless the chemical abortion provider, not later than 24 hours before the chemical abortion—</text><paragraph id="H69ED75D88C2B4EF888F375BD2C5D0B1D"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides to the woman, in both electronic and paper form, a full Food and Drug Administration-approved product label for each abortion-inducing drug to be used, with the <quote>Warnings and Precautions</quote> and <quote>Adverse Reactions</quote> sections of the label (or such other similar sections) highlighted;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB912A02D2A7C4F498EB15CF399153D60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reads to the woman the full text of such highlighted sections; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD706DA2D9FB4A30BC9F230853B511E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>receives confirmation from the woman in writing that the requirements described in paragraphs (1) and (2) have been fulfilled.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7AB3A67A1635480797960E9525279DB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this title, a chemical abortion provider referred to in subsection (a) (or the entity that such provider works in, for, or on behalf of) shall submit to the Secretary a plan for implementing the requirements of this title applicable to such provider.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8C908B9A02194C37B27FA3D0305599B9"><enum>3403.</enum><header>Withholding of Federal funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other law, in the case that a chemical abortion provider is not in compliance with the requirements of this title, the Secretary may withhold the Federal funding of the chemical abortion provider, the entity at which the chemical abortion provider is employed or on behalf of which the chemical abortion provider performs or induces chemical abortions, or both.</text></section><section commented="no" id="H0C11057044A34E9EAE7C03E4533D92C1"><enum>3404.</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subsection id="H7712FDCD0A204F8F973712CB9FCA596E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A woman or a parent of a woman upon whom an abortion has been performed or induced, or attempted to be performed or induced, by a chemical abortion provider in violation of this title may commence a civil action against the chemical abortion provider for appropriate relief.</text></subsection><subsection id="H311D1DAAA6374CBBB144D34224A0B729"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate relief in a civil action under this section includes—</text><paragraph id="H39D52E7EA7B84E1BAB07844B8595928D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>objectively verifiable money damages for all injuries, psychological and physical, occasioned by the violation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C643BBB83DE4B018160121F558F6A96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>statutory damages equal to 3 times the cost of the abortion; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H841DE1C1705147A0A455E47C9E96127E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>punitive damages.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA61B14D803C4B6983BF8564616BF90F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees for plaintiff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs to a prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H699CC275BF104E6EBC57B8264D934F43"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees for defendant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a defendant in a civil action under this section prevails, and the court finds that the plaintiff’s suit was frivolous, the court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee in favor of the defendant against the plaintiff.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5BDB64EC00A24A5D9AA2ABC2597AB6BC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Awards against woman</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any civil action under this section, no damages or other monetary relief, and no attorney’s fees except as provided in subsection (d), may be assessed against the woman upon whom the abortion was performed or induced or attempted to be performed or induced.</text></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HA32CE70FFC6B416FBE13DA6EA3522F60"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendment made by this Act shall be construed to preempt any provision of State law to the extent that such State law establishes, implements, or continues in effect disclosure requirements regarding abortion or penalties for failure to comply with such requirements that are more extensive than those provided under the amendment made by this Act.</text></section><section id="HCCAE0CE90526432A9EF67C3112F3B243"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the amendment made by this Act, or any application thereof, is found to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act or the amendment made by this Act, and any application thereof, shall not be affected by such finding.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

