<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEB811FC38FA24084978555DEA121F558" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 97 IH: Expressing support for the Federal Protective Service and its law enforcement officers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 97</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the Federal Protective Service and its law enforcement officers.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Protective Service (hereinafter referred to as <quote>FPS</quote>) is charged with protecting more than 8,500 Federal facilities, ensuring the safety of Federal employees, contractors, and visitors across the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas FPS law enforcement officers work tirelessly to uphold the rule of law, safeguard critical infrastructure, and defend the United States against threats;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas FPS law enforcement officers selflessly put themselves in harm’s way to deter and respond to criminal activity, terrorism, and emergencies at Federal properties;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas FPS law enforcement officers take an oath to uphold the Constitution and never betray the public trust;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas FPS law enforcement officers are recognized for their public service, professionalism, and commitment to protecting the Federal workforce and United States citizens;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas FPS law enforcement officers routinely face dangerous and complex situations in the course of their duties, including responding to threats and civil protests, conducting security assessments, and collaborating with other Federal, State, and local partners;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a healthy and collaborative relationship between FPS law enforcement officers and the communities they serve, including Federal employees and visitors, is essential to fostering mutual respect, trust, and awareness of FPS’s critical mission; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas FPS law enforcement officers and their families deserve respect, appreciation, and support for their sacrifices and commitment to public service: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6755066A923C4D8EA3E1BB5A88AB0BF6"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H90EA4F9A482C4E54817CA1BC05400F96"><text>That Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H3204C82782C245DAB554BBC73F638506"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and appreciates the dedication and devotion demonstrated by the men and women of the Federal Protective Service (hereinafter referred to as <quote>FPS</quote>) who protect Federal facilities and the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58B78B8D96A24AC3AEB6D40527AA0F0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>extends its gratitude to all FPS law enforcement officers and their families for their sacrifice and service;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A7638C24BD7479094A17D8354155F00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the memory of FPS law enforcement officers who have fallen in the line of duty; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41F1ED711761468CBBECC0288DEBFAF0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages continued collaboration between the Federal Protective Service and the communities it serves to strengthen public safety, awareness, and trust.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

