<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H294152451A2D407594E142351F8655CD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8506 IH: Securing Aid for Every School Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8506</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to improve school security, including by training and hiring veterans and former law enforcement officers as school safety officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF6C8FAFDA25D4DA2B8AC8FE589DDB6A9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6A0A05D7AF9C475F97180F3AF3B166E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Aid for Every School Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE School Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H347A8C56B8E543F9B3C719467AB7C049"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving school security</header> <subsection id="HB3A07588E6A742AF9E52855F81F740C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5AC6E1D61E004BDA971A2254478AEDCF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8001 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9157040FF35A42B1A66DD419021DF096"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E7F95E8D9B7477B92144DF9B344F6E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish within the Office of Justice Programs a grant program under which the Attorney General shall make grants to States and local educational agencies to carry out eligible activities described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C1566B1F8C148F1B425F5BFE09BDBFC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible activities described in this subsection are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD166B80862FA46B4AE5A64220689A403"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Establish, if necessary, and implement a State certification or licensure program, or other training program required by the State, that—</text> <subparagraph id="H63594AFD9E254E7A95798E3C4BED52C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designed to train individuals who are veterans or former law enforcement officers to serve as school safety officers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0DE1B02CA9524F69B93DF7B37116B9DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include firearm or de-escalation training.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE538902B366452D8496F126EF74C2FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hire veterans or former law enforcement officers who have completed the State certification or licensure program described in paragraph (1), or off-duty law enforcement officers, to serve as school safety officers in elementary schools and secondary schools in the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFACBA0C860D45B38AE4DC2AC999B2E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improve the security of elementary schools and secondary schools in the State by installing infrastructure and implementing technology and other measures that strengthen security on school premises, including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF345149D3A9F414A869195F5948932C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">controlling access to school facilities through the installation of metal detectors, x-ray machines, fencing or gating, and surveillance cameras or systems;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EFEEA13EA674762843FB9BA020956FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">securing doors through the installation of external door passcodes, internal door locks, peepholes for classroom doors, automatic door locking mechanisms, and access control doors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB69DB0AE8ABE4C16AB0DDECD878A6F52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>securing glass in the building’s exterior through the installation of forced entry or bullet resistant glass;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43A8E806E3614633A9068E9255A8E855">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>glass in the building’s exterior through the installation of forced entry or bullet resistant glass; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06FED711801E41F2B8E74D08A0D3E2B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhancing emergency responsiveness through the installation of increased lighting on school grounds, emergency call boxes, emergency alerts, and emergency generators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H45DA9E51C1214ED9A68BA30FBD01206F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No Federal interference</header><text>In awarding grants pursuant to subsection (b), Attorney General may not—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCB32967C662F4332892B461A8393F6FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent or discourage any State or local educational agency from using any grant funds for a school security activity described in subsection (b);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H342EA9CE0803486098FAE4BBBAE0A022"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose any requirements relating to the content or structure of the State certification, licensure, or other training program described in subsection (c)(1); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02519DAF94E3472B8348340EC0EE9C42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enforce any requirement relating to grant funds that would prevent a State or local educational agency from carrying out an eligible activity described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF8AAF5A449D4BC3AAD2796372FE015B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text>The Attorney General shall award grants pursuant to subsection (b) without respect to whether a recipient or subrecipient—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3853123A6F64CF3AFEC24074F62B6BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a public or private school;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D60B7DD9A5D4E67BF5A936B4741339F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is religiously affiliated; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7C85F070EF746EEB871E1923F4C5316"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives any Federal or State funding for school resource officers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H986360908F24481BB0D354B8064CE7ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $900,000,000.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

