<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EF6ECD6D56749A88504973D1DC48E8F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1372 IH: Remembering kindness in the United States and affirming our commitment to fostering community and building resiliency through every day acts of kindness.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1372</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Remembering kindness in the United States and affirming our commitment to fostering community and building resiliency through every day acts of kindness.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas kindness means doing something for someone else with no expectation of anything in return;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas kindness can change a family, a neighborhood, a school, a city, a nation, and ultimately, our world;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas residents within the United States have a long history of demonstrating kindness daily in their homes, schools, places of faith, businesses, community organizations, and throughout their neighborhoods;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas kindness has the power to connect people and to build community and is the mortar that connects and builds the social infrastructure of the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the culture of kindness and compassion can heal our country from within and promote a healthier society;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas studies have shown that kindness can improve several aspects of health, mindfulness, self-compassion, compassion toward others, and interpersonal conflict; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas kindness can foster strong bonds that will bring individuals together despite their differences in order to tackle the challenges that face the United States in a nonpartisan manner: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAE347A0C63F240EABFEF5F46DE34A99F"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H25DDD02276BB41BEA288B30062982634"><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States shall recognize kind actions in our country, encourage kindness, spread love, and foster a culture of being kind to one another.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

