<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP26460-SDX-4T-8VK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4352 IS: Fair and Transparent Gas Prices Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4352</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Federal Trade Commission to conduct a study on conduct related to oil and gas prices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair and Transparent Gas Prices Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9b133a943ca64ec0a944c5cf11dc4df5"><enum>2.</enum><header>FTC Study on Conduct Related to Oil and Gas Prices</header><subsection id="id60A187AC4E454C938A7912E4D37A312F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission (in this section referred to as the <term>Commission</term>), in coordination with State attorneys general, as appropriate, shall conduct a study, using the Commission's authority under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/46">15 U.S.C. 46(b)</external-xref>), to investigate anti-competitive, collusive, or other conduct related to oil and gas companies and markets, including the actual price of oil and gas paid by consumers. Such study shall include an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="idFCDCC1BBE8B747AAAF63F833AA9555F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether such oil and gas companies use their financial resources in a manner that would not expand or increase fuel supply, including by reducing investments in the production of fuel, engaging in stock buy backs, or any other conduct the Commission deems appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9A3A4FCDA429461A812D7C46BEFBCE64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether such anti-competitive, collusive, or other conduct may—</text><subparagraph id="idFBDD14F38ECB424799F302FB5843B5CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>result in inflated costs for consumers or be considered price gouging;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06252CF73F9246CBAF6EBB63836F7D0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>delay producing or delivering more fuel supply;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4AF5931DE2554AFEB830D00378464EA9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impact investment decisions that would contribute to additional fuel supply; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6A7E015821B54B858A25FF31F7DE7249"><enum>(D)</enum><text>restrict the availability, accessibility, or affordability of alternative fuels or vehicle technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc5e0792bc0094638ba80157949bfa277"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="id21BDBEC66A7E4A50911872FB943FE653"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 2 years, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Commission determines appropriate or necessary to provide fair, competitive, and transparent costs and markets impacting consumers with respect to oil and gas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6803A03A9CB740E3BDBD23810FB9463B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id32497BB13CB84730955A1916FEC67C18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCFFD7CD63C944925A52776B3919BC1D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA6D12508826F44D1905B66D769FD8FC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60B63EDB7C744EDDB945147A81BF7EF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Subcommittees on Financial Services and General Government of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id86a95c79e8704427a609b9603d1ac1cd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inapplicability of paperwork reduction act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), shall not apply to the collection of information under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idA190997D1C5C4E7E8F0D20EC7B9E616A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional FTC resources</header><paragraph id="id9ba49e4c1d9442cc93e98236e5eb3ac8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional personnel</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commission shall, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint not more than 50 additional personnel, as necessary, for the purposes of carrying out the study and report required under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4404aee671be42c09ed619d397d6df75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

