<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95866CE6538E4B85B191EC2375B0B329" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HRES 1257 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 5, 2026, as the “National Day of Awareness for Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women and Girls”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1257</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000482">Mrs. Fedorchak</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 5, 2026, as the <quote>National Day of Awareness for Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women and Girls</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, according to 2017 data, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention found homicide was the sixth-leading cause of death for American Indian and Alaska Native women and girls under 44 years of age, with murder rates more than 10 times the national average;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 1,500 American Indian and Alaska Native missing persons have been entered into the National Crime Information Center index throughout the United States, and approximately 2,700 cases of murder and nonnegligent homicide offenses have been reported to the Federal Government’s Uniform Crime Reporting Program;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to a 2020 joint study completed by the State of Hawai’i and the Hawai’i State Commission on the Status of Women, 64 percent of human trafficking victims in Hawai’i identified as at least part Native Hawaiian;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas, in 2020, Savanna’s Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/165">Public Law 116–165</external-xref>) and the Not Invisible Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/166">Public Law 116–166</external-xref>) were signed into law, which initiated a joint commission between the Department of the Interior (DOI) and the DOJ to combat violent crime within Tribal communities and develop new law enforcement protocols when investigating MMIW;</text>
                </whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2021, the DOI created a Missing and Murdered Unit within its Bureau of Indian Affairs’ Office of Justice Services to expand cross-departmental and interagency collaboration for the purposes of investigating cases of missing and murdered Indigenous people at the request of Tribal leadership;</text>
                </whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2022, the DOI fulfilled a provision in the Not Invisible Act requiring the establishment of the Not Invisible Act Commission by filling membership with law enforcement, Tribal leaders, Federal partners, service providers, family members of MMIW, and survivors and held their first meeting;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, the Not Invisible Act Commission submitted recommendations to the DOJ, DOI, and Congress to address the epidemic of missing persons and the murder and trafficking of American Indian and Alaska Native peoples;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas, in response to the commission’s recommendations, the DOJ highlighted the MMIW regional outreach program to aid the U.S. Attorney’s Offices to update Savanna’s Act guidelines to provide further training and technical assistance to State agencies and provide uniformity in guidelines across jurisdictions;</text>
 </whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, despite progress that has been made, in 2024, 5,614 Indigenous Women and Girls were reported missing. Of these 5,614 reports, 4,179 victims were under the age of 18, and at the end of 2024, there were 628 active missing person records;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research data shows that national averages hide the extremely high rates of murder against Indigenous women and girls present in some counties comprised primarily of tribal land; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in previous years, May 5 has been designated as the day of remembrance for <quote>Missing and Murdered Native Women and Girls</quote> in honor of the birth date of Hanna Harris, a member of the Northern Cheyenne Tribe, who was murdered after being reported missing by her family in Lame Deer, Montana: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEE332F7BC30846A18A9F009421A506D7"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2F4E0EC5A0684C739D5073064302332D"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H6669583EB68D46E3B4724A944C2EEBBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of a <quote>National Day of Awareness for Missing and Murdered Indigenous Women and Girls</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H673CB9DF3CAC4485BF333746C2FA53C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States and interested groups to—</text><subparagraph id="H86B09A98D1704BA08C97CBFB5F4A4E7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commemorate the lives of missing and murdered Indigenous women and girls whose cases are documented and undocumented in public records and the media; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D8022C80FDB454F8C4CD86017919623"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate solidarity with the families of victims in light of those tragedies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16FEA47840B04C2B84E193339A55BDA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommends that the Department of Justice’s National Institute of Justice commission a new study with focused data on missing and murdered Indigenous women and girls to ensure up-to-date statistics are made public regarding the current state of the missing and murdered Indigenous women and girls crisis given 9 years have passed since their 2016 study was published; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2280BBBD402E4ACD833AD3861C45320B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes that, despite the positive efforts made, there is more work to be done to address this nationwide crisis.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

