<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA6055A9A3AD540AFA6934A42E13180D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7013 IH: Greenland Sovereignty Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7013</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260112">January 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funding to facilitate the invasion, annexation, purchase, or other form of acquisition of Greenland, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF1F1C80B22A9485A851B8BF7745218EA" style="OLC"><section id="H2A23A07B92FA4B5A804A9919DBDE67D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Greenland Sovereignty Protection Act</short-title></quote> . </text></section><section id="H232C2B46B81E41BD981197A5A2FDE2BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on acquisition of or influence campaign over Greenland</header><subsection id="HDC9047DD368446C191712009A50C426D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H7EADDF37D2914311BAC3EB9CBC169B04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any activity that supports, directs, or facilitates the invasion, annexation, purchase, or other form of acquisition of Greenland by the United States or by any official or entity of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98F3F8538B224B50A8FA8E28C73119A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any increase in the presence of the Armed Forces or any United States funding or assistance for, or other form of financial investment in, Greenland relative to the levels (adjusting as appropriate for inflation) of such presence, funding, assistance, or investment as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H450A34848FBF4C11A7CDB120A30C1300"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any program, project, or activity relating to staging or supporting a public or private influence campaign, including any such activity or substantially similar activity conducted overtly or covertly by any Federal official or entity, to sway the self determination of the people of Greenland</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1257259D1EE4CE3964EFD498C2F34BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Explicit statutory waiver</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) may only be waived with respect to a specific activity described in that subsection by the enactment, after the date of the enactment of this section, of specific statutory authorization for such activity that explicitly waives the application of the prohibition and includes a citation to this subsection or to the <quote>Greenland Sovereignty Protection Act</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

