<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H756729F2EDF248DDBADF66B62986B41A">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6977 IH: Better Care for PFAS Patients Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6977</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260108">January 8, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide for the periodic issuance of up-to-date clinical guidance on addressing the health effects of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS), and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H96773F2E9C754B5794854AF15E9E4279">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H963CB84F5EAD4B08987D819A6DED238D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Better Care for PFAS Patients Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCBCBF099DDF144B3930AEC298ABDFB33"><enum>2.</enum><header>PFAS health effects assessment, recommendations, and guidance</header> <subsection id="H85D6E637CA3F44AE831BE041DD0484BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Periodic assessment and recommendations</header> <paragraph id="H9DF3E25FDFD7437EB1003BCFB8546130"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The Director of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (or another appropriate entity if the National Academies declines to enter into such agreement) under which the National Academies or the other appropriate entity agrees—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDC932EA0D3A34FA894C0401293F3F5B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to assess the health effects of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (in this section referred to as <quote>PFAS</quote>) that can be measured in human tissues;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C356F466E8F4D9F8A5E6A2E52DD9EB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to formulate clinical recommendations on addressing such health effects;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H670AD701BDDA40FAAB1D147BA7FFB578"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 2 years after the date of entry into such agreement, to complete the initial assessment under subparagraph (A) and formulate the initial recommendations under subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC60B73065FFC4FE687E0A2F0E855895F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to update the most recent assessment and recommendations under this paragraph—</text>
<clause id="H0C7A764105AB411F8FA6F73593F45D0F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>every 5 years; or</text></clause> <clause id="H18CF9F82FB244716965CDE0ED4D31E31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>more frequently as determined necessary by the Director based on an assessment of the science.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6BFAE1EC08440FB8AB72EB7EA69AF10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the assessments under paragraph (1), the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine or other appropriate entity shall engage with PFAS exposed communities and solicit input from members of such communities regarding their experiences with PFAS exposure, testing, and clinical follow-up.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4164C31B2A3648BA89F5249E7EE2AAC6"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timing of entry into agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall enter into the agreement required by paragraph (1) not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8A933D6AD71F4F41857EFD91667899F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Up-to-Date guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on the results of the most recent assessment and recommendations under subsection (a), the Director, in consultation with the entity with which the Director enters into the agreement under subsection (a), shall—</text> <paragraph id="HDB7DFF1526F64C44BBE188504755FA40"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 5 years after the date of entry into the agreement required by subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCFE53B4AB80C46818593D6A7E1806300"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue up-to-date clinical guidance on addressing the health effects of PFAS;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99BBA8019F7845B189BF797AEA890E18"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">post such guidance on the public website of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H503CD07A166D4C269F681EF7C421022C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disseminate such guidance to State and local public health authorities and appropriate health care professionals; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9899604CC19949289617EC1F62763556"><enum>(2)</enum><text>every 5 years thereafter, or more frequently as determined necessary by the Director based on an assessment of the science, issue, post, and disseminate up-to-date guidance as described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

