<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDAC7AF1E655C4390B69224BFE06AAE29" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6736 IH: Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6736</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the transfer of regulatory control of certain munitions exports from the Department of Commerce to the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4957BFDE42D04425B04058E963019892" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFFC5873AAD614E1CB053447C84BF27FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H572F2592DFA04FCA8F5F9D3773C7D7B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ARMAS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H84D886AB18014ED3984B1F49E6C03C74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HFFC5873AAD614E1CB053447C84BF27FB" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCB0B97BE4D524591BD90FE9022632037" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H75528500A8314479B1374FB69707C1C7" level="section">Sec. 3. Transfer of regulatory control of certain munitions exports from Department of Commerce to Department of State.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB24D9545A5B14E87A1A75BB71CDA885E" level="section">Sec. 4. Reports and strategy on disruption of illegal export and trafficking of firearms to Mexico and certain Central American and Caribbean countries.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5BF56E897D294F3E99737B27F2C60C5B" level="section">Sec. 5. Increasing participation in the eTrace program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBEFE43FFFA5C4DA8878FD14741FDD449" level="section">Sec. 6. Modifications to the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" level="section">Sec. 7. Designation of covered countries.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD7949305365A46C9889B56C9265A52D8" level="section">Sec. 8. Certification requirements relating to certain munitions exports.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H32EE2DAD1D9742EE99D215A832AB9AD7" level="section">Sec. 9. Limitation on licenses and other authorizations for export of certain items removed from the Commerce Control List and included on the United States Munitions List.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3AF9B22330EF44B1B3C9B1DF8A183895" level="section">Sec. 10. Prohibition on promotion of covered munitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5F2BC4627F9646ABB4CA88814DBCE560" level="section">Sec. 11. Definitions.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCB0B97BE4D524591BD90FE9022632037"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H6A8BC69CDB6A468BA69632A8D2CE5A5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Violence in Mexico, Central America, and the Caribbean is exacerbated by firearms originating in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H477FB16C7A734B9FAD42B6359D1D497F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>While firearms are trafficked to Mexico from a variety of countries, firearms originating in the United States account for 70 percent of the firearms recovered and traced from crimes in Mexico, according to the 2021 Government Accountability Office (GAO) report published by the Comptroller General of the United States titled <quote>Firearms Trafficking: U.S. Efforts to Disrupt Gun Smuggling into Mexico Would Benefit from Additional Data and Analysis</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DFC3481C0BD43F0A8C14B178FA4E72C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States-origin firearm flows contribute to human rights violations, organized crime and gang violence, extrajudicial killings, high homicide rates, domestic violence, and femicides in Mexico, Central America, and the Caribbean.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E95DA74956C4954B15A1A08D2E2AB0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Firearms trafficking from the United States and firearm violence are key drivers of immigration and asylum claims from Central America.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC89405B0ECD94B12899034002741B829"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the United Nations Regional Centre for Peace, Disarmament and Development in Latin America and the Caribbean, firearms are used in 70 percent of homicides in the Caribbean compared to 30 percent globally, and while the Caribbean constitutes less than one percent of the global population, it is responsible for 23 percent of all recorded homicides.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DA73823546649B09FD2DCCF531A3147"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In an August 2022 press conference, United States officials of Homeland Security Investigations reported a <quote>marked uptick in the number of weapons</quote>, and an increase in the caliber and type of weapons, being illegally trafficked to Haiti and the rest of the Caribbean.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FCC35DB483947D58ACE49C357325CB0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Caribbean Basin Security Initiative of the Department of State that commenced in 2009 is the regional foreign assistance program of the United States that seeks to reduce illicit trafficking in the Caribbean region and advance public safety and security. The program includes improving the capacity of Caribbean countries to intercept smuggled weapons at airports and seaports, as well as support for forensic ballistics and firearms destruction and stockpile management. Assistance under the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative has also included support for regional organizations, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1B249C89B41B43E79C1DE3606718DED4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Caribbean Community Implementation Agency for Crime and Security (CARICOM IMPACS), based in Trinidad and Tobago, the lead agency involved in the issue of illicit firearms trafficking and increasing the capacity of member states to detect and prevent firearms trafficking; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56E3D5D69EAA42DD81AA300BCF584602"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Eastern Caribbean’s Regional Security System, based in Barbados.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DD86DA92D5E42198D7B9D9CD5821E3B"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two GAO reports (published in 2021 and 2022, respectively) on firearms trafficking have affirmed that firearms trafficking to Mexico and Central America continues to represent a security concern to the United States, as United States-origin firearms are diverted from legitimate owners and end up in the hands of violent criminals, including drug traffickers and other transnational criminal organizations. A GAO report on the effect of firearms trafficking in the Caribbean has not yet been compiled.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34302425D15D4752B86F51D9FDAD6FAF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In these reports, the Comptroller General found that Federal departments and agencies lacked information and analysis of the firearms trafficking networks in Mexico and Central America, that few efforts of the United States Government in the region focused on firearms trafficking, and that, as a result, such agencies lack a detailed understanding of the firearms trafficking that fuels violence and enables criminals in Belize, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, and Mexico.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C17D3147A5E4BBDB5567008B704F1B9">
        <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Firearms used to kidnap and kill a group of United States citizens traveling in Matamoros, Mexico were illegally smuggled from the United States into Mexico. The suspect in these killings admitted to Federal agents that he purchased firearms in the United States, smuggled them across the border, and knowingly provided them to members of the Gulf Cartel.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB45916C160DD45259E5AAB9914DB94CE"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the incident specified in paragraph (11) demonstrates, United States-sourced firearms are being smuggled and diverted to cartels implicated in the supply and flow of illegal fentanyl and other dangerous drugs, threatening the public health and safety of United States citizens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE12E8B45CF6F4B41AD7A0441F039AD7E"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the 2022 GAO report <quote>Firearms Trafficking: More Information Needed to Inform U.S. Efforts in Central America</quote>, the Comptroller General found that efforts of the United States Government focused on firearms trafficking in Belize, El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras lacked information about relevant country conditions and performance measures to ensure such efforts were designed and implemented to achieve the intended objectives and, as a result, the Comptroller General recommended that the Secretary of State obtain information about the conditions in such countries, to support the development of effective programs to reduce the availability of illicit firearms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4603D463631545E89F4C2A515B717C5C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Data on firearms trafficking is limited and to understand the problem, data compilation is crucial.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE99C27BE97846729FEBF3EE3227AD53"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of the date of the publication of the report specified in paragraph (12), the Secretary of Commerce had not assigned any agents to Central America on permanent assignment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9770CF2FC09E491F86A349954DC52989"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2021 and 2022, the annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices of the Department of State included <quote>unlawful and arbitrary killings</quote> as a significant human rights issue in Guatemala, yet despite such inclusion, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security has authorized approximately 99,270 firearms exports to Guatemala since assuming responsibility for firearms licensing in 2020.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF8F50EAAFFB439CBBD38F3D0F302DCC"><enum>(16)</enum><text>When firearms were controlled under the United States Munitions List and the licensing of firearms was the responsibility of the Secretary of State, the average number of firearms licensed for export to Guatemala was approximately 4,000 per year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39F97B8B302840629EEF71062101BDDF"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The current number of exports specified in paragraph (15) represents an extraordinary increase (as much as 25 times the average) from the number specified in paragraph (16), and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security has only been able to conduct a very limited number of end-use checks, according to the 2022 GAO report <quote>Firearms Trafficking: More Information Needed to Inform U.S. Efforts in Central America</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE5A2F56AC7742468BB5514D729760FB"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since the Department of Commerce gained jurisdiction over the control of firearm export licensing, there has been a 30 percent increase in firearm exports in comparison to averages for such exports when the control of such exports was under the jurisdiction of the Department of State. The Secretary of Commerce has also approved 95 percent of license applications for such exports.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD681396612C04245B3A35E078D12726E"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the U.S. Census Bureau, Mexico, Guatemala, and Brazil have been among the top 10 destinations for United States-manufactured semiautomatic firearm exports.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40CF14D151ED4FD1AC5DB0FC6C6020C2" commented="no"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bipartisan Safer Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/159">Public Law 117–159</external-xref>), which was enacted into law on June 25, 2022, implemented key efforts to address firearm trafficking, including by establishing a Federal criminal offense for firearm trafficking and by strengthening the capability of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to interdict firearms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B3A06FFB7674CF9B748C3E6BC9BF53B"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A growing number of firearms exported by United States manufacturers are found involved in violent crimes worldwide. For instance, the pistol used in a mass shooting of 23 children and two teachers in Thailand in October 2022 was linked to a United States factory.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H75528500A8314479B1374FB69707C1C7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of regulatory control of certain munitions exports from Department of Commerce to Department of State</header> <subsection id="H0AE15C8B873F43E0A51750FCCF7DF196"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1468539BBB8B41219E2DBDE8786DAAD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Commerce shall transfer the control over the export of each previously covered item to the jurisdiction of the Department of State; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71664006C30844C391F0E711EEE51ECF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>following such transfer, the Secretary of State may not transfer the control over the export of any covered munition to the jurisdiction of the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H660337C329D94A15801DA217C0CDEC74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to implement this section by the date specified in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67D87C38A77F429A9E17B4B3D79FA542"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting any authority relating to the designation, control, or removal of items under the United States Munitions List or the Commerce Control List, other than the specific authority to transfer the control of an item as specified in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H512F9A32CC50489BB5F45BEEEE658E1E" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on promotion of certain munitions exports by Department of Commerce</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce may not take any actions to promote the export of any previously covered item, including actions before, on, or after the date on which the Secretary transfers the control over the export of the previously covered item to the jurisdiction of the Department State under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB24D9545A5B14E87A1A75BB71CDA885E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports and strategy on disruption of illegal export and trafficking of firearms to Mexico and certain Central American and Caribbean countries</header> <subsection id="H9EBFBD35B50D4F1D98658B959935D62E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="HA82969551A27486EA241561B028D271D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State (in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of State may determine relevant) shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the efforts of the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies to disrupt the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H60FA5F7FC4CD4DBBA72814D39342A7A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The illegal export or diversion of firearms from the United States to unauthorized recipients in countries designated as covered countries under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref> (including through unauthorized third-party transfers).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD42107F12521446E85D642A3BF6A25C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The illegal trafficking of firearms obtained in the United States to recipients in such countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E3E7EAD67494BF3A51C58C72E08E342"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the efforts specified in such paragraph, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H36FC478F278A4B88B6CFE0CDFA5B2931"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of any such efforts, including efforts to accomplish the following objectives:</text> 
<clause id="HBA3BB33D059046C5A3EB63B1E1B9ACA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tracking and verifying information regarding the end-users of firearms so exported, including by entering into data-sharing agreements—</text> <subclause id="H1F72D62234EB4BD6902AE0424CD0BBCE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with appropriate counterparts from the governments of such covered countries; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB9DCBEFB036F45B6B60A51B2DF84829F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>between the relevant departments and agencies of the United States Government.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HDCFF2D54B35447A2A776BFC5A6E6C007"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring the destruction of surplus firearms so exported.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1C479AA7BCE24AE481CC1F58CD99C2F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring that firearms so exported are not used to commit extrajudicial killings or other gross violations of internationally recognized human rights.</text></clause> <clause id="H0F8AA420F907460591853D1BC2C5CB1B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Building the capacity of such covered countries to prevent the trafficking of firearms so exported, including through current programs supported or implemented by the United States Government.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7A5FB002255240A7949E01F4F6903904"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tracking and verifying information regarding the end-users of firearms obtained in the United States and illegally trafficked to such covered countries.</text></clause> <clause id="HE0B8D84EEB91456492D9C8B1211C360E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Combating all forms of cross-border smuggling of firearms from the United States, including via maritime vessels and aircraft.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF06111127B024CE0B402F7F15949E187"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engaging with subnational government officials in such covered countries to effectively implement and enforce agreements relating to the trafficking of firearms that have been concluded between the United States Government and the national government of the respective covered country.</text></clause> <clause id="H65A052C8341B44D9B270B918F190B104"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying the origin of trafficked firearms, including through the serial numbers of trafficked firearms, and sharing such information with relevant law enforcement agencies of—</text> 
<subclause id="HA0C20766A4DF4463B3F36849CA7D968D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the United States;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H924ED1035F2D4540970F933F8106BDCF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the respective covered country; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H558A92213EEE4D6BA42556BAAE26D867"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other country determined relevant for purposes of such information sharing.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H300EB42EF2FE4AD28FA61D5F24A038BC"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementing the proposed security cooperation plan titled <quote>U.S.-Mexico Bicentennial Framework for Security, Public Heath, and Safe Communities</quote>, and any successor or subsequent bilateral agreements on combating firearm trafficking, transnational organizations, or fentanyl.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H72B2A821DA8E4C00A14A1ACB19EDD369">
              <enum>(x)</enum>
 <text>Cooperating with other relevant Federal departments and agencies, including the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, to combat firearms trafficking and prosecute illegal firearm smugglers.</text>
            </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4D0F2026A174A868012B6613684F5A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the results of the efforts identified pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H998B73026F454B30B4855AB47EA71BF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how homicides, extrajudicial killings, and other gross violations of internationally recognized human rights committed in such covered countries using firearms exported from or obtained in the United States have been investigated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2323A600529D45AB99D55571FE19B1DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inter-Agency strategy</header> 
<paragraph id="H33BA5572B78345A59720D17837D362F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, taking into account the findings of the report under subsection (a), shall jointly develop an inter-agency strategy for the disruption of the trafficking of firearms exported from the United States to recipients in countries designated as covered countries under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81D64D3814A24D3999E256570283D5F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6FA785B280194EA4A54B8A7CAEBB8752"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A plan for the United States to accomplish each of the objectives specified in subsection (a)(2)(A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF3F28A858A64C76B5CA0E5364245BA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of specific performance measures, targets (including the baselines for such targets), and timelines with respect to such objectives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A86284F7BA641B0B0701F732FA6B482"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An estimate of the resources and personnel necessary to carry out the strategy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7486358CB04421CB0EFC2F530E24C36"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for cooperation between the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of any other Federal departments or agencies involved in anti-firearm trafficking efforts, including the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H20E4147E17CD492AAE3ED3E7BA009DA8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for coordination between the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and such heads regarding efforts in countries designated as covered countries under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref> to combat the trafficking of United States-sourced firearms—</text> <clause id="HDF5B8C4EC67D40919F9F2E4A587F2A43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>from the United States to such designated countries; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE8204D4DD20349BCAC07AFD6EFBB94E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>from such designated countries to other countries in the surrounding region.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69AE01DB840E41FC9573F14BD1BD12E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required considerations; consultations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the strategy under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H267E1CF907B64D6B81A801634C37AECB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider how the strategy may support or otherwise align with broader efforts of the Secretary of State relating to security assistance, anti-corruption, and the prevention of organized crime and drug and gang violence;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85EE802E1BE24F65A0AB5D5A81A7A9FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider whether the placement in the Western Hemisphere of an export control officer of the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, or other personnel of the Department of Commerce or the Department of State, would support the strategy; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93AF39C0C6FC46E1B38C49FBC9EA7BD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to consult with appropriate counterparts from the government of each country designated as a covered country under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEEF99460E44480ABF01FFEA63A2A049"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1 of the year following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the strategy under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD046261448DA404DBDDA485A821ECB55"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Improved tracking of trafficked firearms</header> 
<paragraph id="H2A23E6F0410B471E862834A5990D61AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment of data availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which a country is designated (or the deemed to be designated, as the case may be), under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of State may determine relevant, shall conduct and submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate an assessment of the extent to which the law enforcement agencies of that designated country make available to the United States Government forensic information of trafficked firearms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69C0F66ACAE9413E8DD9DFF63BC277E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Addressing gaps in data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the duration of the period during which a country is designated as a covered country under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref>, the Secretary of State shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H842E25E83DCA4BA8B673999EE9DF3F33"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to engage with the foreign counterparts of the government of such country to improve the collection and sharing of the forensic information of trafficked firearms confiscated by the law enforcement agencies of such country; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACA12F8C4A1E4FF4AF94DE7CF2288BEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promptly provide any such forensic information shared pursuant to subparagraph (A) to the relevant Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies for purposes of use in criminal or civil investigations into violations of relevant United States Federal laws, including the Arms Export Control Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H596A45152C8B40D9BE4C50DBFC4060B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Forensic information defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>forensic information</term>, with respect to a trafficked firearm, includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H997E8D989DA74A2FBA686448672C3A58"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the serial number of the firearm; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B10FD40758244E0B5FEA6F24039DD30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other information that may be used to identify the origin of the firearm or any person or organization involved in the trafficking of the firearm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD1A956010149400C8E820966D80E9034"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header> <paragraph id="HB25585D5A4154A1989B364826037B971"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary or Secretaries concerned (in consultation with the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary or Secretaries concerned may determine relevant) shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the export of covered munitions to countries designated as covered countries under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H812519C236014C1D95289127565C6EA4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters</header><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the year for which the report is submitted, the following information (disaggregated by country):</text> <subparagraph id="H5F242F806D814FB3952C323EBC6E56AB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information regarding license applications approved or denied, and previously issued licenses modified or revoked, for the export of covered munitions to proposed recipients in covered countries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E88FE531B594CD6BBC0B6FA9CAE38AC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information regarding how evolving country contexts, including with respect to developments in human rights, affected the approval of license applications for such exports.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5A4EE19FB2B43DFA148ED964553CC07" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of licenses issued for the export of covered munitions to proposed recipients in covered countries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E5D3173711E4598B7920E373C7C964C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of covered munitions exported to recipients in covered countries.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65245D3EE16848B8AE377555B1B17A4B" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to end-user checks for covered munitions exported to recipients in covered countries under section 38(g)(7) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(g)(7)</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Blue Lantern</quote> program), the monitoring program established under the second section 40A of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2785">22 U.S.C. 2785</external-xref>) (as added by section 150(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/164">Public Law 104–164</external-xref>), or other applicable programs of the Department of Commerce or Department of State, the following information:</text> 
<clause id="H273567D46C484BBB92DB5E29C1EAAD3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of such end-user checks requested.</text></clause> <clause id="HE896DE6061D146DF9A7806D3943D3309"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of such end-user checks conducted.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H90653CD5EBD742C0AD98A47A959EE9E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The type of such end-user checks conducted.</text></clause> <clause id="H9BAD081642C04EB6999EBC33117D70A2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The results of such end-user checks conducted.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FE68F110AF849B09D1D22770AFED8FF" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the extent to which the heads of the governments of covered countries shared with the Secretary or Secretaries concerned and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies (such as the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives) data relating to the receipt and end-use of covered munitions exported from the United States, and the type of data so shared.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C53FC188EDA4AF6A55ADECAE985DEBD" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each covered country, a description of the United States funding and resources allocated for the purpose of disrupting trafficking of covered munitions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E3CFE5028A9464FB9D804C54964806B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary or Secretaries concerned defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>Secretary or Secretaries concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H36291AC5CD5D4C3196F067E1714C1BDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if a single Federal department or agency has jurisdiction over the export control of covered munitions, the Secretary of that Federal department or agency; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA03E3B0C6BF474FB938A08C135FBD0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if multiple Federal departments or agencies have jurisdiction over the export control of covered munitions, each Secretary of such a Federal department or agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5BF56E897D294F3E99737B27F2C60C5B" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increasing participation in the eTrace program</header> <subsection id="H7E0AB0D8F15E43628856A3734AAECAF3" commented="no"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, shall seek to work with national and sub-national law enforcement authorities of countries designated as covered countries under <internal-xref idref="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140" legis-path="5.">section 7</internal-xref>in order to increase participation by such authorities in the eTrace program.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA6F12CF3C79B4AE09643D63BD8AFB2FB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of subsection (a) and on the number of firearms traced to a purchase or export that resulted in Federal investigations and prosecutions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB2564C86AAD49FDA933AE7382C406F9" commented="no"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Haiti</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives shall ensure that the eTrace program is available in the French and Haitian Creole languages for the purposes of improving the use of the program by law enforcement authorities in Haiti.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9F31D4868E946D395BD58D790DB91D6" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts authorized to be appropriated under chapter 8 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (relating to international narcotics control assistance) are authorized to be made available to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2698056D5FF34ACB9F3C53EA6C7295BB"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Definition of eTrace program</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eTrace program</term> means the web-based firearms tracing system of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives that is available to accredited domestic and international law enforcement agencies to assist in the tracing of United States-sourced firearms.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="HBEFE43FFFA5C4DA8878FD14741FDD449" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Modifications to the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall update the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative’s Results Framework to establish specific indicators relating to trafficking in firearms.</text></section> <section id="H4C3D9A04550B4B4484A5389F15EED140"><enum>7.</enum><header>Designation of covered countries</header> <subsection id="H50A7D1049DC547C987926F7E2A6B553C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall designate each country that the Secretary determines meets the requirements under subsection (b) as a covered country for purposes of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF90525A174D5489E82A87CD598A7BA44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A country meets the requirements under this subsection if the country—</text> <paragraph id="H6632582D2D6F494391893D2911791829"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is located in North America, South America, or the Caribbean;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05775BC48023486CAF050B63CA93AE1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not a member state of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65427FBD66E4419EB908C6DD216A56FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>meets such other requirements as the Secretary may determine appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H56F10B4D8D494F0BACD724CCF4E3FA76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial designations</header><text>The Bahamas, Belize, Brazil, Colombia, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, Haiti, Jamaica, and Trinidad and Tobago—</text> <paragraph id="H4C97EAD038AD4DA99645ECC6A80C0ABA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be deemed to have been so designated by the Secretary of State as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54FA1B3C1AA84E06ADAD9DD8A5692F4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall continue to be deemed so designated for a five-year period, during which time the designation may not be terminated under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H95A87CB73AB0444B93002ACB806F92D4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of designation</header><text>Subject to subsection (c)(2), the Secretary of State may terminate the designation of a country under this section only if, at least 180 days prior to such termination, the Secretary submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of such termination.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD7949305365A46C9889B56C9265A52D8"><enum>8.</enum><header>Certification requirements relating to certain munitions exports</header> 
<subsection id="HAC37116D8AF94C19AAA7DA69F19F30F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial certification; prohibition</header> 
<paragraph id="H364FED2F58E4460B9A05378044DAB4DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no covered munition may be transferred to the government of a country designated as a covered country under section 7, or any other organization, citizen, or resident of such covered country, until the Secretary of State submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification that the program required under subsection (c) has been established.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7B4876003CC495AAC56E5FA8A405643"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>For the one-year period beginning on the effective date of this section described in subsection (d), the Secretary of State may waive the certification requirement under paragraph (1) with respect to the transfer of a covered munition to the government of a country described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is in the national security interest of the United States and includes a written justification with the certification.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF3C67B433EC6491AA11A3FEE95D10693"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and recertification</header> 
<paragraph id="HB1AF2D0298C346379282C7EEDAD5C9F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the submission of the certification under subsection (a) for a country designated as a covered country under section 7, and annually thereafter until such time as the designation is terminated, the Secretary of State shall review, and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a recertification of, such certification.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H753B6924ECF543B095F510BFABBB8DFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>If the Secretary of State is unable to recertify a covered country as required under paragraph (1), no covered munition may be transferred to the government of the covered country, or any other organization, citizen, or resident of such covered country, until the date on which the Secretary is able to so recertify.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1CF33F52910842C49FF7CC2A3FFA51EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program</header> 
<paragraph id="H40C98D939D6E477CB275254AF5436296"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish and carry out a program under which the Secretary shall prohibit the retransfer of covered munitions transferred to countries designated as covered countries under section 7without the consent of the United States and provide for the registration and end-use monitoring of such covered munitions in accordance with the following requirements:</text> <subparagraph id="H28F7CAC6221B465E91873B927595E30C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The maintenance of a detailed record of the origin, shipping, and distribution of covered munitions transferred to countries designated as covered countries under section 7.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA95BC25579F443539265947B51EA57CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The registration of the serial numbers of all covered munitions, to be provided to the governments of such covered countries and other organizations, citizens, and residents within such covered countries.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E0E6244EF3046DF9B8222396EA7C5F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The conduct of a program for the end-use monitoring of covered munitions transferred to the entities and individuals described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47E08652752D4B31B55454C1B33166F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of database</header><text>In prohibiting the retransfer of covered munitions without the consent of the United States pursuant to the program under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H5EF150364D984BC0BD954D76906E3FE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the database of the Department of State that stores records relating to vetting conducted pursuant to section 620M of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378d">22 U.S.C. 2378d</external-xref>) or section 362 of title 10, United States Code, known as the <quote>International Vetting and Security Tracking-cloud system</quote> or <quote>INVEST system</quote> (or any successor database), for any such records relating to the prospective recipients of such retransfer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2490A5B1F9FD4F38BDEF3E766623B1F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that such consent is not granted for any such prospective recipient who the Secretary of State determines, taking into account the review under subparagraph (A), is credibly implicated in a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE51EA24E52B4A11928B8F3CDBA70BFE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data storage and sharing</header><text>In carrying out the program under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEB0FD472DCA640C189B9DA3675F8C7B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that any data received pursuant to such program is stored and maintained in a database of the Department of State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61477B69D9AC4779AE99D5561A5D8436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, provide for the sharing of such data with the Secretary of Commerce and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of State may determine relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F8CA48318224A1AB7CD35856E167A06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of Commerce completes the transfer of the control over the export of previously covered items to the jurisdiction of the Department of State under section 3(a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H32EE2DAD1D9742EE99D215A832AB9AD7" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Limitation on licenses and other authorizations for export of certain items removed from the Commerce Control List and included on the United States Munitions List</header> <subsection id="H4F9B693CC1324036A4BEB1595A8E9683" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may not grant a license or other authorization for the export of a previously covered item the control over the export of which the Secretary of Commerce has transferred to the jurisdiction of the Department of State under section 3(a) unless, before granting the license or other authorization, the Secretary submits to the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the Senate a written certification with respect to such proposed export license or other authorization containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5D1728498198426998BDAECA0E34E4C9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name of the person applying for the license or other authorization;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC9B7F391E2249158CE9708CABB77049" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the name of the person who is the proposed recipient of the export;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36D97B81701341D19B7E6F77DB57699E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the name of the country or international organization to which the export will be made;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDBAC18BFB79459BAA0BA0CF80B5D6C3" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the items proposed to be exported; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6237E5EF8BC64BEA9D164E0569E43671" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the value of the items proposed to be exported.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF2E537A292E847C9A6FD7A6BCE9395BC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>A certification required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, except that information regarding the dollar value and number of items proposed to be exported may be restricted from public disclosure if such disclosure would be detrimental to the security of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H92B728F23985423E989470ED6458E337" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>A certification required under subsection (a) shall be submitted—</text> <paragraph id="HD7290A61E65A4579A4E28747DDDA5B4B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at least 15 calendar days before a proposed export license or other authorization is granted in the case of a transfer of items to a country which is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Israel, or New Zealand, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29EA45CB3C914C43A6454FD6A3CF6D7F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at least 30 calendar days before a proposed export license or other authorization is granted in the case of a transfer of items to any other country.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H30A9905A4E8C4CF980A4FFB146F6F183" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional resolution of disapproval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposed export license or other authorization described in paragraph (1) of subsection (c) shall become effective after the end of the 15-day period described in such paragraph, and a proposed export license or other authorization described in paragraph (2) of subsection (c) shall become effective after the end of the 30-day period specified in such paragraph, only if the Congress does not enact, within the applicable time period, a joint resolution prohibiting the export of the covered item for which the export license or other authorization was proposed.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3AF9B22330EF44B1B3C9B1DF8A183895"><enum>10.</enum><header>Prohibition on promotion of covered munitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce is prohibited from—</text> <paragraph id="HC2A0B1CE79EF416AB992ED3FB3B978C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting the sale or export of covered munition; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC08A4EA7FCE6456D9D317AC0D283A8AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seeking the reduction or removal by any foreign country of restrictions on the marketing of covered munitions.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5F2BC4627F9646ABB4CA88814DBCE560"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H851CA99F01D44627A670CC57F1A42902"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H81032FE483EC474188AB3CFD46B59EAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAECD3823A494A0096C9E6DF1A63BE17"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88A94480744C41C291A50E526E5D0E27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered munition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered munition</term> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD0B83B70627B406D943C7692311A6C38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any previously covered item.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F5F769ED519451381159B310E8E6DA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any item that, following the date of the enactment of this Act, is designated for control under Category I, II, or III of the United States Munitions List pursuant to section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</external-xref>) or otherwise subject to control under any such category.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H169EA24C713843119F479F44F622264A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Previously covered item</header><text>The term <term>previously covered item</term> means any item that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE26554838F33420180F392BEDC6D1F4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as of March 8, 2020, was included in Category I, II, or III of the United States Munitions List; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89BD074C86224E37AF365967D28AAD07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the date of the enactment of this Act, is included on the Commerce Control List.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF74BFB16BD14823ADC98726050DE85E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>firearm</term> includes covered munitions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H451FA72422B4409A952951B8527F3647"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</term> has the meaning given that term in section 502B(d) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA123CC0A12F148A3AEFA193E7783AD71"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Security assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>security assistance</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0100C070F8A3487A9D923D383F4A495D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the types of assistance specified in section 502B(d)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9A4554DFB824C70A93A5D5C02B43784"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assistance furnished under an international security assistance program of the United States conducted under any other provision of law, including under the authorities under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB4E22E6A9914BCDBAC33DDF581FF9FF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United States Munitions List</header><text>The term <term>United States Munitions List</term> means the list maintained pursuant to part 121 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

