<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><bill xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/uslm-2.0.17.xsd">
<!--Disclaimer: Legislative measures that include compacts or other non-standard data structures will require additional modeling and may contain inconsistencies in the converted USLM XML.-->
<meta><dc:title>119 HR 2170 ENR: To name the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Toms River, New Jersey, the Leonard G. ’Bud’ Lomell, VA Clinic, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:type>House Bill</dc:type><docNumber>2170</docNumber><citableAs>119 HR 2170 ENR</citableAs>
<citableAs>119hr2170enr</citableAs>
<citableAs>119 H.R. 2170 ENR</citableAs>
<dc:creator>United States House of Representatives</dc:creator><dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher><dc:format>text/xml</dc:format><dc:language>EN</dc:language><dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights><docStage>ENR</docStage>
<processedBy>GPO Locator to USLM Converter 4.15.98;Stage2.20260514</processedBy><processedDate>2026-07-10</processedDate>
<congress>119</congress><session>1</session><publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate>
</meta>
<preface><dc:type>H. R.</dc:type><docNumber>2170</docNumber>

<congress style="-uslm-lc:I665502" value="119">One Hundred Nineteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session style="-uslm-lc:I665503" value="1">A T T  H  E F  I  R  S  T S  E  S  S  I  O  N</session>
<enrolledDateline style="-uslm-lc:I665504">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-five</enrolledDateline>
</preface>
<main>
<longTitle>
<docTitle class="centered fontsize18" style="-uslm-lc:I665505">An Act</docTitle>
<officialTitle class="centered fontsize8" style="-uslm-lc:I665511">To name the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic in Toms River, New Jersey, the Leonard G. ’Bud’ Lomell, VA Clinic, and for other purposes.<?GPOvSpace 08?></officialTitle>
</longTitle>
<enactingFormula style="-uslm-lc:I650120"><i>  Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa­tives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</i></enactingFormula>
<section id="d7491e62" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1" style="-uslm-lc:I650146"><num class="bold" value="1">SECTION 1. </num><heading>FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau class="indentUp0 firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="x72756630-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756631-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/1" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="1">(1) </num><content>The Department of Veterans Affairs outpatient clinic, a state-of-the-art facility serving the region’s largest veteran population, located at 1055 Hooper Avenue, recently opened in the Township of Toms River, Ocean County, New Jersey, in the Fourth Congressional District.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756632-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/2" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="2">(2) </num><content>The local community, including veterans, believe that this facility deserves to be named in honor of Second Lieutenant Leonard G. “Bud” Lomell, a long time Toms River and Ocean County resident, who served courageously and heroically during World War II.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756633-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/3" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="3">(3) </num><content>Second Lieutenant Lomell was born in 1920, the adopted son of Scandinavian immigrant parents living in Brooklyn, New York, and his family eventually moved to Point Pleasant Beach, New Jersey.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756634-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/4" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="4">(4) </num><content>After graduating from Tennessee Wesleyan College, Second Lieutenant Lomell was drafted into the Army, serving first with the 76th (Liberty Bell) Infantry Division. When the 2nd Ranger Battalion was formed in April 1943, Leonard Lomell was invited to be the First Sergeant of D Company.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756635-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/5" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="5">(5) </num><content>On D-Day, June 6, 1944, First Sergeant Lomell’s platoon landed at Pointe du Hoc, Normandy, France, successfully scaling the cliffs, despite a withering German defensive barrage.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756636-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/6" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="6">(6) </num><content>Pointe du Hoc, a rugged 100-foot-high coastal promenade along the English Channel was located between the American landing beaches, Omaha and Utah. It was heavily defended by the Germans and the mission of Colonel James Earl Rudder’s 225 Rangers was to disable five 155-millimeter artillery guns, which could have rained artillery fire on the American forces landing on either beach, jeopardizing the invasion.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756637-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/7" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="7">(7) </num><content>Unknown to the American forces, the guns had been moved from the tip of the Pointe and hidden, pointed in the direction of Utah Beach, in an inland apple orchard nearly a mile from the coastal batteries.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756638-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/8" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="8">(8) </num><content>First Sergeant Lomell and another Ranger, Sergeant Jack Kuhn, found the guns undefended, and, with Kuhn providing cover, Lomell destroyed the weapons with thermite grenades and used his rifle butt to smash the sights of the guns.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y72756639-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/9" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="9">(9) </num><content>First Sergeant Lomell subsequently received a battlefield promotion to Second Lieutenant, and was awarded some of the Army’s highest honors, including the Distinguished Service Cross, Purple Heart, and Silver Star.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y7275663a-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/10" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="10">(10) </num><content>Renowned historian Steven Ambrose regarded First Sergeant Lomell’s valiant acts along with General Eisenhower’s decision to invade on June 6, 1944, as the most significant actions ensuring the Allied victory on D-Day.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y7275663b-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/11" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="11">(11) </num><content>Following World War II, Second Lieutenant Lomell was appointed as the First Director of the newly organized Ocean County Veteran’s Service Bureau, serving from 1946 until 1948, before he attended law school on the G.I. Bill.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y7275663c-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/12" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="12">(12) </num><content>Leonard Lomell and his wife, Charlotte Ewart Lomell, settled their growing family in Toms River, where, in 1957, Leonard established his own law firm, which grew to become one of Ocean County’s largest firms.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y7275663d-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/13" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="13">(13) </num><content>Leonard Lomell was involved in numerous local civic, business, and charitable organizations, including serving as president of the Ocean County Bar Association, a director of the First National Bank of Toms River, a member of the Dover Township Board of Education, and a co-founder of the Garden State Philharmonic. He was also National Commander of the Legion of Valor (1964-1965) and President of the Ranger Battalion Association of World War II (1967) and served on the French Committee of Pointe du Hoc.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y7275663e-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/14" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="14">(14) </num><content>Second Lieutenant Lomell is profiled in “The Greatest Generation”, former NBC news Anchor Tom Brokaw’s testament to the heroes of World War II, and “Len Lomell: D-Day Hero”, Steven M. Gillon’s entry in the American War Heroes Series.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="y7275663f-7c8f-11f1-9f1f-75bc427816d3" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s1/15" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="15">(15) </num><content>As a decorated war hero, model citizen, and dedicated husband and father, Second Lieutenant Lomell is exceedingly deserving of the posthumous honor of having a new and long-awaited Toms River-based Department of Veterans Affairs outpatient clinic named in his honor.</content></paragraph>
</section>
<section id="d7491e146" identifier="/us/bill/119/hr/2170/s2" style="-uslm-lc:I650141"><num class="bold" value="2">SEC. 2. </num><heading>NAME OF DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS COMMUNITY-BASED OUTPATIENT CLINIC, TOMS RIVER, NEW JERSEY.</heading><content style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  The community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Toms River, New Jersey, shall, after the date of the enactment of this Act, be known and designated as the “Leonard G. ‘Bud’ Lomell VA Clinic”. Any reference to such clinic in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be considered to be a reference to the Leonard G. “Bud” Lomell VA Clinic.</content></section>
</main>
<signatures>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></signature>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Vice President of the United States and  President of the Senate.</role></signature>
</signatures>
</bill>