<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC24F57477C064F6CB11883E0E2ADA423" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7747 IH: State Veterans Homes Inspection Simplification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7747</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to streamline the certification process for State Veterans Homes by allowing certain facilities certified by the Department of Veterans Affairs to be deemed in compliance with specified Medicare and Medicaid requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC95FE74B4F0F4D98BB158BD8B8FF9DFB" style="OLC"><section id="H00C8D4CF734A46168963E641A95FEACB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Veterans Homes Inspection Simplification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBE3FF223E93E4F1CB670F6704074E9B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Deeming of State Veterans Homes certified by the Department of Veterans Affairs as meeting Medicare conditions of participation</header><subsection id="HF7A81E33FF3F4B2A9A3ADEB4D6B37D44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicare deeming authority</header><text>Section 1819 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63365CD3811A447386B349765B769BC6"><subsection id="HA7D61941D53940B982D882CD1704625A"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Special Rule for State Veterans Homes</header><paragraph id="HCCC29ABA05B6449798C56BBC47C6DFB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deemed compliance</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E4FA1170A2D437AB2A1DAE75C13B92E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State home (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code) that is inspected and certified by the Department of Veterans Affairs (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>VA</quote>) in accordance with standards approved by the Secretary shall be deemed to meet the requirements of subsections (b) through (i) of this section if the Secretary determines that the following requirements are met:</text><clause id="H1757F8E65D4C4749821CD3C8E08F29FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The VA provides the Secretary with documentation of inspection and certification, which must include survey findings, statements of deficiencies, and related corrective actions.</text></clause><clause id="H9B25A1193E5E4BEBAEDA834462F34D1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Not less than once every 2 years, the VA submits its State home survey standards and inspection procedures for joint review with the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to confirm continued alignment with Medicare Conditions of Participation, including oversight methodologies.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3BED5625BC0434DADB05889BAD70361"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for approval of standards</header><text>In approving standards under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B1D4BDA31494887992AD4088504FBCC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</text></clause><clause id="HAC9EAC7A0BBB48F0B28C398658D33D56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the inspection and certification process used by the VA, including both standards and enforcement practices—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E4F5EFB000F477B9354CEAB46976217"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes, as a minimum, the survey protocols and enforcement expectations of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEC82E8877D641A2BD25F2DB0A2705E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upholds, at a minimum, the same standards of resident care, safety, transparency, and accountability required under this section.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9431666945784C3483DB72DA34627A1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight and enforcement</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall preclude the Secretary from doing any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4C258CFA8E78472BB540C6A8B3CF67E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conducting complaint investigations or targeted surveys of any State home.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CA4001E05544FFCB9BB2DA102E11CF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Imposing remedies under subsection (h), including civil monetary penalties or termination of participation under this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDFF025E1EFD49DEBEED38FB25D880DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Revoking deemed status under paragraph (1) if the VA certification process is found to be inconsistent with Federal standards of transparency, data quality, or enforcement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31C495D5D886440DBD949575DF7EF80E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public reporting</header><text>Survey and certification data from VA inspections deemed valid under this subsection shall be reported publicly through the Nursing Home Care Compare website under subsection (i) or another publicly accessible platform in a format determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6379F19977A84FB8BBB0F6EE74FCC4BE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Congressional notice</header><text>Not later than 15 days after—</text><subparagraph id="H2965F9995E80488F86BFF11DE3E10034"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approving standards under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A395E02814C49C694590C337902FE61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>revoking or suspending deemed status under paragraph (2); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB299B7ECF9874F7CB32CD2DBC3F9A89C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying material non-alignment between VA inspection practices and Medicare Conditions of Participation;</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the Secretary shall submit written notice to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs and Finance of the Senate.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC67F108A7F524196A1D297EE0398A847"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medicaid conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1919 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC62CC3B1FF934F4EBDF8A037F6E88F93"><subsection id="H7E178CEE693E4BF88F868514550DFD06"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Special rule for State veterans homes</header><text>The provisions of section 1819(l) shall apply with respect to a nursing facility that is a State home (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code) and that is inspected and certified by the Department of Veterans Affairs in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply under title XVIII.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9B1E8B477A644711AAE00B426780BCD1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H083EEE857437442CA60D84FF41F9109C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of enforcement expectations</header><text>The term <quote>Enforcement expectations</quote> means deficiency citations, corrective action plans, and remedies in response to individual deficiencies or repeat-deficiency rates that are as effective as or more effective than, and in lieu of, those resulting from surveys conducted directly by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE1699DF0670C4A159548A9630720BEE1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Alignment of data for public reporting</header><subsection id="HC8725D3D7B57428CBC48B860B09CF00B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>VA survey data on nursing home care compare</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall coordinate with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that inspection findings, deficiency statements, and quality metrics from Department of Veterans Affairs-certified State homes (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code) are incorporated into the Nursing Home Care Compare website (or a successor website), to the extent feasible and consistent with section 1819(g)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(g)(5)</external-xref>), and in a manner consistent with the risk-adjustment and case-mix methodologies otherwise used by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services for public reporting of nursing facility quality measures.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6DFCD50006AC43E587025359FBE50CEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Harmonization of survey processes</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall issue guidance to align certification and data reporting processes to ensure consistency and transparency in the public reporting of quality and compliance information for State homes (as so defined).</text></subsection></section><section id="H813EDAE5A1DB4820B4845B9C21592899"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO review of deeming authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the effective date of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to the Congress evaluating—</text><paragraph id="HBF37D176E9A34820A6D5CA8CEBB53B6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the impact of deeming authority on survey efficiency and costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA42EC33584564A52BCBFD4192BA36F64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>comparative enforcement outcomes between VA-conducted and CMS-conducted surveys;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8DEAC83AE9C4AA0BD7B00484D9170D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>quality of care and safety outcomes for residents of State Veterans Homes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F458C60D9E94CC6B2409945D7D76B5B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations for legislative or administrative action.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

