<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25G57-HNK-0V-LHV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3245 IS: Medical Integrity in Necessary Diagnostics for Our Veterans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3245</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee to improve mental health screening conducted under separation health assessments for members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Integrity in Necessary Diagnostics for Our Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MIND Our Veterans Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id34675e5da1cd478e817b66d6156849af"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvement of mental health screening conducted under separation health assessments for members of the Armed Forces</header><subsection id="idc919d99bf5c1416c9653ff10f7b24ac2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id8953b5fa582943e5abe30b7b8e963a0d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in order to address the mental health challenges following separation of members of the Armed Forces from military service, transitioning members must receive effective mental health screening prior to separation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbc1296e08e88489086e7f442716bb12d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all screens conducted for mental health for members of the Armed Forces under the separation health assessment must be validated screens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1122a02ab6a42729720faf0bd58df00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>it is essential that the Department of Defense fully implement the separation health assessment with validated screening; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7fc9e42649ee4f8f8e5678cc1febb643"><enum>(4)</enum><text>screening for substance use should be considered a necessary mental health screen and included in the separation health assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8a85f3b1aff42a2afd2b1833995a867"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Validated mental health screens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Joint Executive Committee shall ensure the post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) mental health screen, the alcohol use mental health screen, and the violence risk mental health screen under the separation health assessment are each modified to be a validated tool, which may include taking steps to validate an existing screen or replacing an existing screen with an already validated screen.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida6b973b9bb8a4bac8fb207be7a89479e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of substance use in mental health screens</header><paragraph id="idd8bd2424fcfb40899eed49c638510d9a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Joint Executive Committee shall incorporate screening for substance use as a mental health screen and shall assess whether to include such screening in the separation health assessment, including by taking such action as the Joint Executive Committee considers appropriate, which may include taking steps to incorporate a validated screen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id122e659c1ad04879932dc8371527a365"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Joint Executive Committee shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the justification of the Joint Executive Committee to include or not include a substance use screen under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd63b3970b08f48e49b5eacffa52f2726"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation of separation health assessment</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, under the guidance of the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness, shall fully implement the separation health assessment.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id002bb68732bb42f5bc09985a7df6726a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id458262da6ed4476d8d8eacb4c545c356"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d54936e472644d7a633f70b95f40a0e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id061d4d359c5a4279b00d81860b4eef81"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id407fb5324f3541dcbf8d5dafef74a1c2"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Joint Executive Committee</header><text>The term <term>Joint Executive Committee</term> means the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee established under section 320 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideee554058d134ec1a769283e629a643a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Separation health assessment</header><text>The term <term>separation health assessment</term> means the health assessment for members of the Armed Forces separating from military service established by the Joint Executive Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

