<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HCAA92EE3B94144CAA048913DA1A75E16" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 700 IH: Condemning the assassination of Charlie Kirk and honoring his life and legacy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 700</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250911">September 11, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Condemning the assassination of Charlie Kirk and honoring his life and legacy.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was horrifically assassinated on September 10, 2025, at Utah Valley University while speaking to a large group of college students;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk was a devoted husband, father, and Christian;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2012, Charlie Kirk founded Turning Point USA, a conservative campus advocacy group that quickly became one of the fastest growing college campus chapter organizations in the country; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie Kirk frequently engaged college students of all political backgrounds in open debates and discussion, encouraging civil discourse on college campuses and among college students: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> 
<resolution-body id="HEB563A6D39F246F4906C72B1F3E10C28" style="traditional"> 
<section id="H2521B2652DA24851B65217700C321A6E" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House—</text> <paragraph id="HE894FCF156AD41A09E573FCE643143F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the assassination of Charlie Kirk in the strongest possible terms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28B5A1FFAF2D48D59128283A36E383D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>extends its deepest condolences and sympathies to Charlie Kirk’s family, including his wife, Erika, and their two young children; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F4E8E48F9BF4EA19A98DCDC85D6C9AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors Charlie Kirk’s commitment to the constitutional principles of civil discussion and debate between all people of the United States, regardless of political affiliation.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution> 


