<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H68D947F958E34A8395A1D40066A1E2C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6198 IH: Rear Admiral Alene Duerk Ship Renaming Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6198</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To express the sense of Congress regarding the naming of a naval vessel for Rear Admiral Alene Duerk, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9CDFE45BA93B4522888B4C9D6A1647EA" style="OLC"><section id="HCEE3C67468BF4863A9E308B77E29880B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rear Admiral Alene Duerk Ship Renaming Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8B3C6D0B26084E99ABE71A38F728984C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding naming of naval vessel for Rear Admiral Alene Duerk</header><subsection id="H5BBD1769A4D64FDD9FC7DEB94DEAF5FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of the Navy should name a vessel of the United States Navy the <quote>U.S.S. Rear Admiral Alene Duerk</quote> in honor of Rear Admiral Alene Duerk, for the acts of valor described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H41ADE169EB2A4333A20073A63B1628CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acts of valor described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The acts of valor described in this subsection are the actions of Alene Duerk, as a member of the United States Navy, as follows:</text><paragraph id="HB023B2E673504FA6BF6AA01C199FD41F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Following Rear Admiral Duerk’s birth in Defiance, Ohio and graduation from Toledo Hospital School of Nursing, she received a commission on January 23, 1943, and was appointed as an ensign in the Nurse Corps of the U.S. Naval Reserve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05F276F96B8F426295DF38BB1D81FE9B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>During World War II, she was assigned as a Ward Nurse at the Naval Medical Center Portsmouth, Portsmouth, Virginia, and at the Naval Hospital, Bethesda Maryland where she cared for wounded members of the United States Armed Forces. In 1945, she was stationed on the USS Benevolence in the Pacific Theater (AH–13) where she treated casualties from Third Fleet operations until the end of the war.</text>
        </paragraph><paragraph id="H38CCC99A59FD4F1D907B2B43EE800C9C">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>After the war, she progressed in rank and served in positions of increasing responsibility in both the Navy Reserves and Active Duty including posts in Michigan, Virginia, Pennsylvania, Illinois, the Philippines, Japan, California, and Washington, DC. Her dedication and inspirational service culminated with her historic selection for the rank of Rear Admiral on April 16, 1972, as the first woman to become a flag officer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0552C8AF6EC44F28D0D617459A0F885"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Rear Admiral Duerk was awarded the Naval Reserve Medal, American Campaign Medal, the Asiatic-Pacific Campaign Medal with Bronze Star, the World War II Victory Medal, the Navy Occupation Service Medal, Asia Clasp, and the National Defense Service Medal with Bronze Star.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

