<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H071528ABA3DD4CD8821EDB7098485C52" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6179 IH: Clean Cloud Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6179</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Clean Air Act to establish requirements on the collection of electricity consumption data and emissions standards for servers and other computing equipment used for cryptocurrency mining, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF94EABF7F8814AB3B9BDA2FD4F17AB6A" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H58DE86129E6948669D6E0DBE84C32798"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Cloud Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF5A52CEE5C1F4AF28BCD8558D3ADB6DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HC3EE272A87014939A6089C8CE2861D4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data centers are estimated to account for approximately—</text><subparagraph id="H83E0C83A5EA24B729FCF7888822FAD0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 percent of global electricity demand; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1FA9E52C58149F7910681A28D9D6ADC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>4 percent of United States electricity use;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF30DAD63FB97482D97BA5062DFBC40C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the growing demand for information technology and artificial intelligence will increase the demand for data center services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H414B08E34450403FAEFB47F38072BB2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the global COVID–19 pandemic has further increased the demand described in paragraph (2) beyond previous projections;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BA2732E9B0F4DF892BB99CF89BB0EE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>data centers are projected to account for up to 12 percent of United States electricity use by 2028;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DE3AABC8C5147C79C9FDC91F31A96FB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>future electricity consumption and efficiency trends will be determined by management practices, demand for services, and adoption of efficient technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CFD0DF3EC5845679465A17729986D70"><enum>(6)</enum><text>proof-of-work cryptocurrencies are by design an increasingly energy intensive process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CE973024E664C24B0DD1C1CAD573B60"><enum>(7)</enum><text>studies estimate that—</text><subparagraph id="H1DAC5B7DF6114CDB823D3E705CC2F474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total network hashrate for Bitcoin mining in the United States has increased 739 percent between September 2020 and January 2022; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE4190AE28DA4365A20DBB84C03B55E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of July 2021, the greatest share of Bitcoin mining occurs in the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB265B42752684D78B68A3B31DE32A2A1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>there is a lack of transparency regarding the energy sources used to power domestic cryptomining and many data center operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F0F7F0410694EB39868FD6CA6AB19D5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>retired and retiring fossil fuel plants in the United States are being brought back online to power cryptomining facilities and data centers, which increases associated carbon emissions.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B0A3AD076A1425BA6F8F3DDB9ABD6DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Emissions from power consumption of data centers and cryptomining facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title I of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDF630165CB5A4B2BBA7F7DFD8982026D" act-name=""><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H5901B0F6205B4D6ABD7C1027A0B3BF0D"><enum>139.</enum><header>Emissions from power consumption of data centers and cryptomining facilities</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC27FBE27E4334DCEB42A70058DDDD228"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA94CCC0A475242D2B4AAA7ECBAC3F397"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means a data center or cryptomining facility that has more than 100 kilowatts of installed information technology nameplate power.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D6C73CE057F4D46AD243802C746C15B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cryptomining facility</header><text>The term <term>cryptomining facility</term> means a facility used to mine or create cryptocurrencies or other blockchain based digital assets, which may be—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0151E27301AF47FEADAC94CF70F1DFFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a freestanding structure; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48CDDF42D0FB432C8957A74D00EE6EEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a facility within a larger structure that uses environmental control equipment to maintain the proper conditions for the operation of electronic equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CA7DD853CA24A648C3598F47E9F1D5D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data center</header><text>The term <term>data center</term> has the meaning given the term in section 453(a) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17112">42 U.S.C. 17112(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47DBD221918C45B69073B9DC1FA972AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Electric utility</header><text>The term <term>electric utility</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EB6C65679574F9C98D5E1532F331193"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Region</header><text>The term <term>region</term> means a geographic region described in the National Transmission Needs Study of the Department of Energy, dated October 30, 2023.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H820DCA3663CC4982A96215138C3F14CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual data collection of energy consumption of data centers and cryptomining facilities</header><paragraph id="H94DA37E85ACD4B9699A434CE60E84A12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall annually collect—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H702478DBEC7F4BF4B8C056A4520F8C3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information described in paragraph (2) from the owners of covered facilities, including federally owned data centers located within the United States and territories of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H925BA51B87F54AA7B8F8F52A6BF04DDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information described in paragraph (3) from the electric utilities that serve covered facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1389F470F8094EDF960EF463897F24A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information described for covered facilities</header><text>The information referred to in paragraph (1)(A), with respect to a covered facility, is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBECB2B3A80F49EAA711A7AE59B08849"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the location of the covered facility, including in which balancing authority area the covered facility is located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88225C342E954029AC3D1134BEF53AA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the covered facility is a data center or a cryptomining facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C8E4FC38D7449D1A048B4F47752A861"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the owner of the covered facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7144CB3A98894305AFA1207D57D2D686"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the electric utility, if any, that provides power to the covered facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBD604E3F8564FE1B9B8852932245F05"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total annual electricity consumption of the covered facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BD5BB1ACDA046AD912A7E6883ADC01A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the total annual electricity consumed by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5BD6EEDEA284470A105E63ED2425C55"><enum>(G)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (5), the percentage of electricity consumed annually by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility that is generated from wind, solar, hydropower, nuclear, coal, gas, and any other power source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H723B7DE4495349A0A3A999C524A13703"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms of any power purchase agreements or other contractual mechanisms for procuring power from an electricity generator that the covered facility is party to; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3193EA3F1F934938BCA18F7A49848B16"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any other relevant information, as reasonably determined by the Administrator and the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0939404E4A6342B5896075B3BE02CF02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information described for electric utilities</header><text>The information referred to in paragraph (1)(B), with respect to each covered facility served by an electric utility, is—</text><subparagraph id="H8040AAC1C1B34749A32E386E95942EB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total annual electricity consumed by the covered facility from the electric grid;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CD7CF806C084CAEA9FA8EDF8B5F04C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (4), the percentage of electricity consumed annually by the covered facility from the electric grid that is generated from wind, solar, hydropower, nuclear, coal, gas, and any other power source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H504CB2E867DF44C59536855F4A50D4C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the rates charged by the electric utility for each class of electric consumer for the current year and each of the 3 prior years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC26AB4F363D45A2952CCB4A972BAB8B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other relevant information, as reasonably determined by the Administrator and the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC4406E122704A5591702770B156A2B7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Electricity consumed from the electric grid</header><text>For purposes of collecting the information described in paragraph (3)(B) with respect to a covered facility—</text><subparagraph id="H997A996BA1074379B08787E71BD80AB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall consider the average resource mix of the electric utilities that serve the covered facility to be the resource mix for the portion of electricity consumed annually from the electric grid by a covered facility that is not described in subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B94D985A7484D2B8CF4942687422CAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the covered facility or the owner of the covered facility is party to a power purchase agreement or other contractual mechanism for procuring power from an electricity generation asset (such as the voluntary higher rate described in subsection (c)(4)(C)(iii)(I)(aa)), or purchases and retires energy attribute certificates, the Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall consider the electricity generation represented by those instruments as part of the electricity consumed annually by the covered facility from the electric grid only if the owner of the covered facility can demonstrate that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H385BD8551DE74720ADDE2E6804ECEA47"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE02E414D6E7A41619E5627114A121985"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the electricity generation asset began commercial operations not more than 36 months before the date on which operations began at the covered facility;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC82279A40448463AAE02FBEEAD927B2A" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the electricity generation asset would otherwise be retired and the retirement could not be prevented by the use of existing public funding programs;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD054CF4110614BF284D792B237EDFFD0" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the electricity provided by the electricity generation asset would otherwise be curtailed;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20110B62B0C64939A42997DCD402EACA" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the power that the electricity generation asset provides to the covered facility resulted from an uprate that occurred not more than 36 months before the date on which operations began at the covered facility;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA862A5DFFEBB4D769A1BA45C312B9122" indent="up1"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the power purchase agreement or other contractual mechanism was finalized before the date of enactment of this section; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HF06C737A56EC4746B8793A4B8F740EAE"><enum>(VI)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H801FCA7AA73346C7B8A124BB9E011164"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the electricity generation asset has undergone or will undergo a retrofit that reduces the greenhouse emissions intensity of the electricity generation asset, expressed in terms of metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent of greenhouse gases per kilowatt-hour, by not less than 75 percent, as compared to before the retrofit; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H5B5665A58220448E865557AA9D0FCBCC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the retrofit otherwise would not have occurred, even after the use of existing public funding programs, without the power purchase agreement or other contractual mechanism;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HAE47080301A74260BE87BD91D9982636"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the electricity is generated—</text><subclause id="HAE460FFC2EF641AA8BAABE7DC50370C3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the same calendar year as the electricity is consumed by the covered facility, in the case of electricity that is generated before January 1, 2028; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H069E247629D741B49F56771A0A41F9BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the same hour as the electricity is consumed by the covered facility or an energy storage asset that serves the covered facility, in the case of electricity that is generated after December 31, 2027;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5B9E32EB1DFA4E90B9E3F8C006D07BA6"><enum>(iii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H656ADA55E98D40D5A2AE5A17950EB3B4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the electricity generation asset that produced the electricity is electrically interconnected to a balancing authority located in the same region as the covered facility; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H4A89D331FCE4450F863F9E0589934FC3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the owner of the electricity generation asset can demonstrate that the power produced by the electricity generation asset is physically delivered to the covered facility, as determined by the Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8D77BBA4AEE841F0B3BFDE375C310BE1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the electricity generation represented by the power purchase agreement or other contractual mechanism for procuring power from an electricity generation asset are claimed exclusively by the covered facility through the retirement of an equivalent quantity of energy attribute certificates.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5D0DAE835F34C56BB5C7AADE3E15151"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Electricity consumed from assets behind the meter</header><text>For purposes of collecting the information described in paragraph (2)(G) with respect to a covered facility—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6280209C8D14481C90C0CF679E07F854"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall consider the average resource mix of the electric utilities that serve the covered facility to be the resource mix for the portion of electricity consumed annually by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of a covered facility that is not described in subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DA949F3B84C41BB8051006B168ABEB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall consider the electricity generated by electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility as part of the electricity consumed annually by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility only if—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10A2244C435D4512B450FAFC42F6EE36"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the owner of the covered facility can demonstrate that—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56E78063F7CC4D80BD159DD575035876"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the electricity generation asset began operations not more than 36 months before the date on which operations began at the covered facility; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H936E75FAC37F4021BC0F8AE391425858"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the electricity generation asset would otherwise be retired and the retirement could not be prevented by the use of existing public funding programs; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H238EB45D18A84282BA55E7D1035FF3C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator determines that the greenhouse gas emissions intensity, expressed in terms of metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent of greenhouse gases per kilowatt-hour, of the electricity generation asset is higher than the greenhouse gas emissions intensity of the electric utilities that serve the covered facility, based on the average resource mix of those electric utilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H807B1C8899124DDC8DDBE7AF8507ACC2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas emissions intensity</header><text>Based on the information collected under paragraph (1), for each covered facility, the Administrator shall determine the greenhouse gas emission intensity, expressed in terms of metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent of greenhouse gases per kilowatt-hour, of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1498D9CB4B6143A1883CE933403A7223"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total annual electricity consumed by the covered facility from the electric grid; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21AF959B2A7F44659DBC603BC4644EF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total annual electricity consumed by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E2E9187462247878E7F0EC9385B0031"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Publicly available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make publicly available on an annual basis—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E88AA32E1F64004AC6AC012AA47D5D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each covered facility—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD53A3FA87981454095E4E9BF7FA0A663"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information described in each of subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of paragraph (2);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4928632B8DAB4FEB9EC1AB0AF4E6ED69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percent of electricity consumed annually by the covered facility that is generated from wind, solar, hydropower, nuclear, coal, gas, and any other power source; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC14D585E452142D1A2723EC49703A42B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the greenhouse gas emissions intensity of the total annual electricity consumed by the covered facility, as determined under paragraph (6); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35E9E4F420B647FEBAB8840ABE76B67E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each owner of a covered facility, the aggregate annual electricity consumption of all covered facilities owned by that owner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBABD1D9B60654730A03647EAD627985E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Confidential business information</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D57AE297B0A46829EC9A76E122313C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), of the information collected under paragraph (1), the Administrator and the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration shall treat the information described in each of subparagraphs (E) and (F) of paragraph (2) and subparagraph (A) of paragraph (3) as confidential business information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9103B08083849EAA56A5622CEEFC8C9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) does not apply to information that is required to be made publicly available pursuant to paragraph (7)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H158148A87B8F423BA923460187F1032F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Emissions performance standard</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE13DDB0953544D1B00EA13D2B3DD403"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADBB52771A1444D68DE4011F5876D0D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Baseline</header><text>The term <term>baseline</term>, with respect to a covered facility in a calendar year, means the baseline of the region the covered facility is located in for that calendar year as determined under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H532437760D814CAB92D0D0A16A3B2C68"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H169D7C0085594468B21ADFA3A85BE5A9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>greenhouse gas</term> means the air pollutants carbon dioxide, any hydrofluorocarbon, methane, nitrous oxide, any perfluorocarbon, and sulfur hexafluoride.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59434B40EAE9455BA9F2B12273CE962F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Global warming potential</header><text>For purposes of the term <term>methane</term> in clause (i), the Administrator shall use the 20-year global warming potential of methane, as determined in accordance with the Sixth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD52C9033DF50454B897B03DD9C62EBD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of baseline</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AC2759CA2E64CE39D43632F3FAF0879"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Publication of baseline</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2025, the Administrator shall determine and publish in the Federal Register the greenhouse gas emissions intensities of the electric grid of each region, expressed in terms of metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent of greenhouse gases per kilowatt-hour.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94838FCF3BC143F3A2B818A5A3967AAB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial baseline</header><text>For purposes of calendar year 2026, the baseline of each region shall be the baseline of that region published under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30812845688445D5879BAA6560FC0CF6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Baselines through 2034</header><text>For each of calendar years 2027 through 2034, the baseline of each region for that calendar year shall be determined by reducing the baseline from the previous calendar year by 11 percent of the baseline of that region for calendar year 2026.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF146F140B1343F9971C9F98F2EA5ACC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Baseline in 2035 and thereafter</header><text>For calendar year 2035 and each calendar year thereafter, the baseline for each region shall be 0 metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent of greenhouse gases per kilowatt-hour.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H908D1CE37FA0407F97993FC6FEC58348"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessment of fees</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4B08DDF38104E2C89D0D0AB7B3EF541"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Fee on utilities</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8758A792A1DA4A84B69AAE4D77012AC6"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Imposition of fee on utilities</header><text>Beginning on January 1, 2026, the Administrator shall, in accordance with this subparagraph and using the information collected under subsection (b) but subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), assess on the owner of any electric utility providing power to a covered facility a fee with respect to the greenhouse gas emissions of the electricity consumed by the covered facility from the electric grid above the baseline of the region the covered facility is located in for that calendar year.</text></clause><clause id="HE1F6329735E04658AB6ECB8B04BCC4A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount of fee</header><text>The amount of a fee assessed under clause (i) with respect to an electric utility for a calendar year shall be the sum obtained by adding, for each covered facility served by the electric utility, the product (rounded to the nearest dollar) obtained by multiplying—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5A954C75ED7477BA9915524DF0E3A34"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total electricity consumed by the covered facility from the electric grid during the calendar year, as expressed in kilowatt-hours;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C1B7CE69F50413893DDD48BD4324C66"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subject to clause (iii), $20; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAE91FA037304F519B04B60BE48268A4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the amount, if any, that the greenhouse gas emissions intensity of the electricity consumed by the covered facility from the electric grid, expressed in terms of metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent of greenhouse gases per kilowatt-hour, exceeds the baseline of the region the covered facility is located in for the calendar year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H12546736DF4D468EA0C86BC2C25EE36B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Fee adjustment</header><text>Beginning in calendar year 2027, the Administrator shall annually increase the amount described in clause (ii)(II) by the sum obtained by adding—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H044039D8529C4A0CACEAC0BFA61539E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the product obtained by multiplying—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46101011F1E348E389B54DCC47A1AA81"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable amount under clause (ii)(II) during the previous calendar year; and</text></item><item id="H8D57E2EC1DBA44D4BDB7836197C6D67E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the rate of inflation, as determined by the Administrator using the changes for the 12-month period ending the preceding November 30 in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2E065ABF7A64BA99D59583E6DABB634"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$10.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EFA8131A06C4AA5AB4D66C98F9224D3"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Notification of fee amount</header><text>Not later than January 31, 2027, and not later than January 31 of each calendar year thereafter, the Administrator shall notify—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H158F057272AB45A6AD324F0FB0B818A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the owner of each electric utility subject to a fee under clause (i) of the amount of the fee that is assessed with respect to the electric utility for the previous calendar year under clause (i); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A326FF85235441C94F1B692B64AE38B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the owner of each covered facility of the total amount of any fee assessed for the previous calendar year under clause (i) that is attributable, pursuant to clause (ii), to the electricity consumed by the covered facility.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38C869A840C546B3B012924A4D4C5AFF"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Remittance of fee amount</header><text>A fee assessed under clause (i) for a calendar year shall be due and payable to the Administrator not later than March 31 of the calendar year after the calendar year for which the fee is assessed.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97B83A5B519448BEBC8D4A7C4D34BBDA"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Pass-through limitation</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H525AE6DF075D4136AC27080395F5CAEC"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any electric utility assessed a fee under clause (i) may not recoup the cost of the fee by raising rates or assessing fees on any customer that is not a covered facility.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB75A6AFEEC8146D48EBA7C3BE1951427"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Monitoring compliance</header><text>The Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall use the best available data, including the information collected pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) and described in subsection (b)(3)(C), to monitor the compliance of electric utilities with subclause (I).</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98583CCD281E4D1FAF94A949E601C9F8"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>If the Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, determines that an electric utility has violated subclause (I), the Administrator shall assess a fine on the electric utility in an amount equal to 2 times the amount recouped by the electric utility, as described in subclause (I), from customers that are not covered facilities.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A9EFD3D8AFB416784093385F3A30655"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fee on covered facilities</header><clause id="H5809D1A5B0E2495BA1C79A8FB5FA83F2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Imposition of fee on covered facilities</header><text>Beginning on January 1, 2026, the Administrator shall, in accordance with this subparagraph and using the information collected under subsection (b) but subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), assess on the owner of any covered facility a fee with respect to the greenhouse gas emissions of the electricity consumed by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility above the baseline of the region the covered facility is located in for that calendar year.</text></clause><clause id="H4D6D128623364D4C81A14829AA83EAFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount of fee</header><text>The amount of a fee assessed under clause (i) with respect to a covered facility for a calendar year shall be the product (rounded to the nearest dollar) obtained by multiplying—</text><subclause id="H9D224ABB1A1A472EAB5CC14EAC74A612"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total electricity consumed by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility during the calendar year, as expressed in kilowatt-hours;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFCA690047AEE471BB1C81E23330F20A7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subject to clause (iii), $20; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7B0EAB7214F149E19B3B1F48C8DBC872"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the amount, if any, that the greenhouse gas emissions intensity of the electricity consumed by the covered facility from electricity generation assets located behind the power meter of the covered facility, expressed in terms of metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent of greenhouse gases per kilowatt-hour, exceeds the baseline of the region the covered facility is located in for the calendar year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFCB9474361D44FAA9444344B4BBC59A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Fee adjustment</header><text>Beginning in calendar year 2027, the Administrator shall annually increase the amount described in clause (ii)(II) by the sum obtained by adding—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06A292CEF17C4262ACC06F45190317AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the product obtained by multiplying—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2496FAD29BF243A7B5B4A9B725B9814F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable amount under clause (ii)(II) during the previous calendar year; and</text></item><item id="HA85627A90F5D45F281AA483DA033242B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the rate of inflation, as determined by the Administrator using the changes for the 12-month period ending the preceding November 30 in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24CF61266F384AE39879B2D287A08F74"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$10.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB7250BF74C5745ADB7E656713E8C8FA1"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Notification of fee amount</header><text>Not later than January 31, 2027, and not later than January 31 of each calendar year thereafter, the Administrator shall notify the owner of each covered facility the amount of the fee that is assessed with respect to the covered facility for the previous calendar year under clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="H9BD657EBC5B34EB0AEFAEBF5F275BDF7"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Remittance of fee amount</header><text>A fee assessed under clause (i) for a calendar year shall be due and payable to the Administrator not later than March 31 of the calendar year after the calendar year for which the fee is assessed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0A6F0FD2E984AEBA5B23B489D345BE9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability to zero-carbon electricity generation assets</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to a covered facility if the Administrator, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, determines, pursuant to the information collected under subsection (b), that the covered facility is powered entirely by zero-carbon electricity generation assets during all hours of the operation of the covered facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46121A91183B432F9B172BC00E3A52D4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Alternative baseline</header><text>If the Administrator determines at any point that the greenhouse gas emissions intensity of the electric grid of any region falls below the baseline of that region, during the period beginning on the date of that determination and ending on the date on which the Administrator determines that the determination is no longer applicable, subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall be applied to covered facilities located in that region by substituting <quote>greenhouse gas emissions intensity of the electric grid</quote> for <quote>baseline</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56090750A69841279930638A19FBEF85"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E960A6C98A34B80AEADB1C571862C40"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administration</header><text>For fiscal year 2028 and each fiscal year thereafter, there are appropriated, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Administrator an amount equal to 3 percent of the amounts collected pursuant to fees and penalties assessed under paragraph (3) during the previous calendar year to support the administration of the reporting program under subsection (b) and the assessment of the fees and penalties under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD988504441884F5F8A03A097EC155540"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consumer energy costs</header><text>For fiscal year 2028 and each fiscal year thereafter, there are appropriated, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Administrator an amount equal to 25 percent of the amounts collected pursuant to fees and penalties assessed under paragraph (3) during the previous calendar year to award grants to States, Indian Tribes, municipalities, and electric utilities to support programs that lower residential electricity consumer energy costs, such as through energy use savings or direct rebates, to offset cost increases resulting from increased data center electricity consumption.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H365CBE108B35432180F479F500C96173"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Clean firm grants</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58C8B81DBDCD4595B7F2C678E159A84A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2028 and each fiscal year thereafter, there are appropriated, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Administrator an amount equal to 70 percent of the amounts collected pursuant to fees and penalties assessed under paragraph (3) during the previous calendar year to award to eligible entities, as determined by the Administrator, grants, rebates, advanced market commitments, or low-interest loans, as determined appropriate by the Administrator, for the research, development, demonstration, and deployment of—</text><subclause id="H563E247E3D2D418680BEC0E87D00D067"><enum>(I)</enum><text>zero-carbon electricity generation assets that are capable of generating electricity throughout the year, with the exception of planned outages for maintenance, refueling, or retrofits, at capacity factors greater than 70 percent; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49A34E8160694DD5A3A658ACCE87D604"><enum>(II)</enum><text>long-duration energy storage assets that are capable of continuously discharging energy at their rated power output for at least 10 hours.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H41E2B509014949B69F89D848DD0E411D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking an award under clause (i) shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text></clause><clause id="H86EB0F9AE04B4724AD2284F5F96E9A24"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Certification and clawback</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F98569440C3435892404B716DA7896D"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certification</header><text>An eligible entity that receives an award under clause (i) for the purpose of financing the construction or operation of an electricity generation asset or energy storage asset shall certify that any electric utility selling or contracted to sell electricity generated or stored by the asset shall—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB658CCAC168A44C195E2E3720687627F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 2 years after the date on which the eligible entity receives the award, allow the customers of the electric utility to voluntarily pay a higher rate for the purchase of electricity service that is sourced from zero-carbon electricity generation assets, including long-duration energy storage assets charged by zero-carbon electricity, in all hours of the year; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H930D51C8302A4E7490D431F77468B57B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exclusively use the additional amounts collected pursuant to those higher rates to support the financing, development, or acquisition of—</text><subitem id="HF3AE4C1FD8A4451FBC96720B76868531"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>zero-carbon electricity generation assets that are capable of generating electricity throughout the year, with the exception of planned outages for maintenance, refueling, or retrofits, at capacity factors greater than 70 percent; or</text></subitem><subitem id="HA6DAE4E719544F72B89C26683CC588AD"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>long-duration energy storage assets that are capable of continuously discharging energy at their rated power output for at least 10 hours.</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H680FFDCD378440D3A24E09D7ABD9F238"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Clawback</header><text>If the Administrator determines that a recipient of an award described in subclause (I) has violated the certification required under that subclause, the Administrator shall seek reimbursement of the full amount of the award from the recipient.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7FDA28D7FD534C69AF1A892C3423F708"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability to leased facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B3ABA2D03774123BFEA6EB6195DC508"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if a covered facility is leased to a tenant, the tenant shall be considered the owner of the facility; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87857E80ABDE4487927BCCFB34D6F168"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a portion of a covered facility is leased to a tenant and the leased space also meets the requirements described in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D8B657BA85441BB8E0BB0D6694A1443"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the leased space shall be considered to be a separate covered facility from the rest of the larger facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D4F4F36DC4949C6958A4035EE03715A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the tenant shall be considered the owner of the covered facility that comprises the leased space.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H28576967F59C4F8CAC10D3196243D9D8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of the provision or amendment to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected by the holding.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

