<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H57FF0D2EACE842BB8E9411CC9F2F14A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9102 IH: Biotech Investment National Security Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9102</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title VIII of the Defense Production Act of 1950 to alter the definitions of <quote>prohibited technology</quote> and <quote>notifiable technology</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3225933D34194FD298697AB8B10657FD" style="OLC"><section id="H61144CB6182546F5914786AD9B0E93F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited at the <quote><short-title>Biotech Investment National Security Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BINSA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H24C28B806C234286B99220C224022326"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H88B85E8E44134C8388DAE48D1216BF14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>China has pursued a deliberate, state-directed strategy to dominate global biotechnology, including pharmaceutical development, biologics manufacturing, and clinical research and development capabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H411F2DDD3FC3449F8A7290277489FC2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States capital flowing to Chinese biotechnology companies through licensing agreements, joint ventures, and equity investments is accelerating China’s acquisition of pharmaceutical intellectual property and clinical development capabilities in a manner that creates strategic dependency risks for the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E0E189E29A94EC8BAD345F7AB6374A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Cross-border out-licensing transactions between United States and European pharmaceutical companies and Chinese biotechnology firms totaled approximately $136,000,000,000 in 2025, representing a rapid and accelerating transfer of pharmaceutical innovation capacity to entities subject to the direction and control of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F768823CC4E4461A3E1209BB1CD4599"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Biotechnology, including pharmaceutical development and biologics manufacturing, has civil-military dual-use applications and presents strategic dependency risks for the United States comparable to those presented by semiconductors, artificial intelligence, and other technologies already covered under title VIII of the Defense Production Act of 1950.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2500593E9199442DB4A752347F6B5D4A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The BIOSECURE Act, enacted as part of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026, recognized that biotechnology is both a national security asset and a strategic vulnerability, and that the People’s Republic of China seeks to dominate biotechnology as an industry of the future.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEADFC973CB3A4FC88BF57EDE38B672F4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Consistent application of outbound investment screening to biotechnology is necessary to prevent United States capital and intellectual property from accelerating China’s dominance of the pharmaceutical innovation supply chain in a manner that will create long-term strategic dependency risks analogous to those the United States now faces in rare earth elements and semiconductors.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEB00B227764241C3BF31BD8613912C2C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 809 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4589">50 U.S.C. 4589</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H89710AF3BD9C4418AB5CFCDD81FE2B4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10)(A), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8113D27E94284772BFA695968DC1570C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HE32310FB50204155BAEF6648FE172E69"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Biotechnology, meaning the research, development, manufacturing, or commercialization of—</text><subclause id="H7B6B7303C9E646C7BDF71D67531C71DB"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>pharmaceutical products (which has the meaning given the term <term>drug</term> in section 201(g)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(g)(1)</external-xref>));</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFA25F32871234EDFAB857D2F1C289DAE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>biological products (as such term is defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(i)</external-xref>)); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA32F292C6C7041A08D6334545ACD263C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>therapeutic compounds, including drug discovery platforms, clinical research and development capabilities, biologics manufacturing, and intellectual property and know-how relating to therapeutic compounds, </text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6339735A3A77452A9766D9249EA70A2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(A), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H45DECF2534BC4528BAC630773CC92423" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HE51628E4B39E4D8793E9F5D2B0FB7105" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Biotechnology, meaning the research, development, manufacturing, or commercialization of—</text><subclause id="H81D5297C940C4314BBB64BB43F7BF015"><enum>(I)</enum><text>pharmaceutical products (which has the meaning given the term <term>drug</term> in section 201(g)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(g)(1)</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="HC842101EFE93465DA916E59369E685D2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>biological products (as such term is defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(i)</external-xref>)); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDE6C210ED5AE4F2C8C3EBA77FA9F6EF2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>therapeutic compounds, including drug discovery platforms, clinical research and development capabilities, biologics manufacturing, and intellectual property and know-how relating to therapeutic compounds, </text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BF9346A67CF407A90D89B1E295DDDC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H3B4236B6D47D4A0D9C71170D718DFDA0" style="OLC"><clause id="H1787B773D8124C619AB2813284268860"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>licensing a prohibited technology from a covered foreign person.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HF224A74B2D5C41D694C6FA51EB06936B" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><subsection id="HDACEB807AADB498CBF7F5BD8A09F2CAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, issue a rule to further define the parameters of the area of <quote>biotechnology</quote> as it is used in paragraphs (7)(A) and (10)(A) of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H16A7260628E44291929033C5C072082F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>When defining the parameters of the area of <quote>biotechnology</quote> pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury shall—</text><paragraph id="H00B96301B8E34334A688AC006C732740" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of National Intelligence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA539DA6AC9F8428E945DB6394F9E7335" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give particular consideration to transactions involving the licensing of intellectual property, drug discovery platforms, clinical research and development capabilities, and biologics manufacturing know-how to covered foreign persons (as such term is defined in section 809 of the Defense Production Act of 1950);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D9AFAC10414415A9FBB009B95E90150" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give particular consideration to licensing transactions, joint ventures, and equity investments involving drug discovery platforms, clinical development capabilities, and biologics manufacturing as priority categories for both the prohibited and notifiable technology tiers within the biotechnology sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H055D50189F9446AAAD10D73EF0BB6766" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consider the degree to which a transaction would transfer pharmaceutical innovation capacity, clinical development capabilities, or manufacturing know-how to entities subject to the direction or control of the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CFE852E6B4C456E92C2E72A20D99D55" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">define the biotechnology sector to include the research, development, manufacturing, and commercialization of pharmaceutical products, biological products, and therapeutic compounds, including drug discovery platforms, clinical research and development capabilities, biologics manufacturing, and related intellectual property and know-how transfers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA370F6A8552846F7863CA9DF2FEE6D03" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not define the biotechnology sector in a manner that includes or could be construed to include agricultural biotechnology, industrial fermentation unrelated to pharmaceutical or therapeutic production, or basic academic research with no direct pharmaceutical or therapeutic application.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBAAA3187632B40EE8ADA286F6FC752BE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report required</header><subsection id="H7A510554C9274BEC8F63383DEA95A057"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees assessing whether flows of United States capital into China’s biotechnology sector, including through licensing transactions with Chinese biotechnology firms, negatively affect United States national security and military readiness.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA665A808BC1D4A9A96EE7FD1A3937867"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1B0F6E4B0DC41D4A01EF8CB5568A331"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H71293DF9D5D44812908AD87F0A2772D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5A24CD435DE4EE6987A2F28DBFEF43D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB28FD8EE7CA49EA83BDCB355D12D694"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H306E17BB554F49BABEEB6F27CB4B9D99"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>the Select Committee on the Strategic Competition between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCA50CF09A20490581E6378F43451363"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8DB8BB83BDE4BE388B09DD6BB2B6F7F"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H991B0F3DCE5B489DB1C2F1F82499C87B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

