<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H030C80B5CBCF4C1DBCA37A0EA9863E71" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9341 IH: AI-Ready Federal Data Guidelines Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9341</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to develop guidelines to assist agencies with preparing open Government data assets to be used to train artificial intelligence models, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE915B19DC97446098A460F5F8360F234" style="OLC"><section id="H2CF551EA8E3B44C1A8FD816659905D4F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI-Ready Federal Data Guidelines Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H106FC9CB52124B60869208822C1802FA"><enum>2.</enum><header>AI-ready data guidelines for Federal agencies</header><subsection id="H4E33D19C59734D69B04BA4348D62F1A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Institute of Standards and Technology Act is amended by inserting after section 21 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278g-4">15 U.S.C. 278g-4</external-xref>) the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H990C37C038664B7AB5190667BF7ADFA7"><section id="H3A96D075FBCD482B9ECAE1287DE5A1F6"><enum>21A.</enum><header>AI-ready data guidelines for Federal agencies</header><subsection id="H082F7C7A0DE54C4A8089E236F8D57A30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of guidelines</header><paragraph id="HAB2A046DFB654C9C8AF854DC021009BA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Secretary of Energy, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the head of any other Federal agency the Director considers appropriate, shall develop voluntary guidelines to assist agencies with preparing datasets, including open Government data assets, to be used to train artificial intelligence models.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA490D828D5C4D72961001F167E1743E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the guidelines under paragraph (1) the Director shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H60DC43EDDF934577B3FFC8C0F333AC7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Address, to the extent practicable, the following:</text><clause id="H505D4B55E2AA4DB09C60B84E6ECB8E56" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Data formatting and structure, including guidelines to ensure datasets are interpretable by artificial intelligence systems.</text></clause><clause id="H0C15BD64E22B4C0C8D0AF322D43B88AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Data labeling and annotation, including scalable methods such as programmatic, automated, and expert-guided approaches for preparing data for use in artificial intelligence development.</text></clause><clause id="HE5D95A708D854C218AA421E22091D7BF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data quality evaluation, including guidelines to assess the suitability of datasets for use in artificial intelligence systems.</text></clause><clause id="H4C6D9E354A1345E68F2ADD74608C71C0" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Metadata and documentation, including information sufficient to enable appropriate interpretation and use of datasets for artificial intelligence development.</text></clause><clause id="H8E231EAAA2F141169212EE1AFD8048AD" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data maintenance, including guidance for the ongoing management and updating of datasets to ensure continued suitability for use in artificial intelligence systems.</text></clause><clause id="H5F9B1A96210A4A6D94166E1158369848" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data availability, including guidelines for improving and expanding automated access to publicly available information for artificial intelligence model development and use.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFBA4B7EE33D4FD49339DC3D353B74F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enable flexible implementation, to the extent practicable, for various use cases across sectors and scientific domains.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE7920FA2FF6452A83A1E6EA7735B78C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure, to the extent practicable, consistency with Circular A–119 of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0C2444A72484DC89FCA84240A12B408" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conformity assessment procedures, to the extent practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H175AB7E581364D6CBD5733570193E1B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot programs for AI-ready data guidelines</header><paragraph id="HAE1D10753FEF465B95BC0E15B7CDE0C1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Secretary of Energy, and the head of any other Federal agency the Director determines appropriate, may carry out pilot programs to support the development of conformity assessment procedures for AI-ready datasets used in specific sectors and scientific domains.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4246478BABA4A7B9D97482EFFB578D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>If pilot programs under this subsection are carried out, such programs shall—</text><subparagraph id="H331949A7340F438FA877E27F18E54375"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not exceed one year in duration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02DA0640CC5B44D994BA4A3D978AFAA4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop supplemental guidelines for AI-ready datasets used in specific sectors and scientific domains in accordance with the guidelines published under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H708DA3BCFD4B4578B6D78D97B6882593" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the impact of such guidelines on data usability, interoperability, and readiness for use in artificial intelligence systems in specific sectors and scientific or domains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82B8EC9FDD0449D8854FCF3DC5E51114" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify technical, operational, or resource challenges associated with future implementation and maintenance of such guidelines in specific sectors and scientific domains; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4B1467AF773439E9D4E425759A6F580" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, as practicable and appropriate, a process and materials for the transition to an appropriate non-Federal entity of such guidelines for future implementation of and updates to such guidelines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9CABD23D41F41EFBE53233E4CCAD31D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection of topics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If pilot programs under this subsection are carried out, such programs shall prioritize areas—</text><subparagraph id="HD2DF24BAB07C4BA8AB7876634A39684E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with significant national security and industrial competitiveness implications, such as biotechnology and biomanufacturing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEAE264044814A1AB9A8F4E848C63030" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which Federal agencies control and maintain AI-ready datasets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23782705622D4585A10472A257F5DD3B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If pilot programs under this subsection are carried out, the Director shall carry out not more than two concurrent such programs through federally funded research programs, National Laboratories, institutions of higher education, or partnerships with the private sector.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD61C4459B85545499A1C3421E998D835" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional briefings</header><text>Not later than one year after the publication of the guidelines under subsection (a) and annually thereafter for five years, the Director shall brief the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAC72B4AF71264BAABF32E24C01B4F7D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may not transfer or reprogram any funds from any other program, project, office, or other entity or activity of the Institute to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H710AB51992654BA195F4F1035B6570C8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H527DA445BFE340739A9EC602764777AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FB669BC1F864C8A83796B11EC4E3F28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB26C9042EFAA4ACBA72DFEB48CA5E1D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence model</header><text>The term <quote>artificial intelligence model</quote> means a component of an artificial intelligence system that is—</text><subparagraph id="H3AB93B6B9F6D4B9CACA1518003484EEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>derived using mathematical, computational, statistical, or machine-learning techniques; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4D320195FF5448093713306415E9E34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used as part of an artificial intelligence system to produce outputs from a given set of inputs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12B23C31C50A4E26A925F5D51C71D482"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The term <quote>artificial intelligence system</quote> means any data system, software, hardware, application, tool, service, or utility that operates in whole or in part using artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79C036E1DD9C4BB9BC19D0088FA528B1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Biomanufacturing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>biomanufacturing</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 10002 of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18901">42 U.S.C. 18901</external-xref>; popularly referred to as the <quote>CHIPS and Science Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FF769207EC4498CA7D9A45A2112A4F0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Conformity assessment procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>conformity assessment procedure</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 451 of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2571">19 U.S.C. 2571</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DDC7E3E728D4788A0D6D19B9C65B425"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC59057D68AD492586DF4615E8BB3216" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2F3DBAF24A64026BFE956DC841736E1"><enum>(9)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <quote>National Laboratory</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85EC8F65E3A8407CAE3775B9A93C4B45"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Open Government data asset</header><text>The term <quote>open Government data asset</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H55E73729583B4E69AB17C65204412A56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (f) of section 22A of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h-1</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

