<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A72802CFE374FBD951699EE1015E198" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7581 IH: Living Organ Volunteer Engagement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7581</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260213">February 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a demonstration program to provide payment under the Medicare program for living kidney donor transplant facilitator training.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD9DD834D7EC043C1AA49ED2E56D0EB02" style="OLC"><section id="H418A1C39847040FAABEB386FB8787600" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Living Organ Volunteer Engagement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LOVE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H13B62826DB2142668C141335FFC507ED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicare demonstration program to provide payment for living kidney donor transplant facilitator training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1881 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBBD860F867C349E7A3EF824ED17350DB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H696A77F32DE748AE87F6A7D10F71BB70" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Living kidney donor transplant facilitator training demonstration program</header><paragraph id="H54005380528E415BABE534431F1D33C8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish an 8-year demonstration program under which, for each year of the program, the Secretary shall pay to each eligible hospital participating in the program for such year an amount equal to the reasonable costs of the hospital in operating a living kidney donor transplant facilitator training program described in paragraph (3) for such year, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02C87ED0A9E14994B060DF0D4AF8F8F6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible hospital</header><text>A hospital is eligible to participate in the demonstration program under this subsection if such hospital is a hospital in which kidney transplants are performed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2117EC007B3F4E5D9852AB80F0C21E50" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Living kidney donor transplant facilitator training program described</header><text>A living kidney donor transplant facilitator training program described in this paragraph is a program operated by a hospital that trains individuals to—</text><subparagraph id="H0C96C2B22F414052BBBED160211AE92E" commented="no"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>assist individuals who are entitled to benefits under parts A and B of this title and have been determined to have end-stage renal disease in identifying prospective living kidney donors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B9FAEC617BB48F2B000AC533EB9A3F5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assist individuals entitled to benefits under parts A and B of this title pursuant to subsection (d) in successfully navigating the kidney donation process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AECDB47B01C458C817B544B06ADB069"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive such provisions of this title as may be necessary in order to implement the demonstration program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ACA64568380480FAD4378BB72F4DAE3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="H57D1D86C0E5043D891B525BCC81E0945" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes, with respect to the 5-year period following such date of enactment, the following information:</text><clause id="HA7C9171D31994A5E8975C13F2F5B9B45" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any increase in the number of living kidney donors, as compared to the 5-year period preceding such date of enactment.</text></clause><clause id="H10D351392BDA4E40980D1D7783DD3DA2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any increase in the number of transplants conducted using kidneys donated by living donors, as compared to the 5-year period preceding such date of enactment.</text></clause><clause id="H1E800713D0174AC4822F03BFC3D6EC70" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Outcome measures for individuals that received kidneys from living donors during such period.</text></clause><clause id="HAC469CC0B78744FFADFFEB2C5B6480DD" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any cost savings to the Medicare program attributable to the increase in transplant services and the decline in dialysis services, as compared to the 5-year period preceding such date of enactment.</text></clause><clause id="HCE8B774DFEA9498E82E9D6C16E2075DF" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Qualitative information with respect to transplants conducted using kidneys donated by living donors during such period, as determined based on interviews of facilitators, volunteers at eligible hospitals participating in the demonstration program established under <internal-xref idref="H54005380528E415BABE534431F1D33C8" legis-path="(i)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, living kidney donors, and kidney transplant recipients.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10FCDB4483D449B9A4C2BD834E7F628E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the initial report is submitted under <internal-xref idref="H57D1D86C0E5043D891B525BCC81E0945" legis-path="(i)(2)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, and annually thereafter for the next 2 years, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes updates to the information described in clauses (i) through (v) of such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCBCF6899F7E4457A80DFA8E41B47B40" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="H0422A8E72386414CBD55F2168B028DE8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subclause id="H4BAAC277CD1544FAA80489A9140804FC" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD6EDAC6E09784BD2B1BB9DC5E13EE111" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCEC0C18AB80B4D2F9F6E74FF7A08AD87" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Facilitator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>facilitator</term> means an individual who has received training under a living kidney donor transplant facilitator training program described in paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

