<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5364778C92104CA0800380DCB5F0ED31" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6350 IH: College Athletics Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6350</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the name, image, and likeness rights of college athletes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HECE04367BEC3437C936637090D378416" style="OLC"><section id="H4DE45C2FB9AB4538963CB665AB7A4D79" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>College Athletics Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H057644DAD26E4D57A71F5B537061ED85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H774383B3ECEB484A928ADCA9E55C3F42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Athlete agent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>athlete agent</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7801">15 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E7B457EB6EC42FFB75463DDC31AA22E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>The term <term>antitrust laws</term> has the meaning given such term in the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>) and includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7568FC870BAB49779151D68257AE9FA3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>College athlete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>college athlete</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H38CAE6025538430099AAA544E9570C5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any individual who is enrolled (or has agreed to enroll) at an institution and participates in an intercollegiate sports team of such institution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3DD2E74ABD349A1BDE3114C7036E431" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any individual who is solicited to enroll at an institution by, or at the direction of an employee of, the institution in order for such individual to participate in an intercollegiate sports team of such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H879DA60CF7444828B31C9E6404E8D130"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compensation</term> means, with respect to a college athlete, any form of payment or remuneration, whether provided through cash, benefits, awards, or any other means.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25817E0430C543B7AEEA06D8F6174058"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Conference</header><text>The term <term>conference</term> means an entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H4A83CB32DF87450FB25A1C115DF84CEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has as members 2 or more institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3213181095A640888798CF3DA988B22C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arranges regular season intercollegiate athletic competitions and championships for such members; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AE76AFB44624594B62A94FE46C93387"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sets rules with respect to such intercollegiate athletic competitions and championships.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C1FD6CE7DC4E05ABA574ABBE899F79"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Image</header><text>The term <term>image</term> means, with respect to a college athlete, any visual depiction that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to the college athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43C26C9039FF4EF1BB736B6CEDF7DF79"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution</header><text>The term <term>institution</term> has the meaning given the term <term>institution of higher education</term> in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DF785FD2CBA4F84A480FF588898ECF6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Intercollegiate athletic association</header><text>The term <term>intercollegiate athletic association</term> means any entity that—</text><subparagraph id="HD5D9E666A1314A58A4AA2EEDE3D847A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sets common rules, standards, procedures, or guidelines for the administration and regulation of intercollegiate sports teams and intercollegiate athletics competitions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB3732677033402C804B57EEE990513C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is composed of 2 or more institutions or conferences located in more than 1 State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8ED9262D56DA4D5991C3FFC1995B133E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Intercollegiate athletic competition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intercollegiate athletic competition</term> means any contest, game, meet, match, tournament, regatta, or other event in which intercollegiate sports teams of more than 1 institution compete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1952FA2499A64EDAAC27967F761C22D9" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Intercollegiate athletics</header><text>The term <term>intercollegiate athletics</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HAB4A6B0DE41E45DDA397B7502C140898" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the intercollegiate sports teams for which eligibility requirements for participation by college athletes are established by a conference or an intercollegiate athletic association; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2688B453DC524DDB80EAACFDAE1EA84A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any recreational, intramural, or club teams.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56BD8B7B92E74F83B76218E4E14F0F37"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Intercollegiate sports team</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intercollegiate sports team</term> means an entity composed of an individual or group of individuals enrolled at an institution that is organized by such institution for the purposes of participation in intercollegiate athletic competitions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H474D1CC60C04406D885F2EC2C3E25EB5"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Likeness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>likeness</term>, with respect to a college athlete, means a physical or digital depiction or representation that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to the college athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0D4DDD033C24E1EB93AE1A3214F9363"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Name</header><text>The term <term>name</term>, with respect to a college athlete, means the first, middle, or last name, or the nickname or former name, of the college athlete when used in a context that identifies, is linked to, or is reasonably linkable to the college athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H630CEAE7E6B645548CA7D2D73B35D37B"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Name, image, and likeness agreement</header><text>The term <term>name, image, and likeness agreement</term> means a contract or similar written or oral agreement under which a college athlete licenses or authorizes, or a contract or similar agreement that otherwise is in relation to, the commercial use of the name, image, or likeness of the college athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC148135C3B943C0B10B9925F6B25751"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Power Four</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Power Four</term> means the Big Ten Conference, the Southeastern Conference, the Atlantic Coast Conference, and the Big 12 Conference, or any successors to such conferences.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA68957F05EC4940931E3733A2F2AC3C"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Professional representation</header><text>The term <term>professional representation</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H629096075074487A8FFEFCF0EFB2A319"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representation provided by an athlete agent, financial advisor, or collective representative; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9930DDB3C3B74C148145D05FA5C03081"><enum>(B)</enum><text>legal representation provided by an attorney.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB03D96F733841E781941ADCAE68BF26"><enum>(17)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA02A10B7FF2546BAB14A6DDF5B116100"><enum>3.</enum><header>College athlete’s name, image, and likeness rights</header><subsection id="H7672667ECE234AEC807A63F12E2E9562"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right To receive compensation for name, image, and likeness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An intercollegiate athletic association (in this Act referred to as an <quote>IAA</quote>), conference, or institution may not—</text><paragraph id="HF521A1BDF7C341C89A2B08105529DDB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>restrict a college athlete from receiving compensation for the use of the name, image, or likeness of such college athlete; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H030DA58A084449BF97B7CF9BACB99209"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take adverse action against a college athlete because the college athlete receives compensation for the use of the name, image, or likeness of such college athlete.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82AFE84B47AD4730B98F92A8D821AE9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right to representation</header><text>An IAA, conference, or institution may not—</text><paragraph id="H18E7A630701549F498BE9F8F068710B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>restrict a college athlete from obtaining professional representation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED262E9DB1A142FA89A8A441CAF61C52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take adverse action against a college athlete because the college athlete obtained professional representation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45ED48E230C843DB960E0FBBEED92BC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Right to privacy</header><paragraph id="H9854AD163C804B23AB42CF0D69AB5AF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An IAA, conference, or institution may not require a college athlete to disclose the terms of a name, image, and likeness (in this Act referred to as <quote>NIL</quote>) agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63E3EFA384B044E29D6176F516A6083F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voluntary disclosure</header><text>If a college athlete voluntarily discloses the terms of an NIL agreement to an IAA, conference, or institution, that IAA, conference, or institution may not disclose the terms of the agreement to a third-party without the express written consent of the college athlete.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H659FDECC0CD547498E5268F345317A35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Right to transparent agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A name, image, and likeness agreement under which a college athlete is provided compensation in an amount greater than $600 shall be voidable by the athlete if such agreement does not satisfy the following:</text><paragraph id="H840C2C863D0A4CDB8261746E598449B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The agreement is in writing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1406484888B74D719BD35A832903ADB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The agreement contains the following:</text><subparagraph id="H22A660976B314FE28D5C2BD9251C1836"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of any services to be rendered under the agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2E07D66728C4210BF0813EAA54BF701"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The names of the parties to the agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA25C4CFF51FC44EF8CACA3D52AA5080B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term of the agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A8944F76BD84A88AB8D11A47790D52B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The amount of compensation to be provided to the college athlete under the agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H542293B37A5F4DEE9668F8A3E77903E4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A provision specifying the circumstances or events under which the agreement may be terminated due to nonperformance of obligations by the college athlete.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E011FBBD98A487BB34C8E8CD9EB3528"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A provision specifying that the college athlete may terminate the agreement, notwithstanding any other term described in the agreement, beginning immediately after the date on which the college athlete is no longer enrolled at any institution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED5108C9975446A2827FBA4F92743DCF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The signature of the college athlete or, if the college athlete is under the age of 18 years, the signature of the parent or guardian of the college athlete.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7EFAF5797334FCB9075B178C919E1C0" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>International athletes</header><paragraph id="H5EE6F9D92609420A85E7C641AE7E9A32" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility for F visas</header><text>Section 101(a)(15)(F) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(F)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HFDB685EEC83D496DA285A05219E4A483" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(i) an alien having</quote> and inserting <quote>(i)(I) an alien having</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F21C081E6AA4306840F6DDA2BA5C56C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating clauses (ii) and (iii) as subclauses (II) and (III), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5EEBADBC18741BBB442FAFD61880B46" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F3E770835144B2FB0DA0EE308A9D0F3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEDA71189AD941A596F5237D58797122"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9583E65B3A634181AF1DFC2C2F89707B" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien having a residence in a foreign country which he has no intention of abandoning, who is a bona fide current college athlete (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>College Athletics Reform Act</short-title>) qualified to pursue a full course of study at an institution (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>College Athletics Reform Act)</short-title>, and who seeks to enter the United States temporarily and for the purpose of pursuing a course of study at such an institution, that is approved by the Secretary of Homeland Security, while also participating in intercollegiate athletics, which institution shall have agreed to report to the Secretary of Homeland Security the termination of attendance of each nonimmigrant student, and if any such institution fails to make reports promptly the approval shall be withdrawn;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA774573298A340EC8B06E4B8A6828090" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Name, image, and likeness activities by international college
 athletes</header><text>Section 212(a)(5)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B16B02C595C44788C00086C9429D1B8"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD21F9ADA8182450E987EEB6D2A352E9B"><enum>(v)</enum><header>International college athletes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clause (i), an alien who seeks admission to the United States to compete in intercollegiate athletics as an international college athlete nonimmigrant described in subparagraph (F)(ii) of section 101(a)(15) shall not be inadmissible for having participated or engaged in activities described in section 3 of the College Athletics Reform Act (relating to the marketing of the name, image, or likeness, of the alien), individually or as a member of a group of athletes, and such activities shall not constitute a violation of or failure to maintain such nonimmigrant status.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB0E7484CE954D39AAFDF3EFBFFFCAD2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H7B3839049B3745C6BC99DABCAD15652B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header><subparagraph id="H5B4DB1BACACD4FA18E466899268B65D9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section (other than the amendments made by subsection (e)) shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE58C4A243A6F411A8D234C770E956AAE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates such section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EBA6937A841477CAA46A5657A8BB3EA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonprofit organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 4, 5(a)(2), or 6 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>; 45(a)(2); 46) or any jurisdictional limitation of the Federal Trade Commission, the Federal Trade Commission shall also enforce this section in the same manner provided in subparagraphs (A) and (B) with respect to organizations not organized to carry on business for their own profit or that of their members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CCFC36C65184AAA823F3948F452B2D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions by States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of such State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of this Act, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the college athletes enrolled at an institution of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph id="H8CDB4BF76D574C9BB1D12C456047D746"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7940577A4EAA49A69571883B534273AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA9C1461049B40D79DE7487AFFE6A3D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAB0115FA64E4064B1E8AAE1DC7F5752"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain such other legal and equitable relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9B911FF4FE3435F9540F293B3D3F5C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subparagraph id="H838F77394090421FB028B081E87B43C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any college athlete or group of college athletes injured by a violation of this section may bring a civil action against an IAA, conference, or institution for such violation in the appropriate United States district court to receive appropriate relief, including preliminary and other equitable or declaratory relief and actual damages.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDACAC848A88A4C3DADE4462E7E0DFFA1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Costs and fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action brought under this paragraph, a court may award court costs and attorney’s fees to the prevailing plaintiff.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23B5A87612F3436DA06623AC6237994E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text>The provisions of this section shall preempt any provision of a State law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law that conflicts with a provision of this section. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a State from enacting a law, rule, or regulation that provides more expansive rights to college athletes than the rights provided by the provisions of this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4A45F94423784AD9BC3635973C59F11B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulating sports agents</header><subsection id="H0C647898E35D4ECDA2889CBA2EC078E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Updates to Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act</header><text>The Sports Agent Responsibility and Trust Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7801">15 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8269A9D41E044C3D9579D304D4A72856"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3—</text><subparagraph id="H5E99158F0142441D93E10C414B556AEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="HC73D83928EBA4E2F8C48CA3D23095BAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively; and</text></clause><clause id="HED843B067A574DFB87600CACD2AF8404"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD39952489F5D41D49D95D21A81F1F848" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HAF9B7900BB8745FD9283715A750872BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>charge a student athlete a fee with respect to an endorsement contract that is in an amount that is greater than 4 percent of the amount of the compensation provided to such student athlete under such contract;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6338DD1C00D04DA8A553902491D8F5EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">represent a student athlete for an endorsement contract without the athlete agent first registering as an agent with a State and certifying to an athletic association governing the intercollegiate sport the student athlete participates in that the athlete agent is registered with a State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7477A7C63FA4AC8AC9C8CD25F499672"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into an agency contract with a student athlete that does not include a provision specifying that the student athlete may terminate the agency contract, notwithstanding any other term described in the agency contract, beginning on the date that is immediately after the date on which the student athlete is no longer enrolled at any institution (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>College Athletics Reform Act</short-title>);</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B46942B3544490789E850CC32AEB5EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3), by striking <quote>Warning to Student Athlete: If you agree orally or in writing to be represented by an agent now or in the future you may lose your eligibility to compete as a student athlete in your sport.</quote> and inserting <quote>Notice to Student Athlete:</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1416E65DCC914687A2B6699E3AEE50D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 8, by striking <quote>Uniform Athlete Agents Act of 2000</quote> and inserting <quote>Revised Uniform Athlete Agents Act</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF237F91C59F34119AEF09227269C413D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission study</header><paragraph id="H18F2827312C14FB4859933DC6A6D9AF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall conduct a study to analyze the impacts of establishing a program, administered by an entity independent of any institution, conference, or intercollegiate athletic association, to develop standards for, certify as compliant with such standards, and otherwise regulate athlete agents who enter into agreements with college athletes, which shall include an analysis of—</text><subparagraph id="HB973A25C3C384574986D2F5EF9B1AA42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>options for establishing such a program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F6E1CCF7DF3432C98641516BD2A2608"><enum>(B)</enum><text>potential sources of funding for such a program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38A36E883A304501A833D47B92954C9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a reasonable timeline for establishing such a program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H824F69E5D7B24EA190E67339674C930A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the costs and benefits associated with such a program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93817618B8544A8FAD9519043729208D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), which shall include legislative recommendations with respect to the establishment and funding of the program described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0ED499181A194560A35297AAE2564F90"><enum>5.</enum><header>Establishment of Commission</header><subsection id="H7D90AC1111744C4CB80FDC19A839F1FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the legislative branch the Commission to Stabilize College Sports (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD7B141A8F2E246E38CB8F8CC752953E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H8CD972063D534F10A2463879A238433E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><subparagraph id="H7F2AE11E620D4713AF390FE16A102F47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 16 members, of whom—</text><clause id="H8E81576C3A2D4673804497C4289C3952"><enum>(i)</enum><text>4 shall be appointed by the Chair of the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Chair of the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, and not fewer than 2 of these members shall currently or previously have participated in intercollegiate athletics;</text></clause><clause id="H1AE5D7C598A142E8AEA1771AB1B5B7FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>4 shall be appointed by the ranking minority member of the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the ranking minority member of the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, and not fewer than 2 of these members shall currently or previously have participated in intercollegiate athletics;</text></clause><clause id="H7D1CBF49EA2C463F979FA41CA77134D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>4 shall be appointed by the Chair of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Chair of the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and not fewer than 2 of these members shall currently or previously have participated in intercollegiate athletics; and</text></clause><clause id="H784690094C5B4E7DADB762DDD9204578"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>4 shall be appointed by the ranking minority member of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the ranking minority member of the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and not fewer than 2 of these members shall currently or previously have participated in intercollegiate athletics.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCFD17696AAD4A91BBA407C3C6637692"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member appointed under subparagraph (A) shall have experience in one or more of the following areas:</text><clause id="H84F4CF2770CD48CA838DA013EB10138F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Professional or college athletics, including participation, administration, governance, and media.</text></clause><clause id="H71BF377E3216481086196A5D66888536"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement of Federal statutes covering college athletics, including title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H95C39C1E824A43A28940CE7733A758CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Employment and labor issues, especially collective bargaining.</text></clause><clause id="H54F75F2736424D96BC2960814F7F63D5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Civil rights issues, including fairness and advocacy.</text></clause><clause id="HA54552646A0141ED9F75F432F10A8C16"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Leadership experience at a non-Power Four institution, especially a historically Black college or university.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6359A23C61924D9188AA076720C23230"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Diversity of qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making appointments to the Commission under subparagraph (A), the congressional leaders shall not appoint more than 8 members affiliated with the Power Four, including institutions who are members of the Power Four.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H091BCAED71154E758E843E23158B4B05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Co-Chairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall have two co-Chairs, selected from among the members of the Commission and jointly agreed upon by the Chairs and ranking minority members of the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0ED40E95B15446BB8DCADF3905D02F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Date and period of appointment</header><text>The appointments of the members of the Commission shall be made not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act. Members shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA52F85B81434BCBA93447B078DDEAAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Commission shall meet and begin the operations of the Commission as soon as practicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEFE94DEBDB3E45D58CA0976AF068F9FF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quorum; vacancies</header><text>After the initial meeting, the Commission shall meet upon the call of the co-Chairs or a majority of its members. Ten members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum. Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></subsection><subsection id="H82BBA0CE7BEB4C7FBF6BC482925F51EF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duties of Commission</header><paragraph id="H86FB7D611BA041FB868B99BA0B47E0CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><subparagraph id="HFAAF4D0BC0CE4AF4A5B52C03EBF1C916"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall conduct a study on matters related to the governance of college athletics in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E820F00702B4C7CAACCAF7C659D0109"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matters studied</header><text>The matters studied by the Commission shall include—</text><clause id="HE3F265C804A344478B8B40EE0AD5DBAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>proper roles of intercollegiate athletic associations, conferences, institutions, and governmental entities in the governance of college athletics;</text></clause><clause id="H3D831914E4004D7696AD3D80A30FD07C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to collective bargaining between college athletes and intercollegiate athletic associations, conferences, or institutions on bargaining subjects such as compensation (including equitable revenue sharing), the transfer portal, athlete health and safety (including independent medical care), eligibility, academic standards, and time and travel requirements—</text><subclause id="H80E658DBB8C44D57B45DDBF9267BBAC8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods and effects of Congress enabling collective bargaining without classifying college athletes as employees; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA3B969C535514E038B04CA37D2EB6B9F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>barriers and solutions to collective bargaining without congressional intervention;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD1548B4E1DD447E696C4CE2254BB709E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods and effects of Congress chartering a new organization, similar to the United States Olympic &amp; Paralympic Committee, to negotiate college sports’ media rights and govern college athletics, and providing athletes adequate representation and voting power within such an organization;</text></clause><clause id="HE9EA6DF272D54CC2A0F0D6C68CD9EE88"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the state of title IX, especially enforcement by the Department of Education and the statute’s impact on direct compensation and opportunities related to NIL; and</text></clause><clause id="H11262E6F30E44B818F3B3880985D7B67"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how additional revenue generated by the pooling and selling of institutions' television rights, in accordance with section 6, can be deployed to protect and expand opportunities in women’s and nonrevenue sports and support athletic programs at non-Power Four schools, especially historically Black colleges and universities, including by revenue sharing directly with athletes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1205807AF2854B5FAE33C0B0C78DC9D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date on which a majority of the members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall submit a report to the majority and minority leaders of the Senate, the Speaker of the House, the minority leader of the House, and the Chairs and ranking minority members of the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives which shall contain a detailed statement of the findings and conclusions of the Commission, together with its recommendations for such legislation as it considers appropriate. The Commission shall make the report publicly available on a website owned and operated by Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DDA0EC69EBE4C88898FD4ED0857E5FA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><paragraph id="H0C783EC009914E228BF2D4611C000A2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may—</text><subparagraph id="H89DFC001576D44CA9B5FB6874F01CC9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B0526A6E90743FCB3540DA8D8673D8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subpoena an intercollegiate athletic association, conference, institution, or individual the testimony of whom may be relevant to the purpose of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBB042472F9445CB900EDAB6221DAB2C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header><text>On request by the executive director of the Commission, the head of a Federal agency shall furnish information to the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD027F3FA764E49E18429BBAA9F70855B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mail in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F41716A7D6B4E6DAA81154F60334BD1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>The Commission may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D6057F9FFF14FF995F731F6BE2608E7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The co-Chairs of the Commission, in accordance with rules agreed upon by the Commission, shall appoint and fix the compensation of an executive director and such other personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its duties, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that no rate of pay fixed under this subsection may exceed the equivalent of that payable to a person occupying a position at level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF4302D39A9284D2BBE1C4FC9D8466B81"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Compensation and travel expenses</header><text>Each member of the Commission may be compensated at not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day during which that member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Commission. While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission, members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H81A36FEA7AFB4079AE4B40058ED133B7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Termination of the Commission</header><text>The Commission shall terminate 90 days after the date on which the Commission submits the report under subsection (f)(2). The Commission may use the 90-day period for the purposes of concluding its activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB0310B166249436BAB5061D2FB557CF2"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section, of which—</text><paragraph id="HD33B15C90C144589A8725E425F574D4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>50 percent shall be derived from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5CC8EAD82E4C1B8CFD9BD6ED3D3CA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>50 percent shall be derived from the contingent fund of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H96721C552E334B999446AC09CA99F18E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Amending the Sports Broadcasting Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1 of the Sports Broadcasting Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1291">15 U.S.C. 1291</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBEFA2AEF7CA94B0FA9FC015E4C74B8EE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="section">In addition, such laws shall not apply to a joint agreement by or among institutions engaged in or conducting intercollegiate athletics, by which any intercollegiate athletic association sells or otherwise transfers all or any part of the rights of such intercollegiate athletic association’s member institutions in the sponsored telecasting of the intercollegiate athletic competitions engaged in or conducted by such institutions. In this section, the term <term>intercollegiate athletic association</term> means an association that includes, as of the date on which such joint agreement is entered into, more than 136 member institutions.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HBD74BF1E211C452DA00BC30E362B692A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Expanding athletics disclosure requirements</header><subsection id="H25D4387C05B04020ACF5F983E1A348B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Institutions of higher education</header><text>Section 485(g) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H03CAD8F6563C40C6B86EC64C1D8995EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H00016795E08745D0BAFC7CBA5BCCC62B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H86A1F674EF1A450EAA5D7DC76D673B66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>collegiate (including intramural and club-level) or</quote> before <quote>intercollegiate athletic program</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HCCC629409FC945BEBF1EBACEE553D352"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>collegiate and</quote> before <quote>intercollegiate athletics</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5DE60E07BB84E0D901FA14CE06B1D19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><clause id="H7904A7E9EDE7437C970EB97BD158B6B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The total amount</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H46BE60BD9AC34668AFBFEF2C8B02C68E" style="OLC"><clause id="H9395ADFB44A94092AED9E23A80515E58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total amount</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H337B19D06F0E4C59AFD2D55CB19FF74A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF5DFCF6AAB494F89B3A7623ED52E3CA6" style="OLC"><clause id="HC39278FB51C0432FB1D3F7F2EEDFD1F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each men’s and women’s varsity team that competed in intercollegiate athletic competition—</text><subclause id="HDECE0E38DD154A2E81A575013BAEFC3D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the total amount of money spent on athletically related student aid; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H164F6AA2607847528E4D810C0980997E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to athletically related student aid awarded the form of a scholarship—</text><item id="HFF30A7A2E46C45E0AF271EAF1F522D7F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the total number of such scholarships awarded, disaggregated—</text><subitem id="H9524970A221743769EE214175E0E9F86"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>by the total number awarded for a period of not more than 1 academic year; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H20FBAEB7451E40E9B02B53B5954CCBCE"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the total number awarded for a period of not less than 4 academic years;</text></subitem></item><item id="H5BA7054BD9F54621B426D806882A93C7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the average amount of such scholarships;</text></item><item id="H2772007A040C488B9915CBAFDFD45996"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the total number of such scholarships that fund the cost of tuition at the institution for the athlete awarded such scholarship; and</text></item><item id="HF775DB2C5DE84C328A6B7BF0ECFDDB8B"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the total number of such scholarships that fund the cost of attendance for the athlete awarded such a scholarship;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H8A76427E817F4775A829D3A660EACCF7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the total amount of revenues shared directly with athletes on the team.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DB0D65E423A45118AE080CDB9ECF8B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by inserting <quote>and disaggregated by each men’s sport and each women’s sport</quote> before the period at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A447A8C02704675915E732D5FD55EDE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by inserting <quote>(which, for purposes of this subparagraph, includes compensation, bonuses, benefits, and buyouts paid to coaches and reportable by the institution of higher education)</quote> before <quote>of the head coaches of men’s teams</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC38FFF17A7BF4AD388FE32EBB3844745"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by inserting <quote>(which, for purposes of this subparagraph, includes compensation, bonuses, benefits, and buyouts paid to coaches and reportable by the institution of higher education)</quote> before <quote>of the assistant coaches of men’s teams</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C20E3BCD0D94469AB829AB2BC8378CC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I)—</text><clause id="H152048E1D2994ABC851B743CF6C38172"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking clause (i) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H29110265EF5D4DE792194D78A73D4AC3" style="OLC"><clause id="H4CED8CFB3B374EBE95C97216397DCE26" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The revenues derived by the institution from the institution’s collegiate and intercollegiate athletics activities, in the aggregate and disaggregated by each men’s sport and each women’s sport, including—</text><subclause id="H511C3A02687044BB9176A16F49E07FC3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>total revenues; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7CBC463C055A45D080DF5B68A21C37D3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>each category of revenues described in clause (ii).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H300ADF21A60F4E7690A20449C765CBEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text><subclause id="HF199435265DE4E6CB9777B676A9802C1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>collegiate</quote> and before <quote>intercollegiate</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H13BD634DDE4B456CB3060DBAC7A4AF18"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, and advertising, but revenues</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>, advertising, and, to the extent practicable, student activities fees and alumni contributions.</quote>;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE30F0538ADB34E12957E21D8D5C68E2F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J)—</text><clause id="H8E38D2D5265249869C0C563A36605D03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking clause (i) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC99AB1C00CD64F6989FF466059AB23E4" style="OLC"><clause id="H33C72732C3184B3D89AEEA100831B065" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The expenses made by the institution for the institution’s collegiate and intercollegiate athletics activities, in the aggregate and disaggregated by each men’s sport and each women’s sport, including—</text><subclause id="H485CB98212B94A21AF9DFF049615283D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>total expenses; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H96CE5CAFAE584F3CABCD7CB6FCA66EBB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>each category of expenses as described in clause (ii).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H13D442E6DC334AD3A4970C2137782BF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>collegiate</quote> and before <quote>intercollegiate</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E7086C2EC6D494D9FD7F37B2A569E81"><enum>(H)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HEDA4DD2BC9D04129A8074934F7548136" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H02CE31DDB49744248F9788CAD51DA34F"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The numbers of participants who participate in 1, 2, or 3 varsity teams, respectively, at the institution, in the aggregate and disaggregated by each men’s sport and each women’s sport.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85948BE0C0194F2096F3E51FC3BCC655"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The total number of men that practice on women’s varsity teams, in the aggregate and disaggregated by each women’s sport.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47FE62608D6144879C05187D8C22BFDC"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The number of male students, and the number of female students, participating in collegiate (including intramural and club) sports at the institution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D5AE3A972DB44CB8000B6BF5301E8B8"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification, description, and demonstration of the part of the three-part test, as published by the Department of Education titled <quote>Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972; a Policy Interpretation; Title IX and Intercollegiate Athletics</quote> (44 Fed. Reg. 71413, December 11, 1979), that the institution asserts its intercollegiate athletics program satisfies for the purposes of compliance with title IX.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8D92F06C31543119E96817A5B3AC676"><enum>(O)</enum><text>A certification that the institution has verified the information submitted in the report under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9F8B66E780E4F379E9C986AB3B25F9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>For the purposes of paragraph (1)(G)</quote> and inserting <quote>For the purposes of subparagraphs (G) and (H) of paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA23E606FD88E4B8B88529671E41A7B19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H65AF7B116653441E8A7EA99B228D0B47" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H5E95E1FA2CD049B4A9E4A4FD4ECD91F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission; report; information availability</header><subparagraph id="H6299492F0BAF474392788C6ACC87DC4F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Institutional requirements</header><text>Each institution of higher education described in paragraph (1) shall—</text><clause id="H86CAEF597E6D491F89C1056B3411F7F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by October 15 of each year, provide the information contained in the report required under such paragraph for such year to the Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="HB0F9DAD269694847AE9E095E2060C411"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by not later than February 15 of each year, publish such information on a public internet website of the institution in a machine-readable and searchable format.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BBBD948E290463B9D8A39403858ADB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>By not later than February 15 of each year, the Secretary shall make the reports and information described in subparagraph (A) for the immediately preceding academic year available to the public, which shall include posting the reports and information on a public internet website of the Department in a searchable format.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B80180436E544309C276D3D82091497"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on July 1, 2026, and shall apply with respect academic year 2026–2027, and each succeeding academic year</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

