<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4F59C66E92C344BCBB77A8ED5950A95B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6623 IH: Community Development Block Grant Equity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6623</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to revise the formula for allocation of community development block grant funds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H295C3420EE484C038C2F751246DAE34E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEA35A119294D493A8BE3E65A3FAD27E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Development Block Grant Equity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF8663BB8A75A4C5D8DC09D7F961CC9C1"><enum>2.</enum><header>CDBG formula</header> <subsection id="H9DA26C0BD5C34952AEBA9595548115D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revision of formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 106 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5306">42 U.S.C. 5306</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H29C4A9BA72F9474988E158053C82E3B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H689B2ABABE0F4666A8A966234CD888FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the subsection designation and all that follows through the end of paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H28149B8B53994987BEF69DE2A1C7DE91" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="HD27E3D2EDE4647EE8843674640A70821"><enum>(b)</enum>
<paragraph id="HD5B0F2A9F1CC4F4EBE3DAA40565CADF9" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine the amount to be allocated to each metropolitan city, which shall be the amount that bears the same ratio to the allocation for all metropolitan areas as the average of the ratios between—</text> <subparagraph id="H9340240B84D649ED9CE6141C493AB654" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the poverty rate per person in families and elderly households in that city and such poverty rate in all metropolitan areas;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD6623CA071674755B3AFE6ADC160955C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of female-headed households with children under age 18 in that city and the extent of such households in all metropolitan areas;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FE1EA5B0C964FBBB7F3CB342F282158" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent of housing that was constructed before 1950 and is occupied by a household in poverty in that city and the extent of such housing in all metropolitan areas; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H25AB1194C2C844F6A54827359FD8D72D" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent of housing overcrowding in that city and the extent of housing overcrowding in all metropolitan areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H370391F67A8E4EFE987C57B319F359B4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine the amount to be allocated to each urban county, which shall be the amount that bears the same ratio to the allocation for all metropolitan areas as the average of the ratios between—</text>
<subparagraph id="H89A7D6529CE24924A03F92F62C5BB719"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the poverty rate per person in families and elderly households in that urban county and such poverty rate in all metropolitan areas;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9360F934A6A242688B968AB054CA25CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of female-headed households with children under age 18 in that urban county and the extent of such households in all metropolitan areas;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3C89FB6B0D5A41968A7C3E4F0F480B5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of housing that was constructed before 1950 and is occupied by a household in poverty in that urban county and the extent of such housing in all metropolitan areas; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA28488C8F8AD4018AFE58DCE384D992B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of housing overcrowding in that urban county and the extent of housing overcrowding in all metropolitan areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCBE91CE5DDC64DF7B5B72A950BFBFF9A" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the average of ratios under paragraphs (1) and (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HBAD44AD751964ABCB0E3A730788E1652"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ratio under subparagraph (A) of such paragraphs shall be counted five times;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBFBDB6F9CFF94B84985BBF2D8F6A7CD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ratio under subparagraph (C) of such paragraphs shall be counted three times; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B7CA01328B84342A8BA87492EB13E30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each of the other ratios shall be counted once.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0F59C8A12CBF464DB669313CB1CFE267"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text> <clause id="H68B52EE5034840D2ABECFCB0C679A0E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B);</text></clause>
<clause id="H7FFB49CCE3E64343BBF16D3E7983607B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A)</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H31B6B0C559AF4881BE6CA854ED6B5EB1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) through (iii) as subparagraphs (A) through (C), respectively; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H85C426E524374E08A5D99DE90D9E725A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(1), by striking the second and third sentences and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H26477A8E393845299CA98F2AB28FA433" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The allocation for each State shall be the amount that bears the same ratio to the allocation for such areas of all States available under this paragraph as the average of the ratios between—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9DF2D0F8F4784380924AEC1B2B27975A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the poverty rate per person in families and elderly households in the nonentitlement areas in that State and such poverty rate in the nonentitlement areas of all States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED74286C0C7848749C3E64559BB545D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of female-headed households with children under age 18 in the nonentitlement areas in that State and the extent of such households in the nonentitlement areas of all States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFEA9A2F72FD44526BAD31F2DB7E1ACF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of housing that was constructed before 1950 and is occupied by a household in poverty in the nonentitlement areas in that State and the extent of such housing in the nonentitlement areas of all States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81F5C300D890419B82C6FBF45EFE0A21"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of housing overcrowding in the nonentitlement areas in that State and the extent of housing overcrowding in the nonentitlement areas of all States.</text></subparagraph>
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">In determining the average of the ratios under the preceding sentence, the ratio under clause (A) shall be counted five times, the ratio under clause (C) shall be counted three times, and each of the other ratios shall be counted once.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3A7AF0A7D0274700A327ABE518AA45FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H67CF83F84921463E9E0C1B296F5124BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>The term <quote>poverty</quote> means having an income that does not exceed the poverty level.</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1E4F18A0498F443CB32E6DF0BDD04E8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (11) through (16); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE35DCFBDF734B6089F0199801B32ECC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (17) through (24) as paragraphs (11) through (11) through (18), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HD9F8FDACF6F54B24A2FC3E7C6F842EB4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5303">42 U.S.C. 5303</external-xref>) is amended by striking the last sentence and inserting the following: <quote>For purposes of assistance under section 106, there is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2026 an amount equal to $3,425,000,000, as adjusted by adding to such amount a percentage thereof equal to any percentage increase, over the immediately preceding 4 calendar quarters ending before the commencement of such fiscal year, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI–U) and, for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, the amount that is equal the amount authorized under this sentence for the immediately preceding fiscal year, as adjusted by adding to such amount a percentage thereof equal to any percentage increase, over the immediately preceding 4 calendar quarters ending before the commencement of such fiscal year to which such authorization applies, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI–U)</quote>.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

