<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25247-8DH-L9-MYW" key="G">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 124 ATS: Recognizing the 250th anniversary of the United States Marine Corps.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. RES. 124</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20250312">March 12, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20251109">November 9, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc>Committee discharged; considered and agreed to with an amended preamble</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 250th anniversary of the United States Marine Corps.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble commented="no">
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas November 10, 2025, marks the 250th anniversary of the United States Marine Corps;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Marine Corps holds a unique place in the history of this country and in the hearts of our people;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Marine Corps embodies the values of honor, courage, and commitment, inspiring generations of people of the United States to serve and defend their country;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Marine Corps has earned a distinguished reputation for readiness in its role and faithfulness in its mission, both in times of war and in times of peace;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Marine Corps has distinguished itself as a premier fighting force that is consistently prepared to face the challenges of tomorrow and adapt to the evolving character of warfare;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States Marine Corps has consistently demonstrated its ability to adapt to emerging threats and to respond to the security needs of the United States from its founding to the present day;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas tradition has it that the United States Marine Corps had its beginning at Tun Tavern in the city of Philadelphia on the 10th day of November 1775, 250 years ago; and</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas this historic milestone is the result of the skill of the United States Marine Corps in battle, its distinguished leadership, its extraordinary courage, and its selfless sacrifice in every major war of the United States from the Revolution to the Global War on Terrorism, including service at such historic battles as Princeton, Derna, Chapultepec, First Bull Run, Belleau Wood, Guadalcanal, Tarawa, Peleliu, Iwo Jima, Okinawa, the Chosin Reservoir, Khe Sanh, Hue, and the liberation of Kuwait, Fallujah, and Helmand Province: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
<resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" id="H856A31E6C72945F184F091568F260EEB">
<section id="H591A6C9D9F4E4DD598972F2515952296" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="H9EF0640D2EDE43A8A1CB1924128D25DB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the 250th anniversary of the United States Marine Corps;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33F746BD5C1D49E5BC7F21FC319045BC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remembers and venerates the Marines and Navy corpsmen who gave their last full measure of devotion on the battlefield;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04E9EC205FA9454394B4C1CDAFBE9C4E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms the motto Semper Fidelis, embodying the honorable commitment of every Marine, past and present, who remain Always Faithful;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C30BB418C7E415F99350D8B16E058AA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the service and sacrifice of the men and women who serve the United States today carrying on the proud tradition of the Marines who came before them;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F423817542C4860BDE425E18A156388" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms the bonds of friendship and shared values between the United States Marine Corps and allied fighting forces;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H999F269B416B43A0AEA1F3BB96A35BDF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">salutes the 250th year since the founding of the United States Marine Corps;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C8F92EA28474ED48AD0E6AE398805BB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">invites the people of the United States to join in the celebration of the 250th anniversary of the United States Marine Corps by attending commemorative events, sharing stories of United States Marine Corps valor and achievement, and recognizing those who have earned the title of United States Marine over the past 250 years; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H80DC6BA1A5244F05A3D8E3639EE3D3D9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages communities across the United States to recognize and honor the contributions of local Marines, and to partner with the United States Marine Corps to promote civic engagement and mutual support.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

