<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7738E878C03D420F855A08C5B5A80B33" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 918 IH: Honoring and commemorating 200 years of historic contributions to American culture made by the city of Akron.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 918</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring and commemorating 200 years of historic contributions to American culture made by the city of Akron.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the town of Akron was founded 200 years ago, on December 6, 1825;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the land that is now Akron was home to numerous native Tribes for thousands of years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the land was owned by France under the papal doctrine of <quote>conquest</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, following the French and Indian War, the land was ceded to Britain;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, following the American Revolutionary War and the Treaty of Paris of 1783, Britain ceded claims to territories west of the Appalachian Mountains to the new confederation of States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1798, Simon Perkins, a 27-year-old land agent employed by the Erie Land Company, a group of investors that included Moses Cleaveland, came to the Western Reserve of Connecticut, where he helped build a town on the banks of the Cuyahoga River at Lake Erie;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1803, Ohio became the 17th State and the first State carved out of the Northwest Territory;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1806, Simon Perkins surveyed much of the Western Reserve, land that presently constitutes Summit and Portage Counties and was then part of the original Jefferson County;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1807, the Ohio Legislature created Portage County, which encompassed most of present-day Summit County, including Akron;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1810, early settler Major Miner Spicer from Groton, Connecticut, built a log cabin on land now owned by the University of Akron;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the War of 1812, Simon Perkins, now a brigadier general, led 400 men in the Ohio militia in defense of the State against British forces;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1812, Paul Williams purchased 109 acres of land for $2.50 per acre for farming;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Paul Williams built a log cabin for his family near what is now the intersection of Buchtel Avenue and Broadway;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the summer of 1825, Simon Perkins asked Connecticut surveyor Joshua Henshaw to create a plat map of a new village that would rise on land straddling one of North America’s great watershed divides;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the founders named the town of Akron after the Greek word <quote>ákros</quote>, meaning <quote>summit</quote> or <quote>high point</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 6, 1825, the plat map was recorded, and the town of Akron was officially established;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas John Brown and his family lived in Akron, Ohio, between 1844 and 1854, during which he harbored enslaved persons traveling North on the Underground Railroad;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1851, during the Women’s Convention in Akron, abolitionist and activist Sojourner Truth delivered her extemporaneous speech <quote>Ain’t I A Woman?</quote> highlighting the plight of Black women and encouraging equal treatment under the law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the city of Akron became known as the <quote>Rubber Capital of the World</quote>, serving as headquarters for 4 major tire companies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the Akron Rubber Strike of 1936, more than 5,000 workers and supporters protested for 5 weeks, leading to the recognition of the United Rubber workers union;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Akron continues to revolutionize the manufacturing and use of polymers through the Economic Development Administration’s Sustainable Polymers Tech Hub;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Akron is the birthplace of historic athletes such as LeBron James, Stephen Curry, and Butch Reynolds, leading to the city being referred to as the <quote>Birthplace of Champions</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Akron is the birthplace of generations of people who have impacted society, art, education, science, and American life, including world-renowned bands such as Devo and The Black Keys and musicians such as Chrissie Hynde and Howard Hewett;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Akron is the birthplace of renowned actors such as Melina Kanakaredes, Angie Everhart, Lola Albright, John Magaro, and Elizabeth Franz, and television personalities such as Hugh Downs;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas Akron is the birthplace of American astronaut Judith Resnik, the first Jewish woman to fly in space, who tragically perished during the space shuttle Challenger disaster; and</text>
        </whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas Akron is the birthplace of Rita Dove, the first African-American to serve as the Poet Laureate Consultant in Poetry to the Library of Congress: Now, therefore, be it</text>
 </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H944E9AB6362441DEB3348421E0620B64"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2334E34450394EB39DA71273C55EE15D"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HB9DBCF9C28B54408991748B6A1C03377"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors and commemorates 200 years of historic contributions to American culture made by the city of Akron;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED63F0226BF74858840D4AA4256CCDB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the city’s longstanding history of fighting for economic, gender, and racial justice; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C2EE43367FE4091BF35AEE365C35090"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages Akron to continue standing up to injustices and supporting workers’ rights for another 200 years.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

