<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C80DCD31D474E7CBEB7E9B10CE67983" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1246 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives in support of the integration of Kosovo into the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives in support of the integration of Kosovo into the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (<quote>NATO</quote>) has served as the cornerstone of Euro-Atlantic security since its founding in 1949, preserving peace and stability through collective defense under article 5 of the Washington Treaty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas NATO enlargement has historically strengthened the Alliance by incorporating nations committed to democracy, individual liberty, and the rule of law, consistent with article 10 of the Washington Treaty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Western Balkans remain one of the final regions of Europe in which several states have not integrated into NATO, leaving a strategic gap that adversaries of the United States and allies of such adversaries seek to exploit;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Russian Federation, the People's Republic of China, and other malign actors have expanded their political, economic, and paramilitary influence across the Western Balkans, posing a direct threat to the security of United States forces stationed in the region and to the broader strategic interests of the United States in Southeastern Europe;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Kosovo declared independence on February 17, 2008, and has since been recognized by over 100 countries, including the United States and a majority of NATO member states;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Kosovo has demonstrated its commitment to democratic governance, civilian oversight of security forces, and multiethnic coexistence, and has actively sought closer integration with NATO;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Partnership for Peace and the Membership Action Plan have served as effective and proven pathways for aspiring NATO members to undertake the political, military, and institutional reforms necessary for full Alliance membership; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the normalization of relations between Kosovo and Serbia, while a worthwhile diplomatic objective, should not be treated as a prerequisite for Kosovo's progress toward NATO membership: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H41FF950D75BF410F86AA2391BAE3AEA9"><section id="H017F09E738C9428A935D557CED38132D" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><paragraph id="HE00129DE79504A5B9A8C40CE020319AF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the full integration of Kosovo into the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (<quote>NATO</quote>) is a priority for the national security interests of the United States in Southeastern Europe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H366A4F398CDD413897D5941EACB23ADA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States is deeply concerned with the growing malign activities of the Russian Federation, the People’s Republic of China, and other malign actors in the Western Balkans, and the threat these pose to the security of United States forces stationed in the region and to the strategic interests of the United States in Southeastern Europe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4B01EBC51704BD38B361F875F11563B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States strongly supports the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Kosovo as a democratic, multiethnic state, and reaffirms its recognition of Kosovo’s independence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB84C55150FF142C3A510D683EEF02C92"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States strongly supports Kosovo’s aspirations as a democratic, multiethnic state, and encourages Kosovo’s continued progress toward integration into NATO;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4F2352AF52C49E88EBB831C19E41547"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States should continue and deepen its support for the modernization of the Kosovo Security Force, the Kosovo Intelligence Agency, and other relevant security organs of the Kosovo state, in order to strengthen Kosovo’s capacity for self-defense and interoperability with NATO forces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA639DD97F0094C7F93CDADDD09AFDB12"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United States urges the remaining 4 non-recognizing member states of NATO, namely Greece, Romania, Slovakia, and Spain, to amend their positions on Kosovo’s sovereignty, so as to allow Kosovo to formally commence movement toward integration into NATO;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73E50B9F5C064C7392FCB269418EB2E3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the pathway toward Kosovo’s full NATO membership should proceed through sequential steps, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE23216FD36E74E6590EEB13639588FD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Kosovo’s inclusion in the NATO Partnership for Peace program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA99E5958F1F431BA5B6FF2556BF455E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Kosovo’s admission into the NATO Membership Action Plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F24016C0F50434FA0091AA507FF4947"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Kosovo’s full admission into NATO as a member state; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56A283DDE28A41F8BB2D7FE201DADA84"><enum>(8)</enum><text>it is the policy of the United States to—</text><subparagraph id="H12AF4412EBFD43CDBFEE7E7F2640C3AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actively advocate within NATO for Kosovo’s inclusion in the Partnership for Peace and the Membership Action Plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93332E7758FA47AFB93A2FD498ADD25B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage diplomatically with non-recognizing NATO member states to encourage recognition of Kosovo’s sovereignty; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884E7C9D7D7147BAAA66CCF5056B11D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>continue security assistance and capacity-building efforts with Kosovo’s security and intelligence institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

