<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H796BBF6E6E254723ACE815618896F28A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7819 IH: Venezuela Oil Proceeds Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7819</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct an audit of a United States and Venezuela energy deal, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HC9D0099B0E2E49A3A28CFAB7A538C64C" style="OLC">
<section id="H9AA8C97C990F4B89A94BB31B684F794C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Venezuela Oil Proceeds Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08A575E6554C4A67821F2FA2EF8B34C7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA890380A783846F6BC744858B44B52AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on January 6, 2026, President Trump announced a United States-Venezuela energy deal under which the United States will market and sell Venezuelan oil and deposit proceeds into <quote>U.S.-controlled</quote> accounts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC1ABE02904144BD9161DB25C3CCDA4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>according to the fact sheet of the Department of Energy issued on January 7, 2026, on the United States-Venezuela energy deal—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AA7D4AE797742BE9506584CA1E3C116"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Government has engaged commodity marketers and banks to execute and provide financial support for the crude oil and crude products sales;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A445D1BA2E24F3A88634FA19DA2C38F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all proceeds from the sale of Venezuelan crude oil and oil products will first settle in United States-controlled accounts at foreign banks <quote>to guarantee the legitimacy and integrity of the ultimate distribution of proceeds</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEA27A67D1BA4ECFB22BEA8A5042F89C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the funds will be disbursed <quote>for the benefit of the American people and the Venezuelan people at the discretion of the U.S. government</quote> and will continue indefinitely;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33B12062B04846F19C8EC4E1DFA9821B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>under the United States-Venezuela energy deal, the United States is selectively rolling back sanctions to enable the transport and sale of Venezuelan crude and oil products to global markets, and the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury is also issuing new licenses for certain companies to import and export Venezuelan oil; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D12C93021294ECB904404316BB6A15D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>during testimony to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate on January 28, 2026, Secretary of State Marco Rubio said there were plans for an <quote>audit process</quote> to review expenditures from an account in Qatar set up under the United States-Venezuela energy deal, but Secretary Rubio added that <quote>We haven't finalized what that audit process would be.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65FEE9C89D6A411AADA8AB9552D13EC3"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO audit</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1086062A69134C3BB592B4FED23C308A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States (referred to in this section as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall initiate an audit of the United States-Venezuela energy deal announced on January 6, 2026, including the activities of the Department of State, the Department of Energy, the Department of the Treasury, and any other Federal Government agencies, employees, or contractors or entities funded by the United States involved in implementing the deal.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46575439BC444D99A7FF64D7F3FE313D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim briefing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the audit required under subsection (a) is completed, the Comptroller General shall provide to the chair and ranking member of each committee and subcommittee of jurisdiction in the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing on preliminary findings, scope, and any identified risks of fraud, abuse, or conflicts of interest identified while conducting the audit.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB62D77993C0245E5BF8A04BCA8D8968E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of noncompliance</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Comptroller General shall notify the chair and ranking member of each committee and subcommittee of jurisdiction in the House of Representatives and the Senate as soon as practicable if the Comptroller General determines that access to information has been unreasonably delayed or denied by any Federal department, agency, employee, or contractor or entity funded by the United States involved in implementing the United States-Venezuela energy deal described in subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H438EE64A0FAD489BA6FF683E9581192B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9EA4EB94AAE46A1935466C33ED59B73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the audit required under subsection (a) is completed, the Comptroller General shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C347211A48C41B5AADB369F7FC468DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress a report on that audit, which shall include—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B5822839D50434A92CF5F66448EB4A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of the findings and conclusions of the Comptroller General with respect to the audit that is the subject of the report; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3793CD8A7E7C498280C77EC5425E450C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or administrative action, as the Comptroller General determines to be appropriate; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA0A650F0B7F407ABBD16482664CC205"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make the report available to—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4CCD4712595465DBE389F0667946646"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE530D08F9D2741F8B90A77A8083D7A76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the majority and minority leaders of the House of Representatives;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA88C3BF31C9645C7ACF3727E20F48F5D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the majority and minority leaders of the Senate;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55083FA10E8C4D18A81996F60642B4CF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the chair and ranking member of each committee and subcommittee of jurisdiction in the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3809E336F5247DBBC60D998729063CD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any Member of Congress who requests the report.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95B37E0794F245CDAC6A079E23B05BAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

