<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H095A897B28FB4681A1B82A2F46E152F7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9040 IH: Regulate the Price of All Drugs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9040</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260526">May 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish fair prices for prescription drugs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8806325251E944ED9A363E2902D2DC59" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D847DAE681743A3BF1E35908F39506E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulate the Price of All Drugs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBF3A913A2A67470FA7294E000EDDB425" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishing the Prescription Drug Regulatory Commission</header> <subsection id="H4C4D35C1A8D24CF98299EF127D7AECDB" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Prescription Drug Price Regulatory Commission (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFFEF93850AA043A0A4ADA328B749367B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H3F979BBEEFA041D7829302EDD3E858D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the fair price recommendation date with respect to a fair price applicability year, the Commission shall, with respect to each approved prescription drug, submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) a recommendation regarding the price that the Commission determines to be a fair price for such drug in order for the manufacturer of such drug to provide access to such price—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D83FFD4EB8740269EC29C8703070D0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to any fair price eligible individual who is dispensed such drug during such fair price applicability year (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such individuals who are dispensed such drugs); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5BE853C4CD084EAA8B19FF88E9AAFF65"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to any hospital, physician, or other provider of services or supplier that furnishes or administers such drug to such an individual during such year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F983BE7F392477CAEB1E523CAC14FCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fair price revisions and waivers</header><text>At any time during a fair price applicability year, the Commission may submit to the Secretary a recommendation—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39943ACBC0E14DC780C55E19E2CDBEA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the Secretary revise the fair price established for an approved prescription drug for such year under <internal-xref idref="HBCA83B0A64064EA59A1FAA5FC6EBE659" legis-path="3.(b)">section 3(b)</internal-xref>; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4747745A5ABC4DF4B69D265639958FAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that the Secretary authorize a temporary waiver of such fair price under <internal-xref idref="H92D8A60A02F642A6940CF017547916F7" legis-path="3.(c)">section 3(c)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03ED7B44F2B441A8B1DC8881C6FB6CFD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required factors for consideration</header><text>In making a recommendation under <internal-xref idref="H3F979BBEEFA041D7829302EDD3E858D8" legis-path="2.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> with respect to the fair price of an approved prescription drug, or a recommendation under <internal-xref idref="H2F983BE7F392477CAEB1E523CAC14FCA" legis-path="2.(b)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref> with respect to a revision or waiver of such fair price, the Commission shall take into account the following factors with respect to such drug:</text> <subparagraph id="H5FB29D9E208C4B8EAEBBE1FB0E5B8AE4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The costs to the manufacturer of producing and distributing of such drug.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF9963DB2766493B8906D09C0ACC8BED" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cost-effectiveness of the drug and its therapeutic benefit (which may be determined on the basis of quality-adjusted life years, equal value of life years gained, or such other measure as the Commission may specify).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE468F000AA84D52B16E7D5DB6477A58" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The anticipated demand for the drug during the fair price applicability year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H10B9EA3BE1D7419C984DCB7092004AD6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The costs and risks to the manufacturer involved in researching and developing such drug, and the return on investment that would provide adequate incentive to the manufacturer to continue research.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE93BF436597E4504B44F67803A022954" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In the case that such drug is available for purchase in 1 or more comparable reference countries, the average price of such drug in such country.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73DCBC9C59974E208FCEE4B1900D5710" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Such other factors as the Secretary of Health and Human Services may specify through rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H7F3383FAF2C14AEABC34088940C38660" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members of Commission</header> <paragraph id="H1B1E40DB5DD64A5DBAB5F48C4E647F81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 13 members as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H531B9B66385644D7BAA0CD5A082A587B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Seven members appointed by the President from individuals who are not officers or employees of any government.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H481F4EC7F02D49D397444620D0A4B9D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Six ex officio members appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services from each of the following agencies:</text> 
<clause id="H30954D65D7F44DA2AE19000EC5342633"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Veterans Health Administration.</text></clause> <clause id="HFD8968BDB6664E90A11D854B3542F060"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Defense Health Agency.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE98DAE0B3D014589A392BF50749608EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></clause> <clause id="HB7E860802A834D3D8280B8A1F9D445AD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Food and Drug Administration.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H83D2B3D1B93D4CF1960583F66773875C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></clause> <clause id="H18E6E614540648789251021BAEE6B0E6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission.</text></clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7B3978475D444FC960235401203A22F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>Each member shall be appointed for a term of 4 years, except that the Secretary may extend the term of any member for 1 additional year if the Secretary determines such extension appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0AF91FCF74D94A3AB8FD92C695B6EBB7" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties under <internal-xref idref="HFFEF93850AA043A0A4ADA328B749367B" legis-path="2.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, the Commission is not subject to the provisions of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H89B5B334F68149679D31B25BFF2FDB10"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year to carry out the activities of the Commission.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HA6B23E608C22403A8CF742B2EA822594"><enum>3.</enum><header>Publication of fair prices</header> <subsection id="H603D468BF6B2409583CDBF464EDE7F21" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the fair price publication date with respect to a fair price applicability year, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall, with respect to each approved prescription drug, establish and publish the price that the Secretary determines to be a fair price for such drug in order for the manufacturer of such drug to provide access to such price—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB6EF01FEA6504099886BFD79A0B6CCCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to any fair price eligible individual who is dispensed such drug during such fair price applicability year (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such individuals who are dispensed such drugs); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72E305671274497C8FF967004BB44147"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hospitals, physicians, and other providers of services and suppliers that furnish or administer such drug to such an individual during such year.</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">In establishing the fair price for each such drug, the Secretary shall take into account the recommendations made by the Prescription Drug Price Regulatory Commission (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) under <internal-xref idref="H3F979BBEEFA041D7829302EDD3E858D8" legis-path="2.(b)(1)">section 2(b)(1)</internal-xref> for such drug and such year.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBCA83B0A64064EA59A1FAA5FC6EBE659" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>The Secretary may revise the fair price applicable to an approved prescription drug for a fair price applicability year after the fair price publication date with respect to such year has passed if—</text> <paragraph id="H3FA208FCA62F40D3A5B08F8A2DDBCD6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary has received a recommendation from the Commission that the fair price be so revised;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6E6BCBFA0A84B388C20638CC8115833"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the judgment of the Secretary, revising such fair price is necessary to account for significant changes to—</text> <subparagraph id="HE3CE6DFA03BF4A238D4A6C851356157C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supply (or projected supply) or demand (or projected demand) for such drug; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC54550A66F9B437A8974B09C036444D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any of the other factors described in <internal-xref idref="H03ED7B44F2B441A8B1DC8881C6FB6CFD" legis-path="2.(b)(3)">section 2(b)(3)</internal-xref> with respect to such drug; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC56AC57813214A899CC72D96F08EDDD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary notifies the manufacturer of such drug not less than 30 days before such revised fair price goes into effect.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H92D8A60A02F642A6940CF017547916F7" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Temporary fair price waiver</header> 
<paragraph id="H913A20527B904C888296F5353D52F1C3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize a manufacturer of an approved prescription drug to provide access to such drug to a fair price eligible individual described in paragraph (1) of <internal-xref idref="H603D468BF6B2409583CDBF464EDE7F21" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> (or to a hospital, physician, or other provider of services or supplier described in paragraph (2) of such subsection with respect to such individual) at a price in excess of a fair price if, in the judgment of the Secretary, such authorization is necessary to maintain access to such drug for all fair price eligible individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H068BDE5C457546F9820411A04C9F591B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration of waiver</header><text>An authorization under this subsection shall last for a period of 90 days. The Secretary may extend such authorization for 1 or more additional 90-day periods if the Secretary determines such extension is necessary.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA3C9C27F777747DBBE01C06773DF4CB7" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties for noncompliance by a manufacturer</header> 
<paragraph id="H0D10AAC3A88A4D0FBDBC982BD63B7FDC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other penalties prescribed by law, any manufacturer of an approved prescription drug that does not provide access during a fair price applicability year to a price that is equal to or less than the fair price for such drug for such year (or, in the case that an authorization under <internal-xref idref="H92D8A60A02F642A6940CF017547916F7" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref> is in effect with respect to such manufacturer and drug, a price that is equal to or less than the price authorized under such subsection)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB2F5ABAAB995443ABE04DEB9DFA67CD5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a fair price eligible individual who is dispensed such drug during such fair price applicability year (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such individuals who are dispensed such drugs); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F94CEE6E6654E7CA710FDF3DF2880B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to a hospital, physician, or other provider of services or supplier that furnished or administered such drug to such an individual during such year;</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall be subject to a civil penalty, for each year and for each drug for which the violation occurs, equal to 10 times the amount equal to the product of the number of units of such drug so furnished, dispensed, or administered during such year and the difference between the price for such drug made available for such year by such manufacturer with respect to such individual or hospital, physician, provider of services, or supplier and the fair price for such drug for such year (or the price authorized under <internal-xref idref="H92D8A60A02F642A6940CF017547916F7" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, as applicable).</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8506E56DE5A4A22933A1D89A0B14D49" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The provisions of section 1128A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7</external-xref>) (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil monetary penalty under this section in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H13723C6E354A46C5A6FF90B69170358B" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Fair prices for prescription drugs required</header> 
<subsection id="H1E7C9F88B7874789BB5B049B6B739F41" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Section 301 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBC40823C6E9B4982BFF84A2281880856" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H9C7D5EE3BE204594AEDD69EB3B91CB20"><enum>(jjj)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Selling, or offering for sale, a drug (or biological product) at a price that exceeds the fair price published under section 3 of the <short-title>Regulate the Price of All Drugs Act</short-title>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8A9B05A3B074AC981ADC533A0046688" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H9E672AA9EE094FB79C171B8097D9B9BA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of section 301(jjj) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC77E76A910344083AFC5EDB6D1535F05" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce subsection (jjj) of such section 301 and any regulation promulgated under such subsection in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates such subsection or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1659B420652441E7BB5913730BD25948" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions by States</header> 
<paragraph id="H20E97CBB439C4421BD5EF5183EE101FD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of such State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of subsection (jjj) of such section 301 or a regulation promulgated under such subsection, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text> <subparagraph id="H252A22F9159249EA946F7BE23AC138C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H283F0435FF2C4ECCBCAB05986B56A1B0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such subsection or such regulation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2935EE1082494EA8B99D415BF4517EAE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B5F72E8C1104A0D9E5DF31FD881E661" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain such other legal and equitable relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1FC94460D7B847D283FBD6BE3120BEAB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Before filing an action under this subsection, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State involved shall provide to the Federal Trade Commission a written notice of such action and a copy of the complaint for such action. If the attorney general, official, or agency determines that it is not feasible to provide the notice described in this paragraph before the filing of the action, the attorney general, official, or agency shall provide written notice of the action and a copy of the complaint to the Federal Trade Commission immediately upon the filing of the action.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC9BB9D3B0F3464F9A47A273757AC142" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority of Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAAFF8C26FFC44A9099A6229F2A1C6DE6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On receiving notice under paragraph (2) of an action under this subsection, the Federal Trade Commission shall have the right—</text> <clause id="H53B05E50D8824659A1E3AF3B903FD6FA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to intervene in the action;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8F7C207AAFAA4B8396CE7D1A44755C64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3932E7DE22E24C589F83D999EE0A0DCA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A6BF9692FCA424BAACD3E7E14BE715D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Federal Trade Commission or the Attorney General of the United States has instituted a civil action for violation of subsection (jjj) of such section 301 or a regulation promulgated under such subsection (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>Federal action</quote>), no State attorney general, official, or agency may bring an action under this subsection during the pendency of the Federal action against any defendant named in the complaint in the Federal action for any violation of such subsection or regulation alleged in such complaint.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9577C3E5E374347B98F31B2E56CA1C6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing a civil action under this subsection, nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent an attorney general, official, or agency of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, official, or agency by the laws of such State to conduct investigations, administer oaths and affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFBC3855301324F36BAD78A15C256B8D3" commented="no">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Private right of action</header>
                <paragraph id="HFD0AEE35974846C191DBF64000E40E17" commented="no">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person injured by an act or practice in violation of subsection (jjj) of such section 301 or a regulation promulgated under such subsection may bring in an appropriate district court of the United States—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HE31C21D21ECD42E095B781981EA55A06" commented="no">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>an action to enjoin the violation;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CDBB48A635E4D1B95427182EBE1375A" commented="no"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>an action to recover three times the amount of damages for actual monetary loss from the violation, or to receive up to $50,000 in damages for each such violation, whichever is greater; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H1BD5D28EA4834441BEE2DA45D4465DB0" commented="no">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>both such actions.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H277438C8FCD5486F81462127680CFBE4" commented="no"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Willful or knowing violations</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court finds that the defendant acted willfully or knowingly in committing a violation described in paragraph (1), the court may, in its discretion, increase the amount of the award to an amount equal to not more than 3 times the amount available under paragraph (1)(B).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD49C06BDBCA94CA9AC6A829148A19712" commented="no">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Costs and attorney’s fees</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall award to a prevailing plaintiff in an action under this subsection the costs of such action and reasonable attorney’s fees, as determined by the court.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6DD9ACD1D63440C3BC537C7662FE691A" commented="no">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Limitation</header>
 <text>An action may be commenced under this subsection not later than 5 years after the date on which the person first discovered or had a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA5CD8EFA9F4244F8A95FC5080C25879E" commented="no">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>Nonexclusive remedy</header>
 <text>The remedy provided by this subsection shall be in addition to any other remedies available to the person.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H31C955F7DA6046FD844E707D06465B0A" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>March-in rights for patent</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the owner of a patent sells a drug in the United States above the fair price published pursuant to section 3 or does not sell an adequate quantity to meet patient demand of a drug in the United States at the fair price published pursuant to section 3, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may assert the right to claim from the owner of any patent for such drug a nonexclusive, partially exclusive, or exclusive license in any field of use, upon terms that are reasonable under the circumstances.</text></section> <section id="HDFE0F1BA300D477D89BD6121ADF4745D" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Use of the Defense Production Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President may use the authorities under title I, title III, and title VII of the Defense Production Act of 1950 to increase the domestic supply of a drug if the Commission has determined that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCEAA862074694FBA8F1B22235A991ADD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there are inadequate facilities or means of production in the United States to produce an amount of such drug that would satisfy patient demand for such drug; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED8F4390431447449C1195A2D9CC12E4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foreign supplies of such drug cannot be reliably and sustainability imported into the United States in such quantities as are necessary for such drug to be purchased at the fair price established for such drug under section 3.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA1A579BE1E5A4E5B9B8DD1FAA959ADD9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H40CD5915EFEE41759EDC1BC98676D4AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approved prescription drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>approved prescription drug</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8DA6FB7A60524B6FAD398BF622C456E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a drug which may be dispensed only upon prescription and that is described in subparagraph (A)(i), (A)(ii), or (A)(iii) of section 1927(k)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(k)(2)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF83B65EEF114A4EB3CDB22AB58E28E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a biological product described in clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (B) of such section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55BB1FE387494382AF79026142EE6754"><enum>(C)</enum><text>insulin described in subparagraph (C) of such section and medical supplies associated with the injection of insulin (as defined in regulations of the Secretary); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H720F6068BA634784981DB0AFAE1CDD2C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a vaccine licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07C112715FD747939FF6AEA4647415CC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comparable reference country</header><text>The term <term>comparable reference country</term> means any of the following countries:</text> <subparagraph id="HA97D9DE728C94F399AF7B4FD398B654F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Canada.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90863AB7C2FC48199D23ECD1DF1FD1E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>France.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53E5F0F7EE4E428496AD246E30D56CBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Germany.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBFD5F6DD0FDF498F87E3997FEB160634"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Italy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42EA5BBDA73B4B6AA68E4F16B410EF9D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Japan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8CA5E1FF8604EE2A2F96EF40186A480"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The United Kingdom.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBF4DBCFE39843C482905487044008FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fair price applicability year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fair price applicability year</term> means a year (beginning with 2027).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D4D2E5F8C9D48AA9BA20C81E741443B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fair price eligible individual</header><text>The term <term>fair price eligible individual</term> means, with respect to an approved prescription drug, an individual who is located in the United States at the time such drug is furnished or administered to such individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8513BE5AF1F64B3A914C54EC88DBB896"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fair price publication date</header><text>The term <term>fair price publication date</term> means, with respect to a fair price applicability year, July 1 of the preceding year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H604C7BEC7B8049FD968023AF9BC9138A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fair price recommendation date</header><text>The term <term>fair price recommendation date</term> means, with respect to a fair price applicability year, May 1 of the preceding year.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

