<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C446F53B4824BB0BC9BE846ADA7C2E8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6345 IH: Point-Access Housing Guidelines Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6345</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish Federal guidelines for point-access block buildings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBCD96FCC6FB94923B834531B23AE1514" style="OLC">
<section id="H4E7FDAE915F940B591EF465ED1508930" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Point-Access Housing Guidelines Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDA78091DD6E24D08BE06FFF2698D215B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal guidelines for point-access block buildings</header> <subsection id="H6F8E4B45B71C424EB22C8E66B5457062"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall issue guidelines to provide States, territories, Tribes, and localities with model code language, best practices, and technical guidance that could be used to facilitate the permitting of point-access block residential buildings.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC154A4B2E4FE4D998F5FBF953FE58A1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When developing the guidelines under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="HC9DE570F7ADF4393BC436AEFC1A435EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fire safety considerations, including sprinkler coverage, smoke detection, ventilation, and building egress performance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC84C0A1DE36542F7B0933DC1330613AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>construction costs and impacts on housing affordability, including the potential for increasing housing supply in high-cost jurisdictions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF0FE6C4DA944D3DAEC40779C1B5B46C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>flexibility for diverse consumer needs, including family sizes, unit configurations, and accessibility;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AE3B7F85FE340B6A3E597BE8273C6F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examples from jurisdictions that have adopted or considered single-stair codes, including States, cities, and relevant international standards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7104E8744AE340249EE310EA04470CB3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>research and model language produced by organizations focused on point-access block building design and building-code reform;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7C7F8CADBE34DCCB5E464E8CA3D458F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consultation with experts, including developers, architects, fire marshals, researchers, economists, housing authorities, and officials in States that have enacted or piloted single-stair reforms; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28A09C3E4F494581B13BABA8C47796A8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>alternative methods of compliance, incorporating options that utilize additional passive or active safety features.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF638214D719C4FEE909A5EE37899B27F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with the International Code Council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate with the International Code Council to encourage the incorporation of provisions about point-access block buildings into the International Building Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0695DE1AD6EE4572A82BFE7A6E1C4692"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award competitive grants to eligible entities to implement pilot projects that evaluate, demonstrate, or validate the safety, feasibility, or cost-effectiveness of point-access block residential buildings.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H249FC04E68D14037A7F91B2E6686035F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to preempt a State or local building code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H70766B1ADDA24CC8BB5CF811D04BA64C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9357E9704584F2A8B955705E12366B4">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Point-access block building</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>point-access block building</quote> means a Group R–2 occupancy residential structure, as such term is defined by the International Building Code, in which a single internal stairway provides access and egress for all dwelling units in a building that is not greater than five stories in height.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C9ED2530180472885B6F4E47ACFAF15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a State, unit of local government, Tribal government, public housing agency, nonprofit housing or community development organization, private developer or construction firm, qualified design or engineering firm, academic or research institution, or any partnership or consortium composed of 2 or more such entities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

