<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H6CC1B56648D44718B3D655542A668654" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 965 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1689) to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate Haiti for temporary protected status.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 965</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date>
</action>
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1689) to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate Haiti for temporary protected status.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H06A3E20808BC4D87A938B52A47D2B521"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HBEE8FF37BDDC4E3086D6790FAB078BED"> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 1689) to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate Haiti for temporary protected status. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute specified in section 4 of this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the majority leader and minority leader or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text> </section> <section id="H42B656F28DB94B2DBFDA87DBC7017393"> <enum>2.</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 1689.</text> </section> 
<section id="H8E1798A454EA4FE78DDCC0BCC4A61319"> <enum>3.</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.R. 1689 no later than one week after passage.</text> </section> <section id="HDC39120EEC224816984598DC1EC6F6C2"> <enum>4.</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment in the nature of a substitute referred to in the first section of this resolution is as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0937AD6B6E904E5C92226B2CD6B0A5FD"> <enum/> <text>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H72063203D0E24EE2A224FBDE56F37372" style="OLC"> <section id="H21B120DBB25D45B194FD2957E7A0B416" section-type="section-one"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Designation of Haiti for temporary protected status</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall designate Haiti for temporary protected status until the date that is 3 months after January 20, 2029.</text> </section> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </paragraph> </section> 
</resolution-body>
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


