<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22D9D88B97A142B9ADFCE5BDFC2159F8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6613 IH: Nuclear Plant Decommissioning Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to provide for consultation with State, Tribal, and local governments, the consideration of State, Tribal, and local concerns, and the approval of post-shutdown decommissioning activities reports by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDAB1CAA7EFD047A19CDE449EC7F22D1D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H546587CF69504CC3BF4BBA1FCCEBC45A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nuclear Plant Decommissioning Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC92C64B806004C21AEB17D7D5E02C47D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Post-shutdown decommissioning activities reports</header><subsection id="HFE15C3174BE241498D9AA306088A9C7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 10 of title I of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2131">42 U.S.C. 2131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F2CA674C89E40AA9C84C6CC73852E45"><section id="HACC5D31E9D6A466A8462DA92FAE15700"><enum>113.</enum><header>Post-shutdown decommissioning activities reports</header><subsection id="HBEA87E181E3D48A98B040B13953211E6"><enum>a.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H54501CA2C8B046FA8B43C1C3A310A4CB"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Affected State</header> <text>The term <term>affected State</term> means—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="H876D2165ACFA47F9839303E3FE0D247B">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the host State of a covered facility; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE90C27C20AA041C4898D3F483349407D"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>each State located within 50 miles of a covered facility.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85E341293FF04610B6BCEA4ACCA48505"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26E9998D2AC4429CB71C4C42E8A9523A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means a facility of a licensee for which a PSDAR is required.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9CDAEE8EC3144A8DBD7B9C9E6448C79B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered material</header><text>The term <term>covered material</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A2F1AAE27C14C68AD3A90FE87B59DAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high-level radioactive waste;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFDD35E2043304DC7B44DF95BDA0B1DCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>spent nuclear fuel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9DB93B6DE1284B49A9E6282CE8106F06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transuranic waste;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H877EA305AF9B4B04B622816A3F092296"><enum>(D)</enum><text>byproduct material that meets the requirements of section 11 e. (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2AC8E0918098447392A915EB790D29AF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other nuclear or radioactive waste or material for which the Commission determines that a material change by the licensee in the manner of handling, storing, or disposing of that waste or material should be preceded by consultation under subsection b.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8DA57953A01A485FAA2EF9B0CB6D5C59"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered PSDAR</header><text>The term <term>covered PSDAR</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B7648FEB1F54FAB8EFF4F29C7C844E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the initial PSDAR for a covered facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B94C101BED8414ABEFF89F573EEC1CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any subsequent PSDAR for a covered facility in which the licensee proposes, as determined by the Commission—</text><clause commented="no" id="H4ACA173EF658432690F39D60501DC060"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a significant update to the decommissioning strategy; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H94137F2CA874431CB96A91E6BF6C82DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a material change in the manner in which covered material is handled, stored, or disposed of.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55BD5FB98CBA45E78839F670FA4FDEE4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Host State</header><text>The term <term>host State</term> means the State in which a covered facility is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E55C46A1D2A4BAAAA3D60668E38F5EC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>License; licensee</header><text>The terms <term>license</term> and <term>licensee</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 50.2 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF3FDA9FBEC34D7C82E1C4FB744C51AA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>PSDAR</header><text>The term <term>PSDAR</term> means a post-shutdown decommissioning activities report submitted to the Commission and affected States under section 50.82(a)(4)(i) of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18EAF71072AE4B94BFA7855657935B54"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Transferee</header><text>The term <term>transferee</term> means an entity to which a licensee proposes to transfer a license for a covered facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D55C8403851496CBFEB2D2269485488"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the governing body of an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E8152865EF84E4EA8FE6573BBC27617"><enum>b.</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), a licensee may not submit to the Commission a proposed covered PSDAR, or transfer to another entity the license, for a covered facility until the licensee and the transferee, if applicable, conduct consultation regarding the development of the proposed covered PSDAR or the proposed license transfer, as applicable, with—</text><paragraph id="H10662E49489A456890BBF91567DDB2CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each affected State; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5033B1EAD9584A0DB51AF083F6FD22A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each unit of State government or Tribal government that—</text><subparagraph id="H8806DDD0B836445C8D4F7167C8E624D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located in an affected State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01F34BB454DC4A448DA77CA25D61064E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has jurisdiction over land located within 50 miles of the covered facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59F8B211829442F9ACB8E2CB9F451EF4"><enum>c.</enum><header>Submission to Commission; public availability</header><paragraph id="HF9C89733562C4B4CB3395980F3B01D40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After carrying out the consultation required under subsection b. with respect to a proposed covered PSDAR or transfer of a license for a covered facility, the licensee shall—</text><subparagraph id="HAB94166A0B8444ACBD0F7133C5E11801"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Commission, as applicable—</text><clause id="H50C72CF285FD44C2856ED3602E7EFA73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed covered PSDAR; or</text></clause><clause id="H8FACA8C45026437B9DFDBC0CDBE39B22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an application for transfer of a license; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC59A72C619F94A9DB3AAF82E4A795FD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (3), make the proposed covered PSDAR or application for transfer of a license, as applicable, available to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H063F6BBDE73D4BE89E93600A0FCF32A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>On receipt of a proposed covered PSDAR or application for transfer of a license under paragraph (1)(A), the Commission shall, subject to paragraph (3), make the proposed covered PSDAR or application for transfer of a license, as applicable, available to the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AD4C744AA2542CBBE8BC18DA012CC87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion of certain information</header><text>In making a proposed covered PSDAR or application for transfer of a license, as applicable, available to the public under paragraph (1)(B) or (2), the Commission or the licensee, as applicable, may redact such information as the Commission or the licensee, as applicable, determines to be necessary to protect—</text><subparagraph id="HDA5BAEDAA0994CA1A3D511E890B5EAA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trade secrets and commercial or financial information under section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD576C8F1B8AC4C7A99D1C4743A796881"><enum>(B)</enum><text>national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2BF550F73091407883D5FACA7182E9AF"><enum>d.</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>For a period of not less than 90 days beginning on the date on which a licensee submits a proposed covered PSDAR to the Commission under subsection c. (1)(A) or the date on which the Commission dockets an application for transfer of a license under section 2.101 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), as applicable, the Commission shall solicit in the host State public comments regarding the proposed covered PSDAR or notice of proposed license transfer, including through—</text><paragraph id="HB00BF793EE72478FBEB671240F00CDD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the solicitation of written comments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H548D56048E3F4C2195A224941F3BB398"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the conduct of not fewer than 2 public meetings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA722BB2AE854A45AF4FAA1A9A9794AF"><enum>e.</enum><header>Support, conditional support, or nonsupport by host State</header><paragraph id="H45BFC982D3334E6EBA133EE0D1F08DCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of a proposed covered PSDAR or the date on which the Commission dockets an application for transfer of a license under section 2.101 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), as applicable, for a covered facility, the Commission shall notify the host State of the opportunity to file with the Commission, by the date that is 60 days after the date on which the host State receives the notification—</text><subparagraph id="HDA9603BC2526455DB527A52E07563CE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of support for the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6782F5106704DB8ACD88599676C0439"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement of conditional support for the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer, together with specific recommendations for changes that could lead the host State to support the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD3F13DAA8B743FCA57FF4DA42821228"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a statement of nonsupport for the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H492036BB44A54318BE71211CABB67E7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statement of support or nonsupport; failure to submit</header><subparagraph id="H6558D60769FE4495AC7D8D3CCCAFC004"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the host State files with the Commission a statement of support under paragraph (1)(A) or a statement of nonsupport under paragraph (1)(C), or fails to file a statement with the Commission by the deadline specified in paragraph (1), the Commission shall issue a determination regarding whether the proposed covered PSDAR is adequate or inadequate or a determination regarding whether to provide consent for the proposed license transfer, as applicable—</text><clause id="H59AC3A273589492588771FB22393097F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based on the considerations described in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="H136F6EE303A743BD9F207D340AD23B5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after taking into consideration—</text><subclause id="HAD9CB07DD8CE4B3F9239D53532AD9589"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any written comments submitted by the host State, other affected States, and local communities with respect to the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5B2753FFB8BA4EFB9DD41C91B782580D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any input from the public under subsection d.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC795248B653456FA07ED5EA3B77F0B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Commission shall consider a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer to be adequate under subparagraph (A) if the Commission determines that—</text><clause id="HB349937EF0E9410C80AC4EBAC8B406FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer provides for—</text><subclause id="H71CF54C2EE5D459A924EECFB86BC5D51"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the overall protection of human health and the environment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H11252F1B0AF24A16B88250FB31819F63"><enum>(II)</enum><text>adequate protection to the health and safety of the public and the common defense and security;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3A9068B389BE46F9B2708252C17E77D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the licensee (and, if applicable, the transferee) has a substantial likelihood of implementing the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer within the timeframe described in the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer application;</text></clause><clause id="H77F1A96C6FA040B0A24277521B6B9D5A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer is in accordance with applicable law (including regulations); and</text></clause><clause id="HE423054268DE4C3199B5AEBD2E794805"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the licensee (and, if applicable, the transferee) has demonstrated that the licensee has, or will have, the funds required to fully implement the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer within the timeframe described in the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer application, based on—</text><subclause id="H36CA1695294D4FCE83545B7CA05DDF34"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a comprehensive radiological site assessment and characterization; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H78262138F0644B4D8D4E95D0F880DB98"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a nonradiological site assessment and characterization conducted by the host State.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E330B5A5BEE42A3B1023E5D57A6C6D3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination of adequacy</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), if the Commission determines that a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer is adequate under subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Commission shall issue a decision document approving the covered PSDAR or license transfer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H178FFBC9C7F241529061DE73CF983993"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Determination of inadequacy</header><clause commented="no" id="H76F17875FDB34D5296CF183BEE9A3C19"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Commission determines that a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer is inadequate under subparagraphs (A) and (B)—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H6A10D01EDB1844EFA49F5BBA60A270D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Commission shall issue a decision document rejecting the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer, including a description of the reasons for the decision, by the applicable deadline under paragraph (4); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HB1A149D1AFB74FAAA4B0B31396D0E8D3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the licensee may develop and submit to the Commission a new proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer application in accordance with this section.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0F9367F7A72A4A78875B7AAD4957319E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain covered PSDARs</header><text>If the Commission rejects a proposed covered PSDAR that is the initial PSDAR for a covered facility, the licensee shall develop and submit to the Commission a new proposed covered PSDAR in accordance with this section not later than 2 years after the date of cessation of operations at the covered facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49B3F646758B408A9290142CEB61410A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conditional support by host State</header><subparagraph id="H3244FFC48EE146939291A254F6F81D0F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which the host State files with the Commission a statement of conditional support of a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer under paragraph (1)(B), the Commission shall determine whether the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer is permissible under applicable law (including regulations).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H012D39339C994F29996F5CDDA98C724E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Changes</header><text>Notwithstanding the adequate protection of public health and safety or the common defense and security, for each change recommended by the host State under paragraph (1)(B), the Commission shall—</text><clause id="HD74E504B036D4B02A241C7CCB01FB0C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide for the inclusion of the change into the final covered PSDAR or license transfer, unless the Commission determines the change to be inappropriate for inclusion, based on clear and convincing evidence that—</text><subclause id="H618F5645CFFB4515A85C2EC357510FA4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the change violates applicable law; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H63DC0D8F6B744C46B3956D0E558D1C69"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total costs of the change substantially outweigh the safety, economic, or environmental benefits of the change to the host State; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFB0738584CB6484CB7DF15735A762037"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if applicable, provide the rationale for each determination of inappropriateness under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68777D2E69574DD7BBE484EEE033AB2E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Decision document</header><clause id="H9ACC74FEE73F4A2AB79F258CB827D647"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), based on the determinations made under subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Commission shall issue a decision document relating to a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer that, as applicable—</text><subclause id="H8912B8F834BF471DAFB949CC61F0011D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>approves the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer with any changes recommended by the host State that are not determined to be inappropriate under subparagraph (B); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H50C591E4E0734A398969C2E30F875325"><enum>(II)</enum><text>rejects the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE0BDEA90642B41709B417EA52F8E169F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>A decision document issued under clause (i) or subparagraph (C) or (D)(i) of paragraph (2) shall be considered to be a final order entered in a proceeding under section 189 a.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3349529EF24A4BE2AA63D8BA288EF102"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment on approval</header><text>On approval by the Commission of a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer under subparagraph (C)(i)(I) or paragraph (2)(C)—</text><clause id="H9EA54ABC173B40EC934F751C3F13074D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered PSDAR or approval of the license transfer by the Commission shall be final; and</text></clause><clause id="HA42BC4AE09C644048005B2429140D4BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the licensee may begin implementation of the covered PSDAR.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD608670B6F6A4075B3FC87F7E97434A4"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rejection</header><clause commented="no" id="H3E12DC66B3A5411F82706FE8C50B57E2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Commission rejects a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer under subparagraph (C)(i)(II), the licensee may develop and submit to the Commission a new proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer application in accordance with this section.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HDE26878CD8E141F4AC89ABEC1827C4BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain covered PSDARs</header><text>If the Commission rejects a proposed covered PSDAR that is the initial PSDAR for a covered facility, the licensee shall develop and submit to the Commission a new proposed covered PSDAR in accordance with this section not later than 2 years after the date of cessation of operations at the covered facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F0794327A5D481FA1B8E1A608D2A8EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline for decision document</header><subparagraph id="HF049D0BA4B354F5A9C1A4695E0E2E366"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the Commission shall issue a decision document relating to a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer under subparagraph (C) or (D)(i)(I) of paragraph (2) or paragraph (3)(C)(i) by not later than 1 year after the date on which the proposed covered PSDAR or an application for transfer of a license, as applicable, is submitted to the Commission under subsection c. (1)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE9C24FE76DA481C8E96603E7689CED5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proposed intermediate license transfers</header><clause id="HF01CA14A3CCB433082CE42382A26DE85"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition of proposed intermediate license transfer</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>proposed intermediate license transfer</term> means a proposed transfer of license—</text><subclause id="H6302303686BA45C8A19EBDE250094E5A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for a covered facility on behalf of which a proposed covered PSDAR has been submitted by the licensee to the Commission under subsection c. (1)(A)(i); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8E15D589D3334DA5954F31002FA3A06A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the notice of which is submitted to the Commission under subsection c. (1)(A)(ii) before the applicable deadline under subparagraph (A) for the issuance by the Commission of a decision document relating to the proposed covered PSDAR described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H97E6000C2AAE4FAD8450B2ED04478C94"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), in any case in which a licensee submits to the Commission a notice of a proposed intermediate license transfer of a covered facility, the Commission shall issue a decision document relating to the proposed covered PSDAR of the covered facility by not later than 1 year after the date of receipt of the application for transfer of a license.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7676EACC715448918D94CF9B73162B6D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If there are unforeseen circumstances, including unexpected technical issues, site-specific characteristics, or other external factors that could affect the ability of the Commission to issue a decision document by a deadline specified in subparagraph (A) or (B)(ii), the Commission may extend the applicable deadline for a reasonable period of time, as determined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD834678BF7E145C8A9D7CC89CB7F515D"><enum>f.</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><paragraph id="HE02B7317230747268DB8FBD3D434496B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Action by transferees</header><text>On transfer of a license for a covered facility by a licensee to a transferee in accordance with this section, the transferee shall conduct consultation in accordance with subsection b. with respect to each proposed covered PSDAR developed by the transferee for the covered facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3224B07E898D40F7A8F43FE7C88A7699"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State environmental law compliance</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Commission shall not approve a proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer under this section unless the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer for a covered facility includes a requirement that the licensee and the transferee, if applicable, shall comply with applicable State law relating to air, water, or soil quality or radiological standards with respect to the implementation of the proposed covered PSDAR or license transfer in any case in which the applicable State law is more restrictive than an applicable Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H740C52649FA642098CF9284783629865"><enum>g.</enum><header>Application to existing decommissioning activities</header><paragraph id="H602F5B8656894DEE8165AF464D9488D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall notify—</text><subparagraph id="H75987BA9367A4D01998E4F1AABAEE85D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each licensee or transferee, if applicable, of the opportunity to develop and submit to the Commission for approval a revised covered PSDAR for any covered facility of the licensee for which, as of the date of enactment of this section—</text><clause id="H5841C8E175BF4C619E936358F00F4455"><enum>(i)</enum><text>decontamination and dismantlement activities described in an existing covered PSDAR have not commenced at the covered facility; or</text></clause><clause id="HAE4F67F58144446B887C114E4A858B77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>decontamination and dismantlement activities described in an existing covered PSDAR have been commenced at the covered facility for a period of less than 5 years; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F3CE84C153C4B36A91095175B8DAD95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each affected State with respect to a covered facility described in subparagraph (A) of the opportunity to consult with a licensee or transferee described in that subparagraph in accordance with subsection b.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD31ABD559A5D40BD92274B833FEE4FA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><subparagraph id="HEA454D7A9EAD4950B0213FD28907187E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), if a licensee or transferee described in paragraph (1)(A) elects to submit to the Commission a revised covered PSDAR under that paragraph, the process for consideration and approval of the revised covered PSDAR shall be carried out in accordance with—</text><clause id="HBC7B91BF55B04EB797285495F7C45073"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the process for consideration and approval of a proposed covered PSDAR for a covered facility under subsections b., c., d., and f.; and</text></clause><clause id="HE3FC961BBD844BA5BEDDA3C12ECF75F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the process for support, conditional support, or nonsupport by the host State under subsection e.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFC86DA4F80541E69B7917B668C501C1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nonselection</header><text>If a licensee or transferee described in paragraph (1)(A) elects not to revise an existing covered PSDAR under that paragraph, the host State may file a statement of support, conditional support, or nonsupport for the existing covered PSDAR in accordance with the process for support, conditional support, or nonsupport by a host State under subsection e.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H662E5FF29801408FBF8104E7D64E201B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decision document</header><text>A decision document for a revised covered PSDAR submitted under paragraph (1)(A), or for an existing covered PSDAR in any case in which the licensee or transferee elects not to revise the existing covered PSDAR, shall be issued in accordance with subparagraph (C) or (D)(i)(I) of subsection e. (2) or subsection e. (3)(C), as applicable, except that the Commission shall issue the decision document by the date that is 1 year after the date on which the applicable decontamination and dismantlement activities commence at the applicable covered facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC27BDB83DE4EE0B713DDD1DA7C78F1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revision after determination of inadequacy</header><text>If the Commission rejects a revised covered PSDAR submitted by a licensee or transferee under paragraph (1)(A) in accordance with subsection e. (2)(D)(i)(I) or subsection e. (3)(C)(i)(II), the licensee or transferee shall develop and submit to the Commission a new revised covered PSDAR in accordance with this subsection by not later than 2 years after the date of the rejection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H572F1C21DF564DA2A27B67AC7E70E2C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H20C7B777EA70423CB585E198E2EB937F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Atomic Energy Act of 1954 is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA1D36154C8FE4436953C904042FD9E08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 103 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2133">42 U.S.C. 2133</external-xref>), by redesignating subsection f. as subsection e.; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB69B0EB6EF6C429B8E12F1C21D16D798"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 111 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2141">42 U.S.C. 2141</external-xref>), by striking the section designation and all that follows through <quote>The Nuclear</quote> in subsection a. and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H712C8A4581634301915DF47F228AAA9B"><section id="H931B1704601A40B3988B21E164583C63"><enum>111.</enum><header>Licensing by Nuclear Regulatory Commission of distribution of certain materials by Department of Energy</header><subsection id="H85D74AC1129442E1A7A9B906BC499F29"><enum>a.</enum><text>The Nuclear</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86148BC57BC44588BE9143595FB8F5B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (68 Stat. 919; 126 Stat. 2216) is amended by striking the items relating to chapter 10 of title I and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC76B507CA1A41EB89619A8F35A07081"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="chapter">Chapter 10. Atomic energy licenses</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 101. License required.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 102. Utilization and production facilities for industrial or commercial purposes.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 103. Commercial licenses.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 104. Medical therapy and research and development.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 105. Antitrust provisions.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 106. Classes of facilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 107. Operators' licenses.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 108. War or national emergency.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 109. Component and other parts of facilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 110. Exclusions.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 111. Licensing by Nuclear Regulatory Commission of distribution of certain materials by Department of Energy.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 112. Domestic medical isotope production.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 113. Post-shutdown decommissioning activities reports.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE0E80B6E864C467EB76CF8F629C27223"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant programs to support the activities of community advisory boards</header><subsection id="H45884D9CE2C744E4A27F5D9BE7BF7CC7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H114D59A3D75D40929E0C6CDFE648CF04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community advisory board</header><text>The term <term>community advisory board</term> means a community committee or other advisory organization that aims to foster communication and information exchange between—</text><subparagraph id="H91EED2935F914A9B9CF5CBB6FD3F93B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a licensee planning for and involved in decommissioning activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H631A9FFFE04A4D5881AACDF5B18958CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>members of a community that may be affected by the decommissioning activities of that licensee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7F6FE63B937427F8E6923CF780777CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1F22B9BED07041278C25EEB4879C6C8A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decommission</header><text>The term <term>decommission</term> has the meaning given the term in section 50.2 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H278CFE88B6DD490992CE1C18EE882D0C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Licensee</header><text>The term <term>licensee</term> has the meaning given the term in section 50.2 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF7881D04FBF64B948DD16434A25D6A89"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small, rural, or disadvantaged community</header><text>The term <term>small, rural, or disadvantaged community</term> means an area that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD90E6F6FCCBB4B1F9DBE5C0236647510"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a population of fewer than 50,000 individuals; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBAC4B889CA454784A8925DDA142AB679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is disadvantaged with respect to geographic, socioeconomic, public health, or environmental hazard criteria, as determined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H487279B7C113460BA895EF7B00903706"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Short-Term grant program</header><paragraph id="H6DE7AD527D3F46D4851D8B30DE76BA30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of eligible entity</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H476933C82DC346E59D1BB95968E0BD50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State in which a civilian nuclear power plant or nuclear power generation unit, as determined by the Commission, is decommissioned or is in the process of being decommissioned during the 3-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H356C111382A544CE887E2C7A754F2A5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe the land of which contains a civilian nuclear power plant or nuclear power generation unit, as determined by the Commission, that is decommissioned or is in the process of being decommissioned during the 3-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79AFDD7FB7EC4B0B9160C8DD7EB7B549"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall establish a grant program under which the Commission shall award grants to eligible entities to support the activities of community advisory boards.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5B0698CE17B04C539C45F1890364A60D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Commission an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Commission may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18C751C1313345439D10B33488C76222"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph id="H0701A5D14FB34B929369D49FFEF715F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Awarding of subgrants</header><text>An eligible entity shall use a grant awarded under this subsection to make subgrants to community advisory boards for use in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA86050D01FE4652A3FE912B78C8D387"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of subgrants</header><text>A community advisory board may use a subgrant awarded under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HDD458D77C98443689C2C9C35DE208E6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to hire or consult with experts;</text></clause><clause id="HD59B7BA53EEA4C29BAECE992FC45C23B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for administrative costs;</text></clause><clause id="HAAC7D7E469D44231BDC45ABC58241994"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to cover travel expenses;</text></clause><clause id="H798FAADA36344E0C893E6272F11F65B0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for website and social media maintenance;</text></clause><clause id="H9ECDF21B939C45E88725565DBD96353B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for the preparation of annual reports and other communications;</text></clause><clause id="H80794D434E74417685C211023A2BACF6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to contract for services;</text></clause><clause id="H27150B775E254738B7BF8AEB004421FF"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>to reimburse volunteers; and</text></clause><clause id="H18C8CB85045740F6975EADD856A2178A"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to cover other reasonable and necessary expenses of the community advisory board, as determined to be appropriate by the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8904876CF12E4B0E93854A1139A75FD3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><text>The Commission shall establish a formula to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, geographic diversity among grant recipients under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50019DF98D764F07AB84BF58260CFCB8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Commission, to the maximum extent practicable, shall implement the recommendations described in the report submitted to Congress under section 108 of the Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/439">Public Law 115–439</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5577) entitled <quote>Best Practices for Establishment and Operation of Local Community Advisory Boards Associated with Decommissioning Activities at Nuclear Power Plants</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1FBC17B9F4794C2AA5400F2752B02889"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to a subgrant awarded under this subsection, neither the Commission nor an eligible entity may impose a cost-sharing requirement on a community advisory board with respect to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H82FB3EDF3E3643228C0A947FFA620422"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity that is carried out on behalf of, for the benefit of, or to foster communication and information exchange with, a small, rural, or disadvantaged community; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3CFC39D6E62F48488D75ED1EA7CDBA09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any activity of the community advisory board if—</text><clause commented="no" id="HD900C92D2BC14269B33F7EC18CCCA0E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable nuclear power plant or nuclear power generation unit is located in a small, rural, or disadvantaged community; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD65120B3F2254FA9A14A39025D0DCC5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a small, rural, or disadvantaged community may be disproportionately impacted by the applicable decommissioning activities of the licensee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66127B24247B4EB3984A33339BE1D331"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission to carry out this subsection $12,500,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2028, to remain available until the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB839EAA1C95A45878C7FD9011364051E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Long-Term grant program</header><paragraph id="HD46D8F99165E4D4D97D3EDC9CF731B09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H3ACA752628B847DD82A8A34FE9AADF36"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><clause id="H74D27E168C474CD8AC810891EEEDAF84"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State in which a civilian nuclear power plant or nuclear power generation unit, as determined by the Commission, is decommissioned or is in the process of being decommissioned more than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7C99374184343FD9F48C1F174FC8D4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe the land of which contains a civilian nuclear power plant or nuclear power generation unit, as determined by the Commission, that is decommissioned or is in the process of being decommissioned more than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB87EE0C94D6F432F92CCC8375910C9DA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Community Advisory Board Fund established under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H971DF10DF62E4CA3ABB3DAE8353B6053"><enum>(C)</enum><header>PSDAR</header><text>The term <term>PSDAR</term> means a post-shutdown decommissioning activities report submitted to the Commission and affected States under section 50.82(a)(4)(i) of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBEEEC9B819A418C8AE2ADD05FF300EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community Advisory Board Fund</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56608BAC9752491D8090E6F4518567FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the <quote>Community Advisory Board Fund</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB785DE9645C94317B043EAA59E9C1F3C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>Each fiscal year, there shall be deposited in the Fund an amount equal to the total amount collected by the Commission pursuant to the regulations promulgated under paragraph (7) for the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H309EA7839C444D638584298D560CD631"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of fund</header><text>Amounts in the Fund shall be available to the Commission, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, for making grants under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H485E38155CAF49FFB0C750A1F8B8B22C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall establish a grant program under which the Commission shall award grants to eligible entities to support the activities of community advisory boards.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDA00A5B0F6FD49E8A1F22C2A884FECCB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Commission an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Commission may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H928B8E161B7B405EBFE5B0EC8BBB0B18"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph id="H099D2410AE904A02B88D550C55692FC9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Awarding of subgrants</header><text>An eligible entity shall use a grant awarded under this subsection to make subgrants to community advisory boards for use in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F334B59D91F404CB7DB9D7CF8C47A30"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of subgrants</header><text>A community advisory board may use a subgrant awarded under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H6A55BBE4820340C980C2A6326E0D8BDC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to hire or consult with experts;</text></clause><clause id="H7F3F50010E3845268BAA56FA78822E31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for administrative costs;</text></clause><clause id="HE540E3DA64E3427A8C22723E2CAD9E57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to cover travel expenses;</text></clause><clause id="HCED9AD5C177B42FDA0D955D6EFC567D7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for website and social media maintenance;</text></clause><clause id="HA635AAE99FFF4AF6BEA5D342632A33DE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for the preparation of annual reports and other communications;</text></clause><clause id="HA75557AEB4394079A3104B7818782F16"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to contract for services;</text></clause><clause id="HAE858F8436D140E49D7C64E3179B595E"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>to reimburse volunteers; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD32E3F09CDAA40678B018351CF219E33"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to cover other reasonable and necessary expenses of the community advisory board, as determined to be appropriate by the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1B6A238083824739BFC3ED3D8530019A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to a subgrant awarded under this subsection, neither the Commission nor an eligible entity may impose a cost-sharing requirement on a community advisory board with respect to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC524DB19390348A8AC9CE996A1CBA8CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity that is carried out on behalf of, for the benefit of, or to foster communication and information exchange with, a small, rural, or disadvantaged community; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB54D81F110A049929C2BA1E827356D03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any activity of the community advisory board if—</text><clause commented="no" id="H7CAFED01ADEA46AF90839ADE4EB9EF7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable nuclear power plant or nuclear power generation unit is located in a small, rural, or disadvantaged community; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22313E4A377A4D3E952A1BD776CB428C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a small, rural, or disadvantaged community may be disproportionately impacted by the applicable decommissioning activities of the licensee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H389FFA509C6544B1805A84FED4422315"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H729E93D6DD1A4F4290F2FCC53CF5426B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations requiring a licensee submitting to the Commission a PSDAR relating to the decommissioning of a nuclear power plant or a nuclear power generation unit, as determined by the Commission, for which consultation is required under section 113 b. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to certify that the licensee has paid to the Commission for deposit into the Fund—</text><clause commented="no" id="H982252E212334AB6A8FF8492C0F3AAED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a PSDAR relating to the decommissioning of 1 or more nuclear power plants, $500,000 for each of those power plants; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H63B2C7ED4E7849308FCA9BBE79E0CDF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a PSDAR relating to the decommissioning of 1 or more nuclear power generation units, as determined by the Commission, $500,000 for each nuclear power plant in which those units are located.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC6523DA32E44438DB84C9D4D4154A527"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regulations promulgated under subparagraph (A) shall provide that—</text><clause commented="no" id="HD493FF5CD1E5477E9CD946A334B63109"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each subsequent PSDAR relating to a nuclear power plant for which a PSDAR was previously submitted relating to the power plant or any nuclear power generation unit located in the power plant—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HD648C4E5FE3745B5A31F5B1E98DF8E0A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if consultation is required under section 113 b. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 with respect to the subsequent PSDAR or any decommissioning activities relating to the subsequent PSDAR, the licensee submitting the subsequent PSDAR shall certify that the licensee has paid to the Commission for deposit into the Fund $500,000, which shall be in addition to any amounts previously paid to the Commission for deposit into the Fund relating to any previously submitted PSDAR; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HB8896E6259ED49E982A5DEA67B5C4DA3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if consultation under section 113 b. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 is not required with respect to the subsequent PSDAR or any decommissioning activities relating to the subsequent PSDAR, the licensee submitting the subsequent PSDAR shall certify that such consultation is not required;</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF570D0CC32DA4372A4A755FE7FC7C726"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a licensee may pay to the Commission the amounts described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) or in subclause (I) of clause (i) at any time prior to the submission of a PSDAR relating to those amounts; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HAC06F143E16A4684825FB8E31DE30789"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to a merchant power plant, no amounts may be withdrawn from the decommissioning trust fund relating to that merchant power plant for the purpose of paying to the Commission an amount described in—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H89F230578AC34CD496ED77C19E2F8D56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A); or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HABEFD27B4C4D450F930670F42516E1D9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subclause (I) of clause (i).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5C76DB7596A341FDB132DD9DCC917586"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A licensee that has paid to the Commission the amount described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) with respect to a nuclear power plant shall not be required to pay that amount with respect to the same power plant on submission of any subsequent PSDAR relating to the decommissioning of that power plant or any nuclear power generation unit located in that power plant if consultation is not required with respect to that PSDAR or any decommissioning activities relating to that PSDAR under section 113 b. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86305FE63D1E460CA853042568BB3FE4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Commission, to the maximum extent practicable, shall implement the recommendations described in the report submitted to Congress under section 108 of the Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/439">Public Law 115–439</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5577) entitled <quote>Best Practices for Establishment and Operation of Local Community Advisory Boards Associated with Decommissioning Activities at Nuclear Power Plants</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBB8EC238B11C44FC9DADDFF2B9F7EF9A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Assistance for nuclear host communities</header><subsection id="H96937EA0FC3545D6BCB03D62FB53F6E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Section 701(f)(1) of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3231">42 U.S.C. 3231(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2029</quote> and inserting <quote>2034</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5AA9D1A78B14096AAB65227C050A451"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional activities</header><text>Section 209(e)(2)(A) of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3149">42 U.S.C. 3149(e)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including through capacity building and economic resilience activities</quote> after <quote>communities</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA89586BB81F44EEC9A633742818F5A25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Section 204(c) of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3144">42 U.S.C. 3144(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBE28137155A4DE2900C7C358E73E897"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37A482E455004BA9A41E763D1DD3E45E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Certain nuclear host communities</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0122269670074A5B8B4599AC2AE2453F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a grant to a nuclear host community under section 209(e) that is a small, rural, or disadvantaged community, the Federal share of the cost of the project or activity carried out with the grant shall be 100 percent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6732CD2AA079450AB16B3158BE39AD67"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8BED810C483444D8F7AEB814EBC1D20"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Nuclear host community</header><text>The term <term>nuclear host community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 209(e)(1).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H084F2C39CE1043DBBA43CA65406B8955"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Small, rural, or disadvantaged community</header><text>The term <term>small, rural, or disadvantaged community</term> means an area that—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D5F3DC0DF9640BE9BE5385132ADFB6C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has a population of fewer than 50,000 individuals; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7B6068A3D8E4B43839BA2CBBF97453F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is disadvantaged with respect to geographic, socioeconomic, public health, or environmental hazard criteria, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H4E1FEA982D814F7EB73BCA215321FE94"><enum>5.</enum><header>Financial assistance for communities with stranded nuclear waste</header><subsection id="H495E837632B74C799585BD79B254B5FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B1BD51FDADB48FF9C23C880D3B1AFA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affected community</header><text>The term <term>affected community</term> means a unit of local government, including a county, city, town, village, school district, or special district, that contains stranded nuclear waste within the boundaries of the unit of local government, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H73971F6954EC4B12A46D5E796C2F3F6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible civilian nuclear power plant</header><text>The term <term>eligible civilian nuclear power plant</term> means a nuclear power plant that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C92628239FA4C0F9B12E06F2E9A8B5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been decommissioned; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6BCB517307F54335A61779C03E2CB28A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is in the process of being decommissioned.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17D5B51A3B954893BBC812AE1B76B3B2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12085ED1AA884EDDADE5B553722E7E34"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Stranded nuclear waste</header><text>The term <term>stranded nuclear waste</term> means nuclear waste or spent nuclear fuel stored in dry casks or spent fuel pools at a decommissioned or decommissioning nuclear facility.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEE87878AA4949ECA88EC7749D0C4A22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish and carry out a noncompetitive grant program to provide financial assistance to units of local government within the jurisdictional boundary of which an eligible civilian nuclear power plant is located to offset the economic and social impacts of stranded nuclear waste in affected communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8B4784AB8621416387709E1AA892A7E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A unit of local government that is an affected community shall be eligible to receive a grant under this section for a fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE73D4C556DEC4FE693AACA91828715A3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Awards</header><paragraph id="H7DF1905203C9490F82CC91D3075A695F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of a grant awarded under subsection (b) shall be equal to $15 for each kilogram of spent nuclear fuel stored at the eligible civilian nuclear power plant in the affected community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D580885E534933B7B5DB175D07B8BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number and frequency</header><text>With respect to each eligible civilian nuclear power plant, the Secretary may only award 1 grant under subsection (b) to each eligible unit of local government for each fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04443C4DCCF248929C3CCC5168C0993C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H59B43DD472C64BD8B56C6B7EF0B15EFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2035.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DF69A03F1114BE0A922C517793A9D99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No offset</header><text>None of the funds made available under this subsection may be used to offset the funding for any other Federal program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8995737C6AE847298DACA665090C879A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Economic development in host communities</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FD1C34D23724D50803FE924A834B21A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H35FC1E6470D64F57BBFDC15004F7321F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification of permanent cessation of operations</header><text>The term <term>certification of permanent cessation of operations</term> means a written certification of the determination of a licensee to permanently cease operations of a civilian nuclear power plant required to be submitted to the Commission under section 50.82 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38616F3F53924D09AB0F6564EE69AD1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H393ADF9C792A4A40BD22E188140CB7AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means a civilian nuclear power plant for which decommissioning activities will be carried out after the date of enactment of this Act, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA023964755E416F8DF389F9EC710977"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">new and existing civilian nuclear power plants for which decommissioning activities have not begun as of that date of enactment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA31908692298495FB38D97677FE79C1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>existing civilian nuclear power plants for which decommissioning activities have begun as of that date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED247DCE4DEB4191959F01439DE1F369"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Decommission</header><text>The term <term>decommission</term> has the meaning given the term in section 50.2 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H196F216DDA7545DEBFA5CF59F9278CF1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Host community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>host community</term> means a State, unit of Tribal government, or unit of local government, including a county, city, town, village, school district, or special district, that contains a decommissioning civilian nuclear power plant within the boundaries of the State, unit of Tribal government, or unit of local government, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AE93F3435664D46A650B4A32B1FA346"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Host community economic recovery account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>host community economic recovery account</term> means a host community economic recovery account established by the Secretary under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA50720685F748A8803CB776177D16EE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Licensee</header><text>The term <term>licensee</term> has the meaning given the term in section 50.2 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H661B11381F224308841BEFC4FE8576C4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Nuclear decommissioning trust</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nuclear decommissioning trust</term> means a nuclear plant decommissioning trust fund described in section 35.32 of title 18, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDD9D527E6834865883AD1D85C0341DA"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB606A2CD96604DA984DAE63C07D83DD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Host community economic recovery accounts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0865CA5FEAD447386E5AF32B6A51D9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each covered facility, the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish in the Treasury of the United States an account, to be known as a <quote>host community economic recovery account</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DE721B9BD0946B7BA389B073519CED9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Each host community economic recovery account shall be administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0D623D39A2E47649CC898C5B1B5C5D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAEB27525899452DB9469D3EEB79FCB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, each licensee of a covered facility shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB750C8DC56B74D0CAC738EEA1A907965"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if a nuclear decommissioning trust has been established for the covered facility, transfer to the Secretary, from that nuclear decommissioning trust, an amount sufficient to ensure that the balance of the host community economic recovery account relating to that covered facility is not less than 2 percent of the sum obtained by adding—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE29BA9CF0544353982C3DBF4CF05413"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the balance of that nuclear decommissioning trust; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE29D8B7B7FBB4F50A57B887AA6BA9683"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the balance of that host community economic recovery account; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6356A85966E3497E926CAE774FF1D505"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if a nuclear decommissioning trust has not been established for the covered facility, transfer to the Secretary an amount sufficient to ensure that the balance of the host community economic recovery account relating to that covered facility is not less than 2 percent of the greater of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63D3C60BDB24493CA0173EA7F2EEFF47"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sum obtained by adding—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECBA65C988D24AE1BCAF03FECA876D9B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of financial assurance for decommissioning of that covered facility provided by the licensee using a method other than a nuclear decommissioning trust; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBFAE4FF37A842D68FE112C535B71C19"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the balance of that host community economic recovery account; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFB7CB4C34E5403B99104FBA9E53C746"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the sum obtained by adding—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DBCAA37E45F421B8B5ED9625D10E30D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable minimum amount determined under section 50.75(c) of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), for the covered facility; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA56B8B9ACF2E469DA25CE50EB0D748C6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the balance of that host community economic recovery account.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89A2668852974999AA0560A749C56DF7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Any amounts distributed by the Secretary to host communities under subsection (c)(1) from a host community recovery account shall be considered to be part of the balance of that host community recovery account for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B9E325E83DF4C4586128F4197A4BE36"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Secretary under paragraph (3) shall be deposited in the applicable host community economic recovery account.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF086848F6B7948E4936E57B303251054"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD866B993108242C896E4FDDA9C1CD718"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts deposited in a host community economic recovery account under subsection (b)(4) shall be used by the Secretary to provide grants to host communities within the boundaries of which the applicable covered facility is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF816EE07D57E4EA38868432CF9B2D001"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Economic development</header><text>Amounts provided to a host community under paragraph (1) shall be used for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DC20D2D949A4BD1990DADBFBDD54F10"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">economic development planning (as defined by the Secretary); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE93BA0EC71249E987F5FBB8C4B61CAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carrying out a comprehensive economic development strategy (as defined in section 3 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3122">42 U.S.C. 3122</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6021247D08F149E18A3C9DF62FD0BC7C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F23A57E5CF44C60AD4B92506C8E9564"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts deposited in a host community economic recovery account under subsection (b)(4) shall be available to the Secretary without appropriation or fiscal year limitation for providing grants in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7067FA40C19B48E4893A550B0F34ACBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall begin the process for making grants to applicable host communities under subsection (c)(1) not later than the earlier of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DD12AAD07304A849009C9EB9C61B208"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 5 years before scheduled shutdown of the applicable covered facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85567B51B527466F80F38C2A0B42DFB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the applicable licensee submits to the Commission a certification of permanent cessation of operations with respect to the applicable covered facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACCF9054318C4C75BB600851FB244788"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may not impose a cost-sharing requirement with respect to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EA2F56F31CE49AC80CD864E335010FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a grant provided under subsection (c)(1) to a host community that is a small, rural, or disadvantaged community (as defined in section 4(a)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD259F99DB4494DE8A2057D7AE0DAAEB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any activity carried out by, or for the benefit of, a small, rural, or disadvantaged community (as so defined) using a grant provided under that subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD142F508368462FBA1CE1C60CC48CBA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certain covered facilities</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C548A3665074A2BBE310A1B635C3907"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of currently decommissioning facility</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>currently decommissioning facility</term> means a covered facility for which decommissioning activities have begun as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1725AEE129841EE985BD98DE121BE2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding of host community economic recovery accounts</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, each licensee of a currently decommissioning facility shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02FD92E01C824BC29E0CAA12362CDD71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if a nuclear decommissioning trust has been established for the currently decommissioning facility, transfer to the Secretary, from that nuclear decommissioning trust, an amount equal to 2 percent of the balance of that nuclear decommissioning trust as of that date of enactment for deposit in accordance with subsection (b)(4); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF0F82AE1C9049FA8163A6B9012D55C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if a nuclear decommissioning trust has not been established for the currently decommissioning facility, transfer to the Secretary, for deposit in accordance with subsection (b)(4), an amount equal to 2 percent of the greater of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF93F2BE9F0D84C03A245D172974C7E4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of financial assurance for decommissioning of that covered facility provided by the licensee using a method other than a nuclear decommissioning trust as of that date of enactment; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13041B84CA4E45EF8AE76ECD04DBCCE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable minimum amount determined under section 50.75(c) of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), for the covered facility as of that date of enactment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4BB3D02C5DD4B5FB247AAA226965616"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>With respect to a currently decommissioning facility, the Secretary shall begin the process for making grants to applicable host communities under subsection (c)(1) not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD0E38015B684A46AE2C2BD7F13C51CB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (b)(3) and (d)(2) shall not apply in the case of a currently decommissioning facility.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EC80A240AE5442CA97988E9F9FC9FF0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall revise such regulations as are necessary (including, if applicable, section 50.75(c) of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations) to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that nuclear decommissioning trusts will contain sufficient amounts to carry out this section without compromising the ability of the nuclear decommissioning trust to fund other legitimate decommissioning activities.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

