<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26618-10G-8K-Y6G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 765 ATS: Expressing support for the designation of July 2026 as “National Sarcoma Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 765</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of July 2026 as <quote>National Sarcoma Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas sarcoma is a rare cancer of the bones or connective tissues, such as nerves, muscles, joints, fat, and blood vessels, that can arise nearly anywhere in the body;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States—</text><paragraph id="id12507d2cbd814621812ca50cbea48ab1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>about 18,000 individuals are diagnosed with sarcoma each year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b238b3829e3421b88c2dc5e988faef3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>approximately 7,600 individuals die from sarcoma each year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b605758d83c4ef6a825de2c403e6b80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>over 236,000 individuals struggle with sarcoma at any given time;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, each year, about 1 percent of cancers diagnosed in adults and around 21 percent of cancers diagnosed in children are sarcoma;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 100 subtypes of sarcoma have been identified;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the potential causes of sarcoma are not well understood;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas treatment for sarcoma can include surgery, radiation therapy, or chemotherapy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sarcoma is often misdiagnosed and underreported; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas July 2026 would be an appropriate month to designate as National Sarcoma Awareness Month—</text><paragraph id="idae19a7e0fd7c4786a96a9565a9af8e01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to raise awareness about sarcoma; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31e43575f52c4742ba88c7dbf9885329"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to encourage more individuals in the United States to get properly diagnosed and treated: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate supports the designation of July 2026 as <quote>National Sarcoma Awareness Month</quote>.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

