<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H5680A307A7D940249F80F13527B87DFE">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7068 IH: No Convicts Running the Capital Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7068</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the District of Columbia government from appointing individuals convicted of crimes of violence or dangerous crimes as employees of the government or from entering into contracts with vendors who employ individuals convicted of crimes of violence or dangerous crimes, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H46CB5C712A41463FBDFBC6DD7E0593A0">
<section id="HEE087F304FDA4EA19726C19175CF6214" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Convicts Running the Capital Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCEB41C4CB1384517BD1FD40D4D647CBB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting employment with district of columbia government of individuals convicted of violent crimes</header> <subsection id="H0A7552A8D25C4C8782C34B30761AA9DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An employing authority of an office of the District of Columbia government may not appoint an individual to a position in the District of Columbia government unless the individual certifies that the individual has not been finally convicted of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H43C852218551468BB8AABEA55F501A0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date; termination of current employees</header>
<paragraph id="HA45C2A7303B04C49A11764B960439BD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to an individual appointed to a position in the District of Columbia government after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H980BAC0E40A74DBBAE3BBDC4F9D98634"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Termination</header> <text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the District of Columbia shall terminate the employment of any individual who has been finally convicted of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime who holds a position in the District of Columbia government on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H88D3B72C53474457ACEC0FFECEC5ECDC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting district of columbia government from entering into contracts with vendors employing individuals convicted of violent crimes</header>
<subsection id="HE866271CF55C49B6ACE68B438AB3BC96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An office of the District of Columbia government may not enter into a contract with a vendor for the provision of goods or services unless the vendor certifies that the vendor is not a covered vendor.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFD19125F2925423D9DEB78A2FDE4DC15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered vendor defined</header><text>In this section, a vendor is a <quote>covered vendor</quote> with respect to a contract if either of the following applies:</text>
<paragraph id="HCD4302C633874DBA99642CEB21A712AC">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>In the case of a vendor who is an individual, the vendor has been finally convicted of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime.</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H91CE96CA9F8540559B7C3DB22303C646"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of a vendor who is an entity—</text> <subparagraph id="HE3A9419126FD463782E0B80E503E4CBD"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the vendor employs an individual who has been finally convicted of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime to provide goods or services under the contract;</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H682676742E46402FB595F0398B0866E6">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>an individual who has been finally convicted of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime serves as an officer or director of the vendor, including by serving on the vendor’s board of directors; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9D2746CF4354443AB9C07034BB114247">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>an individual who has been finally convicted of a crime of violence or a dangerous crime has a controlling ownership interest in the vendor.</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1A7230ACF8B64E11BE6980C264FDEDD1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date; termination of current contracts</header>
<paragraph id="H93D8C3405A934F468499332A2D59E1DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to contracts entered into after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FB1824DACA142239C4741B7483C4B3F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the District of Columbia shall terminate any contract with a vendor who is a covered vendor which is in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HE85F6B26400E4BD886D00365CD77E6FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H84D3413F149346DEA11DC2EDB4E957DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>crime of violence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 23–1331(4), District of Columbia Official Code, except that such term includes an offense under Federal, State, or local law which is substantially similar to an offense described in such section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33E24490B9D34D669BA08A911CE7BF5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>dangerous crime</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 23–1331(3), District of Columbia Official Code, except that such term includes an offense under Federal, State, or local law which is substantially similar to an offense described in such section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A9EADBFBFF94D32A8B120252BF0B8CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>finally convicted</quote> means a conviction—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5AC85D03168E4F87B67B99C98196667E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which has not been appealed and is no longer appealable because the time for taking an appeal has expired; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA53706BF09F343E2B6A771CDF261A3BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which has been appealed and the appeals process for which is completed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

