<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL26270-0VP-LH-VPF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4833 IS: No Robot Bosses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4833</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit certain uses of automated decision systems by employers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6D9AC8B28C214961A9C2226125C3D06A"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Robot Bosses Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD3C9E770263A405B93E58DD72A7AFEEA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="id34c81add0c4149cf8301806fff82c21e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adverse work action</header><text>The term <term>adverse work action</term>, with respect to a covered individual, means a change by the employer of the covered individual in the compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of the job of the covered individual that puts the covered individual in a materially adverse position than prior to the change, including a termination, reduction in benefits, disciplinary action, demotion, transfer, imposition of a work schedule more burdensome to the covered individual, reduction of scheduled hours, adjustment in the ability for a promotion, or other modifications to the compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of the job of the covered individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0656172777fb44f4b827de342ecb644f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term>, with respect to an employer, means an individual who applies, or applied, to be employed by, or otherwise perform work for remuneration for, the employer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb38b1c2a7c77422eaf2bd1db9280cfd9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Automated decision system</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id854079bfe978471fa65fc79b58d9e431"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>automated decision system</term> means any system, software, or process (including one derived from machine learning, statistics, or other data processing or artificial intelligence techniques and excluding passive computing infrastructure) that uses computation to produce a prediction, score, ranking, recommendation, decision, evaluation, metric, conclusion, inference, or profile.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7581863ce744d0d89b884a316e7d325"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Passive computing infrastructure</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>passive computing infrastructure</term> means any intermediary technology that does not influence or determine the outcome of a decision, make or aid in a decision (including through evaluations, metrics, or scoring), inform policy implementation, or collect data or observations, including web hosting, domain registration, networking, caching, data storage, or cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEB684E588A104130A3DB094074CEAA62"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term>, with respect to an employer, means an individual—</text><subparagraph id="id37D96B33BB0C4059ABB272F936127759"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is employed by, or otherwise performs work for remuneration for, the employer, including such an individual who is—</text><clause id="id3b5021013e8f4e6cb64d0a3042763d5d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employer described in clauses (i)(I) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A);</text></clause><clause id="id33b60316436d4429844a7c7efa5ff7f5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an entity described in clauses (i)(II) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A);</text></clause><clause id="id94d2296c53f549079b13e62b93ed3d0a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing office described in clauses (i)(III) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A);</text></clause><clause id="id83ecf24959e84aff8b01438eab8edd21"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing office described in clauses (i)(IV) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A); or</text></clause><clause id="iddbce838f9b5242738d63434f20719b6a"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing agency described in clauses (i)(V) and (ii) of paragraph (9)(A) who is not covered under clause (iv); or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1D9D5698D3874D439B289EF3C8BA662C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is an applicant with respect to the employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddde96d91c64f4f8eab21e27bd77bb81b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Developer</header><subparagraph id="id2674ca27889142178b3a76a8ff5e32b2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>developer</term>, with respect to an automated decision system that is intended or reasonably likely to be used by an employer to make a work-related decision, means any person that designs, codes, customizes, produces, or substantially modifies the automated decision system, including such a person that is the employer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc147556874c64f8cb1cd88ba8ced86cf" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assumption of responsibility by employer</header><text>If an employer assumes the responsibility of a person that would otherwise be a developer of an automated decision system as described in section 5(b)(2)(B), the person shall not be considered a developer for purposes of the use by the employer of the automated decision system and the employer shall be considered a developer for such purposes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56fca12f439f4a188865ec88825dc047"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Subparagraph (A) or (B) shall not be interpreted to mean that an employer may not also be a developer described in such subparagraph or that such a developer may not also be an employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e93a78e74ff4d7eac5068c76ccf1aec"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Fairness and Transparency Office established under section 6.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d582106110f4242a0ffcfa9c8ee56b1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Disparate impact</header><subparagraph id="idad938789c0de47e78746474a7fd1c6e3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>disparate impact</term> means an unjustified differential effect on an individual or group of individuals on the basis of an actual or perceived protected characteristic.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2ea4cf21e8e4100b90923c402b705c3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unjustified differential effect</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), with respect to the action, policy, or practice of an employer, a differential effect is unjustified if—</text><clause id="id76ed71ecd50a4e91bf8e02774e00a95f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the developer or employer fails to demonstrate that such action, policy, or practice causing the differential effect is necessary to achieve a substantial, legitimate, and nondiscriminatory interest; or</text></clause><clause id="idf5c4f841318f4226b6c129b5cf2c5389"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the event the employer demonstrates such interest, an alternative action, policy, or practice could serve such interest with less differential effect.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf335efa230c468f909a6a2210de294e"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to automated decision system</header><text>With respect to demonstrating that an automated decision system causes or contributes to a differential effect, the automated decision system is presumed to be not separable for analysis and may be analyzed holistically as a single action, policy, or practice, unless the developer or employer proves that the automated decision system is separable by a preponderance of the evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1660f307a86e4bd1b57420e8f93feff7"><enum>(8)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Egregious misconduct</header><text>The term <term>egregious misconduct</term>, with respect to a covered individual, means deliberate or grossly negligent conduct that endangers the safety or well-being of the covered individual, co-workers of the covered individual, customers, or other persons, including discrimination against or harassment of co-workers, customers, or other persons.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id52DE8F95220A4909BC8C71D2F560B0D4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Employer</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="idDCEADEFEB2C2440BB909A03FDE3ECFFB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means any person who is—</text><clause id="id7625abce42354696ac52ed7fefa9f666"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id63BE6B3208784208B41D2485D5328CEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a covered employer who is not described in any other subclause of this clause;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6FBEE878227A4886A956F6EC9FB0408A" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an entity employing a State employee described in section 304(a) of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16c(a));</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="idCA6AA11ADF7E434BA514D2EB1E1FC9D7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an employing office, as defined in section 101 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="id26AF651F9A9B495E9EEA25E00CCEB036"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an employing office, as defined in section 411(c) of title 3, United States Code; or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="idFCD0C25611A8421EBDD969442E79FB02"><enum>(V)</enum><text>an employing agency covered under subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id8526c67a569f4303baaa0055ac0148fe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engaged in commerce (including government), or an industry or activity affecting commerce (including government).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0F43B7A4BBE14BA1B7A2D2D958C2E3E0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered employer</header><text>In subparagraph (A), the term <term>covered employer</term>—</text><clause commented="no" id="ide41b02e0943343fbaaef18b78743dadf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means any person engaged in commerce or in any industry or activity affecting commerce who employs, or otherwise engages for the performance of work for remuneration, 11 or more covered individuals;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id7cac9097436744db83ac1e3969e17498"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes—</text><subclause commented="no" id="id412a140c0f8d499ab619ee30d529e248"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any person who acts, directly or indirectly, in the interest of a covered employer in relation to any individual performing work for remuneration for such covered employer;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id04925216ee16421a93cd8ded2f9312d4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any successor in interest of a covered employer;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id957DF676370946D1AA499A4B4E669A79"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any public agency; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id124E5DF62AA345D89DED7CF572E0A658"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="idD8CC4D0448DD4DF992D6262E9BC95F16"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include any labor organization or worker advocacy organization (other than when a labor organization or worker advocacy organization is acting as an employer) or anyone acting in the capacity of officer or agent of such labor organization or worker advocacy organization.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ideedacf5630a245389ae2ffa750bbe59b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public agency</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, a public agency shall be considered to be a person engaged in commerce or in an industry or activity affecting commerce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id65c95a3ef78b403b96a52c72e1fdc8bf"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <term>commerce</term>, <term>person</term>, and <term>public agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id07974F1A45B048F9BDDDE19879D82F92"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Government entity</header><text>The term <term>government entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6BB8AA8AE0854FC88A2757A0035C4AB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal agency (as such term is defined in section 3371 of title 5, United States Code);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id2BDF886BAECA46348FAEB2B073066911"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State or political subdivision thereof;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE9DAC4B7DF5740B18A2C367CBA86B047"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any agency, authority, or instrumentality of a State or political subdivision thereof; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD2266693AB004D0BAB4763ACC0805918"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Tribal government or political subdivision thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id59C14089F9714408ACEDB81BAF0CBDEF"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this Act pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfefc4c012a294934b6b4e81eac172b6c"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2(5) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152(5)</external-xref>), except that such term shall also include—</text><subparagraph id="id7ea76995bd8047bdb244210ebbe73361"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any organization composed of labor organizations, such as a labor union federation or a State or municipal labor body; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3e06276302c4ec28506f2fe2a737b8b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any organization which would be included in the definition for such term under such section 2(5) but for the fact that the organization represents—</text><clause id="id502828e396d34b99a22fc3ddeb7f1269"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals employed by the United States, any wholly owned Government corporation, any Federal Reserve Bank, or any State or political subdivision thereof;</text></clause><clause id="idca16c8f1844847848ef92a67797f4841"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals employed by persons subject to the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="id4ba3980256b64e048abdcfcfed6f492d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individuals employed as agricultural laborers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id33bf1d267a634d97917ed3f4fbb9c9ab"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Personal data</header><text>The term <term>personal data</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id37704da1a104493baeee245883ed3bc7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means information that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable, alone or in combination with other information, to an individual or an individual’s device; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e8c24cc5825477a872a6c3d1357f0d9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes derived data and unique persistent identifiers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc41e059ccc6c4bbaa893af6d70e6c276"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Predispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddac618e65524418ca9aadc0a60a35984"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Predispute joint-action waiver</header><text>The term <term>predispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement, whether or not part of a predispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3676adb2339143db866725ce6e98e9f1"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Protected characteristic</header><text>The term <term>protected characteristic</term> means any of the following actual or perceived traits of an individual or group of individuals:</text><subparagraph id="id156b66fa8d3d46d885bed64c4627732d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Race.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide79da17034f84f39ab098e8be0c588c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Color.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79ad1d98b49c48b2a9474bb3b00692d1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Ethnicity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9de9e3af73e048a7b8ead1e49cbc9097"><enum>(D)</enum><text>National origin, nationality, or immigration status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0343d84da78b47b6b72caf2f9899af3e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Religion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b7d0a345fb848f780d9f3a79b7d9ce5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Sex (including a sex stereotype, pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition, sexual orientation or gender identity, and sex characteristics, including intersex traits).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28947a52a12245918884227814587b55"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Disability.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd06541d8fe2c43fca62563ba4b49d3f5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Limited English proficiency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd9bf353678945d3a120eb23f2ebcb85"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Biometric information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide713b8aa4b2f49afa884bb176eca0162"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Familial or marital status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id741bee14f0f04c6fa3e88d18d2e5fb79"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Source of income.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc6d99bc12b34fb7aaeb6f0d598760fa"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Income level (not including the ability to pay for a specific good or service being offered).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfbc1390d0ec4497594a7de3454013387"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Age.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41d3df6de43a4db3abff28dc20001ded"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Veteran status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida2c813ee39004bc6a62dbd51b1e67d41"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Genetic information or medical conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa6ade856f3444558d08ab109c6ccb7c"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Any other classification protected by Federal law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idBEFEBA6A2FEB433B832317E85DDB2075"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5AD14963AC77419987FD1EFC1BA915CF"><enum>(18)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEC451172510B4B8FA0707C2A88745A97"><enum>(19)</enum><header>State attorney general</header><text>The term <term>State attorney general</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idB5B69B8DBB2F4540B7AA52BFDC7F6E73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a State, the attorney general or chief law enforcement officer of the State, or another official or agency designated by the State to bring civil actions on behalf of the State or the residents of the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id97B799C057FB48898254E644CCAE3C58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a Tribal government, the attorney general or chief law enforcement officer of the Tribal government, or another official or agency designated by the Tribal government to bring civil actions on behalf of the Tribal government or the Indian Tribe of the Tribal government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idB06DD2C4658140EC8CFFEB084BCB4F54"><enum>(20)</enum><header>State privacy regulator</header><text>The term <term>State privacy regulator</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id1e72aeafabb24018baca14a0bf238af7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chief consumer protection officer of a State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a2028f214394d0681220d902442edf5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State consumer protection agency with expertise in data protection, including the California Privacy Protection Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddff0eb628fef4fc59bd3c12e5a89d989"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4D11C0ECEFF0433A9BF2F764600CE2AF"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Work-related decision</header><text>The term <term>work-related decision</term> includes a decision by an employer with regard to—</text><subparagraph id="idfae9d96ee0d44bf5958a5479cc35c631"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hiring or engaging a covered individual (including any decision with regard to recruiting, screening, interviewing, reviewing, or selecting an applicant);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida460a9022bb940b3a9ee516a30ac033b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>firing, retaining, taking a disciplinary action against, demoting, deactivating, or reassigning duties of a covered individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC8A0C11634244EE08266E91B722FB0DE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other term, condition, or privilege of employment or other work of the covered individual, such as relating to wages, wage setting, work hours, scheduling, attendance requirements, workload, performance standards, assignment of work, access to work and training opportunities, productivity requirements, promotion, workplace health and safety, health care or long-term care coverage, or other benefits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id1A7100682A724CA4A9F86E73D73E47E3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of an automated decision system by an employer</header><subsection id="idBDA5987540AC46D5B9C5906F6DC0CCA2"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Work-Related decisions</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd22454fd237747d3a5c8ee9ce85e19cf"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id721351D3A976409FABCF0376361581A6">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>may not rely predominantly on an automated decision system in making a work-related decision with respect to a covered individual; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idf81d459b722a4c60a21ba73335e846a9">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>may not use an automated decision system in a manner that would—</text> <clause id="id05b71c37c2b04417bd0a742e01021f29"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>prevent compliance with, or result in a violation of, any Federal, State, or local labor, occupational safety and health, employment, or civil rights law, including regulation;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id679ff3a4c07142769fec62c87e31a361">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>prevent compliance with any right of a covered individual to reasonable accommodations or nondiscrimination as required by Federal, State, or local law; or</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id4d6e14ce3cc94562a1b3253ed7e60d27">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>prevent or discourage a covered individual from exercising any right under the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) or any similar rights under any other Federal, State, or local law.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="idf203aeaabcd747f3bdf844599ab78d39">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Disclosures</header>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id8f771b8eb7ee4959a0b27cbd216d369d">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer that uses or intends to use an automated decision system in making a work-related decision with respect to a covered individual shall, in accordance with subparagraph (B), disclose to such covered individual—</text>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="idf62c64dc70994ccbbcbf9a4fc2d5da6a">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the employer uses or intends to use an automated decision system in making such a work-related decision;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="idc0d1ad0257b3426a901c467ef8a85e57">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description and explanation of the automated decision system, including—</text>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="idaba5c28a157c4bd3b98f734b359ba039">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the types of data collected or intended to be collected as inputs to the automated decision system and the circumstances of such collection;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id0cd1c71a377d447ebaba4a10c6e0bb3d">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the characteristics that the automated decision system measures or is intended to measure, such as the knowledge, skills, or abilities of the covered individual;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="idb4d83cecf5b14951a651b2f8cf0a61ca">
                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such characteristics relate or would relate to any function required for the work or potential work of the covered individual;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="idbe5b64fd73104e73882692b9e11e50a8">
                <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the system measures or is intended to measure such characteristics;</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="id501ab215819549589c87a9be861de9a3">
                <enum>(V)</enum>
 <text>any performance standards or metrics used as inputs or produced as outputs of the automated decision system; and</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="idadaace0b36134ae9889b2d47c6ca0115">
                <enum>(VI)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the covered individual can interpret the output of such automated decision system in plain language;</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id7570c01971e2418689ec861c3d7458df">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the identity of the individual or entity that operates the automated decision system;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="idb01c2cd11ae043e190c34a894e3316c5">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the employer uses or intends to use such an automated decision system in making such a work-related decision;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id1a80ac1f0e324f45928a330198eee600">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>how the covered individual may dispute or appeal a work-related decision made with respect to the covered individual using an automated decision system; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="idd31ce7dcf5b64cbcbbbe9e295bfd4f36">
              <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>the trade name of the automated decision system.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id1836bfd760444b96935e1c974ab3f58e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Timing of disclosures</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6bb7d8ee97ca41b9ab06c84076ae095a"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Disclosures with regard to hiring and processing applications</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69851f43ef2d40e0816c9d41b421cdc0"> <enum>(I)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer shall provide a disclosure required under subparagraph (A) to the covered individual—</text>
                <item id="id764B1B8635C5441EAD7F0E7BF12FBC50">
                  <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a covered individual for whom a work-related decision with regard to the hiring of the covered individual—</text>
                  <subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id95ed5b61f70d49a1a03da82e9a46b1da">
                    <enum>(AA)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was made on or after the date that is 5 years prior to the date of enactment of this Act, but before such date of enactment, not later than 30 days after such date of enactment; or</text>
                  </subitem>
                  <subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id645213beb720448eae62e0b710db1b31">
                    <enum>(BB)</enum>
 <text>except as provided in item (bb), is made on or after the date of enactment of this Act, prior to making such work-related decision; and</text>
                  </subitem>
                </item>
                <item id="id8801172F7ADF4A6EA24A72ABA6618B61">
                  <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>in the case of an applicant who applies to the employer on or after the date of enactment of this Act, prior to processing an application by the applicant to be employed by, or otherwise perform work for remuneration for, the employer.</text>
                </item>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="ida3c4b28852eb46f9a69165a6ec06e576">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <header>Employers needing information for prior work-related decisions</header>
 <text>With respect to a disclosure described in subclause (I)(aa)(AA), in the case of an employer that did not maintain, prior to the date of enactment of this Act, all of the information described in subparagraph (A) required for such a disclosure, the employer shall—</text>
                <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="id0a0da8fbae9149b684442d3e94e95f92">
                  <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the disclosure in accordance with this paragraph with respect to as much information described in subparagraph (A) as the employer did maintain; and</text>
                </item>
                <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="idac1737ccb55e4994b3288a073710c6c2">
                  <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform the covered individual in accordance with such subclause that the employer did not maintain records of the other information required under such subparagraph.</text>
                </item>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="idd1d8fdf6f2e24aad8d94b441d40229ab">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <header>Other disclosures</header>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="idd2493348fbca4c3ba677a7cda1437aa6">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any work-related decision not described in clause (i) that is made on or after the date of enactment of this Act, an employer shall provide the disclosure required under subparagraph (A) prior to making such work-related decision.</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id7cfcca0dc6ed425f8ce23c28cdca7069">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
                <header>Adverse work actions</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding subclause (I), in the case the work-related decision described in such subclause is for an adverse work action against the covered individual, the disclosure described in such subclause shall be required at least 7 days prior to taking the adverse work action.</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause id="iddf19b22dc65a49da8ac19370a63a56ff">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <header>Updated disclosures</header>
 <text>With respect to a covered individual for whom an employer provided a disclosure under subparagraph (A), the employer shall provide the covered individual with an updated disclosure—</text>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id331f0de433cb43b68b45b2bfb99b4f98">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 7 days before implementing changes to practices disclosed under clause (ii) or (iv) of subparagraph (A); or</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="id3d0d4232a4064858a5b7b91d7c20fc5f">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>immediately upon significant new information required to be provided in such a disclosure becoming available.</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id091c50baec524fc881a071ad9dbff76c">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Exceptions</header>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id1c28b679fdd847cab8e087f37c5121eb">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any provision in this paragraph, no disclosure is required under this paragraph for any work-related decision made prior to the date of enactment of this Act, except for such a decision with regard to the hiring of a covered individual that is made not prior to the date that is 5 years before the date of enactment of this Act as described in subparagraph (B)(i)(I)(aa)(AA).</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id9b9b848e051b413ab1d88491b37e58bd">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
              <header>Egregious misconduct</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision in this paragraph, in the case a covered individual engages in egregious misconduct, an employer may issue a disclosure under this paragraph for a work-related decision made by the employer with respect to such egregious misconduct after the employer makes such work-related decision.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id154288adc5ea4924a56989e10207cc7c">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Training</header>
 <text>An employer that uses or intends to use an automated decision system in making a work-related decision with respect to a covered individual shall train any individual or entity that operates the automated decision system on the use of such system, including on—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="idc2a078f72fa54f1f8e2deef3267cb191">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the input information used by such automated decision system;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id94d1616501384527a2ff29ac17b0b350">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appeals process for the output of such an automated decision system;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="ida27d1bf877bd437a8a55eb420862c979">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">potential biases in automated decision systems;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id2f739011ebcd41f7badd0567a5496d4c">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any limitations of the automated decision system, including intended use cases, known performance issues outside of those use cases, and proper interpretation of outputs;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id6da3d0b362054c92abfcee61a3ad1811">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any potential adverse effects to covered individuals due to the automated decision system;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id5b96824305804e3aa3fba03a9d8ff94a">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any potential errors or problems related to the automated decision system; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id58cfc37997cd461bac0171573312f1c8">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examples of inappropriate uses of the automated decision system, such as misinterpretation of outputs or exclusive reliance on outputs to make a decision.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id030eef5c60a34aa3ae9f1c3fef6ae4fa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management by an automated decision system</header><text>An employer that manages a covered individual through an automated decision system shall enable the covered individual to opt out of such management and instead be managed through a human manager who is able to make work-related decisions with respect to the covered individual.</text></subsection><subsection id="idadd36a61eed04c92971f4fcc81a5cdcb"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Applicant opt out</header> <text>An employer shall enable applicants to opt out of having application materials screened, reviewed, or processed by an automated decision system and instead be screened, reviewed, or processed by a human, including in cases in which the employer engages a third party to screen, review, or process application materials.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id2018c2246483407190cd116c0e38c051"><enum>4.</enum><header>Predeployment evaluations and post-deployment impact assessments</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d6d64ad0dbc49a9b5b8723b1d9b32a8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Predeployment evaluations</header><paragraph id="ide4f3563dd14048ce89aed99fb3122359"><enum>(1)</enum><header>For developers</header><text>Before a developer deploys, licenses, or offers an automated decision system (including deploying a material change to a previously deployed automated decision system or a material change made prior to deployment) that is intended or reasonably likely to be used to make a work-related decision, the developer of the automated decision system shall conduct a predeployment evaluation that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3324a2b0aed14ec8b8ae9ec9259de2d1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a detailed review of the automated decision system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c3b0e64439344fbb11bee9b948880f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">results in a report, sufficient for an individual having ordinary skill in the art to understand the functioning, risks, uses, benefits, limitations, and other pertinent attributes of the automated decision system, that includes—</text><clause id="id3841853bc2c741e8a15dbe94a347652b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the automated decision system’s design and methodology, including the inputs the automated decision system is designed to use to produce an output and the outputs the automated decision system is designed to produce for purposes of specific work-related decisions;</text></clause><clause id="id28bb5dffecd24201b826925172f2806a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the automated decision system was created and tested, including—</text><subclause id="id266d4b3710724833bb14a4ff2bc56224"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any metric used to test the performance of the automated decision system;</text></subclause><subclause id="id553bfdb5005a4c8fa3939df7ef14beb1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>defined benchmarks and goals that correspond to such metrics, including whether there was sufficient representation of demographic groups that are reasonably likely to use or be affected by the automated decision system in the data used to create or train the automated decision system, and whether there was reasonable testing, if any, across such demographic groups;</text></subclause><subclause id="id578666ab74f743729428e978087fa5da"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the outputs the automated decision system actually produces in testing;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf00c7c1c82e34af68169ca5b81302444"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a description of any consultation with relevant stakeholders, including covered individuals that will be impacted by the automated decision system, regarding the development of the automated decision system or a disclosure that no such consultation occurred;</text></subclause><subclause id="idb45eeb2ac5164fd1bd685389631c4136"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any computational algorithm incorporated into the development of the automated decision system and a description of the training process for such algorithm including the training, validation, and test data used to confirm the intended outputs; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id5a97b209860f46a5b1f49e47a9fa4fb5"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a description of the data and information used to develop, test, maintain, or update the automated decision system, including—</text><item id="id3d1078003e7948c99e3a520ada19a55b"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>each type of personal data used, each source from which the personal data was collected, and how each type of personal data was inferred and processed;</text></item><item id="idd9c4a8947fbd4ec189bca082f25356e8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the legal authorization for collecting and processing the personal data; and</text></item><item id="ida0ee609b840f483b9e7e338baa661f85"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>an explanation of how the data (including personal data) used is representative, proportional, and appropriate to the development and intended uses of the automated decision system;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id6d0390246466419391c67ac8493f6c8e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf945d40c0b2b4be49dbac1d0cb9b00ca"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential for the automated decision system to pose risks to workers' rights, including with respect to the privacy, physical and mental health and safety, dignity, and autonomy of workers or to result in the chilling of legally protected activity (including organizing and collective bargaining); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0092451f751d4e57b7fc9605cd25207f"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any potential economic impact of the automated decision system on workers, such as with respect to wages, hours, schedules, benefits, skills training, work opportunities, and advancement;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id64b007ef01444aeeb122ec50fa4e3026"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the potential for the automated decision system to discriminate, including by having a disparate impact on the equal enjoyment of goods, services, or other activities or opportunities, and a description of such discrimination; and</text></clause><clause id="idd64d31e218ba4253ab43c0cdbdf5c73a"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>a description of alternative practices and recommendations to prevent or mitigate risks to workers' rights and recommendations for how the developer could monitor for risks to workers' rights after offering, licensing, or deploying the automated decision system.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08d38917e9ea4984a84fbd99ba00371f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>For employers</header><text>Before an employer deploys an automated decision system (including deploying a material change to a previously deployed automated decision system or a material change made prior to deployment) that is intended or reasonably likely to be used to make a work-related decision, the employer shall conduct a predeployment evaluation that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01a91dc15c094026bb5f98af689524b5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a detailed review of the automated decision system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6647ef50eb334134848c6f468e602386"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">results in a report, sufficient for an individual having ordinary skill in the art to understand the functioning, risks, uses, benefits, limitations, and other pertinent attributes of the automated decision system, that includes—</text><clause id="idd27ca257e4d8411c996e5319c318bb0a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the manner in which the automated decision system may be used to make or contribute to a work-related decision and the purpose for which the automated decision system will be deployed;</text></clause><clause id="id2cfa556cd5734b048e1d1076d03b0ad6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the necessity and proportionality of the automated decision system in relation to its planned use, including the intended benefits and limitations of the automated decision system and a description of the baseline process being enhanced or replaced by the automated decision system, if applicable;</text></clause><clause id="idcc80ccc86865494dafdb71877d0f37ff"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the inputs to the automated decision system that the employer plans to use to produce an output, including—</text><subclause id="id106b76f1947f46b28bf18444ad26c6c5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the type of personal data and information used and how the personal data and information will be collected, inferred, and processed;</text></subclause><subclause id="id392fcf364a5041549796dc4bb6cc19ca"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the legal authorization for collecting and processing the personal data; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id9e52e017ec46414fa8491028ca907ccb"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an explanation of how the data used is representative, proportional, and appropriate to the deployment of the automated decision system;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id53e71a7289ce440aa8b0a52abab93725"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the outputs the automated decision system is expected to produce and the outputs the automated decision system actually produces in testing;</text></clause><clause id="idc166909499d5413c8cf215a635b35545"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of any additional testing or training completed by the employer for the context in which the automated decision system will be deployed;</text></clause><clause id="id4c4ec99cd3fd42a2b2d30f2b29753275"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of any consultation with relevant stakeholders, including covered individuals that will be impacted by the automated decision system, regarding the deployment of the automated decision system;</text></clause><clause id="idd17c2acc31ba408193a8d50d3c36c0e4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a description of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e18ab2eeb0542bcad55e7668a504b1d"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential for the automated decision system to pose risks to workers' rights, including with respect to the privacy, physical and mental health and safety, dignity, and autonomy of workers or to result in the chilling of legally protected activity (including organizing and collective bargaining); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2a4efab325f4597a9d34166ccde6175"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any potential economic impact of the automated decision system on workers, such as with respect to wages, hours, schedules, benefits, skills training, work opportunities, and advancement;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idbb8eb9b7c7d6491fa432117efd83f832"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a description of the potential for the automated decision system to discriminate, including by having a disparate impact on the equal enjoyment of goods, services, or other activities or opportunities, and a description of such discrimination; and</text></clause><clause id="id275ebfccd1dc42519a193f909216feb2"> <enum>(ix)</enum> <text>a description of alternative practices and recommendations to prevent or mitigate risks to workers' rights and recommendations for how the employer could monitor for risks to workers' rights after offering, licensing, or deploying the automated decision system.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6dd5d8a3a88490189260064a23b8b80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The requirements for predeployment evaluations under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall only apply with respect to the deployment, licensing, or offering of any automated decision system that occurs on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id003c453e805b45169856b551a3085298"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employer annual impact assessment</header><text>An employer that deploys an automated decision system used to make a work-related decision in any year shall conduct an impact assessment of the automated decision system with respect to the use of such system in such year in accordance with the following:</text><paragraph id="ida156ec19a38f4bcd9cf8c75834b48468"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Impact assessment</header><text>The employer shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f5e04351b164f3ba224331c2200bd45"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a full impact assessment on the automated decision system with respect to the year, including the information described in paragraph (2) as relevant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd200fa837ef14a8b9eb025d20cfc07e3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prepare a report on such assessment, including—</text><clause id="id58b68d8d898f4e94b3a9d5cf528730ef"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which the automated system during the year infringed on the rights of any worker, including with respect to the privacy, physical and mental health and safety, dignity, and autonomy of workers or to result in the chilling of legally protected activity (including organizing and collective bargaining), or had an economic impact on any worker, such as with respect to wages, hours, schedules, benefits, skills training, work opportunities, and advancement;</text></clause><clause id="ida5131e10a4384fd4b87047095415e12e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which the automated decision system produced a disparate impact in the equal enjoyment of goods, services, or other activities or opportunities, including the methodology for such evaluation, of how the automated decision system produced or likely produced such disparity;</text></clause><clause id="idd6c14d340e9d4050a2f8294279b8acdb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the types of data input into the automated decision system during the reporting period to produce an output, including—</text><subclause id="id839a1a9c0b6547a2867af184d6ca054d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>documentation of how data input into the automated decision system to produce an output is represented and complete descriptions of each field of data; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7e5e6f6418ae483ab95165832a119df4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether and to what extent the data input into the automated decision system to produce an output was used to modify the automated decision system;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0f2a96e21e924aa0a14614bed614e817"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>whether and to what extent the automated decision system produced the outputs it was expected to produce; and</text></clause><clause id="ide7db29aec8884bb2be44b96eccf95888"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a detailed description of how the automated decision system was used to make a work-related decision.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf477fb64ea794aa799afba262618c4c4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employers with a deployed automated decision system</header><text>An employer that deployed an automated decision system used to make a work-related decision before the date of enactment of this Act and has not otherwise conducted a predeployment evaluation under subsection (a) or a review under this paragraph with respect to the automated decision system shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32c00a10be50482eb6c26b0ba64146d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a detailed review of the automated decision system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3573467f791458eb3ccd51e54cb68f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include in the first impact assessment of such automated decision system under paragraph (1) a report, sufficient for an individual having ordinary skill in the art to understand the functioning, risks, uses, benefits, limitations, and other pertinent attributes of the automated decision system, that includes—</text><clause id="idf23295be4c664fc3bdbf14389040a3db"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the manner in which the automated decision system may be used to make or contribute to a work-related decision and the purpose for which the automated decision system will be deployed;</text></clause><clause id="id8bbd27bd6c96439892c3a14cef4d164f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the necessity and proportionality of the automated decision system in relation to its planned use, including the intended benefits and limitations of the automated decision system and a description of the baseline process being enhanced or replaced by the automated decision system, if applicable; and</text></clause><clause id="id110080afee074ce784614bf69183df53"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the inputs to the automated decision system that the employer plans to use to produce an output, including—</text><subclause id="id4f0b2d1420ce4f9a87fba07e711a7213"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the type of personal data and information used and how the personal data and information will be collected, inferred, and processed;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8d4fb916534946218fda8236542ce5a0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the legal authorization for collecting and processing the personal data; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id8478b6c9a1934c80b0c293eb2f189754"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an explanation of how the data used is representative, proportional, and appropriate to the deployment of the automated decision system.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8aa117ef9afe45b4b7899a1663fb71ec"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the completion of a report on an impact assessment under paragraph (1)(B), an employer shall submit to the developer of the automated decision system a summary of such report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id17d86204dacf4161a4be65db35e6df9f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Developer annual review of assessments</header><text>A developer of an automated decision system used by an employer in any year to make a work-related decision shall review each impact assessment summary submitted by an employer under subsection (b)(3) with respect to such system in such year for the following:</text><paragraph id="id8598b40b2e0f4228afea34b51e412dac"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To assess how the employer is using the automated decision system, including the methodology for assessing such use.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7edb77ef071b4745a6c9526270e863b0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To assess the type of data the employer is inputting into the automated decision system to produce an output and the types of outputs the automated decision system is producing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0660e970f1464eb19672805bd05538aa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To assess whether the employer is complying with any relevant contractual agreement with the developer and whether any remedial action is necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9caadfd92c914d69be9bd8589b9edb71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To compare the automated decision system’s performance in real-world conditions versus any predeployment testing available, including the methodology used to evaluate such performance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0023f8479b364f0e8ce095a3cc68c0cb"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>To assess whether the automated decision system infringed on workers' rights or is reasonably likely to be infringing on workers' rights.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc8c2e689006e4e629bdf73246147c490"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To assess whether and, if so, how the automated decision system is causing, or is reasonably likely to be causing, a disparate impact in the equal enjoyment of goods, services, or other activities or opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fba9aa5f4f3453e8327c881442649f1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To determine whether the automated decision system needs modification.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21b48ad4b88d4f4eb7f74e3f7578e72c"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To determine whether any other action is appropriate to ensure that the automated decision system remains safe and effective.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7db05c3946374fea8170bb5303cd5d3a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint developer and employer obligations</header><text>If a person is both the developer of an automated decision system and an employer deploying an automated decision system, the person may conduct combined predeployment evaluations and annual assessments, provided that each combined evaluation or assessment satisfies all requirements for both developers and employers.</text></subsection><subsection id="id993b781140934f848b191d36a072c7a0" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relationships between developers and employer</header><text>The developer of an automated decision system shall, upon the reasonable request of an employer using the automated decision system, make available to the employer information necessary for the employer to demonstrate compliance with the requirements of this Act, including—</text><paragraph id="id8f03a0f8194c4f8889034d7f8225e302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>making available to the employer a report on the predeployment evaluation required under subsection (a) or the annual review of assessments conducted by the developer under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a97e074b7b641aa8b8cce787542b687"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing information necessary to enable the employer to conduct and document a predeployment evaluation under subsection (a) or an impact assessment under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3762d8dc9ac2427c9be71566fe8fe8b9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting and retention requirements</header><paragraph id="idfbb2d137358f421b94cb3bfb3f7dbe80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>A developer or employer that conducts a predeployment evaluation, impact assessment, or developer annual review of assessments under this section shall—</text><subparagraph id="ida7bf74d0442845bbadf5c550a9ac255a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after completion of such evaluation, assessment, or review, submit the evaluation, assessment, or review to the Fairness and Transparency Office of the Department of Labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id380e423daa6e45d188ded2e8434cf379"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon request, make the completed evaluation, assessment, or review available to Congress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id830afd3c2e114b73b92d056f1f6c1526"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after such completion—</text><clause id="idac4ad33f04ff48c08ecc23292e024256"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publish a summary of the evaluation, assessment, or review on the website of the developer or employer in a manner that is easily accessible to individuals; and</text></clause><clause id="id01fe82535eb94c46879f39108cd65adc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit such summary to the Fairness and Transparency Office of the Department of Labor.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3a4a128d25a4e97818b5fc9f09f90bc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retention</header><text>A developer or employer shall retain all evaluations, assessments, and reviews conducted under this section for a period of not fewer than 10 years after the completion of the evaluation, assessment, or review.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id809055b957b84e459d46b24bb140a6eb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Trade secrets and privacy</header><text>A developer or employer—</text><subparagraph id="id30d0fb60c2c644cca163ed7a6b1130c1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may redact and segregate any trade secret (as defined in section 1839 of title 18, United States Code) from public disclosure in the summary published and submitted under paragraph (1)(C); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b620003895e452abaf31844ebdcd512"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall redact and segregate personal data from public disclosure in such summary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb74d86e816c34e1f9c45a87bfee760d3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><paragraph id="ide1c6bfe373814158aef2a71a5ccc67f9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Director of the Fairness and Transparency Office of the Department of Labor may, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, promulgate such rules as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad6335500f08461fa05f530c785b96b5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional regulations</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Fairness and Transparency Office shall—</text><subparagraph id="idac1d2373347d4c02ad8ed3979f8f4854"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promulgate rules, pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code, specifying—</text><clause id="idd58250ff76034314a4bf87bb23f38e79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>what information and factors a developer or employer shall consider in making the predeployment evaluation required under subsection (a);</text></clause><clause id="id7d1ad99b23594229a3daada201137579"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>what information a developer or employer shall include in a summary of an evaluation, assessment, or review described in subsection (f)(1)(C); and</text></clause><clause id="idf8892d5080a04e2aa9abf459a4214bc9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the extent to and process by which a developer may request additional information from a employer for purposes of the review under subsection (c), including the purposes for which a developer is permitted to use such additional information; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbd38946691148c1ac2e9d499ffc450c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in promulgating such rules, consider the need to protect the privacy of personal data, as well as the need for information sharing by developers and employers to comply with this section and inform the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3742a3f6b607441bba9956f1441f2b89"><enum>5.</enum><header>Automated decision system standards</header><subsection id="id972dce211c1a44ca949037c168be6aee"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Automated decision system use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A developer of an automated decision system that is intended or reasonably likely to be used to make a work-related decision and each employer using such automated decision system shall—</text><paragraph id="idc6d7336b32604467beed47aacf6896fb"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>take reasonable measures to prevent and mitigate any risks to workers' rights from the automated decision system that are identified by a predeployment evaluation under section 4(a) or an impact assessment under section 4(b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id47cff6d8f7414f16bfd7deae36b4e5e7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult stakeholders, including stakeholders representing any community that will be impacted by the automated decision system, regarding the development or deployment of the automated decision system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9001df3da62e4f8cb7641b294de50c23"><enum>(3)</enum><text>certify to the Director before deploying, licensing, or offering the automated decision system that, based on the results of the predeployment evaluation under section 4(a) or an impact assessment under section 4(b), use of the automated decision system is not likely to result in—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfda1035c7ec349ada03e07891a12d878"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">risk to workers’ rights, including with respect to the privacy, physical and mental health and safety, dignity, and autonomy of workers; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54465b5c963042cb990812ca15b9f6e4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the chilling of legally protected activity (including with respect to organizing and collective bargaining).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id90026a6b93424a9c89ebef68ce95a0a1"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Off-Label use</header> <paragraph id="id0eb601df468943a6bfcdf8814ced4123"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Developers</header> <text>A developer of an automated decision system may not knowingly offer or license the automated decision system for use in producing outputs for purposes of any work-related decision other than those described in the predeployment evaluation under section 4(a).</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id6ac77038eeb1455589a239f5d27f3757">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Employers</header>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id7f2065955fcf461392429b964ea3c386">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an employer may not knowingly use an automated decision system to produce outputs for purposes of a work-related decision other than for purposes of a work-related decision that is described in the predeployment evaluation under such section by the developer of the automated decision system.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id5d5b70c4422f49a2aedf4fe36a87802f">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Assumption of responsibility</header>
 <text>An employer that intends to use an automated decision system to produce an output for purposes of a work-related decision that is not described in the predeployment evaluation under such section by the developer of the automated decision system shall assume the responsibilities of the developer required by this Act (other than with respect to conducting a review of assessments under section 4(c)) with respect to the use by the employer of the automated decision system.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><section id="id33BBE7EBC2214F679D8861D31BEE35ED"><enum>6.</enum><header>Establishment of Fairness and Transparency Office</header><subsection id="idb669648baf504436a1b962a861630188"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor the Fairness and Transparency Office.</text></subsection><subsection id="idac8084fc480f4f158dd89eaac15a7e4e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The President shall appoint a Director of the Fairness and Transparency Office to head the Fairness and Transparency Office.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2e827b325dcd4899b3a3263480fad279"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employees and advisory boards of the Office</header><paragraph id="id6e137cc592d24bc8bedd30a3eb2be35e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director—</text><subparagraph id="id774908e6a2b84a5f8aafc9c57ef89688"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may select, appoint, and employ, without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3318 of title 5, United States Code, individuals, including technologists, directly to positions in the competitive service, as defined in section 2102 of such title, to carry out the duties of the Director under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2156be6ddfc346e087191ba768d29da0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may fix the compensation of the individuals described in subparagraph (A) without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for such individuals may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70d4a59fe5c040319bdd2ddec90f5ac0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory boards</header><subparagraph id="idb168d9efea3241b0a8315e17d1cd6359"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director shall establish advisory boards to advise and consult with in the exercise of the functions of the Director under this Act and to provide information on emerging practices relating to the treatment of data by employers that are the following:</text><clause id="id624e6e5fc6654c62a5d6b5d175d1d1f3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The User Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of experts in consumer protection, privacy, civil rights, disability rights, labor organizations and worker advocacy organizations, and ethics.</text></clause><clause id="id900afa571c69433f882f5757c51b788b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Research Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfadc2483f795472d874d17f4f6d71df4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals with academic and research expertise in privacy, cybersecurity, computer science, innovation, design, ethics, economics, civil rights law, disability law, labor organizations and worker advocacy organizations, and public policy; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc39644a9fae14a9b881d11aeea4f95e9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of labor organizations and worker advocacy organizations.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id05ae207fce11408ba7f4c999c36a204d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Product Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of technologists, computer scientists, designers, product managers, attorneys, representatives of labor organizations and worker advocacy organizations, workplace technology experts, accessibility experts, and other representatives of employers and workers.</text></clause><clause id="idFF44E6C9AA004018A2A07DA32200FADD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Labor Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f311721a7d841b9a66caacfddaf3f02"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of labor organizations and worker advocacy organizations; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b156be43d3e4f6ca74d084208de2f4d"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of workers.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b162965f94a4a469007be88d6c42ef6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appointments</header><text>The Director shall appoint members to the advisory boards established under subparagraph (A) without regard to party affiliation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4bed9501e9f54b1393551d4baa6197c5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Each advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall meet—</text><clause id="idCDA1D57F6E734589B9E6849817D286E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the call of the Director; and</text></clause><clause id="id1483BEDEE31A4230BF07BD54361D347D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 2 times annually.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida215749b1790453f94b0114cf9a972dd"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Compensation and travel expenses</header><text>A member of an advisory board established under subparagraph (A) who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall—</text><clause id="id0e0db434c2c043f99cef81de6abe763b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be entitled to receive compensation at a rate fixed by the Director while attending meetings of the advisory board, including travel time; and</text></clause><clause id="id295c8138c0bc41da9ea2815e7a1fd155"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b1b0a40fb734ee78e1603332eb9b91b"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Exemption from the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>Each advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall be exempt from <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id21544852363f48f3930d7df19144bf10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of voluntary services</header><text>The Director may, as may from time to time be needed, use any voluntary or uncompensated services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id182e56270cd645b5ab54f3b99489a285"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attorneys</header><text>Attorneys appointed under this subsection may appear for and represent the Director in any litigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id85eb8331bc464f3fadc02052539bb7df"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Offices</header><paragraph id="idD593BEF064444FBE9FD82E197A5C226B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The principal office of the Fairness and Transparency Office shall be in the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id756A2E0C2F5C40CDBBFBDE34C7EAF0BC"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Regional, local, and other offices</header> <text>The Director may establish regional, local, or other offices, including an office in the city of San Francisco, California, or the San Francisco Bay area in California.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB39D0827F4D840C89E6032C91A39FE2A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Regulations</header><subsection id="id4266b7490f2b408f965a9d7fc1c0216a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="ide118a5edfd2846178925e5b1ce10b7d6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><subparagraph id="id47FE53D87E084229995DBE1636AAD85A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary, acting through the Director, may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A) (other than covered individuals described in clauses (iii) through (v) of such section) and other individuals affected by employers described in subclause (I) or (II) of section 2(9)(A)(i), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA24BF3D793741F4AE2602C93641EDCE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In prescribing any regulations authorized under this paragraph, the Secretary, acting through the Director, may consult with—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id543ed067e65c4fbb8f084a8d1788c053"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over Federal privacy laws or expertise in privacy, including the Federal Trade Commission;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id184d55ad9dfc4260ac72065f818f6fdf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over labor and employment issues, including the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the National Science Foundation, and the National Labor Relations Board; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf77db70b5594c768ca2da33125da6b5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal agencies with relevant expertise, including the United States Access Board and the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd7fe27b3bbf49db947bbf62d39af1b5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Government accountability office; library of congress</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress shall prescribe any regulations described in paragraph (1)(A) with respect to covered individuals of the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress, respectively, and other individuals affected by the Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide41543ffc01d43a58bd99f7a5e1e6244"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individuals covered by Congressional Accountability Act of 1995</header><paragraph id="ide97f9143b6db47bb8890fee4b82633b4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance shall prescribe (in accordance with section 304 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1384">2 U.S.C. 1384</external-xref>)) such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A)(iii) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(III), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8769b53d183b4c7ead26eda71d0cb0c2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0929d127843e4dab859dce1d383bf8b4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Individuals covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code</header><paragraph id="id7cdf92ae05e545788e78855463f018cf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the President (or the designee of the President) shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A)(iv) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(IV), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d774625562246179bd19bab4cc3c24f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the President (or designee) may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide2686fef37af45808b838fb06256b7fc"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Individuals covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</header><paragraph id="id996dfda29d564530a67b931fa5aca642"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A)(v) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(V), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id420d58b732a9499c8c9d2f72331c3a0c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the Director may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idD3F28D50B800492BA8AE038013789F9F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An employer may not discriminate or retaliate (including through intimidation, threats, coercion, or harassment) against any covered individual of the employer—</text><paragraph id="idF88B4525B0C34CB5A850049EE82A3359"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for exercising, or attempting to exercise, any right provided under this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDBF1DA965B59489BAED401717B865CEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>because the covered individual (or another individual acting at the request of the covered individual) has—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1D0140C0A6ED45ADBF0C58BA8A4AE89C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made a written or oral complaint to the employer or a Federal, State, or local government entity of a violation of section 3;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id3F8D696B18754AF793B4B520F74207C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sought assistance or intervention with respect to a worker privacy-related concern from the employer, a Federal, State, or local government, or a worker representative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id73A794E3E72340B39FF5764BD71CF87A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>instituted, caused to be instituted, or otherwise participated in any inquiry or proceeding under or related to this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idF9B893712CC74D0F8E6CFE0A8E4F48D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>given, or is about to give, any information in connection with any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id2738105B172A4E9298DD49801B6B09F5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>testified, or is about to testify, in any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd340aeb427a14143a2a950512fa4368f"><enum>(F)</enum><text>refused to follow the output of an automated decision system when exercising professional judgement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id926c2da24cec4643a2f2689d71a03988"><enum>9.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="id3803CCE206B04FD4A042F25F8EF1CE3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="id63F44A5C67C6484BB257A54CA7E8CE74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Notwithstanding section 2, for purposes of this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id5B1A3143F83441E193039B8BD441982A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means a covered individual—</text><clause id="id4E9E99247E174DA88AE9D85C06326478"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in section 2(4)(A) (other than covered individuals described in clauses (iii) through (v) of such section); or</text></clause><clause id="idF34FA29183BF460187BEABBAE1C0B995"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id971123DE93624553BC07CF72EFD139C3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means an employer described in subclause (I) or (II) of section 2(9)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5C6F4C68A07A448E997FD874153CED49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Fairness and Transparency Office</header><subparagraph id="id7CED9A15441842EFAC8CDA455C132452"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Investigation</header><clause id="id9C8364A4ABB4482788E29E446B1E98E9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure compliance with the provisions of this Act, or any regulation or order issued under this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Director—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40b90fc8af0642368523301b3cfa1700"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may investigate and gather data regarding the wages, hours, and other conditions and practices of employment (and other work) in any industry subject to this Act, and may enter and inspect any place or record (and make such transcriptions thereof), question any covered individual, and investigate any facts, conditions, practices, or matters as the Secretary may deem necessary or appropriate to determine whether an employer has violated any provision of this Act, or which may aid in the enforcement of the provisions of this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idF78FCB3804404782BE2545F6384009A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may require, by general or special orders, an employer, to file with the Secretary, in such form as the Secretary may prescribe, annual or special reports or answers in writing to specific questions, furnishing to the Secretary such information or records as the Secretary may require as to the organization, business, conduct, practices, management, and relation to other corporations, partnerships, and individuals, of the employer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idA9ABE5A1D976436BA7E3E3D547B1F74E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reports and answers</header><text>An employer shall file the reports and answers (including information and records) required under clause (i)(II) in such manner, including under oath or otherwise, and within such reasonable time period as the Secretary may require.</text></clause><clause id="id3299caec7602499b8ca12260ae531620"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Joint investigations</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, may conduct investigations and make requests for information, as authorized under this Act, on a joint basis with another Federal agency, a State attorney general, or a State agency.</text></clause><clause id="iddbda4d3ae8f845c49d59d8e079ab11f8"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Obligation to keep, preserve, and make available records</header><text>An employer shall make, keep, preserve, and make available to the Secretary records pertaining to compliance with this Act in accordance with section 11(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211(c)</external-xref>) and in accordance with any regulation or order issued by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idB75D04C4F3C1400CB0FF088635E4EA12"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>With respect to employers and covered individuals, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall receive, investigate, and attempt to resolve complaints of violations of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 in the same manner that the Secretary receives, investigates, and attempts to resolve complaints of violations of sections 6 and 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 206 and 207).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35DE192B88874AB0B2C0CB920EFC4056"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Referral for criminal proceedings</header><text>If the Secretary, in the course of the performance of any act or duty under this Act, obtains evidence that any employer has engaged in conduct that may constitute a violation of Federal criminal law, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General for prosecution under any applicable law. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect any other authority of the Secretary to disclose information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55E5549AE8AB45D3865314A7449B8327"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Litigation</header><text>The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary on any litigation brought under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE36BD0C575264B15B632CE615A0AA7E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id996948684CE94378B2E2F4A103750F18"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" id="idA782CD8B63B54220A1376E83C97E4F82"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered individuals</header><text>Notwithstanding any action by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B), any covered individual adversely affected by an alleged violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8, may commence a civil action against any person that violates such section in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id55B8E4E399A34D1EA2594425EA7019AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Labor organizations and worker advocacy organizations</header><text>Notwithstanding any action by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B), any labor organization or worker advocacy organization may, on behalf of a covered individual adversely affected by an alleged violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8, commence a civil action against any person that violates such section in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8535B4E725374DF3ACA31D2D138AA2FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header><clause commented="no" id="id5C78669457074ACA8005773467E05AFF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the covered individual, labor organization, or worker advocacy organization prevails, the court may award the covered individual, labor organization, or worker advocacy organization—</text><subclause commented="no" id="id3740F4027E01430ABEE0EDF7E34BA67C"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>damages of an amount equal to the sum of any actual damages sustained by the covered individual; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idECBE6499A1584F55BBBAE270F0AF79A4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>statutory damages described in clause (iv);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id65B6BCBF07174C439BB8AC9DAECB5157"><enum>(III)</enum><text>injunctive relief; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id9E0B1B9B9BFC4D5AB224E3CA17A7D670"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>equitable relief.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id59A4806153DA406C99E456097E6E4A8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Attorney's fees</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the covered individual, labor organization, or worker advocacy organization prevails, the court shall award the covered individual, labor organization, or worker advocacy organization reasonable attorney's fees and litigation costs.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id7D0E5F3D38A54E80A704B667E9AF0312"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Temporary relief for whistleblowers</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) regarding a violation of section 8, the court may award the covered individual, labor organization, or worker advocacy organization temporary relief while the case is pending, including reinstatement.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id23C487DDBCE14932B82D8495B585E594"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Statutory damages</header><text>The court may, in accordance with clause (v), award statutory damages under clause (i)(II) against a person in the following amounts:</text><subclause commented="no" id="id42E309A893C849CE82E4F6147ACD93DF"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Using an automated decision system for prohibited activities</header><text>For each violation of section 3 by an employer with respect to a covered individual, the court may, subject to clause (vi), award—</text><item commented="no" id="id292F86A64FF8432AADA904325D2D853E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>damages of an amount not less than $5,000 and not more than $20,000; or</text></item><item commented="no" id="id79B6A73569B74A38B909D43C7CB83E29"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for any willful or repeated violation by the employer, damages of an amount not less than $10,000 and not more than $40,000.</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idCCE712037B40498798FC723245285F5A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Retaliation on whistleblowers</header><text>For each violation of section 8, the court may, subject to clause (vi), award—</text><item commented="no" id="idB31D081DE4B841B99A33D4A4B66ECB62"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>damages of an amount not less than $5,000 and not more than $50,000; or</text></item><item commented="no" id="id87E152BB0EF6463FA05CEF705829B60B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for any willful or repeated violation, damages of an amount not less than $10,000 and not more than $100,000.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id343E07F8B0C64E26BB11785A8CE53830"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Considerations for statutory damages</header><text>In determining the amount of statutory damages assessed under clause (iv), the court shall consider any relevant circumstances presented by the parties to the action, including—</text><subclause id="id3CE527F379B54B56B1A7C2B8D653B492"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the nature and seriousness of the violation;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0342C1FF88AB43219F515EC893420A70"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of violations;</text></subclause><subclause id="idBB5E23E1DCA343AF91E42E80E5C73A3D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the persistence of the misconduct;</text></subclause><subclause id="id78C6CEECDF2D4E6C9ED13195100082D2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the length of time over which the misconduct occurred;</text></subclause><subclause id="idAAA5B7FD140046C4922736AD24B382AB"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the willfulness of the misconduct of the employer; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id39E04E76271945119AE561E6C452AFC5"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the assets, liabilities, and net worth of the employer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idc2528e821ccf46459d9d6d85a6f863fc"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text>The dollar amounts referred to subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (iv) shall be increased annually, for fiscal year 2027 and every fiscal year thereafter, by the percent increase, if any, in the consumer price index for all urban consumers for the most recent 12-month period for which applicable data is available.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCED9A93533D2437097DD35A3B7BC6336"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remedies for State workers</header><clause id="id48023A9B576147C7B695E8CA4DA2B9F1"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header> <text>A State’s receipt or use of Federal financial assistance for any program or activity of a State shall constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity, under the 11th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or otherwise, to a suit brought by a covered individual of that program or activity, or a labor organization or worker advocacy organization on behalf of such a covered individual, under this paragraph for equitable, legal, or other relief authorized under this paragraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id89C0EE8E2B984246975106F4669CC4B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Official capacity</header><text>An official of a State may be sued in the official capacity of the official by any covered individual, or such a labor organization or worker advocacy organization, who has complied with the procedures under this paragraph, for injunctive relief that is authorized under this paragraph. In such a suit, the court may award to the prevailing party those costs authorized by section 722 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">42 U.S.C. 1988</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="id85B1422F339A4D67BD89DA9DB5827D12"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>With respect to a particular program or activity, clause (i) applies to conduct that occurs—</text><subclause id="id3DD6D0B22E374685A4F62AD1DFA2EDEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idB87349618E614487B8458B4FE6DF9D22"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after the day on which a State first receives or uses Federal financial assistance for that program or activity.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id891F8E14DC7D40918AF3E95946FA0B38"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definition of program or activity</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>program or activity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41E85EF29F04456D9CBE0B1865F6C837"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Remedies for Tribal government workers</header><clause id="id35AD0BD4D8DD4A46B407EBF060D0A133"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header><text>A Tribal government's receipt or use of Federal financial assistance for any program or activity of the Tribal government shall constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity to a suit brought by a covered individual of that program or activity, or a labor organization or worker advocacy organization on behalf of such a covered individual, under this paragraph for equitable, legal, or other relief authorized under this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="idA39174790E764B3683E1228CCEBECCD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Official capacity</header><text>An official of a Tribal government may be sued in the official capacity of the official by any covered individual, or such a labor organization or worker advocacy organization, who has complied with the procedures under this paragraph for injunctive relief that is authorized under this paragraph. In such a suit, the court may award to the prevailing party those costs authorized by section 722 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">42 U.S.C. 1988</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="idDA9C09A7F7DF4A0A920F5A99E0B89BE7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>With respect to a particular program or activity, clause (i) applies to conduct that occurs—</text><subclause id="id3C990FF1FF444FE49D376C0F6B877763"><enum>(I)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4776F594FBB84030BE5C6F416C011EF1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after the day on which a Tribal government first receives or uses Federal financial assistance for that program or activity.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03571516B68B49B1917B189A27A6BDF6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definition of program or activity</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>program or activity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1cfd7e063ce648da9780472ad81654e0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Government Accountability Office and Library of Congress</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, in the case of the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress, the authority of the Secretary under this subsection shall be exercised respectively by the Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id919b42d146c7483da04bb6053bb0a89b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individuals covered by Congressional Accountability Act of 1995</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) to the Board (as defined in section 101 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>)), or any person, alleging a violation of section 202(a)(1) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1312">2 U.S.C. 1312(a)(1)</external-xref>), shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to that Board, or any person, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 against a covered individual described in section 2(4)(A)(iii) or described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(III).</text></subsection><subsection id="ida1f5906af6d64c659e2576953922e845"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Individuals covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code, to the President, the Merit Systems Protection Board, or any person, alleging a violation of section 412(a)(1) of that title, shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to the President, that Board, or any person, respectively, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 against a covered individual described in section 2(4)(A)(iv) or described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(IV).</text></subsection><subsection id="id40698d10c0814f59a0e33d41a546b1c3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Individuals covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in title 5, United States Code, to an employing agency, provided in chapter 12 of that title to the Merit Systems Protection Board, or provided in that title to any person, alleging a violation of chapter 63 of that title, shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to that agency, that Board, or any person, respectively, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8 against a covered individual described in section 2(4)(A)(v) or described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(9)(A)(i)(V).</text></subsection><subsection id="id37837AFFABD241C49CD0CA3003121B96"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header><paragraph commented="no" id="id799C094792C54E55817D3789A9F46D64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which a State attorney general or a State privacy regulator has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of a State has been or is adversely affected by any person who violates any provision of section 3, 4, 5, or 8, including a regulation or order prescribed under this Act, the State attorney general or State privacy regulator, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0C2F053EF4484D3AAB2FFA3886A22145"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin further violation of such provision by the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idDA304EF31DDD4071B2034F686296BE1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compel compliance with such provision;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id3FD46807E91E4EDF863E98E3F822586B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages (including statutory damages described in paragraph (4)), civil penalties, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of the residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD3EFB587F6A64F4AAE0347C7373D125B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain reasonable attorney's fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCC45D1A8DD9F488D98E310A0E490E3DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of agency</header><text>Before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the State attorney general or State privacy regulator, as the case may be, shall notify the Secretary in writing of such civil action. Upon receiving such notice, the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id23799A61CA3049058659605EEF1ECF89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intervene in such action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id98DE45A2FAD9418DA6445FEAB29F6378"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text><clause commented="no" id="id8C8E24379F244481967C79142688EDDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in such civil action; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id65EBBE95B8BC47F1B3C99DCC29087EE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in such action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idEF87DFAD83DD478DA85E976C277374AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preemptive action by agency</header><text>In any case in which a civil action is instituted by or on behalf of the Secretary for a violation of this Act, including a regulation promulgated under this Act, a State attorney general or State privacy regulator may not, during the pendency of such action, institute a civil action against any defendant named in the complaint in the action instituted by or on behalf of the Secretary for a violation that is alleged in such complaint. In a case brought by the Secretary that affects the interests of a State, the State attorney general or State privacy regulator may intervene as of right pursuant to the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedb631f2a095459e9fa7876cf3824294"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Statutory damages</header><text>In a civil action instituted under paragraph (1), a court may award statutory damages under paragraph (1)(C) against a person for a violation of any provision of section 3, 4, 5, or 8—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idA898A56A1C3D4AFB93B65B58A025CE2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in an amount not more than $50,000 for each such violation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE61CC82AE2F24D509EF03D6AA988B6AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of such a violation that results in the discharge of a covered individual or other serious economic harm to a covered individual by such a person who has, within the preceding 5 years, committed another such violation resulting in such a discharge or other serious economic harm, not more than $100,000 for each such violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id584AF26C07AE445C92100D87DFEC9017"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Preservation of State powers</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), no provision of this subsection shall be construed as altering, limiting, or affecting the authority of a State attorney general or State privacy regulator to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id048903109A6A40D28293CDBDA5CDECEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bring an action or other regulatory proceeding arising solely under the laws in effect in that State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62975B6E00A74E2ABA1B93B464C1B30D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exercise the powers conferred on the State attorney general or State privacy regulator by the laws of the State, including the ability to conduct investigations, administer oaths or affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc7e5293de76c4e728553c5887b545cf5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Arbitration and class action</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e9f0253cf834109b4fd920c710418d3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no predispute arbitration agreement or predispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable with respect to any alleged violation of section 3, 4, 5, or 8.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6315acf107b94948aa5365b5e1fb278b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Arbitration pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall limit the enforceability of any arbitration provision in a collective bargaining agreement between an employer and a labor organization or worker advocacy organization.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4559D78EA2E643A7B5FAD1FE28873D6E"><enum>10.</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall coordinate with any appropriate Federal agency or State regulator to promote consistent regulatory treatment of automated decision systems.</text></section><section id="idc2094e83fe544bf9ae198d2468083ba5"><enum>11.</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as explicitly provided otherwise in this Act, nothing in this Act, including any regulations promulgated under this Act, shall be construed to preempt, modify, limit, or supersede—</text><paragraph id="id943646c7664240a7a7401ad9f22bd1fa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any provision of Federal or State law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc8af4da3084c48f7963214659ef11340"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of the Federal Trade Commission, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, National Labor Relations Board, or any other Federal agency.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id8bd9f41974494ceca9d6978cd954bf12"><enum>12.</enum><header>Relation to collective bargaining agreements</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb45147760ad54367979a45328c438b2a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, including any regulations promulgated under this Act, shall be construed to supersede or preempt employment or other work terms or conditions agreed upon in collective bargaining agreements that are more protective of or more beneficial to a covered individual than otherwise required pursuant to this Act, including any regulation promulgated under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6d962fe39a2e4e74a888d36f530987b1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for notice and bargaining</header><text>An employer shall provide advance notice to the relevant collective bargaining units or the representative of any covered individuals of the employer for purposes of collective bargaining and bargain in good faith with such units or representative over the decision to implement and effects of implementing any policy, practice, or automated decision system covered by this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="idF8E52E15DCDA452B9EB180C8D7A82BF7"><enum>13.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provisions of such Act to all other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text></section><section id="idca9391953fc24cb3b37727abd7b9a2ee"><enum>14.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2036.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

