<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA08EFB2D63BD475CBE0B8D8E7A147D0C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7954 IH: Don Young Doug LaMalfa Indian Buffalo Management Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7954</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor
          name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000482">Mrs.
          Fedorchak</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>)
        introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name
          committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assist Tribal governments in the management of buffalo and buffalo habitat and the reestablishment of buffalo on Indian land.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF6F447186AB74F779A6D87325BAADC7A" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H9A3D07817F4F421CA6F83EF2AF38DC84"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Don Young Doug LaMalfa Indian Buffalo Management Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC326505F353E4E47887DD8C5ECCF3354"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header> <subsection id="HB16B2FA2C222428D9FECF766B57C13C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="HA399D04CCB3649408DFD3E34B6778295"><enum>(1)</enum><text>buffalo sustained a majority of Indian Tribes in North America for many centuries before buffalo were nearly exterminated by non-Indian hunters in the mid-1800s;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9C3AFF7CB4A404F8264305F9BA333D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the historical, cultural, and spiritual connection between buffalo and Indian Tribes has not diminished over time;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6BC427E18D04B118370113BAD243D05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Indian Tribes have long desired the reestablishment of buffalo throughout Indian country for cultural, spiritual, and subsistence purposes; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D9CE1A53439403599BC50CA378F36B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the successful restoration of buffalo would allow an Indian Tribe to benefit from—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB150915240EA4BACBA64438F9A8E874E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reintroduction of buffalo into the diets of the members of the Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EE50E1120B94CC4855C5E651E47904E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the rekindling of the spiritual and cultural relationship between buffalo and the Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H829B987844564AC5A25EB49345CA74BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the use of buffalo for economic development, in the case of an Indian Tribe that chooses to use buffalo for economic development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7400316267C445D78763BA3DD745C3A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text>
<paragraph id="H26C0DC2D4153481480BD6D4618A16177"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fulfill the government-to-government relationship between Tribal Governments and the United States in the management of buffalo and buffalo habitat;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H624A0997E9EB4781B8569E11E2FDA9F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote and develop the capacity of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations to manage buffalo and buffalo habitat;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H478FE1A88F054CE8B5043873A3242037"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protect, conserve, and enhance buffalo, which are important to the subsistence, culture, and economic development of many Indian Tribes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB113506F2B140EF8D5ECB1614C82EE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote the development and use of buffalo and buffalo habitat for the maximum practicable benefit of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations, through management of buffalo and buffalo habitats in accordance with integrated resource management plans developed by Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8235D826ACD946C39EB3BF6CD248FF8B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop buffalo herds and increase production of buffalo in order to meet Tribal subsistence, health, cultural, and economic development needs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5EA03D328C84ACBB8FA5AFA049E5D5B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>promote the inclusion of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations in Department of the Interior, local, regional, national, or international—</text>
<subparagraph id="H302530D5344343FE87CCD6EBB03A3F87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>decision-making processes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD4AAE0162274C1C988780D96DF6B39C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>forums.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H640AC14C9FFC419C8E84EBEDC9BE944A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H97B2A4421150472681ED06B7DCA8D999"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Buffalo</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>buffalo</term> means an animal of the subspecies Bison bison bison.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8CA5AD8D065A45FAA2BDCA641E11DDD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Buffalo habitat</header><text>The term <term>buffalo habitat</term> means Indian land that is managed for buffalo.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3220566C5F5143A1BC7FDE6EA81155C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD3E3F7F3EA549269568EE4722D76545"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian land</header><text>The term <term>Indian land</term> has the meaning given the term in paragraph (2) of section 2601 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3501">25 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref>), except that, in that paragraph, the term <term>Indian reservation</term> shall be considered to have the meaning given the term <term>Indian reservation</term> in paragraph (3) of that section, without regard to the date specified in paragraph (3) of that section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77F75578BCA74B9D9B449B71BB503B45"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFD2E58B0F0DD4D62A74D506F4B57D3CB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H694502E333554A3AB5A4FEE4F30720B1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal organization</term> means any legally established organization of Indians that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB6225FE3380F4FBF8CE173F6C9BEB8C2"><enum>(A)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE847B08CA44F47C080D88E6145105ED6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is chartered under section 17 of the Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5124">25 U.S.C. 5124</external-xref>), and recognized by the governing body of one or more Indian Tribes; or</text></clause> <clause id="H6A14FA5FBDC343ECA6850D147EF55604" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a Tribal corporation federally chartered under section 3 of the Oklahoma Indian Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5203">25 U.S.C. 5203</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1F753C29A714412D9B48003CE57E13ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has demonstrable experience in the restoration of buffalo and buffalo habitat on Indian land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H79B497E20C034F1B9C575F3DF5A2EC26"><enum>4.</enum><header>Buffalo resource management</header> <subsection id="H06F51D4DFB234FC59883DA0AD22E1DF1" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direction for coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is directed to work with Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations to—</text>
<paragraph id="HB150151E30A04CC5B4399779CF46E52C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote and develop the capacity of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations to manage buffalo and buffalo habitat;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5957DACDB11402A857D3CFC1D8F4AC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote the ability of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations to protect, conserve, and enhance populations of buffalo that are owned by Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38B9EDB721414119B488496ABB6C1E1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the development and use of buffalo and buffalo habitat for the maximum practicable benefit of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47567996D8B047AE9071F3314A9E47B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote the inclusion of Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations in Department, international, national, regional, and local decision making and forums regarding buffalo and buffalo habitat.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE5DBFD27AE4B441DA99C44EFA5E5E9A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contracts and grants authorized</header>
<paragraph id="H259B939A895F47248F537870EDDB4B28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, and award grants to, Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations to enable the Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B8EBD4F726244E29347C53CBFBAB159"><enum>(A)</enum><text>plan, conduct, or implement a buffalo restoration or management program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD5243E86FEB42C9BB032AA5AE5426A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>plan and execute commercial activities related to buffalo or buffalo products;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63EC5FBE2FDB4C5A8FC2957F63310984"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the use and deployment of mobile Tribal or Tribal organization meat processing facilities; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC0BA4D2DBCB44883A368AA1953AC0BC2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>carry out other activities relating to buffalo restoration and management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11479461E204481EB64C1844BB33A0CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No diminishment of laws and regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection diminishes any Federal or State law (including regulations) regarding diseased buffalo or buffalo that escape from Indian land.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCCE2FCF509E4426FA3543E5A5AB5B7CF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization that enters into a contract or cooperative agreement or receives a grant under this section to assist the Indian Tribe or Tribal organization in—</text> <paragraph id="HB0CBBF279E10463BAE951B6EA6244CA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carrying out the activities of a buffalo or buffalo habitat restoration or management program; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5EE7119D96D4B32BCCC00AD64E4B560"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H72C78411AAE6454BBED5E81480D33B24"><enum>5.</enum><header>Consultation; coordination</header> <subsection id="H34A8BB35684F4F5E9C91DAE751C4E307"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and on an ongoing basis thereafter, the Secretary shall consult with Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations on initiatives of the Department that affect buffalo or buffalo habitat, including efforts of the Department to contain or eradicate diseased buffalo.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5EB01B9E5BE74EE4BF1FEF3631546ED7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a policy relating to buffalo and buffalo habitat management activities on Indian land, in accordance with—</text> <paragraph id="HB5072C5D59A64E8DA8C391B7DFFD6062"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the goals and objectives described in buffalo management programs approved by Indian Tribes; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H567436FF325F43978E9373693907ADA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Tribal laws and ordinances.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H88BB6C8E1F304DDF881271F637D00F62"><enum>6.</enum><header>Protection of information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not disclose or cause to be disclosed any information provided to the Secretary by an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization that is identified by the Indian Tribe or Tribal organization as culturally sensitive, proprietary, or otherwise confidential.</text></section>
<section id="HDF1577841D94468783F37BBBDE659E07"><enum>7.</enum><header>Buffalo from Federal land</header>
<subsection id="H4CF9C413A9BA4229B45B09339636E2DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into an agreement with an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization to dispose of surplus buffalo on Federal land administered by the Department, as applicable, by transporting such buffalo onto Indian land.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3BFC3054475441248D85FB3ABB52742D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An Indian Tribe or Tribal organization may submit to the Secretary an application to receive buffalo described in subsection (a) at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H46C9DB01B7CF48C184A6DE9221066930"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver of charges</header><text>The Secretary may waive any charges for the buffalo described in subsection (a), including any deposit or payment for services as described in section 10.2 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0FA34439924644A5B2D012557A7F301C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Treaty rights retained</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act alters, modifies, diminishes, or extinguishes the treaty rights of any Indian Tribe.</text></section>
<section id="HE05021252F9D4C64852CA05C6EC403BF"><enum>9.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority provided by this Act ceases to be effective 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill> 

