<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC13F2F76F2DE4895AFAA83D9D11FBC41" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 70 IH: Affirming the partnership between the United States and Denmark and Greenland.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 70</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Affirming the partnership between the United States and Denmark and Greenland.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States, the Kingdom of Denmark, and Greenland maintain a close partnership based on shared democratic values, collective security, and mutual respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States maintains a long-standing defense presence in Greenland in cooperation with the Kingdom of Denmark and the Government of Greenland, contributing to collective security in the Arctic and the North Atlantic region;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Denmark and Greenland are important partners under the North Atlantic Treaty, which was ratified by Congress in 1949;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Article 1 of the North Atlantic Treaty requires NATO members to settle any international dispute in which they are involved by peaceful means and to refrain from the threat or use of force;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas recent public statements by senior executive branch officials have suggested that the United States may seek to acquire Greenland, including through the potential use of miliary force;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas such statements have prompted public concern and objections from the Governments of the Kingdom of Denmark, Greenland, and other NATO allies who have reaffirmed that Greenland is not for sale and that its future must be determined by its people;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas leaders in Denmark and Greenland have emphasized that threats, pressures, or coercive rhetoric have no place between allies and undermine trust essential to collective security; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Constitution of the United States vests in Congress the exclusive authority to declare war, authorize the use of military force, and regulate the expenditure of funds for national defense: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H818774767B32425CB0FDFD95A6E887CB"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF32514458250427C8F286C836E235794"><text>That it is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H7E047784A2DF41B5AAEB2FA4B887DF30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States Government affirms its respect for the sovereignty of the Kingdom of Denmark, including Greenland, consistent with longstanding treaty commitments, including the North Atlantic Treaty;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1795E2878A764BBC8ABBED2311148C4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any change in the status of Greenland, or any use of United States military force involving Greenland, must comply with treaty obligations and is subject to authorization by Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AFAB52278864FA39F6C2FAAB07D4794"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should continue to strengthen diplomatic, economic, and security cooperation with Denmark and Greenland through partnership, consent, and alliance-based engagement; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6A8E3E91F474D4FA1F5BF8166ED0FBC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Arctic remains the most secure when the United States leads through cooperation with allies rather than coercion.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

