<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDD99C16E10614DA89F4BB41ACCC0B2AE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9675 IH: Expanding Opportunities for Recovery Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9675</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, acting through the Director of the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment, to award grants to States to expand access to clinically appropriate services for opioid abuse, dependence, or addiction.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCAD9EFE529F14F2DA6C5C10711A3BBF6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H17FBB34BD5B245D7968DB02A892F673E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Opportunities for Recovery Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H089F15E5BDCF476C9339F18BF7DD2F72"><enum>2.</enum><header>Opioid addiction treatment</header> <subsection id="HA035B90B1CFD4292A32B4B6493A7026D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, acting through the Director of the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment (in this section referred to as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>) shall award grants to States to expand access to clinically appropriate services for opioid abuse, dependence, or addiction.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9368F882BCCE46DCBC2C10A7EE4E9307"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>As conditions on the receipt of a grant under this section, a State shall agree to comply with the following:</text> <paragraph id="H25A59E13BE444A7AA3CE2CF1C89078C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The grant will be administered through the head of the State’s primary agency responsible for programs and activities relating to the treatment of substance abuse.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CC5B9B984B24702878308CC37332B63"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The services through the grant will be evidence-based such as medication-assisted treatment for substance use disorder.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE07ABC8ECB574137B73AEC807CDBFF95"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The services through the grant will be provided according to a physician or a clinician’s recommendation to ensure that individuals receive the optimal level of substance use disorder treatment for the amount of time that is deemed medically necessary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1CA2D362A7E4655BE3F2E8CB2BA2FCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The services through the grant will be provided exclusively to individuals—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FFE010B19B546F7B3D2404DA9F8F9DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who lack health insurance; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC661616A5E864443908FAD8AAB3544CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose health insurance—</text> <clause id="H77F67BB08992476B90968E1FCA492276"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not cover such services; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H35EF29EFD6F14414830CBC9A463FE73C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>places other barriers on the receipt of such services, such as—</text> <subclause id="H96E2A5F39D9446629A8052123B90D917"><enum>(I)</enum><text>limiting coverage of such services to a certain period of time; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3F679C6AA3B540FC96BF454947390358"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imposing nonquantitative treatment limitations that are more stringent than treatment limitations imposed on other medical conditions (such as a requirement to use less expensive services, like outpatient treatment, prior to more expensive, but physician-recommended services, such as inpatient or residential treatment).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88B924BC24254919818FCDDBA0477850"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The grant will not be used to pay or subsidize the cost of more than 60 consecutive days of opioid abuse, dependence, or addiction treatment in the case of any individual.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC5919333BF542938023DCE73B9AD7CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permissible provision of medications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In expanding access to clinically appropriate services for opioid abuse, dependence, or addiction through a grant under this section, a State may provide for the use of medications, in conjunction with other treatment, so long as the medications—</text> <paragraph id="H017961116A064AEE8C6B6E310DF55541"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are lawfully marketed under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A6F7A2CF8B3418E8482B05A32497290"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are clinically indicated to address the abuse, dependence, or addiction; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87E733A293E34B5F85A100037E34EB9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are offered consistent with consumer choice.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFD35D96494F747078024719088CED9FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall coordinate the program under this section with the program for prevention and treatment of, and provision of recovery support services for, substance abuse under subpart II of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-21">42 U.S.C. 300x–21 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6FF9A63303F74C36A7D9CB06BEF8AA03"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation; dissemination of information; technical assistance</header> <paragraph id="HEE26C7B44D3E4DBCB6DD3900780F794D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H28795CEAA01E4D1DB881A76C1C9418F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require States receiving a grant under this section to report appropriate outcome measures associated with use of the grant, including any—</text> <clause id="H782F31C0288843CEBF0EB73E11E63496"><enum>(i)</enum><text>decreases in substance use;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H45ED85610BE64B049F40EAC1FAA32EB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>changes in retention in care;</text></clause> <clause id="H927A2A1839B145B5BB72C08BE9B87EA8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>connections to the next appropriate level of care;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA2B3B7EBF3914FAEA3EEC9E584DC49B7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>decreases in involvement with criminal justice activities; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC23B58F0FADA4FA4A040392566011B4A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other outcome data as appropriate;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD97F4DF78EAD477E9959B44980285ABD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require States receiving a grant under this section to report data on individuals’ length of time under clinically appropriate addiction treatment, and the use of medication-assisted treatment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE0EF32D3738467ABD6527B632AAAD66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluate the activities supported by grants under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC2BD242B5084196BD377F926887E1D7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Congress and the Secretary, and make publicly available on the internet site of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, information about the results of such evaluation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD70C04D89A2648E7BF26992FBD623630"><enum>(E)</enum><text>offer technical assistance to States receiving a grant under this section regarding activities funded through the grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H416B0F97E488474282A799BD0C77A97C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of certain funds</header><text>Of the funds appropriated to carry out this section for any fiscal year, 5 percent shall be available to carry out activities under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

