<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAI26037-MN3-VP-MS1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4932 IS: No Lead in Toys Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4932</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Consumer Product Safety Commission to implement children's product safety recommendations of the Government Accountability Office.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Lead in Toys Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a26b2fd0c5e4824974fa74d1e895284"><enum>2.</enum><header>Children's product safety improvements</header><subsection id="id6a4df006ad91417ea7877a74ce651a1c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>children's product safety recommendations</term> means the recommendations set forth in the report of the Government Accountability Office entitled <quote>Consumer Product Safety Commission: Opportunities to Strengthen Oversight of Toxic Substances in Children’s Products</quote>, which was published on January 22, 2026.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb3bb50f620844396be5ccd8b0d1e89e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Consumer Product Safety Commission shall implement the children's product safety recommendations, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf376fa15e56d4f0c9d5383813625f803"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a plan to oversee compliance with applicable e-filing requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf199b6353df141b9b483436a52dd093b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a process for using violations data to assess risks associated with independent and government laboratories;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3821fa178c774dfd85359cb45033c24b"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reviewing applicable lead requirements and documenting a process for completing such reviews every 5 years; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc8d3c47ac11450da6121b2bd45b31e2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documenting a process for keeping up-to-date on changes related to phthalates and other toxic substances.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id41e9d0a3452546f5ab6b0ab9a1c23961"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Consumer Product Safety Commission implements the recommendations pursuant to subsection (b), the Chairman of the Consumer Product Safety Commission shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that explicitly describes the steps taken by the Commission to complete such implementation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

