<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA11874B225CC47709D90D61932C9D51D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6451 IH: Veterans Access to Transit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6451</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program for grants to improve access to public transportation services for veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E32BFB997B44DD3B8F38E2B09F06457" style="OLC"><section id="H94873957E7464FACB491332BE6008ADF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Access to Transit Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VA Transit Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H07E0AA4653BF47E7BBFEC808AE215595"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for grants to improve public transportation services for veterans</header><subsection id="HA8665989C59346E7AF6EAFCC19AB5673"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall establish a pilot program to award grants for the improvement of public transportation services for veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5EC054EDF1AD45B98CE80E4943CF4F3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Award of grants</header><paragraph id="HE848A38B12E7471580F8C87E3AC84370"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary of Transportation may award grants to eligible recipients for eligible public transportation projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD17771E14914223BCCF17B97B107378"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equitable distribution</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, grants awarded under this section are equitably distributed across geographic regions, including rural and Tribal communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23D7A0A602C442789C6AEAE7C361A675"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant recipient requirements</header><text>A grant under this section shall be subject to the requirements of—</text><subparagraph id="H36C4F71E79324E658ADAB957FB89CC0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 5307 of title 49, United States Code, for eligible recipients of grants made in urbanized areas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D844C3F19E343629DE1534F26A9F6F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 5311 of such title for eligible recipients of grants made in rural areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29B63B54DF2B4690A85EE6634C9E3C6F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Allocation to subrecipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a grant under this section may allocate amounts provided under the grant to a subrecipient.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA5FE114F22049809A890E99D84E4EBA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under the pilot program to eligible recipients at not fewer than 5 eligible locations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AD35913F86945069FD6350D5E251173"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant application</header><text>An eligible recipient seeking the award of a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary of Transportation an application in such form, in such manner, and containing such commitments and information as the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this section, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H53BD15565CD54EC2B19CDF65951219CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the public transportation services that the eligible recipient intends to provide with such grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H294A9E9E0ED444E3B1518DF91E6C7D4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of all sites to be served by such services, including any sites that are facilities and organizations that serve veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78C175A6E0F243FBACBD02834C5B263E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The frequency and hours of operation of such services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC30B8CBBC2484648BBCB8F04F194DA4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An estimate of the number of veterans that would use such services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEFF8F6D9C14449EB9E6432035885742"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Evidence that the eligible recipient has the legal, technical, and financial capacity to carry out the project proposed to be carried out with such grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5453191926E46B8A73756879097A20D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification to veterans</header><text>Each recipient awarded a grant under this section shall publicize and conduct outreach targeted to veterans regarding the transportation services funded under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H419458D1B7F44C8EAE80AB844FA9F2FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot program established under this section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the pilot program commences.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E389DFC5FE6469BBF7C977F51A5E840"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the termination date described in subsection (e), each recipient of a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary of Transportation a report containing information on the projects carried out with such grant, including—</text><paragraph id="H6A11C6F35BF74B389C3E824D5CF55861"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the effects of expanded geographic coverage, improved service quality, increased frequency, or other activities funded with such grant on public transportation services for veterans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A2E133B8E864B8AB1B00358B457F361"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any accessibility improvements made as a result of such projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A5209B3B3BD4A999854D12A51A3E858"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of changes in ridership due to such projects, including estimates or data regarding both general ridership and the number of veterans served;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD5C3FF4802497488E5E67E5B3F811F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the size and type of public transportation vehicles used in services funded with a grant awarded under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBEBDED3FDB54E17997F65244F907F70"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information on whether the use of facilities or organizations that serve veterans has increased due to such projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H112AB666292A4258ADAC48E1A3406438"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary requires.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C43AFFA448B4DA2890DC2441054CBE1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the reports required under subsection (f) are submitted, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, a report on the results of the pilot program carried out under this section based on the information provided in the reports required under subsection (f).</text></subsection><subsection id="HFCEB27E4C58C4412A38FA6569AF53187"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text><paragraph id="H19C49D6F39A241FEB99904A219A0C36D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text>The term <quote>eligible recipient</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF90F1710ABFF4E87ADFE8DEE8E6021FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State or local governmental entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD78473441D7A491E9B6293AB0E0D07C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Tribe or Tribal governmental entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3D8A5DA947B4D2EB9751D72801028A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible location</header><text>The term <quote>eligible location</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H69012ABEDA414D52A1C2F2183130EA95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a rural area, as defined in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA987ACC04DAD48DBB8C8F10289C5DE3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an urbanized area, as defined in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code, that has a population of fewer than 200,000 individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B961482C6E5426BA078F239CE83DD60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible transportation project</header><text>The term <quote>eligible transportation project</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD11DD5D37956426C8BCA844F834F76EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a project planned, designed, and carried out to expand, modify, retain, or establish public transportation services that provide veterans access to locations of facilities or organizations that serve veterans that is—</text><clause id="HC6CD54FC6BD14816B349D9666711EFB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a capital project; or</text></clause><clause id="H244716D409304FCDB0362F09364F64EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a project to acquire such public transportation services, including entering into service agreements with private providers of public transportation; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FCA00C340A24A33B0F25D753B530E14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operating costs associated with such project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2EA97FB385E433F8BF7A1A0B28E3037"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Facility or organization that serves veterans</header><text>The term <quote>facility or organization that serves veterans</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H37381F6634694D33AE04E6AED2842252"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H491A041D2AD64CF689F10B52A23611C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an organization or facility that provides services to veterans using funds provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD41D481A25F144349A1604823B911703"><enum>(C)</enum><text>and organization or facility proven to serve a significant number or percentage of the local population of veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE40A84B3F03B4971BF92F373BEBC5B08"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Net project cost</header><text>The term <quote>net project cost</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H536391A40A624E9E96B238DCA664873C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Subrecipient</header><text>The term <quote>subrecipient</quote> means a State or local governmental authority, a private nonprofit organization, or an operator of public transportation services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

