<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL25730-T4X-K4-SKR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3201 IS: Good Government Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3201</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to prohibit transactions involving certain assets by Members of Congress, to require Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children to place certain assets into blind trusts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Good Government Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id69EE7B4A3A804F339FEF5DF1FA91CFEE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Covered financial instruments of Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children</header><subsection id="id4431553CEDD64D118171AB95B62D7ACF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">Chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id650DB2DF228B45A995ADDA2CCACAE070" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="USC"><subchapter id="id15109DFE420243379CF020AC9EE1BAAA" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Covered financial instruments of Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children</header><section id="id67a63ee06986481bbd5c2b35de16ccbd"><enum>13161.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text><paragraph id="id97405eedc24c4e24b3745afbfe777745"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commodity</header><text>The term <quote>commodity</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id36439fd7681e410781fc58e2d1962738"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered financial instrument</header><subparagraph id="id572E7630B5F24C2B93671D632DDD6F7E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered financial instrument</term> means—</text><clause id="id5f9ee68c074d4f9f8c81c3993b6ba795"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any investment in—</text><subclause id="id680D261A0C6F4B1A94230AACDD82EAF7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a security;</text></subclause><subclause id="idA64B5968FB5B4DBEAE962F1B4D45B032"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a security future; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id5F7780DF021F46648047FF4887686564"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a commodity; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id8df32512baf64f49883bf53325907ed0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any economic interest comparable to an interest described in clause (i) that is acquired through synthetic means, such as the use of a derivative, including an option, a warrant, or other similar means.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f6a36a583874e90a5e7f9ec36a62a01" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>covered financial instrument</term> includes an investment or economic interest described in subparagraph (A) that is held directly, or in which an individual has an indirect, beneficial, or economic interest, through—</text><clause id="id3D14FF86FC1049EFA72E81E51E39DCEB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an investment fund;</text></clause><clause id="id4E7E5EB12F8D4D21B365F28D7C9890F5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a trust (other than a qualified blind trust);</text></clause><clause id="idE4A4A1E908BF4D17B276E009A7896561" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an employee benefit plan; or</text></clause><clause id="id44F28CAAA4A247BFBB7141AF603AFC70" commented="no"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>a deferred compensation plan, including a carried interest or other agreement tied to the performance of an investment, other than a fixed cash payment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id540A39F7B32642F2AF1A2ED139335CA7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>covered financial instrument</term> does not include—</text><clause id="id9815e35239e948489ede8da429403f8b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a diversified mutual fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause><clause id="id2a5b3d79485f450f878f45d2510bd955"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a diversified exchange-traded fund (including any holdings of such a fund);</text></clause><clause id="id63b611f75e8a430d8f0e284d5f85a6e7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a United States Treasury bill, note, or bond;</text></clause><clause id="id0995da3d1a964d578d96e1aa8129b3e0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>compensation from the primary occupation of a spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa01672c74144afba816eb0df1f5f521"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any investment fund held in a Federal, State, or local government employee retirement plan.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id49FC74AC13BC4B7F96B54E8D74632E21"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>An investment that achieves compliance with applicable environmental, social, and governance criteria shall not be considered to be a covered financial instrument solely by reason of that compliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE07CD7AFFB5345C285966EC5A0442AB0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Current</header><text>The term <term>current</term>, with respect to a Member of Congress, means an individual who is serving as a Member of Congress on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Good Government Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id331820d216af49fd833612b700f4c4c7"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dependent child; Member of Congress</header><text>The terms <quote>dependent child</quote> and <term>Member of Congress</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 13101.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide509faaa69454aab9fc7c73b8db64260"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Diversified</header><text>The term <term>diversified</term>, with respect to a fund, trust, or plan, means that the fund, trust, or plan does not have a stated policy of concentrating its investments in any industry, business, single country other than the United States, or bonds of a single State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc36de4022094439d8730c0f5333e0110"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Initial property</header><text>The term <term>initial property</term> means an asset or financial interest transferred to a qualified blind trust by, or on behalf of, an interested party or a relative of an interested party, regardless of whether the asset or financial interest is transferred to the qualified blind trust on or after the date of establishment of the qualified blind trust.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idace3441270634955b2772eec0fd07aea"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Interested party</header><text>The term <term>interested party</term> has the meaning given the term in section 13104(f)(3)(E).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id167C4CFC526B46A68E3D2EBA998FDC4D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>New</header><text>The term <term>new</term>, with respect to a Member of Congress, means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="idADD88B8BE6DF4EBDAEF7D0A666D649A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not a current Member of Congress; but</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id615E4A677EE9420297FC7C9177E796D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>commences service as a Member of Congress after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Good Government Act of 2025</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id953babd5ac974f8ebb19fe9be708d221"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualified blind trust</header><text>The term <term>qualified blind trust</term> means a qualified blind trust, as defined in section 13104(f)(3), that has been approved in writing by the applicable supervising ethics office under section 13104(f)(3)(D).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd78009e29703463a9c498b9d720e65d6"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Security; security future</header><text>The terms <quote>security</quote> and <quote>security future</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 3(a) of Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb656a8e7e164b048c853b1530fdcc39"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Supervising ethics committee</header><text>The term <quote>supervising ethics committee</quote> means, as applicable—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4bb2a2ec7cb4a4994570e0779102f19"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7b66283f42a482ea0d951819b0c1aa7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idB57EBDB2A5B442A8B6AAE1DED54E6142"><enum>13162.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain transactions and holdings involving covered financial instruments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 13163, a Member of Congress, or any spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress, may not, during the term of service of the Member of Congress, hold, purchase, or sell any covered financial instrument.</text></section><section id="id8CD04813C47D4339AE7449CDE286D0C0"><enum>13163.</enum><header>Divestment and placement of covered financial instruments in qualified blind trusts</header><subsection id="idE66CCCF534864B9A9AE49034531E4A15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Current Members of Congress</header><paragraph id="id696845B210E54DAF9743882E75197CD8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Good Government Act of 2025</short-title>, each current Member of Congress shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office a certification that, as applicable—</text><subparagraph id="id4b63eb2bfc3e439ba3ee13bdb5b7963a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each covered financial instrument owned by the Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, the Member of Congress, or the applicable spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, will, in accordance with paragraph (2)—</text><clause commented="no" id="id0B2D7B2FC7E54EC880726B836E86296D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>divest the covered financial instrument; or</text></clause><clause id="id3648234384EE4432B0620D07F674068B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>place the covered financial instrument in a qualified blind trust, including by establishing a qualified blind trust for that purpose, if necessary; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id742531B6C98F4287AAA36F33463DEDD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>neither the Member of Congress nor any spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress owns a covered financial instrument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6F0C69C509A34373B0A84642410F35F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Divestiture or placement in qualified blind trust</header><subparagraph id="idC3BCECB8022340BC831EA9C308E6E0E7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Good Government Act of 2025</short-title>, each current Member of Congress shall divest, or place in a qualified blind trust (including by establishing a qualified blind trust for that purpose, if necessary), each covered financial instrument owned by the Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida73956d8250843bcb8d22c0a61aff0cb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Divestiture</header><text>A current Member of Congress shall divest a covered financial instrument held by the Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress if—</text><clause id="id6cd82f6802cb4938b2286646add579ed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Member of Congress, or the applicable spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, is unable to place the covered financial instrument in a qualified blind trust by the date described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id87F97C9CFA4340358E9CDC549F47F2B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Member of Congress fails to obtain an extension pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id304335D5A1CB4451901B84AC4719E856"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>If a current Member of Congress, or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, is unable to place a covered financial instrument in a qualified blind trust by the date described in paragraph (2)(A), the Member of Congress may request, and the supervising ethics office may grant, 1 or more reasonable extensions, subject to the conditions that—</text><subparagraph id="id5A700857F8514DD69BBDD4D04C54524A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total period of time covered by all extensions granted to the Member of Congress for the covered financial instrument shall not exceed 180 days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A767D97A3484E0692CA238C35B74BEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the period covered by a single extension shall be not longer than 45 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5A666F6839D045718279B9863955828B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>New Members of Congress</header><paragraph id="idCAD5E3E5F7F140C9AC11CC56E5880DBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which an individual becomes a new Member of Congress, the new Member of Congress shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office a certification that, as applicable—</text><subparagraph id="idE51D5DAF97F5484B869241FB9A230A29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each covered financial instrument owned by the Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, the Member of Congress, or the applicable spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, will—</text><clause commented="no" id="idF5B74832837046D196DAFD68C6DC3B71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>divest the covered financial instrument; or</text></clause><clause id="id39BF351C81FA4617879E3DFE484E2E3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>place the covered financial instrument in a qualified blind trust, including by establishing a qualified blind trust for that purpose, if necessary; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB933D1179AF848C3A26BCEA6264E0274"><enum>(B)</enum><text>neither the Member of Congress nor a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress owns a covered financial instrument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4CAE47025D8241179910C05A8A413ABC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Divestiture or placement in qualified blind trust</header><subparagraph id="id1D6891F993014A82BEDAA856BC14AE35"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), not later than 120 days after the date on which an individual becomes a new Member of Congress, the individual shall divest, or place in a qualified blind trust (including by establishing a qualified blind trust for that purpose, if necessary), each covered financial instrument owned by the Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5EABA882FF78433F95D07DA174031846"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Divestiture</header><text>A new Member of Congress shall divest a covered financial instrument held by the Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress if—</text><clause id="id17CE712E723E4A4297FA82E3D2424150"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Member of Congress, or the applicable spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, is unable to place the covered financial instrument in a qualified blind trust by the date described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id214E92868B4147399ADB07E58991409E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Member of Congress fails to obtain an extension pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3FF5DE0BDACC4861B7F2A93465D54C15"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>If a new Member of Congress, or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, is unable to place a covered financial instrument in a qualified blind trust by the date described in paragraph (2)(A), the Member of Congress may request, and the supervising ethics office may grant, 1 or more reasonable extensions, subject to the conditions that—</text><subparagraph id="id2AC1FA3CCA224F69B2A575A6E38D59B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total period of time covered by all extensions granted to the Member of Congress for the covered financial instrument shall not exceed 180 days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68F07A401ADE4144B2CF590AEDC6CEA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the period covered by a single extension shall be not longer than 45 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id371ca17f582d4b29af6f2771ed1c246d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mingling of assets</header><text>A spouse or dependent child of a Member of Congress may place a covered financial instrument in a qualified blind trust established by the Member of Congress under subsection (a)(2)(A) or (b)(2)(A), as applicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="id33b330945be447e1b5b26654f97835a8" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Separation from service and cooling-Off period required for control</header><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an individual becomes a Member of Congress and ending on the date that is 180 days after the date on which the individual ceases to serve as a Member of Congress, the Member of Congress, and any spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress, may not—</text><paragraph id="id936CFA15507446979EA30F7C0156ED45" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>dissolve any qualified blind trust in which a covered financial instrument has been placed pursuant to subsection (a) or (b); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id10A2C0EBE9C54C71A705D07E06F72C39" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>except as provided in this section, otherwise control a covered financial instrument.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide4e1431fb07443488523d244efced86c" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="id1EAD75AEA63D4CF5AFCEB002A4499827" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supervising ethics offices</header><text>Each supervising ethics office shall make available on the public website of the supervising ethics office—</text><subparagraph id="id73F74E43EF8D40248DB3DB1F6CF9A16D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of—</text><clause id="id27357287EC7B41FC91C36989F8FC14A8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each certification submitted to the supervising ethics office under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1);</text></clause><clause id="id7c40054aeb71441f9d9162ad838fbe05" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each qualified blind trust agreement of each Member of Congress; and</text></clause><clause id="id9F623707950B47FE957FA6525FC50FA8" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each notice and other documentation submitted to the supervising ethics office under paragraph (2) or (3);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id577ebef1cbec484ab8845a96cab33e13" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a schedule of all assets placed in a qualified blind trust by each Member of Congress and interested party; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbd97b4c7da14b5dbc2a4958a0e67e15" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of each extension granted, and each civil penalty imposed, pursuant to this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide6753198b29d40759a77be23ebed56c5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trustees</header><text>Each trustee of a qualified blind trust established by a Member of Congress shall submit to the Member of Congress and the applicable supervising ethics office a written notice in any case in which the trustee—</text><subparagraph id="id3124950ca01f4ae59840c3e915271dc9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>learns that—</text><clause id="id76BF3B74E4974E01AB838A329B9E64BF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an interested party has obtained knowledge of any trust property other than the initial property of the qualified blind trust; or</text></clause><clause id="id837B1002FAC6451E9B8C9B4BB0DCB00B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the value of the initial property of the qualified blind trust is less than $1,000; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c60496aa489424483f414578c892155" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>divests any initial property of the qualified blind trust.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6453c92191014ed4bbc6722f7d003f0b" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Members of Congress</header><text>Each Member of Congress who is a beneficiary of a qualified blind trust shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics office—</text><subparagraph id="iddb9b78ab2c3041d5a99f2eb2467ec8c8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of the executed qualified blind trust agreement by not later than 30 days after the date of execution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfece16040be74a86a5b132cf7114c6ef" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of each asset and each financial interest transferred to the qualified blind trust by an interested party by not later than 30 days after the date of the transfer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideedc5cdea8f54697b8def45bf5e90a32" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a copy of each notice submitted to the Member of Congress under paragraph (2) by not later than 30 days after the date of receipt;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3391bc3eccde4e24a5fb7f3a55298561" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a written notice that an interested party has obtained knowledge of any holding of the qualified blind trust by not later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Member of Congress discovered that the knowledge had been obtained; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99a16a9fdc894581978355175fc38af9" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a written notice of dissolution of the qualified blind trust by not later than 30 days after the date of dissolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2ab6956343674d66af0f8d6a9957e30a"><enum>13164.</enum><header>Annual certification of compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not less frequently than annually, each Member of Congress shall submit to the applicable supervising ethics committee a written certification that the Member of Congress has achieved compliance with the requirements of this subchapter.</text></section><section id="id489442905D3048C8B5F8B2E43B677385" commented="no"><enum>13165.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="idA9DBE15D60EA476CAA1E368DEFEDB4D9" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The applicable supervising ethics office shall provide a written notice (including notice of the potential for civil penalties under subsection (e)) to any Member of Congress who—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id289e56e8945e48408092dc6d34f11201"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fails—</text><subparagraph id="idC5C2345A30814F65917CFD323132C318" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to submit a certification under subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) of section 13163 by the date on which the certification is required to be submitted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15710ADC251B455A9FF6C76E0C8EB115" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to place 1 or more covered financial instruments owned by the Member of Congress or a spouse or dependent child of the Member of Congress in a qualified blind trust in accordance with subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) of section 13163 by the applicable deadline, subject to any extension under subsection (a)(3) or (b)(3) of that section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8b5d0cb146b43a4bfec92250489fbe4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit an annual certification under section 13164; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc910c258a4dc42eb85c584c59339a349"><enum>(2)</enum><text>otherwise violates this subchapter.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc6a7356039784dbb90e6c1448fba05de"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text>Any Member of Congress to whom a notice has been provided under subsection (a) shall be afforded an opportunity, with respect to each alleged violation that is the subject of the notice—</text><paragraph id="id170d9602822a4638b2a0de1a036841fa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for a hearing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide603cf1d22044b74b12ffcf307490358"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to achieve compliance with the requirements of this subchapter.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14502aa4a4724c768fea265aa3662cec"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disgorgement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member of Congress shall disgorge to the Treasury of the United States any profit from a transaction or holding involving a covered financial instrument that is conducted in violation of this subchapter.</text></subsection><subsection id="idD77E9DBEF3284BD38DA654E61EC8FEA1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fines</header><paragraph id="id0DB5216E14494DAAAC09704FEA33BCE4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A supervising ethics office shall impose a civil penalty, in the amount described in paragraph (2), on a Member of Congress to whom a notice is provided under subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="idB4A106BDE37149EFA70BB4A0778232CE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the date that is 30 days after the date of provision of the notice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id879A0DA1796542BB8E10F1DFF04D126F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 30 days thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49D75A1AB38F4DED932DBD924D4FF11F"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Amount</header> <text>The amount of each civil penalty imposed on a Member of Congress pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be equal to the monthly equivalent of the annual rate of pay payable to the Member of Congress.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2feecdf73eec43938e3d8015112b1492"><enum>13166.</enum><header>Authority of supervising ethics committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each supervising ethics committee may implement and enforce the requirements of this subchapter, including by—</text><paragraph id="id8437A2F67BD24ADAB8FDB52FFC039E58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issuing—</text><subparagraph id="idEE26CE83A1D14872B891641369BB3969"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for Members of Congress—</text><clause id="idF016A4A8AE52441E98241FE1D4E49627"><enum>(i)</enum><text>rules governing that implementation and enforcement; and</text></clause><clause id="id9ABEE88114124871A3D827BDC45A764A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 or more reasonable extensions to achieve compliance with this subchapter, if the applicable supervising ethics committee determines that a Member of Congress is making a good faith effort to divest any covered financial instruments; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBC4845AF64D54290B9B9543F467B987D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance relating to covered financial instruments;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd80d5bd4f4a4c17bda5fe576028d97c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publishing on a publicly available website a description of—</text><subparagraph id="id747534022e7440f8addcb32bda24e26d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to each civil penalty assessed by the supervising ethics committee pursuant to section 13165—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca00a442bf824ac48beed8c627da070d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of such civil penalty;</text></clause><clause id="id8bd2aaa16298452080de67106483197b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reasons why each civil penalty fine was assessed; and</text></clause><clause id="id7f4777fc0d8040f4a7d65603944b04a1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the result of each assessment, including any hearing under section 13165(b) relating to the assessment;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide725ea96de004a038234cd518c097599"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the information described in section 13163(f)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e23353dc9904b9093312609bdbb36f4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each notice, rule, and other documentation issued or received by the supervising ethics office under this subchapter; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf87cfde8e8214b4fa64e35dd41bbebea"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish such procedures and standard forms as the supervising ethics office determines to be appropriate to implement this subchapter.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc275a7bd9a14452a9be1ec0c04d73755"><enum>13167.</enum><header>Audit by Government Accountability Office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Good Government Act of 2025</short-title>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="id947EC72B2A8244979E8D8C5DC2675801"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an audit of the compliance by Members of Congress with the requirements of this subchapter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d573856aded424e822feb0c77cc54a1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the supervising ethics committees a report describing the results of the audit conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb42b441887314541a0552c2ca646adad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2ad057386864dc2a4c524679e641a8f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id0e581560-ff17-4e11-ab3e-101ec78fe2bc"><toc><toc-entry level="subchapter" idref="id15109DFE420243379CF020AC9EE1BAAA">SUBCHAPTER IV—Covered financial instruments of Members of Congress and their spouses and dependent children</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id67a63ee06986481bbd5c2b35de16ccbd">13161. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idB57EBDB2A5B442A8B6AAE1DED54E6142">13162. Prohibition on certain transactions and holdings involving covered financial instruments.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id8CD04813C47D4339AE7449CDE286D0C0">13163. Divestment and placement of covered financial instruments in qualified blind trusts.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id2ab6956343674d66af0f8d6a9957e30a">13164. Annual certification of compliance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id489442905D3048C8B5F8B2E43B677385">13165. Enforcement.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id2feecdf73eec43938e3d8015112b1492">13166. Authority of supervising ethics committees.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc275a7bd9a14452a9be1ec0c04d73755">13167. Audit by Government Accountability Office.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idecde4c27e06a49408e0117ba8645d159"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Persons required to file</header><text>Section 13103(f) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01305efea9184cac848a4fe251c80504"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d35a65455c9482bb50968c29318b4b2">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc1f55a389be42c0a3b06cafd1214bdf">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (11), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1772be4d9805421e8de002b47dce530e">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>as defined in section 13101 of this title</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9D7F33DCFFC64651AE22E3F3E9E6B5CF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(4)(D) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602(4)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>legislative branch employee serving in a position described under section 13101(13) of title 5, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>officer or employee of Congress (as defined in section 13101 of title 5, United States Code)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

