<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6575D440BC9147CD91D3FECB1B24389C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8753 IH: Gas Tax Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8753</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax holiday for gasoline and diesel fuel.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H552B37B6886B43F2ABE975C94D04EE04" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB3E930E279CD45F28058D2343FF89678"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gas Tax Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H259A0D58A0664EEA8360664B8FF4ABD8"><enum>2.</enum><header>2026 tax holiday for taxable fuels</header> <subsection id="H56B527D3B72940F689608679347B207A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of taxable fuel (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4083">section 4083(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) removed, entered, or sold on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and before the applicable date—</text> 
<paragraph id="H799B58D2F1E744429472C4C172BD97A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the rate of tax under clauses (i) and (iii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4081">section 4081(a)(2)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be zero, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBB31D80919D44BE99819AC115D6BFAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate under section 4081(a)(2)(B) of such Code shall not apply to taxable fuel to which the rate under paragraph (1) applies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50C5DB38E57E4AC499760FD12F24ADF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to Trust Fund</header> 
<paragraph id="H25641843B576471682BFB242F77C7069"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the general fund to the Highway Trust Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund established under section 9508(a) of such Code amounts equal to the reduction in amounts credited (but for this subsection) to each such Trust Fund by reason of subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H918C402A838D4411AE4124EBBFE5BA9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination rules</header> <subparagraph id="HA674B3800431421EB05A73928204DED6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund under paragraph (1) shall be treated for purposes of sections 9503(b)(1) and 9508(b)(2) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C2AF2DC6A364FF99238097BBF0828FA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Highway Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Highway Trust Fund under paragraph (1) shall be treated for purposes of section 9503(b)(1) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code which are not attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C5C11869A4A467183374BE3B0A24FF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable date</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>applicable date</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FD42F294C9848048C09691795ADFB57">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the date which is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act,</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08567DDEF853463387D20CB5D2433FD9"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>if the President determines, in the President's sole discretion, that economic conditions merit an additional suspension of the tax on taxable fuels described in subsection (a), the date that is 215 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and</text>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph id="a1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if the President determines that a phased-in reimplementation of the tax on taxable fuels described in subsection (a) is appropriate, the President may provide for such phased-in reimplementation through incremental restoration of the rates otherwise applicable under section 4081 beginning on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill>

