<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG26054-5XV-PJ-W06"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3888 IS: Small Business Artificial Intelligence Training Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Commerce to develop artificial intelligence training resources and toolkits for United States small businesses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id5e574989-798e-4b3a-ab7e-23de87e46295" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Artificial Intelligence Training Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id12f905a2-c06a-4001-8080-a171f2b51916" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence training resources for small business concerns</header><subsection id="id79940899-fa68-4d60-8401-281be295712b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc12b4884-4f86-4e38-971d-e46073f71ea4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72f8ce3b-ea26-4f96-9b7b-f485b7858db6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8deec8f-6050-4efd-9fd9-355f193386b1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ee57546-7429-4133-a7b4-7c869de71acc" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6c913a3-d01a-43f4-8f22-99f907d1e05e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Center</header><text>The term <term>Center</term> has the meaning given such term in section 25(a) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278k">15 U.S.C. 278k(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8659f39-5c39-4f75-9ca8-2f7603fe0842" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7da4e70-08ea-4d16-b5c9-7c5b2a1695c3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership</header><text>The term <term>Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership</term> has the meaning given such term in section 25(a) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278k">15 U.S.C. 278k(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id372f3ed2-c6f2-461a-89ce-d04dc4cf5a90" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id50123f7c-8591-4ce8-b299-c3e4c109b5cc" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(7)</enum> <header>Key emerging technologies</header> <text>The term <term>key emerging technologies</term> means the technologies included in the initial list of key technology focus areas set forth by section 10387(c) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/19107">42 U.S.C. 19107(c)</external-xref>), photonics, and electronics.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd124327d-8e94-40f4-b1ea-3ccabe81e37b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Rural community</header><text>The term <term>rural community</term> means a community that is located in areas that are not classified as urban by the Bureau of the Census.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id61c9443b-d28b-4995-bae7-8f3cc4077a4c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f5f55ce-35c5-4f4f-a5fa-bf4759a39198" changed="not-changed"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id87e89151-fec0-49a2-9743-6d183c33868a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of training resources required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f5a8777-a062-4d90-ab3b-522394397b1e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, acting through the Director, the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership, and the Centers and in consultation and coordination with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Secretary of Agriculture, and such persons in the private sector as the Secretary of Commerce considers appropriate, develop training resources for small business concerns, including small business concerns located in rural, Tribal, or underserved communities or involved in advanced manufacturing, relating to the adoption and use of artificial intelligence and such other key emerging technologies, such as quantum-hybrid computing, as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d694ae7-12de-4712-b86a-f0e79db6f4ea" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The training resources developed under paragraph (1) shall include prompt engineering and the use of artificial intelligence or emerging technologies, such as quantum hybrid tools, relating to access to credit and capital, financial management and accounting, business planning and operations, cybersecurity, marketing, supply chain management, government contracting, and exporting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id44fb5082-7c9c-430d-aacc-f93818dc8e94" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review and update of training resources</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once each year thereafter, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0401fc41-237d-42d5-a241-264fbd2e7dfe" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the training resources developed pursuant to subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05b30f95-21b5-4f73-b7d1-8ee9cf57d493" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update such resources as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id11ca5e1c-4c7f-4ee1-91b8-5b17db7e6933" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution and use of training resources</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration on the distribution and use of the training resources that are developed pursuant to subsection (b) through the resource partners of the Small Business Administration, including small business development centers, women business centers, SCORE, veteran business opportunity centers, and the Apex Accelerator.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11885d5d-3175-446f-990e-2adb9da2e708" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants program</header><text>The Secretary may, in coordination with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, carry out a program on the award of grants to persons providing training relating to artificial intelligence to small business concerns using the training resources developed under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id686f2619-8125-469a-9608-03df94b522ed" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><paragraph id="idc95a83f1-76a4-46b1-85ab-c7d638c4a106" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the development, distribution, and use of the training resources developed pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idce8ecfc6-9ab6-434b-b4ae-c40f3cde68c7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><subparagraph id="id92a6ec9a-638e-4b10-babe-e53ba40c400a" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once each year thereafter, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, submit to appropriate committees of Congress an annual report on the development, distribution, and use of training resources developed pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44a1773b-e558-4d06-94f4-d1f9bcf10e85" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Contents</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted to subparagraph (A) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text>
                        <clause id="idd0dab69f-1c26-451d-adfe-4bb175bead5c" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>A list of the training resources developed pursuant to subsection (b).</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                            id="idaf84bf6a-708f-44c8-a65e-2dcc8d2ebe3b" changed="not-changed">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the measurable outcomes of the distribution of such training resources, including the following:</text>
                            <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="id36d21698-b36f-45d9-a1a4-4ea218717524" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and type of small business concerns using such training resources.</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="id4d048e08-9a9c-4065-b73a-9204e7c68b0c" changed="not-changed">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effect of such use on the revenues, sales, and workforces of the small business concerns.</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7876f49d8e6744299d2208c67e604dc3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authorities and requirements under this section shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

