<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3241B22DFA204443AE82A74F6607AF77" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9609 IH: Less Bureaucracy, Better Student Aid Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9609</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure the Department of Treasury will manage all federal student
      loans, federal student debt, and policies regarding student aid eligibility, and for other
      purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H64711AB4DC6A435AA17C9498536FBB76" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4FBB921C0E854C588E31F778D939A810" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Less Bureaucracy, Better Student Aid Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEF151C21E80F4114AAE6F1779BB415CA" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfer of Department of Education functions relating to Federal student aid</header> <subsection id="H7187A5EFC21F4A82AD173C9AD0C4D21E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are transferred, in accordance with the applicable effective dates in subsection (b), to the Department of the Treasury—</text> 
<paragraph id="H18AD0CC0A0C241B6A87684C707DE505C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">functions of the Secretary of Education (including the performance-based organization established pursuant to section 141 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1018">20 U.S.C. 1018</external-xref>) and all related functions of any officer or employee of the Department of Education) related to the servicing and voluntary and involuntary collections of defaulted Federal student loan debt, including certification of debt, due process, borrower notification, disputes, bankruptcy, rehabilitation, consolidation, compromise, repayment agreements, and credit reporting;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D80973B3F7E4B06A26594A99EC41024" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">functions of the Secretary of Education (including the performance-based organization established pursuant to section 141 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1018">20 U.S.C. 1018</external-xref>) and all related functions of any officer or employee of the Department of Education) related to the servicing of non-defaulted Federal student loan debt, including borrower notification, processing of payments, repayment plan administration, consolidation, disputes, and credit reporting; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB823BCCFC9A249E684CDC025FDFEAF64" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all functions of the Secretary of Education (including the performance-based organization established pursuant to section 141 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1018">20 U.S.C. 1018</external-xref>) and all related functions of any officer or employee of the Department of Education) that remain after the transfer of functions required under paragraphs (1) and (2) with respect to each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3370EDD73CF04A28A5B01DF49DA137C1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative Provisions for Delivery of Student Financial Assistance under part D of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1018">20 U.S.C. 1018 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0AD5DD69219841C382AC084BC4518A6E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lender and Institution Requirements Relating to Education Loans under part E of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1019">20 U.S.C. 1019 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67DB5E77B99C42D69DE3B0BD8C73868A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Pell Grants under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85DE010F15F0487894156720B3E02273" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Supplemental Educational Opportunity Grants under subpart 3 of such part A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070b">20 U.S.C. 1070b et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB803C703B38B4A58AC63546380F7F08B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Family Education Loan program under part B of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H722EE53DE7A54E5FA5DEF4ED4EF9D4DE" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Work-study programs under part C of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-51">20 U.S.C. 1087–51 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFEE34C5F563944BBB9E02670295FB360"><enum>(G)</enum><text>William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan program under part D of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBA8890942174D1E9C376BA73798E5E5" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Federal Perkins Loans under part E of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087aa">20 U.S.C. 1087aa et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA458872765D4959BA4FEF49F650CF0C" commented="no"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>Need Analysis under part F of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087kk">20 U.S.C. 1087kk et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F18B72FA5314ED18B2520D04CEEE3E8" commented="no">
            <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">General Provisions Relating to Student Assistance programs under part G of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBFFFA5EBF9E94F54ADC30F80A7F61826"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligibility and Certification Procedures under subpart 3 of part H of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099c">20 U.S.C. 1099c et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B41535D1C2C410DA9B30DEF2DEECC45" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Health Education Assistance Loan program as provided in part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC6ADEFAF7A34ADB9D510C9DB060DEA1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> 
<paragraph id="HC9637D9319334F27A76D6EA1B5682147"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective dates determined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education and the Secretary of the Treasury shall jointly determine effective dates for the transfers required under subsection (a), in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA99749685B7B482DB5F9CB7CB4FA95E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable effective dates</header><text>The transfers required under subsection (a) shall take effect as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H59E0094DFCBD421C8B94A1AAEF0EC82D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Paragraph (1)</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the transfers required under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), on the effective date determined in accordance with paragraph (1) that is on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H521543FC7A694AB4AD38EBDA29C49201"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Paragraph (2)</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the transfers required under paragraph (2) of subsection (a), on the effective date determined in accordance with paragraph (1) that is on or after the effective date described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA4343BBB9B64833AD7F90E443535BBA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Paragraph (3)</header><text>With respect to the transfers required under paragraph (3) of subsection (a), on the effective date determined in accordance with paragraph (1) that is on or after the effective date described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H6C0981CBD90B41F883D4CEF84DD1438F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exercise of authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary of the Treasury may, for purposes of performing a function transferred under this Act, exercise all authorities under any other provision of law that were available with respect to the performance of that function to the Secretary of Education immediately before the effective date of the transfer of the function under this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="HF2DACD4F1D834D78926F7E3BADFA7CFE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transfer and allocations of appropriations and personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, used, held, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with the functions transferred under this Act, subject to section 1531 of title 31, United States Code, shall be transferred to the Secretary of the Treasury. Unexpended funds transferred pursuant to this section shall be used only for the purposes for which the funds were originally authorized and appropriated.</text></section> <section id="H347712787A334F92AFF4C059B1DF21FB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority of Director of the Office of Management and Budget with respect to functions transferred</header> <subsection id="H5327937738C04BD8AD3F56F131D80B89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Personnel determinations</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall ensure that this Act does not result in a net increase in full-time equivalent employees at the Federal agencies impacted by this Act, based on the number of such employees at such agencies on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H941395191D5A408A860A3DB2C31F5653"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Function determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If necessary, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall make any determination of the functions that are transferred under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC42076CA1656469EB036BA342242636D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incidental transfers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, at such time or times as the Director shall provide, may make such determinations as may be necessary with regard to the functions transferred by this Act, and to make such additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act. The Director shall provide for the termination of the affairs of all entities terminated by this Act and for such further measures and dispositions as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38B4526543AE44D3A9FEE91382F4FB2B" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification of compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On each of the effective dates under section 3(b), the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall certify compliance with the provisions of this Act that take effect on such date, including the requirement under subsection (a) as applicable on such date, to the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H28E1C3DA767945429FF846E0A9C89FA5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Delegation and assignment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly prohibited by law or otherwise provided in this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury may delegate any of the functions so transferred to such officers and employees of the Department of the Treasury as the Secretary may designate, and may authorize successive redelegations of such functions as may be necessary or appropriate. No delegation of functions under this section or under any other provision of this Act shall relieve the Secretary of the Treasury of responsibility for the administration of the function.</text></section> 
<section id="H6F6C2061723C47189CA1DE6B894E570F" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With regard to functions transferred under section 2, a reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to—</text> <paragraph id="H9B105CE67BEB4FE4B38409FCF4FA80E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education shall be deemed to refer to the Secretary of the Treasury; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAF14EFD005643E7BB61F8C830C1C49F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Education shall be deemed to refer to the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF53084269D6F4ABC918D037A28C99A95"><enum>8.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header> <subsection id="HC50E29EEA5A44429A7CF20B0B0B7C78A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Legal documents</header><text>All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, grants, loans, contracts, agreements, certificates, licenses, and privileges—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7EE773D6159D458CB272CFB2CA053FD7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>that have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, any Federal agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of any function that is transferred by this Act; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2933EDA571CA432F852BACFF3E7E1651"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that are in effect on the effective date of such transfer (or become effective after such date pursuant to their terms as in effect on such effective date),</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the Secretary of the Treasury, any other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or operation of law.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="H23FCCA613EDC441B8254BA8EE5D6CBA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceedings</header><text>This Act shall not affect any proceedings or any application for any benefits, service, license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending on the date of the enactment of this Act before the Department of Education (with respect to functions transferred by this Act). Such proceedings and applications shall continue, orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this Act had not been enacted, and orders issued in any such proceeding shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this subsection shall be considered to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this Act had not been enacted.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0291785DF8E3421F9556CB537D9DDDC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Suits</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (e)—</text> <paragraph id="H3CF68A7C89AC480DB07F89DC692C25D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act shall not affect suits commenced before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H715BB19402A3493AB96F0E3092A8AEA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in all such suits, proceeding shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if this Act had not been enacted.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAE5F87B71631429381AF11627AC3731C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonabatement of actions</header><text>No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against the Department of Education (with respect to the functions transferred by this Act), or by or against any individual in the official capacity of such individual as an officer or employee of the Department of Education (with regard to functions transferred by this Act), shall abate by reason of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14196CAAA9C64D8B87531CAB91C40385"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuance of suits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, before the date on which a transfer of a function under this Act takes effect, the Secretary of Education or any officer or employee of the Department of Education in the official capacity as such an officer or employee is party to a suit relating to the function, then such suit shall be continued and the Secretary of the Treasury, or other appropriate official of the Department of the Treasury, shall be substituted or added as a party.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3F13B4BB164243A79F26C1F47D7B166B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative procedure and judicial review</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by this Act, any statutory requirements relating to notice, hearings, action upon the record, or administrative or judicial review that apply to any function transferred by this Act shall apply to the exercise of such function by the Secretary of the Treasury, and other officers of the Department of the Treasury, to which such function is transferred by this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA039AE4B83ED4D24949483D85E6F9778" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Terminating exemption from Debt Collection Improvement Act</header> 
<subsection id="HC945F3ECD3E3426BA7A40B6EE82E3227">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Termination of authority To exempt student loans from the Debt Collection
          Improvement Act</header>
 <text>Beginning on the effective date of the transfers required under paragraph (1) of section 2(a) (as determined in accordance with section 2(b)), delinquent or defaulted Federal student loan debt may not be subject to an exemption under paragraph (2)(B) of section 3711(g) of title 31, United States Code, from the requirement under paragraph (1) of such section.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H17867600F658458A985E90CDB7E56787" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1FAE387A6C0D4A0BB7E90E47BAA2F121" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Delinquent or defaulted</header><text>The term <term>delinquent or defaulted</term>, when used with respect to student loan debt, means debt that is considered delinquent or in default in accordance with the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78B9F54A4C7047AC9B74CDB115BB4AF3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student loan debt</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>student loan debt</term> means any debt under part B, D, or E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>), or any debt that arises from a Health Education Assistance Loan as provided in part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>), that is assigned to or otherwise held by the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC51D9998F7AB4747A9585CAE6B52CF05" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>10.</enum><header>Transition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to use, for such period of time as may reasonably be needed to facilitate the orderly implementation of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE07736C673F040D1AC2A6B68AB00C800"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the services of officers, employees, and other personnel of the Department of Education with regard to functions transferred under this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78B3881CD9014DD08CEC5B5068EAFEEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assets of the Department of Education with regard to such functions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59363E28869A44CC8A23DCB6BB841279"><enum>(3)</enum><text>funds appropriated to such functions.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H8C13DAD2ABD14D08B68DD756B6B839C0"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definition of function</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>function</term> includes any duty, obligation, power, authority, responsibility, right, privilege, activity, or program.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

