<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3C1095DBE9114B30B418118421E4B7B7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8224 IH: National Veterans Strategy Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8224</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the President to define veteran success and to develop and implement a National Veterans Strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0A7D704A08E541F99F21DA20B1BA4FAE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6EE8EAE19B82402981582ABBAFFF376C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Veterans Strategy Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H084CF9E7E4AE43C6B74822A3CC8931D2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H28074AE0A6B44CAC9C6A72B29410429E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It is in the national interest of the United States for veterans to be successful after their service in the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H520EF1B595884369940471BAA1F571F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Veterans who are successful across various aspects of their lives after their service in the Armed Forces provide a continued return on investment to the United States for the time and resources spent on their training that made them successful in the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD21AE4E1B9354E1DB985C6AE1CBFF1FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Veterans bring highly valued skills to the civilian workforce, including leadership, problem-solving, technical expertise, and teamwork that make the economy of the United States stronger.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C66470F549D4AB08687D166FB4EB249"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Veterans’ success after service can include starting a business, working in public service, raising a family, pursuing further education, competing in athletics, working to serve other veterans, and improving overall health.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H085A3198E9E449B0A1E0BC4AF13835BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The success of veterans enhances national security and military readiness. Demonstrating a lifelong commitment to those who serve strengthens recruitment, retention, and morale throughout the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF52610CAD1C41AEA426B04CB96E8E91"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A veteran who uses military experience and veteran benefits to achieve success after leaving service in the Armed Forces is a positive influence on the next generation of people of the United States who will consider serving in the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H764D99DCCB744435A594C1FD3C20943E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Defining veteran success and National Veterans Strategy</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3783B8AF40B4837A40C144BBD56AF84"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Chapter I of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D465E82171F4358BA203B80C80658FD"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA711ED19C3864DC686838A93E0008DEE"><enum>120.</enum><header>Defining veteran success and National Veterans Strategy</header> <subsection id="H26119BDB4F904175A779B4E39FD65D01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Defining veteran success</header> <paragraph id="H14FD409CEFF446E38A065FEE03678C8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Metrics required</header><text>The President shall, in collaboration with the key stakeholders described in paragraph (3), establish metrics to determine the well-being of the population of veterans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB1F3CA096C743D5907A8C7C1D4814EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Areas</header><text>The metrics established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall apply to areas of physical health, mental health, spiritual health, economic security and opportunity, education, family and social engagement, and civic engagement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7227B39A7638451495B56DE36DED5B13"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Key stakeholders</header><text>The key stakeholders described in this paragraph are such stakeholders as the President considers key stakeholders for purposes of this subsection and shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3B94FCA0E37540F5A7F0DDB74970F14C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Congress.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD23FE64B52264B30AF0F14F809C3C1A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1AA46F23DF5A454FB6A5CFED38EAE27C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93BBCB74E7DE4FB8BFBB570872030214"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9CFA40238FC4A1B805ABB546919841C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE43446DF91CD477A964D0B1BAD2DAC3D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C4401100B5B4C2B82D2038E5513D96F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABA98E7A5AA14459A29FB776EA588D92"><enum>(H)</enum><text>State governments.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2BD612AC4B704C95947F52FEDE700913"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Local governments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3B4705B39E74C05A1EB9089656164F8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Tribal organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7BEA322F41674365B01BCE31533B4C77"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Veterans service organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF2C916D07A348E6990CDE8A552ACE87"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Nonprofit organizations that serve veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H701264ED538347FC82B1099A30CFEDCC"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Institutions of higher learning.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65A0971F4BD342809C45068EA8D21518"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Research organizations with expertise on the veteran population.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1539DFF6003849C3B04D56D137F0EBEB"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Philanthropy associations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2239E85634F4E2B8BC0B5141EF25451"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Trade and professional associations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBC2B8659E3846079285A3361718CD3A"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Private sector companies, including both large corporations and small business concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H938890C7985549C38913E6E0FC8452E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Veterans Strategy</header> <paragraph id="H46FDAB40CF79488E8FF348B561389852"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><text>The President shall formulate and submit to Congress, not less frequently than once every four years, a national strategy (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Strategy</quote>) to align the resources and efforts of various government, nonprofit, and private sector organizations to help veterans achieve success in the metrics established under subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36ECEA826DF84BCBBE5098B2636F4B38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F957477DB7B43C09A4C0AF93371B7F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In formulating the Strategy, the President shall consult with the key stakeholders specified under subsection (a)(3) and the general public.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29E7CA5186E548D7BA062539C650A07F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>The President shall ensure that consultation under subparagraph (A) includes public input through public hearings, surveys, or such other methods as the President considers appropriate to gather feedback from veterans, families of veterans, and the general public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0716B0286FA4C04B4422EFB47363804"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration of needs across demographics</header><text>The Strategy shall include consideration of the various needs of veterans across demographics that include age, geographic locations, sex, race, period of military service, disability, health conditions, education level, and marital and family status.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3A3232DC6F24876AC5FF1EEE04E4B89"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Methods for evaluation of overall well-being</header><text>The Strategy shall provide for methods to evaluate overall well-being of veterans using the metrics established under subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DB5BB183C9A4BEC8954AA373427D8D8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Direction for application of benefits and services</header><text>The Strategy shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9DB855494AC40CC9B0B6C33B5FE2480"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide direction for what benefits and services should be applied to assist veterans who do not meet the metrics established under subsection (a)(1) in certain areas of health and well-being; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18B1666E92094FC1B426620B77E46868"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prescribe how and by whom such services and benefits should be applied to maximize effectiveness and efficiency across Federal, State, local, nonprofit, and private sector resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DAD21617459414BA5CA300BFC1206AA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Delineation of services provided to organizations</header><text>The Strategy may include delineation of what services should be provided by certain types of government or nongovernmental organizations, as well as in what order different types of services or benefits should be provided to achieve the best result in the most efficient manner.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CE9459DE44D4E449C0535E86D2B21DC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Direct services and Federal grants</header><text>The Strategy may include considerations on how best to coordinate the use of both direct services provided by Federal agencies, as well as Federal grants for State and local governments and nonprofit organizations, or the use of commercial services, to provide direct services to veterans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4375245CF07749AE93B8CB4EAE1EA8B7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Evaluation of outcomes</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71CFFFF0E3904A3BA666596A80E37C4F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Strategy shall include standard metrics to evaluate the outcomes achieved from delivering services and benefits to veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4249851BA3C74B7C863F918EEC42E134"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consistent and uniform application of metrics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal agency and recipient of a Federal grant, as a condition on continued receipt of the grant, shall apply the standard metrics included under subparagraph (A) consistently and uniformly across programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H64B2BC4ADBFA4DE88ED63DC20634B29E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional disapproval procedures</header> <paragraph id="H928CBC21C1884D249F31C1D9DBB15770"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the President may not take any action with regard to a national strategy developed under subsection (b) if, within 60 days after the date on which Congress receives a national strategy under such subsection, Congress enacts a joint resolution disapproving the national strategy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6F0106B128B4C1B94B29BF96DB45885"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of resolution</header><text>For the purpose of paragraph (1), <quote>joint resolution</quote> means only a joint resolution introduced after the date on which the national strategy referred to in section (b)(1) is received by Congress the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the National Veterans Strategy established by the President as submitted to Congress on ______ (the blank space being appropriately filled in).</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC7F79627206487A9015C5ABE96A2B64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Referral to committee</header><text>A resolution described in paragraph (2) introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives. A resolution described in paragraph (2) introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate. Such a resolution may not be reported before the 8th day after its introduction.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10E1E5FBA2C94C479E8849E42EC9E744"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Discharge of committee</header><text>If the committee to which is referred a resolution described in paragraph (2) has not reported such resolution (or an identical resolution) at the end of 15 calendar days after its introduction, such committee shall be deemed to be discharged from further consideration of such resolution and such resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar of the House involved.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D1AC1EB6F7343E4BA8657F9C5A1A008"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Floor consideration</header> <subparagraph id="H0844E4D9CA584F2CAE7B9ED1B2478AF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>When the committee to which a resolution is referred has reported, or has been deemed to be discharged (under paragraph (4)) from further consideration of, a resolution described in paragraph (2), it is at any time thereafter in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) for any Member of the respective House to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution, and all points of order against the resolution (and against consideration of the resolution) are waived. The motion is highly privileged in the House of Representatives and is privileged in the Senate and is not debatable. The motion is not subject to amendment, or to a motion to postpone, or to a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the resolution is agreed to, the resolution shall remain the unfinished business of the respective House until disposed of.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99D492FE560B4DC2BB16492CCD1F967C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Debate</header><text>Debate on the resolution, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the resolution. A motion further to limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the resolution is not in order. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the resolution is agreed to or disagreed to is not in order.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5214AA11E5CF43059977143E8E5FF8C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vote on final passage</header><text>Immediately following the conclusion of the debate on a resolution described in paragraph (2), and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the appropriate House, the vote on final passage of the resolution shall occur.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BBCEE80897C40249277305029A011FE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate or the House of Representatives, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a resolution described in paragraph (2) shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A99BE6CEF414156976ABF57EE27F2F5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Coordination with action by other house</header><text>If, before the passage by one House of a resolution of that House described in paragraph (2), that House receives from the other House a resolution described in paragraph (2), then the following procedures shall apply:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H63277F20180C459FA28DDA487D63BFEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The resolution of the other House shall not be referred to a committee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC84B9EE7A12E483BAFEAC28D8A581C3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to a resolution described in paragraph (2) of the House receiving the resolution—</text> 
<clause id="HED2127D8EA284B6F9DFFBF5919E116F6">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the procedure in that House shall be the same as if no resolution had been received from the other House; but</text>
                                    </clause> 
<clause id="HD977C9BABF374DBDAE96CDA2CC05E1AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the vote on final passage shall be on the resolution of the other House.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03BC28A5BDCD4D4E9A25B77988C7FB69"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rules of house of representatives and senate</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1EC8DF02E6114E54A58FDDCDB7790A2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and House of Representatives, respectively, and as such it is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a resolution described in paragraph (2), and it supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44C890A593684695AC7793B5C8E236CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H46B5750540DC4391BEFB9C1A8AACE381"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation of National Veterans Strategy</header> 
<paragraph id="H24AB5F8263D04D3DBE2C546A2BAC5B4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal, State, local, nonprofit, and private sector coordination</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c) and not before the date that is 60 days after date on which the President submits to Congress the Strategy under subsection (b)(1), the President shall direct the heads of Federal agencies to coordinate with State and local governments, nonprofit organizations, and the private sector to implement the Strategy. Each head of a Federal agency shall ensure that the agency aligns its resources, services, and initiatives with the objectives outlined in the Strategy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAAD4EC854A049BBA22717BC40E87AF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incorporation into agency strategic plans</header><text>Each head of a Federal agency shall, as applicable, incorporate the metrics established under subsection (a)(1) and the Strategy into the strategic plan of the agency required by section 306 of title 5.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E5F14BED2C449F1893588E64ACADC0C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual reporting</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3D609A2023C4E859B25B6FE06DF7793"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once each year, the President shall submit to Congress an annual report detailing the implementation of the Strategy, including progress toward achieving the goals of the Strategy in the areas specified in subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2F46237A69A4A19B488C05BAF39A601"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text> 
<clause id="H9076E97D4902417B80E76A52B117BBF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A review of the performance metrics developed under subsection (a)(1).</text></clause> <clause id="H6F03164D68E2498A8AD6B2AA2B9FC7D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An assessment of spending pursuant to the Strategy in each of the Federal, State, local, nonprofit, and private sectors, how such spending aligned with the objectives outlined in the Strategy, and identification of effective programs and best practices at the State and local levels that could be replicated in other jurisdictions.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC6B6DF90302746C9A05ED750AF54DB99"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Identification of barriers to success in implementing the Strategy and recommendations for such legislative or administrative action for the various jurisdictional levels observed as the President considers appropriate to improve the well-being of the population of veterans.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF6FDDC66E32843DAA1192C1406D28E4A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quadrennial reviews</header> <paragraph id="H0271C6AA61F24F4088D62A53538E2B89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than once every four years, the President shall—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECB3D0869F3945D6B1D2F7CE5B65B00F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the national strategy formulated under subsection (b)(1) and the metrics established under subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8867376C6BAB4117BCE12E75B6E5391B"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as the President considers necessary, update such national strategy and metrics.</text>
                                </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA489D1FAEDFE4FD1A8E820AF8209215C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each review carried out under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03CB114162A6430CB276F00DAF8CA60C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessment of the effectiveness of initiatives carried out pursuant to the Strategy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H074CDBF5A1C34983A1F7ABB88835595C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of challenges encountered by the Federal Government in carrying out the Strategy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09513F4C7F754235944AD71513D29904"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for legislative or administrative action to address the challenges identified pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1BFA82E73124E50B170D5E69D1BFF3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>The President shall ensure that each review under paragraph (1) includes public input through public hearings, surveys, or other such other methods as the President considers appropriate to gather feedback from veterans, families of veterans, and the general public.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9156102F90D04D60BB920FAD8794C26C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government to carry out any program or policy that is inconsistent with any other provision of Federal law, including the elimination or rescission of any program, benefit, or service required by a provision of Federal law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0DD1DD3EB4FF4AFA82D4C0139561F09B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H76CF1678372D4AE1A236C231C77E75DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>Tribal organization</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DE5AB1C733F445B879B225D92E39D81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB9EF7A739B2471A8C3ADBAA94576974"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Veterans service organization</header><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H107B05F359E4417981860DAF794EB8E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial metrics</header><text>Not earlier than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall establish the metrics required by section 120(a)(1) of such title, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45EF34CBDF9F4C9A8808E48A2FFBDB8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial strategy</header><text>Not earlier than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act and not later than four years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to Congress the first strategy under section 120(b)(1) of such title, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BE27A90FA3B43899CB5AD4CFCB1E356"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 1 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 119 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65602326406F4EEE8E8DB186D606EEE8"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" bold="off">120. Defining veteran success and National Veterans Strategy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

