<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26387-6DJ-N9-5LW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4552 IS: Moms Matter Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4552</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260518">May 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To address maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9F6C79C2B1C7402DA17FA48693BBE762"><section section-type="section-one" id="HFE2CFFFC340343A28B7FF0BB89FE5E6A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Moms Matter Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC111D7749D714B0B99E1A958A4E7ACFD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Maternal mental health equity grant program</header><subsection id="H0801A633D19249068EB10EF5802E7728"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall establish a program to award grants to eligible entities to address maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders, with a focus on demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA948792CD47C4AB0AFC40DDE8D16EAB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7A71C56220DE4404A032744E517860B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an eligible entity that—</text><paragraph id="HF44E5694204F412D9E87E29EE6FBCB00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is, or will partner with, a community-based organization to address maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA43832A6D2644C3A6811C021B2DA7AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is operating in an area with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08E7C6D50A844FF7B6DB1247F1F19FA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is operating in a health professional shortage area designated under section 332 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AB6F2871CEA4B55BE2DD0B6ABEA53DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant for the following:</text><paragraph id="H4BDD03B921FE40AE816BF0ECCF62A808"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing or expanding maternity care programs to improve the integration of maternal mental health and behavioral health care services into primary care settings where pregnant individuals regularly receive health care services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD2C0DED8D244AA694F7F641901AC894"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establishing or expanding group prenatal care programs or postpartum care programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE664627C1FEC4DC0A1A9951E1AD6F36C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expanding existing programs that improve maternal mental and behavioral health during the prenatal and postpartum periods, with a focus on individuals from demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F7B2DAC2F2548239776A0331196A139"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing services and support for pregnant and postpartum individuals with maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders, including referrals to addiction treatment centers that offer evidence-based treatment options.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73C1F18B63D1417DA6FC6C180E6A39A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Addressing stigma associated with maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders, with a focus on individuals from demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36D7289593D34A30A4D3DD786C07A1D1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Raising awareness of warning signs of maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders, with a focus on pregnant and postpartum individuals from demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA08990425A0404C8781710D86104515"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Establishing or expanding programs to prevent suicide or self-harm among pregnant and postpartum individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CF1216222AF4D8DB08B2E1E94048059"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Offering evidence-aligned programs at freestanding birth centers that provide maternal mental and behavioral health care education, treatments, and services, and other services for individuals throughout the prenatal and postpartum period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F79743C3F948EC80B9096222BEB6F9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Establishing or expanding programs to provide education and training to maternity care providers with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HB8910A3EDFCB461BBE680A52BD50AF4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying potential warning signs for maternal mental health conditions or substance use disorders in pregnant and postpartum individuals, with a focus on individuals from demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EBB831CE09D4AE8BE07B37C24DA17A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case where such providers identify such warning signs, offering referrals to mental and behavioral health care professionals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36F15257AEC143AE8E28AF76F2627DD7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Developing a website, or other source, that includes information on health care providers who treat maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C948CA01B2E48CAB6C3C70AF72B855A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Establishing or expanding programs in communities to improve coordination between maternity care providers and mental and behavioral health care providers who treat maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders, including through the use of toll-free hotlines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C4F666B676E43B8B737FEC293826BF8"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Carrying out other programs aligned with evidence-based practices for addressing maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders for pregnant and postpartum individuals from demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8094F9B41C54A889D234D600250D46B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="HC1EE6F8050FF4DC1863EE1A5A3CB68D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall submit annually to the Secretary, and make publicly available, a report on the activities conducted using funds received through a grant under this section. Such reports shall include quantitative and qualitative evaluations of such activities, including the experience of individuals who received health care through such grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC917F4CDC0EE4C6885D3845C5A691461"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Not later than the end of fiscal year 2030, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H75FD91854BD8406096DE8D15DD403C4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the reports received under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7BE97B8D18B4FFBB4F1E5A39AE274B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the effectiveness of grants awarded under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B08B8078ADF4681BC74BFE212FE1C85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations with respect to expanding coverage of evidence-based screenings and treatments for maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A1C0A43F0D34CC1B2EBB77F32E770D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations with respect to ensuring activities described under subsection (d) continue after the end of a grant period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H969D3A9F3A644A5597EE3D2582FCF1A0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HFAE6DEFC0451444D932BCC10CA18F848"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H96D81871265C433EB6A66F1766E27226"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community-based organization serving pregnant and postpartum individuals, including such organizations serving individuals from demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9BFCB698A104918B9F4A3A1B7040DBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit or patient advocacy organization with expertise in maternal mental and behavioral health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8602608D0C9142378DC0423BCAB39590"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a maternity care provider;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1108F69D8AA9474CB0548F50B25B19E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a mental or behavioral health care provider who treats maternal mental health conditions or substance use disorders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F79F1EF93244533BCCDCC4653F0117F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a State or local governmental entity, including a State or local public health department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A9D8A32E7D34793A4FBFD7EBFA25F76"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as such terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H860BBCCBA6D348459D2AC09558E55A16"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an Urban Indian organization (as such term is defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6F03407D9D24515A48B89905A97291F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Freestanding birth center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>freestanding birth center</term> has the meaning given that term under section 1905(l) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H773D7B3E9A3741C8BC604339B3C3EBD9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maternal mortality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>maternal mortality</term> means a death occurring during or within a 1-year period after pregnancy, caused by pregnancy-related or childbirth complications, including a suicide, overdose, or other death resulting from a mental health or substance use disorder attributed to or aggravated by pregnancy-related or childbirth complications.</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF76E390D48C4DF196C8C99B96D236D3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Maternity care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>maternity care provider</term> means a health care provider who—</text><subparagraph id="H8301BE6655B34F099667FC1373BA71F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a physician, a physician assistant, a midwife who meets, at a minimum, the international definition of a midwife and global standards for midwifery education as established by the International Confederation of Midwives, an advanced practice registered nurse, a doula accredited by a State to receive reimbursement for doula services under a State plan (or a waiver of such plan) under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), or a lactation consultant certified by the International Board of Lactation Consultant Examiners; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H963E9FC6729147B5BF4A9BB36F194422"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a focus on maternal or perinatal health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD6B8F2D6A5C4AC88B2767F6F8B673A0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Postpartum and postpartum period</header><text>The terms <term>postpartum</term> and <term>postpartum period</term> refer to the 1-year period beginning on the last day of the pregnancy of an individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09907720336047FDA741E021002657D8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EB9F678D7F84985BB93D74DC6149820"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Severe maternal morbidity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>severe maternal morbidity</term> means a health condition, including a mental health condition or substance use disorder, attributed to or aggravated by pregnancy or childbirth that results in significant short-term or long-term consequences to the health of the individual who was pregnant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H635C30C0489A4B109C358278D052933D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><section id="H71AEF49733764CCE9EE51FC197B25E68"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to grow and diversify the maternal mental and behavioral health care workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 757 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294f">42 U.S.C. 294f</external-xref>) the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H47C9A570D9524EE2AF81C30FB99855FF"><section id="HE3241B9FB25A4B18BFBF6E5B9A52D468"><enum>758.</enum><header>Maternal mental and behavioral health care workforce grants</header><subsection id="H31D18EAA0AC842AB9D9921F6257D539F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to entities to establish or expand programs described in subsection (b) to grow and diversify the maternal mental and behavioral health care workforce.</text></subsection><subsection id="H723646F7E275494BB4E7BBB07E96EB22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Recipients of grants under this section shall use the grants to grow and diversify the maternal mental and behavioral health care workforce by—</text><paragraph id="H100A255D5C0C440B89BE2291A02E1301"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing schools or programs that provide education and training to individuals seeking appropriate licensing or certification as mental or behavioral health care providers who will specialize in maternal mental health conditions or substance use disorders; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E55A0CA620B4EC1B6417D9D4C2AD156"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expanding the capacity of existing schools or programs described in paragraph (1), for the purposes of increasing the number of students enrolled in such schools or programs, including by awarding scholarships for students.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H811226329F094FF19D65F22E819EC759"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to any entity that—</text><paragraph id="HDDE7F9E046464DE09567E885A3B4DA3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has demonstrated a commitment to recruiting and retaining students and faculty from racial and ethnic minority groups;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE97192AFF6F24673AF15A7B85663FE17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has developed a strategy to recruit and retain a diverse pool of students into the maternal mental or behavioral health care workforce program or school supported by funds received through the grant, particularly from racial and ethnic minority groups and other underserved populations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EEAFB405ECB44BDAEC15ED75002CECA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has developed a strategy to recruit and retain students who plan to practice in a health professional shortage area designated under section 332;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C2E281248E544ACB71D5ECE216726E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has developed a strategy to recruit and retain students who plan to practice in an area with significant maternal health disparities, to the extent practicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC500068197984A1E82E13A299A514039"><enum>(5)</enum><text>includes in the standard curriculum for all students within the maternal mental or behavioral health care workforce program or school a bias, racism, or discrimination training program that includes training on implicit bias and racism.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H472C6E75E28549EBBBBAC0B4C57669F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section for a maternal mental or behavioral health care workforce program or school, an entity shall agree to submit to the Secretary an annual report on the activities conducted through the grant, including—</text><paragraph id="H802128D54B15433F8C9F239E6908F93C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and demographics of students participating in the program or school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H705D2BFEC3F24234AEF40F1BAB53E363"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which students in the program or school are entering careers in—</text><subparagraph id="HDC8CE5D9B6054C699FD7FA4A651B76C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health professional shortage areas designated under section 332; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5145B48EBAD1407F8115B64999F22FED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>areas with significant maternal health disparities, to the extent such data are available; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA52FEC79D0104D1AA07DF01F9C54AD20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the program or school has included in the standard curriculum for all students a bias, racism, or discrimination training program that includes training on implicit bias and racism, and if so the effectiveness of such training program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EF0FD3F007644DEACBD577BB6EEEED5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Period of grants</header><text>The period of a grant under this section shall be up to 5 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H694AE67399794CB18526A480D79114D5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, an entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including any information necessary for prioritization under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0FDF266E7A1648B8BD8A57253B53F81B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide, directly or by contract, technical assistance to entities seeking or receiving a grant under this section on the development, use, evaluation, and postgrant period sustainability of the maternal mental or behavioral health care workforce programs or schools proposed to be, or being, established or expanded through the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA463AB143E874D5AA09E55382173712E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report by the Secretary</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress, and post on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services, a report on the effectiveness of the grant program under this section at—</text><paragraph id="HD711A2EB83CB4844AC722D561D72861F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recruiting students from racial and ethnic minority groups and other underserved populations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC726DDA8D68425789E2F00EAB469430"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing the number of mental or behavioral health care providers specializing in maternal mental health conditions or substance use disorders from racial and ethnic minority groups and other underserved populations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6AF0D394886452CAA9FBDF6B55ED4BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing the number of mental or behavioral health care providers specializing in maternal mental health conditions or substance use disorders working in health professional shortage areas designated under section 332; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD02F1FF72DF4319B811718AFBAAA5A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>increasing the number of mental or behavioral health care providers specializing in maternal mental health conditions or substance use disorders working in areas with significant maternal health disparities, to the extent such data are available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CC347A84D854EB495F76BAA4D73EBEA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H522F21A9EC68428EA95077196CAB8ADB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Racial and ethnic minority group</header><text>The term <term>racial and ethnic minority group</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1707(g)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A1C210766CE4FC5B8D441A793F97E32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mental or behavioral health care provider</header><text>The term <term>mental or behavioral health care provider</term> means a health care provider in the field of mental and behavioral health, including substance use disorders, acting in accordance with State law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52EF3ADC06C34C14838B0F2F19AE802E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

