<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H48DDC1D9EBA7485BB23ABEC41B75D6B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5946 IH: Stamp Out Veterans Medical Debt Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5946</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the issuance of a Veterans Medical Debt Relief Stamp.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H243F7BF0CADC4A76A8433F87E6ADB289" style="OLC"><section id="H2B6E55E6D28549E5B4CF4FD1D0A4B813" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stamp Out Veterans Medical Debt Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFF2B02FFFE4A435993565071F38964CA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans Medical Debt Relief Stamp</header><subsection id="H173C6502C0DC4660A0CFA0E25725F2C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to afford a convenient way for members of the public to contribute to funding to pay medical debt incurred by veterans for hospital care, medical services, and extended care services furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs, including through the Community Care Program under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, the United States Postal Service shall provide for the issuance and sale of a special postage stamp which shall be known as the <quote>Veterans Medical Debt Relief Stamp</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D8A24EAD688454F9EAD325327E06381"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The issuance and sale of the Veterans Medical Debt Relief Stamp shall be governed by section 416 of title 39, United States Code, except that—</text><paragraph id="HF6C158F26C72463F8CADD0C9C5CA539E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all amounts becoming available from the sale of the stamp shall be transferred to the Department of Veterans Affairs in accordance with section 416(d) of such title; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF767F2EA14904A80A8DCE651C6322E44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the stamp—</text><subparagraph id="H05409BD6E20741AE8D7F3D1C270C9E35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be issued in time for Veterans Day of each year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H648C0677F2974B31BA12F5ED34C2C120"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall bear such illustration, depiction, design, or other image as the United States Postal Service shall determine; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C2A71775DCF4022A2B916F823D2C8B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall not be subject to any numerical limitation under section 416(e)(1)(C) of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD19EF55857E34A878E9AD1B50F537523"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall disperse all amounts received by the Department of Veterans Affairs under subsection (b)(1) to the applicable Department offices (including the Veterans Health Administration, the Debt Management Center, the Financial Service Center, and the VHA Revenue Operations) for the purpose of paying down veteran medical debt incurred via unresolved copayment and coinsurance billings related to services furnished by the Department and the Community Care Program.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

