<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H980E9CB213D3495D9F2D19F0C387C135" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1205 IH: Encouraging military discounts in honor of the 250th anniversary of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1205</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Encouraging military discounts in honor of the 250th anniversary of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this resolution recognizes the service and sacrifice of members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and their families;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this resolution encourages businesses across the United States to voluntarily offer military appreciation discounts to members of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves, and veterans in honor of the 250th anniversary of the United States in 2026;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the 250th anniversary of the United States represents a historic milestone celebrating the Nation’s founding ideals of freedom, liberty, and democracy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this initiative invites the American private sector to participate in a nationwide gesture of appreciation during the America 250 celebration;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas participation by businesses would be voluntary, requiring no mandates and no taxpayer funding;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Congress encourages small and large businesses to highlight their participation as part of the America 250 celebration;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Congress recognizes that businesses that support the military community strengthen the patriotic and civic traditions of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas encouraging businesses to offer military discounts would directly benefit members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and military families across the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas such efforts would strengthen ties between businesses and military communities nationwide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas small and large businesses continue to be among the most military-supportive sectors in the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States is home to nearly 18,000,000 veterans, along with millions of members of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves, and military families;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas military families are an essential part of the United States economy and local communities across the country;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas voluntary military discounts from businesses provide meaningful everyday financial support to those who serve and have served;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this initiative would encourage widespread participation by businesses in America 250 celebrations across the Nation;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this initiative would help create a visible national culture of appreciation for military service during the 250th anniversary year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this initiative would resonate strongly in communities across the United States, particularly those surrounding major military installations and areas with strong military ties;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas businesses across the United States, from local shops to major retailers, can lead by example in demonstrating the Nation’s longstanding tradition of supporting the Armed Forces;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas supporting veterans and military families remains one of the most bipartisan priorities in Congress and resonates strongly with communities nationwide; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas participating businesses may identify themselves as <quote>America 250 Military Appreciation Businesses</quote>, helping to visibly demonstrate national support for veterans during this historic milestone: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H84AB0F9A4DFB44A79E2D11267AAA8BC9"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF191D97FF41846DE82F6DA4E56F81626"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives to encourage small businesses and major retailers across the United States to voluntarily offer military appreciation discounts to members of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves, and veterans in honor of the 250th anniversary of the United States, as a meaningful and nationwide gesture of appreciation that strengthens communities, supports military families, and upholds the Nation’s enduring commitment to those who have served.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

