<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H0A51956190A747F8B0EAEDC39BDE5965" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4294 : Mitigation Action and Watermen Support Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4294</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a pilot program with respect to the sale of blue catfish caught within the Chesapeake Bay Watershed.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HEAF6431923A6491982B8B430D5730C13"><section id="H2142FB979C164F78B477DE5B968A37BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mitigation Action and Watermen Support Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MAWS Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H94844EA8FBA04EBD9D952DBE81160423" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Blue catfish pilot program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 307 of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1511d">15 U.S.C. 1511d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3306562BEAA7418CBF79F229B4AE63F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F753312343A4443A142076890D3D061"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEBB9E021CD1B492F9CB704A527B09578" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HCB5E7A11B70A4EBEA0C6E609290C198C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Blue catfish pilot program</header><paragraph id="H408CDD7F8A714D9980EA7194F14C832F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, utilizing and coordinating with applicable programs and activities described in subsection (b)(3), shall carry out a pilot program to enter into cooperative agreements with covered entities for such covered entities to purchase, in accordance with paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H4D955BED2C1F4D2AB95FEF11A32AC29D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from watermen, blue catfish caught within the Chesapeake Bay Watershed by such watermen; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5431BCBD564646D988AF01DE301FC491"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from seafood processors, such blue catfish purchased by seafood processors from such watermen.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5389A460E211480C9660191A87F5A80A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to enter into a cooperative agreement under the pilot program, a covered entity shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9494D0EDB1414CF9AFF3D298EC6D7FE1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header><text>A covered entity that enters into a cooperative agreement under the pilot program—</text><subparagraph id="HBB78F683F78949FD9890B9A6E9A1FB36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall use any amounts awarded under such cooperative agreement to purchase blue catfish from watermen or seafood processors for at least the amount determined by the Secretary under paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H126C246250AF4045B09107ECDA417919"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may use not more than 15 percent of such amounts to offset the cost to transport such blue catfish to manufacturing or processing facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85B9A3DFC85F46B1BAC6BD54F6D38802"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waterman and seafood processor eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to sell a blue catfish under the pilot program to a covered entity that enters into a cooperative agreement under the pilot program—</text><subparagraph id="H8205C4734BA744E5B96F94B1AD12E8B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a waterman shall certify to such covered entity that the waterman caught the blue catfish within the Chesapeake Bay Watershed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80E974912DA64469A6A5F72EA30AF4D4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a seafood processor shall certify to such covered entity that the seafood processor purchased the blue catfish from a waterman who caught the blue catfish within the Chesapeake Bay Watershed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA843FD14573426A9FBE8D0C457DB87A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Determination of minimum purchase amount</header><text>With respect to blue catfish sold by watermen or seafood processors under the pilot program, the Secretary shall determine the minimum price per pound, taking into consideration—</text><subparagraph id="HFBB8DF45D4F647DDB0A032B9775844AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>market factors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AC35503ED8F46F5A4D90BB09E36A150"><enum>(B)</enum><text>feedback from watermen, seafood processors, and covered entities that participate in the pilot program, if available; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68F9DAF85DC049F8839BF04E26CC3802"><enum>(C)</enum><text>differentiation of price points for fillet and byproduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H374FC28B7009488A8723BCDB896AA753"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Abundance baseline</header><subparagraph id="H455309410550427FB10169D14E8D70AF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding with eligible non-Federal partners—</text><clause id="H33B1F1CD96E741C394EC257A3029706C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to compile existing non-Federal data necessary for the Secretary—</text><subclause id="H52D21D37E36C448DA6CFC3CA664785F2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to develop under subparagraph (B) an estimate of the abundance of blue catfish in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H46E50D3237F344E5AB3DDF9EB4B6F50B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to provide the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (7) in the report required under that paragraph; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5A1828C8A5964C7FA4C148677BE86257" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to adjust the collection by such eligible non-Federal partners of relevant data such that such data can be used as described in subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H933316DD4045497AB0AB0D951497A314"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Abundance estimates</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2027, and annually thereafter through fiscal year 2032, the Secretary shall develop, pursuant to the memorandum of understanding described in subparagraph (A), and make publicly available on the website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration an estimate of the abundance of blue catfish in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E2874110004B16954BE53331248675"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the pilot program terminates in accordance with paragraph (9), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report regarding the pilot program, including the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H697ACAEBB73F43868C38B64023F47504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A summary of available information regarding the size and spawning stock biomass of the blue catfish population in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed prior to and at the conclusion of the pilot program, using the most recent data available.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H420C14186E2A4F9AB2D88FCCCA98C508"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A summary of available data regarding the size distribution and diet of the blue catfish population in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed during and at the conclusion of the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AAA8ECB5D224A939C940ACCB34B4B4E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of blue catfish and the amount of blue catfish (measured in pounds) caught by watermen who participate in the pilot program during the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB03BDA65998947AB9F4FF26A040D0252"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The effects of the pilot program on species other than the blue catfish in and the environment of the Chesapeake Bay Watershed, to the extent known.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26D979D4EAE24A8DB439D61DAF2BE646"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The economic effect of the pilot program on watermen who participate in the pilot program, including—</text><clause id="H72F1E50ACC824BC4AC3F70F60F80DE85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the revenue generated by each such waterman by selling blue catfish under the pilot program; and</text></clause><clause id="H0D761E03DA1A49299931330B41CCCBA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>catch data with respect to and revenue generated from other species fished by such watermen during the pilot program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55B050666F6A4C278729DFACE54A6ED7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The market response to the pilot program, including—</text><clause id="H83D59F1FC1A1451F88B03566B2F264B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount awarded under the pilot program to covered entities that enter into cooperative agreements under the pilot program; and</text></clause><clause id="H7ACE5D03C7804608AFEDAFE538063D3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trends in the types of such covered entities.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCDF2DB2A5C74EAAA7BFC8C828482871" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the manufacturing or processing practices of each covered entity that enters into a cooperative agreement under the pilot program, information regarding whether each such covered entity—</text><clause id="H43E2CD29D47F4D938875F46315BDD578" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>uses internal or third-party manufacturers or processors;</text></clause><clause id="H8C733A65DDF34749958B0ACF47044209" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>uses, for each type of food product produced by the covered entity, whole fish, fillet, or byproduct; and</text></clause><clause id="H76794C9938FA4418A04C9B8DC44F4D36" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the covered entity uses only part of the fish, sells the remainder to third parties.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C05FC8A45F5474293E7788D6DB01590" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How each covered entity that enters into a cooperative agreement under the pilot program transports blue catfish purchased by the covered entity, including—</text><clause id="H2AEBDADC18FC40CCA2FCCD45CD5476DF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the covered entity freezes such blue catfish;</text></clause><clause id="HC898223A08B14678A8B2A47E6B9BF07A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how often the covered entity picks up such blue catfish; and</text></clause><clause id="HBB653BD28BAB41B5958BFFC36C418DA5" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether the covered entity uses a seafood transport company that is local to the Chesapeake Bay Watershed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79D58EAE557A4AA6AE67600EAEED91B7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Policy recommendations regarding—</text><clause id="HFA3509ADBA0E41299863EC8EBBF5451C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the continuation of the pilot program in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed; and</text></clause><clause id="H4C5B944DED77499B98E0A839137DE5D9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the expansion of the pilot program to other watersheds, including—</text><subclause id="H49B5CA0ADA214B0FB7FA3AC79AF91B36"><enum>(I)</enum><text>best practices;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1911486BA4344FDDA532282B2001D880" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>specific recommendations regarding invasive species of carp in the Mississippi rivershed;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEAEE23750C594FF08290296D156CC5C3" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>with respect to other invasive aquatic species and watersheds that may benefit from the pilot program; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE6FD5A4B907B4FDAAD09E9111A53F969" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other strategies with respect to the mitigation of aquatic invasive species for Congress to consider piloting.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7263CF21930141FF9671FFBE3ACDAC32" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Additional data necessary for Congress to shape related policy, including—</text><clause id="HDE2635D2A9B04D9CA3B7F327412A4F5F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>data—</text><subclause id="H3751A8FE2B2C42D4BD66DDC7E0A956FC" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary was unable to collect; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3F01594FA85747CFBA63B3F57A69B3BD" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not collected by eligible non-Federal partners; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2CD2D804561844759FFB45F191A66544" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations for congressional action to support the collection of relevant data sets.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6191CB4BBA3B4615B1A1CA1ADBE08706"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection and quarterly thereafter until the date on which the pilot program terminates in accordance with paragraph (9), the Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate briefings on the status of the implementation of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2E92ED66C874F0B89718D2559FF8FA8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Duration</header><subparagraph id="H9C28005D81684C1B9ADA20A03F9ED9DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program during the 2-year period that begins on the first day of the fiscal year immediately following the later of the fiscal year in which the Secretary—</text><clause id="HA64AA62F664F4B64A71CF53F828822A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>first makes publicly available the first abundance estimate under paragraph (6); and</text></clause><clause id="H61EA5B956FE847FCB8823AFABA99094B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>issues guidance under subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H238226137AFA4A8FA9D098B3E96D36AA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary, in consultation with the Chesapeake Bay Program Invasive Catfish Workgroup and the heads of relevant Federal agencies with experience administering similar programs, shall issue guidance for the pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD577231259044C1D885594CC4C093FCA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H42666136E96E4433BC353FA18BF92DAD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Animal feed</header><text>The term <term>animal feed</term>—</text><clause id="H9861CC2A4B3C44278CB0C51676797CBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means an article that is intended for use—</text><subclause id="H52BBFAEE13524DD3AD75CE8FC341334A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for food for an animal other than man; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC8BEE0B2EF6644EB859114AAA6FB277E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as a substantial source of nutrients in the diet of such an animal; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE577F858025E4B6FA7C4919F6159B21F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not limited to a mixture intended to be the sole ration of such an animal.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27739F1043A4437CBA5B8233B8DA6CD4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aquaculture feed</header><text>The term <term>aquaculture feed</term>—</text><clause id="H9D74F2957C5440F4B859B8EA551B184C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means an article that is intended for use—</text><subclause id="HADEC95B8B3124A4DA0778270BE7C88D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for food for an aquacultural species, including any species of finfish, mollusk, crustacean (or other aquatic invertebrate), amphibian, reptile, ornamental fish, or aquatic plant that is propagated and reared in a controlled or selected environment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2E32FABB0BF54D778645F009910DC7A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as a substantial source of nutrients in the diet of such an aquacultural species; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7EA276485AB6474BBBDAE2A3D9BCA447"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not limited to a mixture intended to be the sole ration of such an aquacultural species.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1CB2EC9AAEF4E11B01013A06E86A33D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Blue catfish</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>blue catfish</term> means the species Ictalurus furcatus.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C852F0BE4784AF5890BCEC0B31CC1E7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Chesapeake Bay Watershed</header><text>The term <term>Chesapeake Bay Watershed</term> means the region that covers—</text><clause id="H641A84E7AB624A5C8F6683BAF8ECEF97"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Chesapeake Bay;</text></clause><clause id="H48B5E412599341C8BD4185FEC34DA453"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the portions of the States of Delaware, Maryland, New York, Pennsylvania, Virginia, and West Virginia that drain into the Chesapeake Bay; and</text></clause><clause id="H4D451888174542E58A5F02C8BB2A886B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the District of Columbia.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497ED2EE785A4AC097E550428B6A7FA2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means a person engaged in the business of manufacturing or processing—</text><clause id="HF71BC945CC6943739050D4A73A732FF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pet food;</text></clause><clause id="H9F84960BD54B4B5DA1C92C5B3ECC36BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>animal feed; or</text></clause><clause id="HDAF02B4D2CE24CF0B4ADE98DEFCED52F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>aquaculture feed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2188B182560144C184F0DCC8B9DDBE14"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Eligible non-Federal partner</header><text>The term <term>eligible non-Federal partner</term> means—</text><clause id="HF13CF751A08040718C984126723C3355"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Maryland;</text></clause><clause id="H947B404A97584EBA8DC0F6C21F27662C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Virginia; and</text></clause><clause id="HFC79AE4B47DB4AE397075BBACCA815AB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>research institutions, including research institutions with expertise in—</text><subclause id="HA1C9B113FA2C47B88CFB72D3E73B0443"><enum>(I)</enum><text>blue catfish research in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H86E682EC9ADC4C7EA3BDBA7258EABDFB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>acting in coordination with the Invasive Catfish Workgroup of the Chesapeake Bay Program.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C9AE70CEC6F4B5A91558CB28B737EB2"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>The term <term>pilot program</term> means the pilot program established under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2EF2B576DBD4C25B27977C8AA54FFE4"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Seafood processor</header><text>The term <term>seafood processor</term> means a person engaged in the business of preparing or packaging fish or fish products (including fish harvested by the processor) for sale.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37A9F9B948B14270ACD891E260A2F07D"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260317" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 17, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

