<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73EDE857C350498491C6D7A2406AA76B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8512 IH: To amend the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 to extend the authorities of title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 through April 20, 2029, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8512</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 to extend the authorities of title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 through April 20, 2029, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H935FE1EDAAD644D080AEDD16F2C75BFD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H79FAD56015C348B8A74F5A5CCEAA1E16" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Extension of authorities of title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978</header> 
<subsection id="H74C04914FB474D0FAABC47DE609E4275">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Extension of repeal date of title VII</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 403(b) of the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/261">Public Law 110–261</external-xref>), as most recently amended by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/84">Public Law 119–84</external-xref>, is further amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="H5518094BA2044DB680E3DDD15B115F96">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881">50 U.S.C. 1881</external-xref> note) by striking <quote>April 30, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>April 20, 2029</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H30E0F703A6344E2EB30174E92E1117D1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2511">18 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref> note), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>April 30, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>April 20, 2029</quote>.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1396C7F6D01482E8E91D5827EE476B4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the earlier of the date of the enactment of this Act or April 29, 2026.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H16D0074CA11743A19960F777931C8FBA" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Warrant requirement for targeting for acquisition communications of United States persons</header> <subsection id="H237FFCD699864360A7BE46A8EA40E0EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of subsection (n) of section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3CAC63A0E37F4DC1BE34ADC2DC51228A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HFD6098FA7A2F4BB48DE6454D8E8041D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Bureau of Investigation may not ingest unminimized information acquired under this section into its analytic repositories unless the targeted person is relevant to an existing, open, predicated full national security investigation by the Federal Bureau of Investigation. If the subject of such predicated, full national security investigation is a United States person, for purposes of this paragraph, the investigation must be supported by probable cause.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H0305E15A9FDA41F5B5CA74DC0D033EF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Section 702 of such Act is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0E5C5C8120A944E2812421FB59D584B8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H580B9208E66549D982AD2B61BB5972C1"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Warrant requirement for certain targeting</header> 
<paragraph id="HA62074EDD9A04C959226F4A50BB5CD5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to subsection (b), no officer or employee of the United States Government may intentionally target for acquisition the communications of a United States person pursuant to an authorization issued under subsection (a). Pursuant to other provisions of this Act and the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, the Government may seek a warrant or other appropriate order supported by a probable cause showing to target for collection the communications of a United States person if there exists probable cause that the United States person to whom such communications relate—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D83A71EBD8741D88BBFF63375362D5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a foreign power or an agent of foreign power, in which circumstances the Government may seek authorization for electronic surveillance in accordance with title I, a physical search in accordance with title III, or for acquisitions in accordance with section 703, 704, or 705; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F46BF9F8CF649B6A7B89EB5718AAA8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is committing or has committed a crime, in which circumstances the Government may seek a warrant issued pursuant to the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EAF06D4D66C4B54BFDB703C53D764C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures and standards</header><text>The Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence shall jointly establish procedures and standards for officers and employees of the United States Government to determine the existence of probable cause described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA874DC07AF6E4D848E9AE77E97976A10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Government under any applicable laws or the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HABB9D9EF6C7746389502AF074807DAF3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 706(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881e">50 U.S.C. 1881e(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB1140E0D058B40C0BECAFD8228AA4526" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H1B632C9D846348319C0F6D3326AC6B13" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information concerning a United States person acquired under section 702 may not be used in evidence against that United States person pursuant to paragraph (1) in any criminal proceeding if such information was acquired in violation of subsection (o) of such section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HE21F2BFBA2B844D0AB475618AE0DE975" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional criminal penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 709 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881h">50 U.S.C. 1881h</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows (and conform the table of contents at the beginning of such Act accordingly):</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H958F1832A0494B59955E88B2F6DCE27C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H99A6014039194C1D88EEE5F689479FB9" commented="no"><enum>709.</enum><header>Penalties for unauthorized disclosure and other actions</header> 
<subsection id="H32C367E1DA5D45429E2491A12EBE01A5" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offenses</header> 
<paragraph id="H4ED78C37D8F440779610D16FCFEC51A2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unauthorized disclosure or retention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person is guilty of an offense under this paragraph if that person knowingly and willfully—</text> <subparagraph id="HDF0336BD97BF4A5790A92A77F1BBA19F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>communicates, furnishes, transmits, or otherwise makes available to an unauthorized person, or publishes, or uses in any manner prejudicial to the safety or interest of the United States or for the benefit of any foreign government to the detriment of the United States any classified information that contains the contents of any communication acquired under this title to which a known United States person is a party; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H334748ABF8434CDCBEFA7B593404B3C1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retains with specific intent to violate, without authorization, including by approved procedures, any classified information that contains the contents of any communication acquired under this title to which a known United States person is a party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA450B3F53494ECBA0695A616AC03727" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unauthorized query</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person is guilty of an offense under this paragraph if that person, while serving as an officer or employee of a department or agency of the United States, with specific intent to violate this paragraph, willfully conducts a United States person query of information acquired under section 702(a), knowing that the query does not support a duly authorized purpose within the scope of the authority of such department or agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80AF60A201844BADB872A236EFA53535" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Falsifies or misrepresents compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person is guilty of an offense under this paragraph if that person knowingly and willfully, with specific intent to violate this paragraph, falsifies a record, or makes a material misrepresentation to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review, regarding compliance with the procedures or requirements for querying information acquired under section 702(a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F315C22DF664EABB457586967FF97CD" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header> <paragraph id="H556DEBE724B44E8C896D9F2DE926C87A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unauthorized disclosure or retention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person guilty of an offense in subsection (a)(1) shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 8 years, or both.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF14CFB6298984A8A8FF934EB31F59585" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unauthorized query</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person guilty of an offense in subsection (a)(2) shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88821F69AD294B26A4B050DD0E6D6287" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Falsifies or misrepresents compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person guilty of an offense in subsection (a)(3) shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD355B7B7454442CBF918E0BACB4CAF6" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Defenses</header> 
<paragraph id="HE64C3C8E459A46C48701EA676856BC4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unauthorized query</header><text>It is a defense to a prosecution under subsection (a)(2) that—</text> <subparagraph id="H62E6629F346C4CADAC2C12703E26D2B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the defendant conducted the query in the course of the official duties of the person and such query was authorized by a supervisor, attorney, or member of the Senior Executive Service (or equivalent); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF463FEEE98B8400AA9A94B04D756720F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such query was conducted pursuant to a duly authorized purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F3E57F20F0841F8981D0BBC6D5E7E8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Misrepresents compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is a defense to a prosecution under subsection (a)(3) that the defendant made the misrepresentation in the course of the official duties of the person and such misrepresentation was authorized by a supervisor, attorney, or member of the Senior Executive Service (or equivalent), or that the defendant made the misrepresentation acting based on a good faith understanding of the authorities, in compliance with approved procedures, and the facts known to the individual at the time.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H69186F196D96482597299792A604CDCD" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is Federal jurisdiction over an offense under this section if the person committing the offense was an officer or employee of the United States at the time the offense was committed.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HA7A827EEA0D1437E867E7ACF309321F0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Attendance procedures for Member access to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court and Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDCC3AA1497A648E681D8BC7205B52792"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revoke the procedures issued by the Attorney General on or before December 31, 2025, pursuant to section 5(d) of the Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/49">Public Law 118–49</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1803">50 U.S.C. 1803</external-xref> note); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5CA5D0FF0E64D40AA0D8F033FDA6A33"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue new procedures that comply with such section and ensure the access of the Members of Congress and staff specified in such section to any proceeding of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or any proceeding of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF12F2983779F4776B1D04C1679507F27"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requirement for attorney approval of FBI queries using United States person query term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 702(f)(3)(A)(i) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(f)(3)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>supervisor (or employee of equivalent or greater rank) or</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H92CAF548DAF1442C9AEDD64FB32AA961" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office audit of targeting procedures under section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978</header> <subsection id="H8A157D9D8B494B81B05437903042B1F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States, consistent with the protection of sensitive sources and methods, shall conduct an audit of the targeting procedures used for acquisitions under section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>), including the technical mechanisms, implementation, and operations used by the Federal Government for targeting capabilities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1AD4CA409D6D400BA59FFF51153146E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report containing the results of the audit required by subsection (a), including an analysis of whether the targeting procedures as implemented are appropriately limiting targeting under section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>) to non-United States persons located outside of the United States.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

