<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG26B20-VWM-GM-LRS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4681 IS: Optimizing Acquisition Strategies for Integrated Security in the Middle East Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to take action to improve air and missile defense acquisition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id91b002de0c734f5e97acfadb7d9d396f" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Optimizing Acquisition Strategies for Integrated Security in the Middle East Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>OASIS Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6138bbc1888a4d2298c8d1739b40669e" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to air and missile defense acquisition</header><subsection id="id005090f55e174880b4425232df6dca0f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment of air and missile defense systems and interceptors</header><paragraph id="idb150d16cd4fd4a4e8a735f1d9aab8c3d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36d336704d294486951c8286b8ef6ec0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complete an assessment of United States and foreign specified partner air and missile defense systems and interceptors in the area of responsibility of the United States Central Command; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65d8c7d820f043f9ad9280a6392e8211"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the findings of the Secretary with respect to the assessment completed under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa0edcf0f947449b8139fff6a5a26c59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) shall include the following</text><subparagraph id="iddb9b78d9e6144090aaa9321d3091ffad"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of current air and missile defense systems and interceptors used by the United States and foreign specified partners to defend against attacks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d2cd1705a484fae8be85261e131f903"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of current inventories and production rates of air and missile defense systems and interceptors produced by the United States and foreign specified partners.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c260c63dce8477f9149320fefc1fb6e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the number of air and missile defense systems deployed and interceptors expended to defend against attacks within the area of responsibility of the United States Central Command since October 7, 2023, disaggregated by—</text><clause id="id55cd983150bf489c9bbe69212de84f78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="id7d42273688634bac81535450c8f0b50c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>foreign specified partners.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id562e129052204aa1a661df16af11c63b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of the air and missile defense systems within the area of the responsibility of the United States Central Command that have been damaged or destroyed in attacks since October 7, 2023.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id111ebd8cfcd94da7b6012ad592afe8c9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of the air and missile defense systems and interceptors developed and produced by the United States for which the United States defense industry cannot fulfill the orders placed by foreign specified partners so as to necessitate acquisition from other sources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4797fd9b01bb418592ebf031eb12961c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><paragraph id="id9af19bd6d05449e7a16845f1eb81b964"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State, submit to the congressional defense committees a strategy and implementation plan for cooperation with foreign specified partners to implement a multinational air and missile defense system and interceptor acquisition strategy to defend United States nationals and assets and foreign specified partners from attacks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ffa9e49d8c6416d913887f55d3844eb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy and implementation plan submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id4f62abeca0b645839e0ab5e7819d11b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of current efforts by the United States to engage foreign specified partners to prioritize air and missile defense needs, including coordination—</text><clause id="idb3031b38b7334136a8357cc8f5f5af52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to replenish interceptor stock supplies;</text></clause><clause id="idd4e9eed2450b4a5495d7d0c3e17e7130"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to facilitate the transfer and delivery of air and missile defense systems from the United States to foreign specified partners; and</text></clause><clause id="id5d91b3370ff644fdb8ab927c74fdc2f4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to increase air and missile defense system and interceptor supply bases located within the area of responsibility of Untied States Central Command.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00519d97151b47dda9e723a52f78363e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>An assessment of the feasibility and cost of creating an air and missile defense system and interceptor stockpile located within the area of responsibility of United States Central Command to be exclusively used by—</text>
                        <clause id="id0ecc2065c9d24c54bc1798c32b707d90">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the United States; and</text> </clause> <clause id="id762f6e8b66b24c77bd774f28bb735648"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>foreign specified partners. </text>
                        </clause>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3fcaed38d8c4b8a9170f45febba6d7d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the feasibility of establishing joint ventures, licensing agreements, and co-production and manufacturing partnerships between the United States and foreign specified partners to accelerate the production of air and missile defense systems and interceptors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide6a0a622f55b4f5aa8c010327015a6e8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An identification of steps that can be taken to accelerate the joint research, development, acquisition, and transfer of alternative or lower-cost interceptor solutions and complementary air and missile defense capabilities between the United States and foreign specified partners, and the co-production of interceptors in the United States, where feasible.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd00878a5c4c44581bcb192260be759fb"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An analysis of the legal, economic, and defense policy aspects of a closer air and missile defense acquisition partnership between the United States and foreign specified partners.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ea101c75caa4ac5be4c792be3ce4b1c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An analysis of lessons learned from air defense efforts in regional theaters, including Ukraine, the Middle East and North Africa, the Caucasus, and the Horn of Africa.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b3656fc5456465aaa973541aa6a14ff"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Protection of sensitive information</header><text>The strategy and plan submitted under paragraph (1) shall provide that any activity carried out pursuant to the strategy and plan is conducted in a manner that is consistent with protection of intelligence sources and methods and appropriately protects sensitive information and the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd51943664f434ad9aeb878b9919848f3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy and implementation plan submitted under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id924fa85589244a89baee3daa619f6f98"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Missile Defense Agency regional working group</header><paragraph id="idefeb24dc17ea4c3c83a0069480b640e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idada89dc476c1443a9bc89a3f0f864d2c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall, in consultation with the commander of United States Central Command, and the Secretary of State, establish a working group—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide50f139f83ac4417bb26f5ffb92934da" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to facilitate the systematic and regular sharing of lessons learned on the battlefield to inform future air and missile defense requirements, including research, development, testing, evaluation, production, procurement, training, and doctrine; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="ida66619a0bfc74f5c90c70bf89ba7e20c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to integrate ideas, policies, proposals, findings, and best practices into regional strategy and other relevant regional planning documents relating to missile defense.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a13eb282da1450c8fe047a43e7321fa" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The working group established under subparagraph (A) shall be known as the <quote>Multilateral Middle East Missile and Drone Defense Working Group</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="iddf7d7d9cfa3843a9b4c606b89816137a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Working Group shall consist of representatives of the following:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef12d6aa65c84e119cd787af126e2c1a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id359d7244f19a40e7882a3f66d4ff2295"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Foreign specified partners.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4f5111550764ed5a7a1ed8d5b2bb795"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such others as the Director considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ab38f898430424b8fa129fbc6c22a65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties and responsibilities of Director</header><text>The Director shall, in consultation with the Commander of United States Central Command, lead the working group and be responsible for regularly engaging with foreign specified partners to exchange information and develop best practices to expand upon existing efforts to integrate air and missile defenses and to replenish and expand interceptor inventories and air and missile defense capacity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88bd4ca815764f1896bb18151edb72e7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Convening</header><text>The Working Group shall convene not less frequently than once every six months, with meeting frequency determined by the Director, in consultation with the Commander of United States Central Command and foreign specified partners.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b838b285a3f4e6e90d6f95f098435e7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idb9f497e8fa71457c94aea08e79c938e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than one year after the date of the establishment of the Working Group, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Director shall, in consultation with the commander of the United States Central Command, submit to the congressional defense committees an annual report on the activities of the Working Group.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c3523bfe5bc4408b698136515b98f7f" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text><clause id="idb283f5c7a0f4425a833c03456dcfce8d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A list of partner governments participating in the Working Group and a description of the degree of participation of each partner.</text></clause><clause id="id2aa6e1cf16f14bd6aaaeacf2cf3a3647"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the meetings conducted.</text></clause><clause id="id7325705bb380476b9ed7449e905794c2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A summary of battlefield lessons learned shared through the Working Group, including lessons derived from operations against attacks in the area of responsibility of United States Central Command.</text></clause><clause id="id504e01be8f3245339ced9f473b364b43"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>An identification of capability gaps among the United States and foreign specified partners and recommendations for how such gaps should be addressed to inform future air and missile defense requirements.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb2054a2e4dc3458a8abf96ee4d93038a"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Such recommendations for legislative or administrative action as the Director may have to improve the effectiveness of the Working Group.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e100586a27a4985a2c18f36f0e0d38a" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in an unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddc7fc65ed7d94f3787b43a36938ec55a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="idcf7cbb2cd24f4efd8240c6390012cd42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>air and missile defense systems</term> means air and missile defense articles, unmanned aerial defense articles, rocket defense articles, including kinetic and nonkinetic capabilities, and all of their component parts, including command and control centers, sensors, radars, and launchers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44e285a559b549f0b7cef25378a5813a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>attacks</term> means missile, manned and unmanned aerial system, and rocket attacks from Iran and armed groups linked to Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b0a6f508ed94783880c98acbfbd7535"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f65324b85934d37a240b170c0453a0c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>foreign specified partners</term> means allies and partners in the area of responsibility of the United States Central Command.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12dcee5fa03f429bbb38f8e95657e0fe"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>interceptors</term> means air and missile, unmanned aerial, nonkinetic payloads, and rocket defense articles designed to detect, track, disable, or destroy incoming missiles, manned and unmanned aerial systems, and rockets.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

