<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07D8FB5A1093459C9A7D807364418500" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8837 IH: Retirement Investment in Small Employers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8837</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a microemployer pension plan startup credit, to permit the assignment of small business pension plan startup credits, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5EAA0C001F444B21A0F62F91E5502149" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC06241BE31884684ACA7C8662B3B8A1C" section-type="section-one"> <enum>1.</enum> <header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Retirement Investment in Small Employers Act</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>RISE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="HD3CF3DFAFC144F1F8052C14204336294"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Microemployer pension plan startup credit</header> 
<subsection id="H7B358599C44C455DB9BABADB9BB28016" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45E">Section 45E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB871E9234F0A45F1B12AED049BA2562A"> <subsection id="H86DC9C2CEC0C40FEB41876A9F302F324"> <enum>(g)</enum> <header>Credit for microemployers</header> <paragraph id="HB81DCC1CFF934979840F6DFA6DBC9518" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text>In the case of a qualified microemployer—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H490D1FDB276E4E9086222740B849F70F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>100 percent</quote> for <quote>50 percent</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA96EA58C583B465F9D4F93DC94241E1D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsection (b)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$2,500</quote> for <quote>$500</quote> in subparagraph (A) thereof.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B0A93DE0AEA43EF94466AC1E16D9AFD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Qualified microemployer</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified microemployer</term> means an employer which would be an eligible employer if section 408(p)(2)(C)(i)(I) were applied by substituting <quote>10</quote> for <quote>100</quote>, but only if the eligible employer plan established or maintained by such employer, under the terms of the plan, accepts payment of the matching contribution under section 6433.</text>
                        </paragraph> </subsection> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block> </quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC84A9D74EB2474996F63367FF1F465F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Effective date</header> <text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H7A5DB48B945D4AF28EDF4B64EC2D4F48"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assignment of small business pension plan startup credits</header> <subsection id="HF767D5CF8C7246CCA5B7FDFC1E4AF8EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45E">Section 45E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 2, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4ACBEE3FE7DB4D9191CB309D674D5FE5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H563EBED9CD0041939248A58E2543CEFC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Credit for eligible service providers</header> 
<paragraph id="HF45A229373614D32838D0E629C5D5129"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible entity that provides services with respect to an eligible employer plan, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount determined under paragraph (2) for each of the first 3 credit years with respect to such plan, provided that the requirements of this subsection are satisfied.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF03C1328ABE84F84AE64D7FFE3ECD092"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of credit</header> <subparagraph id="HB9031EA629A04EA4B615D80A8BF4AAB4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the credit allowed under this subsection for any taxable year shall be equal to the credit that would have been allowable to the eligible employer under subsection (a) for such taxable year (determined without regard to subsection (f)), subject to the limitations of subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96437EDF14EB48E2BCB8A9595E5CC37D">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Determination of credit years</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>credit year</quote> means, with respect to a plan, the taxable year of the eligible entity which includes the date that the eligible employer plan becomes effective with respect to the eligible employer and the two taxable years immediately following such taxable year.</text>
                            </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81AF3A1EAC6E4A23B7E3731AC84D245F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means, with respect to the plan for which the credit is allowed under subsection (a), an entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="H94212B8C694F4291BDA802E38BB1AAC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to the plan, provides services that generate qualified startup costs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB88A61DDEF9D449480AB45E6F7972B68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduces the amount of fees that would otherwise be charged to the eligible employer for such services by an amount not less than the credit determined under paragraph (2) for the taxable year; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91EA9017D36343E88ED7A846A7752EFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtains the certification described in paragraph (4) prior to claiming the credit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD1704261C484A329C18AF3547FD8C95"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employer certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The certification described in this paragraph is a written certification that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0201380DCA1D4B8FAEA65CF552F8C357"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is made by the eligible employer not later than the date on which the services generating the qualified startup costs for the plan for which the credit is allowed under subsection (a) are provided; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECC54C446C484EED9B9C7F699EE15170"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> <clause id="H008831A328C843C2A98C8C80BF5AE814"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of employees of the eligible employer who are not highly compensated employees (as defined in section 414(q)) and who are eligible to participate in the eligible employer plan maintained by the eligible employer as of the date such plan is established;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2C832F33EE564A7EB7F476FC48AFAF24"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that neither the employer nor any predecessor established or maintained a qualified employer plan with respect to which contributions were made, or benefits were accrued, for substantially the same employees as are in the qualified employer plan during the 3-taxable year period immediately preceding the 1st taxable year for which the credit under this section is otherwise allowable for the qualified employer plan;</text></clause> <clause id="H1242B3AC3166490498C6C45E1B37F50D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that the employer will not claim a tax credit for qualified start up costs with respect to the plan for any taxable year;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB96CB56733FD44E0AA6893852151C5C2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that the employer has not provided a certification to any other service provider for purposes of claiming tax credits with respect to the plan; and</text></clause> <clause id="H55960386BE17425DAEF6BC2BDCFA4FCD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require in published regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22A3E430E2484FCB9C60FE5B27BA7773"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination with credit to employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) to an eligible employer with respect to a plan for which a credit is allowed under this subsection to an eligible entity with respect to such plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F0E523042B0450294D913EBF2241A9D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tax treatment of payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the reduction in fees described in paragraph (3)(B), such payment—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC33B1778449E494885AD99416CEB777B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be includible in the gross income of the employer, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DA406DF64BB49D6ABBA62683EE9C41F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the eligible entity, shall not be deductible under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38D7403ED29E44E4A9598E4D9D2D5B9A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Certain other requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tax credit allowed to an eligible entity under paragraph (1) will not be reduced in taxable years following the first credit year due to a change in the number of employees of the eligible employer described in subparagraph (b)(1)(B)(i).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H103F8334003F40819E5E2A0DC72E4233"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Recapture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the amount received by an eligible entity with respect to a qualified plan is greater than the credit under subsection (a) that would otherwise (but for this subsection) be allowable to such employer with respect to such qualified plan, for example because the employer is not an eligible employer or incorrectly certifies the number of employees under (4)(B)(i), the tax imposed on such eligible entity under this chapter for the taxable year in which the credit is received with respect to such qualified plan shall be increased by the amount by which the credit received exceeds the amount that would otherwise (but for this subsection) be allowable to such employer.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C24C3280C804D81971A6177A3CCCF23" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Effective date</header> <text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

