<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H792151861E5943DABEC3BCB9122BFA69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6599 IH: Leasing and Infrastructure Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6599</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish an independent authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into leases for major medical facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3705DA5702DF4BD0942CC7BBBB3D36F9" style="OLC"><section id="H3FFFC885173846CDB8ED7D24BF4949A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leasing and Infrastructure Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0EEFEA0A91F44190B7058003EC5EB1D4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Independent authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into leases for major medical facilities; establishment of Veterans Leasing Fund</header><subsection id="HE51F78B705E9451B9CB5FE742023E9E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent authority</header><text>Section 8103 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7D876B63FE7E4566B023A7C227E76C84" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HE1DB384054224A3C9454B3ED35F8E01B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Independent leasing authority</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5A7F16CEB91247D1BA76A573B390C6BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 3307 of title 40, the Secretary may enter into a lease for any major medical facility (as defined in section 8104 of this title) without delegation from the Administrator of General Services, if the prospectus for such a lease has been—</text><subparagraph id="H9D817AA72DE345209D74F79AF5DDCAD1" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approved by the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB54E841E05B44250ACD0D3ED0BEBF806" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transmitted concurrently to—</text><clause id="HB03BB8C3F87343A99C467BC383587F75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="H0698A8B6B194433980D0617E90582D98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9DFBED40AF44293BA91605DEBB7A2E0" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE78296FA430F46F0B3EFD3AF443CAA32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The firm term of a lease under this subsection may not exceed 20 years. No lease under this subsection may be extended beyond the firm term unless—</text><clause id="H6ABED52D4FAE400C914553A3BEE1D9AE" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such extension is authorized in the prospectus; or</text></clause><clause id="H7658D6D662A4482B9FB22BA0C0CA3B13" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Congress approves such extension.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC6261AE7CBE464CB551F70D9941930A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>firm term</quote> means the initial, non-cancellable lease period approved in the prospectus.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CBDEEBBC3224EC7ADA8C758D7E78E65" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A lease under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HC09A138BCACC405EB3CB75C049AD72FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be executed only to the extent and in the amount provided in advance in the Veterans Leasing Fund established by subsection (j); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10CA4D58174042FAB9885175B5471337"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be scored and funded in accordance with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3604D11CD5D3407C8B8188C638D98BBD" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5051709443B04729B3CE43C1BEC05748"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In exercising the authority under this subsection, the Secretary shall, for each purpose-built medical facility constructed pursuant to a lease awarded under this subsection in each locality, submit to Congress accurate, market-based cost estimates. Such estimates shall—</text><clause id="H788F6DBC72F34222B559172FDBB437BA" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>account for construction costs, material costs, and land acquisition costs; and</text></clause><clause id="H1EADB762D612470CBBAAE83EAAA40996" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be informed by qualified sources, including licensed appraisers, valuation experts, professional estimating firms, or commercial real estate firms.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7CA91F0E7424123B104F9C1E4CB7543" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary may also request technical assistance from the Administrator of General Services with respect to market surveys, cost estimation, or lease scoring.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H015E284FF3304618A8BD92DA789732C1" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If, at any point in the procurement process (including during cost estimation, the expression of interest phase, or upon receipt of pricing from offerors) projected costs exceed approved estimates by more than ten percent, or exceed any congressional budget authority, the Secretary shall, not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary is notified of such projected costs, submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works a notification that such projected costs exceed approved estimates or congressional budget authority, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7976B7D6CD3841378464A626BAEBB97D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Veterans leasing fund</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H14EB649C8DDD4EC0894A02E42B4D3812"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is established in the Treasury a revolving fund to be known as the <quote>Veterans Leasing Fund</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71BA5B079DE54BF38E6D2589BF8E332C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There shall be deposited in the Fund—</text><subparagraph id="HDE70CCA55CD74B02A75CE75CA50D895C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>amounts appropriated for the purpose of carrying out the independent leasing authority under subsection (i); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C502DADFB8B411C90311F5F5730F569"><enum>(B)</enum><text>amounts transferred, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, from the <quote>Medical Facilities</quote> account of the Department (or any successor account) for the payment of annual rent, taxes, or operating costs for leases executed under subsection (i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H198325A355FB4616ACA6B753819DBD75" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Amounts in the Fund are hereby made available as contract authority to enter into obligations to carry out subsection (i), including obligations in advance of receipts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C31322A1B0C4C7686E6EB0E23124D85" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary may obligate amounts in the Fund for rental payments, tenant improvements, real-estate taxes, operating expenses, and pre-award due diligence costs, including design, environmental, and professional service fees associated with leases entered into pursuant to subsection (i).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B4F18292CB74E1EBE3B64E5FEEAB4E5" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary shall include, in the annual budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department—</text><subparagraph id="H5A1D01565CF54B42A057F3D3050BA988" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the projected unobligated balance of the Fund;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C958048D5B74290B923B1C91260CCD7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>new obligations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88D8792E620342F69F8EA68B881BA791" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collections for the year covered by such budget justification materials and the four fiscal years succeeding such year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8861DC8D6AD4577911B4C0D69677386" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>One-Year target for lease awards; annual report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6BEA42EE7290419C86133CE14C1D5F2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, award a lease for a major medical facility not later than not later than the end of the one year period beginning on the date on which the Secretary issues a solicitation for the lease agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70BD0521128A4CCEAABAEDA76A6DC28F" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall revise internal guidance, milestone reviews, and approval workflows to—</text><subparagraph id="HDEAFD2B7451A4A3FBCFDFC1BFEB80876" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support the requirement under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDAAACCEDE044AC6AB39B429ED81D5FE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eliminate duplicative or sequential reviews that delay procurement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1B26FBE9C7F40898061C4C1130558CB" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A contracting officer may not issue a solicitation described in paragraph (1) unless, before the date of issuance, the officer has placed in the official contract file a written certification that—</text><subparagraph id="H74B31BCD52D447E087AD1FD57244F8CF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sufficient funds are obligated to cover all due diligence and pre-award professional services reasonably anticipated for the project, including environmental, geotechnical, title, survey, appraisal, brokerage, and architectural-engineering services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36786E28DCDA46CCA73537B2D3D089AC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each such service is available for task-order issuance within 30 days under an existing indefinite-delivery, indefinite-quantity contract or other competitively-awarded vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBE67585E4A94AB8B3B593E2ECF576BB" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Obligations under paragraph (3) may be made from the Veterans Leasing Fund established in subsection (j) or from other appropriations for medical facilities that are available for the applicable fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6946FC6ECC734BD5A30E0B7B799DC0C8" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H50C148E0DA2F41A59F2A4E3B4AC545D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>As part of the public notice during the expression of interest phase of the acquisition process, the Secretary shall require each prospective developer to provide price estimates, including the cost of land, to enable the Department to evaluate whether projected costs are at or below the unserviced shell rent authorized in the approved prospectus.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AE0A479C47F43A9A84A4C49E8C6DF6F" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H274B1390CA294BBD99F48C5EB085C706"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If such estimates exceed such amount authorized, the Secretary shall, not later than 14 days after the date on which the Secretary completes such evaluation, submit to Congress a notification that such estimates exceed such authorized amount.</text></clause><clause id="HEB285CD397FD42D68FD5917F8492091A" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Not later than 45 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the notification under clause (i), the Department shall finalize a plan to address the discrepancy between such estimates and such authorized amount, which may include—</text><subclause id="H7B3B9FF298C04F6B8FC7C9B00E21B22A" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reducing the scope of the project;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF9863A7EB6434761930B1C5DA27CB005" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>requesting additional budget authority; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF4FE8C8FF0474B19A7EEDF6AA14BFB4B" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>postponing, or canceling the project, as appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE756E85E52646FFB41C15FF9F52FA1D" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall, not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the notification under subparagraph (B), notify prospective offerors of the potential effect to procurement timelines, including the estimated release date of the request for lease proposals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB92B6AE79D4BD1AD5DD1B74E573C46" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary shall include, in any request for a lease proposal made pursuant to the leasing authority under subsection (i)—</text><subparagraph id="H5BFB23F708614958915AB90E5518D292" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the procurement milestones applicable to such request; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9F40C743F084E7A92FA4BA5301DE697" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement that a reimbursement under paragraph (7) would become effective on the date that is one year after the date on which the Secretary issued such request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92EDF9DFCB4E403792F47939C63ECB90" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE1D243F057DD48C4984D65164132A6BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the Secretary does not award a lease pursuant to a request for a lease proposal before the date that is one year after the date on which the Secretary issued such request, the Secretary shall be required to reimburse each prospective lessor in the competitive range for costs directly associated with the delay in awarding the lease.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EAB58F6402F4147A19270EF95507217" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any reimbursement under subparagraph (A) shall be calculated based on one percent annually (paid in equal monthly installments of one-twelfth of one percent) of the average land acquisition cost, as proposed by all offerors remaining in the competitive range under the request.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CCE7193C6164930851A312822746F5F" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Payment of such reimbursements under this paragraph shall cease—</text><clause id="H75F03FA6BBDD4770982562D6EE5EFCC5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>immediately upon the award of the lease; or</text></clause><clause id="H7646E2687890432482800633B8A34766" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the project is cancelled, if applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6B8193DB94B489AB484A49CE48A9BA3" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary shall issue guidance establishing documentation requirements and procedures for administering reimbursements under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C338BFA618A4AB3AB1924E96D610A11" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HEF1A3C1BF6024EED8A326C65575D9893" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of each major medical facility lease for which a request was issued during the preceding calendar year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H991683BA609D48D3884F280A58D45D26" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement of whether the lease was awarded within the one year period described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13DE1051EB6F4C119EB0AB552E2E974A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for any lease not awarded within such period, an explanation of the reasons the lease was not awarded during such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E6285E052F74C3E9F35640A3AF9CA89" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall issue internal guidance that establishes the policies and thresholds the Secretary determines necessary to administer the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9890A0558634B83A02E93A49A680542"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Revisions To design guides</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4F77770647C14345BB14F9B6D5BDB4F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, and not less frequently than once every five years thereafter, the Secretary shall revise the design guides of the Department applicable to outpatient clinics and other leased medical facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2640550B20334452AAD2ADF99A772255" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with subject matter experts, including health care professionals and representatives of the private health care industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50CE733D456B43788EDEB7586DC3A7CB" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any revision to design guides conducted pursuant to this section shall not be over-engineered or unnecessarily prescriptive specifications unless required for clinical safety, functional performance, or applicable building codes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B1A758F501C4BE0BDB135E771627C12" commented="no"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Mitigation of risk premiums</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2B85491EA16248E1AFA74FFB8B137F22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may include in a lease agreement under this chapter terms that mitigate risk premiums to the Department, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3C76A70453A942F0803EAEB21BD386F7" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>post-occupancy self-insurance arrangements by the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEAA19925EC246D4824CFBF55B2712B5" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reimbursement to a prospective lessor for reasonable holding costs incurred as a result of delays attributable to the Department in excess of established procurement milestones;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73FB0936235D42958B52D1BF1FA84292" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorization to structure major medical facility leases as triple-net leases (NNN) or modified-gross leases, as appropriate, to align with prevailing commercial market practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6B97CD6834D4D91BC9C570107F65770" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>definitions of the terms <quote>shell work</quote> and <quote>tenant improvements</quote> to ensure cost allocation is consistent with prevailing commercial market standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1052BC8FB9E5403A98F1AFE792718A0B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall issue guidance with respect to the use of such terms in lease agreements under this chapter. In such guidance, the Secretary shall ensure—</text><subparagraph id="H6F0F9FC2A4B94530B340AB66C57EECDA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>heating, ventilation, and air conditioning system capacity is included in the definition of <quote>shell work</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H499A20B25193437C99EB61C2863FA1EA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">heating, ventilation, and air conditioning distribution and controls required to meet tenant-specific needs are included in the definition of <quote>tenant improvements</quote>, unless otherwise negotiated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE026E9911E5248EBBF4A81AF4107A125" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>triple-net lease</quote> means a lease under which the lessee is responsible for payment of real estate taxes, insurance, utilities, janitorial services, and routine operating costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECCF126BC35A42309452742730B8CE73" commented="no"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Consolidation of documentation</header><text>The Secretary shall consolidate internal documentation required to support lease decisions under this chapter into a single decision memorandum, to the maximum extent practicable. Such memorandum shall include project justification, site selection rationale, estimated costs, design summary, and other information necessary for internal approval and submission to Congress.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H71F72E95C3904225B7832CC4935FEE99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8104(a)(3)(B)(i) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>through the General Services Administration under section 3307(a) of title 40</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB5B554E164F42AF81E617CE21E99D3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HE78F866321F341DB97D4A94FF27D9333"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Veterans Leasing Fund established under section 8103 of title 38, United States Code, (as amended by this Act), such amounts as may be specifically authorized for lease obligations under subsection (i) of such section (as added by this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H092F2F93011242C6AC92862462E64CFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit of future appropriations</header><text>Any amounts appropriated for lease obligations for a fiscal year shall be deposited in the Veterans Leasing Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H86569982A3854B9EBDBCDE6B93DCE4EB" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cost estimation requirements for major medical facility leases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8104(b)(2) of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6B7D421F68D944119666BA4C339196E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Whenever</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) Whenever</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA37793A07C14BDAB87174F32E9E5C0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (E) as clauses (i) through (v), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF6306ABC07E49E0B9B396F61846F188"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as designated by paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H26CA93DECFA343BB9B34E7A5612946CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (v), as so redesignated—</text><clause id="H697CD4E7E38F4B7E9C18E1065E83A1E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) through (iii) as subclauses (I) through (III), respectively; and</text></clause><clause id="H07DA2CE87EAB4342954E957D7C823BC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7582591723D142FB9302768C3C7917F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE7E15ACA1224D15B646C179358C04F7"><clause id="HBF69470538F74B7C8932E00B70B87BFA" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A market-based cost estimate for the facility to be leased that includes an evaluation of—</text><subclause id="H8AB8594A39B44B8E8D5B6005DBA4BA07"><enum>(I)</enum><text>local land values;</text></subclause><subclause id="H665D3285CFAD46A89547E30FDF244A44"><enum>(II)</enum><text>applicable construction costs; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD8EB758C6DEC415AB805BC1787DFCB31"><enum>(III)</enum><text>other cost factors the Secretary determines relevant to build-to-suit facilities.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1355CFA34FF547AFB5AF8DD10ED3A7D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBFE5EB2263594DD2808649E5FE95FAAF"><subparagraph id="H43AC09C6BDF14541B43F67CE5B0C572C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAA94C9E74A2740B1B908ECEB0AF8B7AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall adopt and apply a standardized methodology for estimating the full life-cycle cost of major medical facility leases and prospectus-level leases.</text></clause><clause id="HBFDAED696F284BADB74EE450D940F1E9" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Such methodology shall include, at a minimum—</text><subclause id="H985767EB1BC14C9A80A6B67EE6DCBD3C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>base rent projections over the full lease term;</text></subclause><subclause id="H31CCD4F0839F48BD8A6FA06591FD4874"><enum>(II)</enum><text>tenant improvement and buildout costs based on current medical facility standards;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFECEBC672A4B419CB55C45F5198173EC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>estimated operating expenses, including utilities, maintenance, and security;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB5B01C19C067480FA74C9F9C6B0BF158"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>annual escalation factors tied to construction cost indices, labor rates, and market trends;</text></subclause><subclause id="HED65C47449D840BABDD8D7B556255399"><enum>(V)</enum><text>cost assumptions for option periods or potential renewal terms; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H23193644FCED46EE951E77CF1D467794"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>geographic adjustments using current regional market data to reflect location-specific construction and leasing conditions.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB03BE622075342F79D1C9779470E7580" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To reflect inflation and market escalation, the Secretary shall annually adjust each cost estimate for a lease submitted to Congress for authorization or prospectus approval during the period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits the first cost estimate for the lease and ending on the projected award date for the lease. In adjusting a cost estimate pursuant to this subparagraph, the Secretary shall use such medical construction or real estate indices as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="HE69DF95E6C404BCD9A68EA203E6C4CEF" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>If the Secretary does not award a lease during the one year period beginning on the date on which the Secretary completes a cost estimate for the lease pursuant to this paragraph, the Secretary shall update and revalidate such cost estimate prior to obligating any funds for the lease or submitting such cost estimate to Congress.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H134C7D8FD16C403A9D52F8FF510CBA44"><enum>4.</enum><header>Development of streamlined procurement model; report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Comptroller General of the United States, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and private sector stakeholders, shall develop a revised process for the procurement of major medical facility leases under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, and submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that includes a description of such revised process.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

