<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD9AC295EADC54267BF10713D32A4DD18" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8130 IH: Tax Filer Voter Registration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8130</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to treat certain tax return preparers as voter registration agencies under such Act for purposes of distributing voter registration application forms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5C95FF1881F949ACA7C793B810D65C06" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFD8925CA5E7B4224A804DCEF259DA77E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tax Filer Voter Registration Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Filer Voter Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HED6C79E2CB954F1FB0BC4B8789D54AA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of tax return preparers as voter registration agencies for purposes of distributing voter registration application forms</header> <subsection id="HDD32DA7359934086A879098F4205D3D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tax return preparers as voter registration agencies</header> <paragraph id="HEE849C9D52CF4DFF8E2BE63EAFCB3195"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20506">52 U.S.C. 20506</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3920F14A960D4658889969C66982D616" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H769E13699AB04EFABAC145E074AE2E50"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules for tax return preparers</header> 
<paragraph id="HD787D6E3B80A4A398C32C608CABBC20D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment as voter registration agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2) and except as provided in paragraph (3), each tax return preparer in a State shall be treated as a voter registration agency designated by the State for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H220FEE9BAFDC4F4190B9243AA5E47E72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methods of meeting requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H87C420B7FEBF4092A4AEF40D9AA43A00"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Availability of forms in office for customers who meet preparer in person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A tax return preparer who provides tax return preparation services to customers who meet the preparer in person at the preparer’s office may meet the requirements applicable to the tax return preparer under this section by displaying copies of the mail voter registration application form used by the State in which the office is located in a manner which ensures that the forms are visible and accessible to any customer who visits the office.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DEAB6D530AC46C496FE9F74958AB344"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of forms through hyperlink for customers who receive services online</header><text>A tax return preparer who provides tax return preparation services to customers through online methods may meet the requirements applicable to the tax return preparer under this section—</text> <clause id="H1AFA216B8D3B48D3B5C69807672CEA6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by providing a hyperlink to the mail voter registration application form developed by the Election Assistance Commission under section 9(a)(2), or to the website of the appropriate election official through which an individual may register to vote online, through the same computer software, service, or program by which the tax return preparer provides services to the customer online; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA8FA47CBEC53443080C0BF3D473A2772"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by ensuring that the hyperlink is prominently displayed to each customer who receives any tax return preparation services from the tax return preparer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5874E2B003DA4B4CAA34D5565E5368EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>A tax return preparer shall not be required to meet the following requirements of this section which are otherwise applicable to a voter registration agency designated by the State for purposes of this section:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7E6B4CBDCECA4EF2A4487607D88AD196"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Clause (iii) of subsection (a)(4)(A) (relating to the acceptance of completed voter registration application forms for transmittal to the appropriate State election official).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2489A10E265D41BFB95D4DB79B7ACFF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subparagraph (B) of subsection (a)(6) (relating to the provision of the form by which an individual may apply to register to vote at a voter registration agency and related forms and statements).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5D7E3AA690048F9B19534082C0A9616"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Subsection (d) (relating to the deadline for the transmittal of completed voter registration application forms to the appropriate State election official).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB7F48C56CBA4494A718EBBFA257F116"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>tax return preparer</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H47B3ED1D48BF41F29C2E9F6257C45E4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a tax return preparer described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(36)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, other than a tax return preparer who—</text> <clause id="H4AFE0A1C637E4761909F1A4A6899F848"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>during the taxable year, reasonably expects to prepare fewer than 100 individual tax returns; or</text>
                                    </clause> 
<clause id="HB1696AF3189440F6A3A7266C9FA29289"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during the previous taxable year, prepared fewer than 100 individual tax returns; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B44869D167341ED9F90A00D922AE711"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any certified volunteer tax preparer who receives funding from the Secretary of the Treasury under the Community Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grants Program or the Tax Counseling for the Elderly Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A605E350B614D64969BF59493FC3174"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Election Assistance Commission, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall promulgate such regulations as the Commission considers appropriate to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A771AF718024BEBA0487B8C5CE8EFE3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to taxable years occurring after December 2021.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H433BDE65A6C343E8A4052BDD53FEBA44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Secretary of the Treasury relating to certified volunteer tax preparers</header> 
<paragraph id="HBC9DED8B57CE4225980F91FEE549C0CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidance to certified volunteer tax preparers receiving funding under certain programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide assistance and guidance to enable certified volunteer tax preparers who receive funding under the Community Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grants Program or the Tax Counseling for the Elderly Program to meet the requirements of section 7(e) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (as added by subsection (a)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFC24FAD81F3416EADDFCEF18981856A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision to intake and interview and quality review sheet</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall revise the intake and interview and quality review sheet provided to an individual who utilizes the services of certified volunteer preparers to include the following question: <quote>Do you want to receive a form today to register to vote or update your voter registration information?</quote>, as well as a box for the individual to check to indicate whether or not the individual wants to receive such a form.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C52ED3EC406449EA80070C78A87EF33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Display of information at sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall revise the quality site requirements for volunteer tax preparers who receive funding under the Community Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grants Program or the Tax Counseling for the Elderly Program to include a requirement that the sites clearly and prominently display voter registration application forms.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

