<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25A79-2S7-7M-3V8">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 476 IS: Supporting the designation of October 2025 as “Substance Use &amp; Misuse Prevention Month” to raise awareness of substance use and misuse in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 476</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20251030">October 30, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which
                was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health,
                    Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of October 2025 as <quote>Substance
                Use &amp; Misuse Prevention Month</quote> to raise awareness of substance use and
            misuse in the United States.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas initiation of substance use during adolescence is associated with substance use and misuse in adulthood;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2024, an estimated 58,000,000 people in the United States aged 12 and older participated in binge drinking;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2024, more than 73,000,000 or 1 in 4 people in the United States aged 12 and older used an illicit drug, including cocaine and methamphetamine;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2024, an estimated 48,000,000 people in the United States aged 12 and older had a substance use disorder;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2024, an estimated 28,000,000 people in the United States aged 12 and older had an illicit drug use disorder;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2024, an estimated 9,000,000 people in the United States aged 12 and older received substance use disorder treatment; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2024, more than 23,000,000 people in the United States aged 12 and older were in recovery from a substance use problem: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text>That the Senate supports—</text> <paragraph id="id21019dc0a168483fad5f5e6c9d76fe3a"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>effective programs to prevent substance use and misuse;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id49500f7687bd4b7fba28ced2b94364a0">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>programs to help stem the drug addiction and overdose epidemic in the United States; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id5a3c4351498c4f28b33395ca8edf4f85">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the designation of October 2025 as <quote>Substance Use &amp; Misuse Prevention Month</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

