<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE505D06F558D460D9D18630604BE213A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7682 IH: Closing the Workforce Gap Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7682</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to base the numerical limitations for H–2B nonimmigrants on economic need, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D958B96DC9E4FF09BB224F6B2AD651B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H705E94272A5A4E60A14DDDB868340966" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Closing the Workforce Gap Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H5F868BAA7EB04FEEBA096FC2159D5B7F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Numerical limitations for H–2B nonimmigrants based on economic need</header> 
<subsection id="H9B437556480342F6A6C5688E8A07080A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 214(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6B5238AC0F9F473CBEC0B43590E73261"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (1)(B) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7200680715344230B84442C3C11EF297" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H69A752A6A75742748EB963E07D77E6EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subsection (s), under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b) may not exceed the number of Department of Labor certified positions for the previous fiscal year with respect to nonimmigrants described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4D8D3DBAE004F74868CC51D73BE6695"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>33,000</quote> and inserting <quote>half of the number described in paragraph (1)(B)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E90058DC84D45EEAD578FD19B90E907"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption from numerical limitation for rural and seasonal location workers</header><text>Section 214 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0F3E780536294BC2976B490EE61C266E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H9625F591CC624826982234C17939A9AD"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Exemption from numerical limitation for H–2B rural and seasonal location workers</header> <paragraph id="H64BDA2F6D902466187FABA15C075E894"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exemption from numerical limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The numerical limitation under subsection (g)(1)(B) shall not apply to nonimmigrants described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b) who work for an employer in a rural and seasonal location.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4259051163C4B0AA189C69717EE32C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation for exemption</header><text>Any employer seeking an exemption under paragraph (1) shall submit the relevant documentation to the Secretary of Labor during the labor certification approval process.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3723897A1D0435F8EC55516AB50D620"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>In any labor certification that the Secretary of Labor issues to such employer, the Secretary shall verify to the Department of Homeland Security the number of cap-exempt positions to which the employer is entitled.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57FFAA2063A64DD194041F4B2FE38C30"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>rural and seasonal location</term> means an area that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC167A01F456D4913B6C214E80A7C3284"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not within a metropolitan statistical area, as designated by the Office of Management and Budget, or within the outer boundary of any city or town having a population of 20,000 or more people according to the most recent decennial census of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2FA0435B0964BC5B3DDF28F0348B32E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a population on January 1 or July 1 that is at least 50 percent higher than the number of residents who continuously live in the area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H870CEA168A924D168C81FC278D514792"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9DD8D57483B947DFBFEEBED70398FED5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increased sanctions for willful misrepresentation or failure to meet the requirements for petitioning for an H–2B worker</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 214 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8B2BB392FB53443D9916D42C0641242B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(13)(B), by striking <quote>$150</quote> and inserting <quote>$350</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A3788D21B974199BB5EB61749C1E274"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(14)(A)(i), by striking <quote>may, in addition to any other remedy authorized by law, impose such administrative remedies (including civil monetary penalties in an amount not to exceed $10,000 per violation)</quote> and inserting <quote>shall impose civil monetary penalties in an amount of not less than $1,000 but not to exceed $10,000 per violation, in addition to any other remedy authorized by law, and may impose such other administrative remedies</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H08630C7D0D204F5BAF4779A2B4F6B840"><enum>4.</enum><header>Workplace safety</header> <subsection id="H58A8E29FAD534E75818A62946C1BFD00"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Worksite safety and compliance plan</header> <text>If an employer is seeking to employ an H–2B worker pursuant to this Act and the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>), the employer shall maintain an effective worksite safety and compliance plan to ensure safety and reduce workplace illnesses, injuries, and fatalities. Such plan shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="HF493C79CE4534897B113DA8650FC15B0">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>be in writing in English and, to the extent necessary, any language common to a significant portion of the workers if they are not fluent in English; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE8663080DB0C49728AB47539D90BCD35">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>be posted at a conspicuous location at the worksite and provided to employees prior to the commencement of labor or services.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA1E50D8D7F2F4EB88750304346BCC7DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of plan</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish by regulation the minimum requirements for the plan described in subsection (a). Such plan shall include measures to—</text> <paragraph id="H318BB8230D5B4A9C9DE88715E68DFF8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protect against sexual harassment and violence, resolve complaints involving harassment or violence, and protect against retaliation against workers reporting harassment or violence; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F384BF4440E4AF9AD1A8B46F62AE841"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contain other provisions necessary for ensuring workplace safety.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA64100E461AF481EB62C11A66945A15F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Foreign labor recruiting; prohibition on fees</header> <subsection id="H96FE7567789744E796DF5E4AB0574FF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Foreign labor recruiting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an employer has engaged any foreign labor contractor or recruiter (or any agent of such a foreign labor contractor or recruiter) in the recruitment of H–2B workers, the employer shall disclose the identity and geographic location of such person or entity to the Secretary of Labor in accordance with the regulations of the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE75D006A82DF4E33963D299489CB2BF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition against employees paying fees</header><text>Neither the employer nor its agents shall seek or receive payment of any kind from any worker for any activity related to the H–2B petition process, including payment of the employer’s attorneys’ fees, application fees, or recruitment costs. An employer and its agents may receive reimbursement for costs that are the responsibility, and primarily for the benefit, of the worker, such as government-required passport fees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H01D75CFB798F4A2CB51FAC63E4E3B7D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Third-Party contracts</header><text>The employer shall contractually forbid any foreign labor contractor or recruiter (or any agent of a foreign labor contractor or recruiter) who the employer engages, either directly or indirectly, in the recruitment of H–2B workers to seek or receive payments or other compensation from prospective employees. Upon learning that a foreign labor contractor or recruiter has collected such payments, the employer shall terminate any contracts with the foreign labor contractor or recruiter.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H792FB7C9770B4C21964485AD1E4E13F1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Program integrity measures</header> 
<subsection id="H0F8F368670694BF58A01DF78C9C6A7F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement authority</header><text>With respect to the H–2B program, the Secretary of Labor is authorized to take such actions against employers, including imposing appropriate penalties and seeking monetary and injunctive relief and specific performance of contractual obligations, as may be necessary to ensure compliance with—</text> <paragraph id="HF1549EB73F4746B89EB04005A6D705F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requirements of this Act and the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE38B0414FC84E23B778EA04956810AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the applicable terms and conditions of employment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H195C50D4131141DDBCABA2B4545BD833"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Complaint process</header> <paragraph id="H2E96A82CECAF47DBB5D4DAB694632B49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the H–2B program, the Secretary of Labor shall establish a process for the receipt, investigation, and disposition of complaints alleging failure of an employer to comply with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8AD77BE35A4C418EB2BDD7808C8A0E94" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the requirements of this Act and the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2435269E2B094F89B4E897AFD4D19422"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicable terms and conditions of employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5583EA263EED4E6EB60619BAB95B0C88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Filing</header><text>Any aggrieved person or organization, including a bargaining representative, may file a complaint referred to in paragraph (1) not later than 2 years after the date of the conduct that is the subject of the complaint.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAF71F39BD1F4DD8BEAD3551DA79E98B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Complaint not exclusive</header><text>A complaint filed under this subsection is not an exclusive remedy and the filing of such a complaint does not waive any rights or remedies of the aggrieved party under this law or other laws.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3467675D441A453899D6382C0C9D6C27"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Decision and remedies</header><text>If the Secretary of Labor finds, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that the employer failed to comply with the requirements of this Act, the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>), or the terms and conditions of employment, the Secretary of Labor shall require payment of unpaid wages, unpaid benefits, damages, and civil money penalties. The Secretary is also authorized to impose other administrative remedies, including disqualification of the employer from utilizing the H–2B program for a period of up to 5 years in the event of willful or multiple material violations. The Secretary is authorized to permanently disqualify an employer from utilizing the H–2B program upon a subsequent finding involving willful or multiple material violations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H120BA5CF1A354F2481B6EC114F2D8A6A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disposition of penalties</header><text>To the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts, civil penalties collected under this subsection shall be used by the Secretary of Labor for the administration and enforcement of the provisions of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98A4C44978CA4A1AAD0C6962ADBD07AD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Statutory construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed as limiting the authority of the Secretary of Labor to conduct an investigation in the absence of a complaint.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A7532A0B30C4980A727708A50A08798"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Retaliation prohibited</header><text>It is a violation of this subsection for any person to intimidate, threaten, restrain, coerce, blacklist, discharge, or in any other manner discriminate against, or to cause any person to intimidate, threaten, restrain, coerce, blacklist, or in any manner discriminate against, an employee, including a former employee or an applicant for employment, because the employee—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE24EA86BF0D44870A4664F4C0BF535E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has disclosed information to the employer, or to any other person, that the employee reasonably believes evidences a violation of the immigration laws relating to the H–2B program, or any rule or regulation relating to such program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46348AC75A6C4A4BB7CB5E2DB6E4FC2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has filed a complaint concerning the employer’s compliance with the immigration laws relating to the H–2B program, or any rule or regulation relating to such program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C6340CF62CB40BE85A01470BCD6FE83"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cooperates or seeks to cooperate in an investigation or other proceeding concerning the employer’s compliance with the immigration laws relating to the H–2B program, or any rule or regulation relating to such program; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5877B924E50C4C76947166D109F23B5F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has taken steps to exercise or assert any right or protection under the provisions of this section, or any rule or regulation pertaining to this section, or any other relevant Federal, State, or local law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC3BD0D68A51A41F3936F7ADED23B9C8C">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Interagency communication</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, Secretary of State, and the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, shall establish mechanisms by which the agencies and their components share information, including by public electronic means, regarding complaints, studies, investigations, findings, and remedies regarding compliance by employers with the requirements of the H–2B program and other employment-related laws and regulations.</text>
            </subsection></section> 
<section id="HB38D0D70CDB249719A99B1378ADFE661"><enum>7.</enum><header>Program eligibility</header> 
<subsection id="HB467F48EA4F340CFAF7924DBD2F34405"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A petition filed by an employer under subsection (c)(1) initially to grant an alien nonimmigrant status under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b)</external-xref>), or to extend or change to such status, may be approved only for nationals of countries that the Secretary of Homeland Security has designated as participating countries, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, in a notice published in the Federal Register, taking into account for each such country factors, including—</text> <paragraph id="HE755F400743F4E14A8326B270098327C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the fraud rate relating to petitions under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)</external-xref>) filed for by nationals of the country and visa applications under such section filed by nationals of the country;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H664E2C37F0AF477792EA5C937D2DB591"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the denial rate of visa applications under such section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii) filed by nationals of the country;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24FD73E53A88422EAB840EB0BF1BCD77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the overstay rate of nationals of the country who were admitted to the United States under such section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3400D5176E084BE18EE68852EBB0E231"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of nationals of the country who were admitted to the United States under such section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii) and who were reported by their employers to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9CF0F6E5D2C44F4B90075049EBC1B88C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have failed to report to work within 5 workdays of the employment start date on the petition or within 5 workdays of the date on which the worker is admitted into the United States pursuant to the petition, whichever is later; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BF2024ED8784B29B2A9BF69EF161D66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have not reported for work for a period of 5 consecutive workdays without the consent of the employer;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF93E34A7F838470D90AA4D43FE392ACD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of final and unexecuted orders of removal against citizens, subjects, nationals, and residents of the country; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10AB9D3C05444A728AE8F31036068A6C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other factors as may serve the United States interest.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC5E265389FDD440AB4C405BC567ECA5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A country may not be included on the list described in subsection (a) if the country denies or unreasonably delays the repatriation of aliens who are subject to a final order of removal and who are citizens, subjects, nationals, or residents of that country.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82C8C4E9A26840BD9441E25181585F4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statistics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall include in the notice described in subsection (a), for each country included in the list of participating countries, the statistics referenced in paragraphs (1) through (5) of that subsection, if available, for the immediately preceding fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H85BB2F88EAC8445581B85F589AEBFE04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National from a country not on the list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A national from a country not on the list described in subsection (a) may be a beneficiary of an approved petition under such section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii) upon the request of a petitioner or potential petitioner, if the Secretary of Homeland Security, in his sole and unreviewable discretion, determines that it is in the United States interest for that alien to be a beneficiary of such petition. Determination of such a United States interest will take into account factors, including but not limited to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H93AD1B27A41543DAA5F0EF8C0107F49F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence from the petitioner demonstrating that a worker with the required skills is not available from among foreign workers from a country currently on the list described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H830DC221905648EF9ADF0CF40E5377D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evidence that the beneficiary has been admitted to the United States previously in status under such section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DDC356471C14C0194699EE2D1B449C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the potential for abuse, fraud, or other harm to the integrity of the visa program under such section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii) through the potential admission of a beneficiary from a country not currently on the list; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1C3351BDF3A4097928948E17FEF49C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other factors as may serve the United States interest.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72BB773F577D4AB28E9B15C4680CA663"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Once published, any designation of participating countries pursuant to subsection (a) shall be effective for one year after the date of publication in the Federal Register and shall be without effect at the end of that one-year period.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H231EC208E8DA49F0885B5C382471A136"><enum>8.</enum><header>H–2B employer notification requirement</header> <subsection id="H135EA2FE0F014388A8D00C31C55DD237"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer of one or more H–2B workers shall, within three business days, make electronic notification, in the manner prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, of the following events:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0D4B54D86CD84C55B2A46C25475FE495"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Such a worker fails to report to work within 5 workdays of the employment start date on the petition or within 5 workdays of the date on which the worker is admitted into the United States pursuant to the petition, whichever is later.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0D8B1840DFB42B894069D40339D3AFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The labor or services for which such a worker was hired is completed more than 30 days earlier than the employment end date stated on the petition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF45E4E6BC1564556A2C8352FE69C17F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The employment of such a worker is terminated prior to the completion of labor or services for which he or she was hired.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H594A759D30BE414BA75E89C3DEF3F966"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such a worker has not reported for work for a period of 5 consecutive workdays without the consent of the employer.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5CFD356BAF34930A729569F6FDE6876"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evidence</header><text>An employer shall retain evidence of a notification described in subsection (a) and make it available for inspection by officers of the Department of Homeland Security for a 1-year period beginning on the date of the notification.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H51E8FCD104DE43B0AD602683974942A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>The Secretary shall impose civil monetary penalties, in an amount not less than $500 per violation and not to exceed $1,000 per violation, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, for each instance where the employer cannot demonstrate that it has complied with the notification requirements, unless, in the case of an untimely notification, the employer demonstrates with such notification that good cause existed for the untimely notification, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Secretary’s discretion, waives such penalty.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8430AE3CC77944C7B76D3462AF9D9124"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Process</header><text>If the Secretary has determined that an employer has violated the notification requirements in subsection (a), the employer shall be given written notice and 30 days to reply before being given written notice of the assessment of the penalty.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H716FE63F1883420BA20FFA2A24256B99"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Failure To pay penalty</header><text>If a penalty described in subsection (c) is not paid within 10 days of assessment, no nonimmigrant or immigrant petition may be processed for that employer, nor may that employer continue to employ nonimmigrants, until such penalty is paid.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5795C08BAFBC44569A32C56289D41EA4"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD638D80E78C54932A483F64977FDFF7C"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>The term <term>H–2B</term>, when used with respect to a worker or other individual, refers to an alien admitted or provided status as a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b)</external-xref>). Such term, when used with respect to a petition, procedure, process, program, or visa, refers to a petition, procedure, process, program, or visa related to admission or provision of status under such section.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97F9A82244FA4F99B48194F72CD14CED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>job order</term> means the document containing the material terms and conditions of employment, including obligations and assurances required under this Act or any other law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H457C1A187793425B83569D5F20236663"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States worker</term> means any employee who is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB52CA178F8C8424F8A383C46D4951B58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a national of the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB33F18DE76044F209C51DA6813C5E7FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, is admitted as a refugee under section 207 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>), is granted asylum under section 208 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>), or is an immigrant otherwise authorized by the immigration laws (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)) or the Secretary of Homeland Security to be employed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

