<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E0D0EBEFDB64ED988EE15071A16F7E0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7327 IH: Empowering Young Readers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7327</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260203">February 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Education to establish a pilot program to award grants to eligible organizations to carry out activities related to book access, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEA5FC8EDE1E1455D82EF7611F226215E" style="OLC"><section id="HB790839864E14E28A2D0F7F88D7AF873" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering Young Readers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2F253E3C6EA945E083ADB51C233EAF7E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for book access</header><subsection id="HF2A27264AC264AE19D6616D5416F00FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall establish a pilot program to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible organizations to carry out the activities described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD2DBC039799D4780B925B7E09810EF06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible organization desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including—</text><paragraph id="H5AA18D742A444F06BB7846B68C5D8073"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information about past work the eligible organization has performed related to book access;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB388BED81C2D461CB7BBC93595334A2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comprehensive strategic plan for how the eligible organization would use a grant under this section to carry out one or more of the activities described in subsection (c), including a description of how such activities would address the needs of the community served by the eligible organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFD08213632442FEB53D0B7553EA6E84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a letter from a leader in the community served by the eligible organization in support of the eligible organization and the comprehensive strategic plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19BA28CE904D45AE976A02B230547B81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds awarded under this section shall be used by an eligible entity to carry out one or more of the following activities:</text><paragraph id="H25D169313D7A4DE690B6CCF87DC06980"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Purchasing or otherwise acquiring new or used books for distribution to children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89F901426DDC489896095135330953AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Distributing new or used books to children, including through delivery or in-person events.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2ED9511D4EBC417BB182EFA3E429EEFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Donating new or used books to public libraries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H726EC28E99A34DEEAC845F1881549301"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hosting or organizing literacy-related programming for children and their families, including book fairs, reading hours, book drives, and story times.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B2A6BDBDA2748058F829D66D2F0A55F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any other activity the Secretary determines appropriate related to book access.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4BE206EA28F4366BF2ED66993422378"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant amounts and duration</header><text>A grant under this section—</text><paragraph id="H0314892EE8F24355B489B860B9A31392"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be in an amount that is not more than $200,000; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5218AB1315446ABA57BD05EBB21AD88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be for a period of 2 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC53E63239FC6421081E3A021AB1D495B"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Viewpoint-Neutral</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure that applications submitted pursuant to subsection (b) are reviewed based on viewpoint-neutral criteria.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H42A5DB9CAEB1409EB12469E9696FC010"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the grant period of the final grant awarded pursuant to this section expires, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="HE28C10AEAEA54F70AF19E80635A9C12F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualitative data with respect to the activities carried out by grant recipients, including the number of books provided to children and their families; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67101497601E48E08F91B827EBC53CF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the extent data is available, information about how child literacy rates in communities served by eligible organizations changed during and after such activities were carried out.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2252CE793E384AD2821377D4544B304C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as restricting, infringing upon, or otherwise interfering with the ability of a public library or other entity to reject all or part of a donation of books.</text></subsection><subsection id="H16519522D83D420F9A24940C37891A33"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8806CB7C6C6C48B686005D4637BC274F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <quote>child</quote> means an individual under 19 years of age.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CB039AE41CB4A2AACCB6891ECCA37E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible organization</header><text>The term <term>eligible organization</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H023B1E0BD4B643C696066FEB4F31ED42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nongovernmental organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90264693FEFE4A7EA1FA6DCA14366729"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD79FB0F760F4C9CA319BF930C8007A7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, to remain available through fiscal year 2027.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

