<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H038E91DD8BD24EF0A49365B98F023475" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9745 IH: Orlin’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9745</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001246">Ms. Mejia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require certain protections for any dependent child whose parent is a detained alien, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA092146DFFF445F91CFB1293153FCF9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC41B875528AC490C9EC947F41BE001E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Orlin’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1A280B2D22F34EE6B315A35C28DF7191"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1250680359344B95A40FFDE472E9EE8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>family units should be considered a <quote>humanitarian or significant public benefit</quote> as it relates to the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to grant parole under section 212(d)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E8ECA2FB9D0412789436BC2DD01163E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>being an alien parent shall not be considered a negative factor when determining child custody.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HEAFB2F597303443097FE42850362FB10"><enum>3.</enum><header>Special rule for parents</header> 
<subsection id="HAE56FBBAB38D4C0398F12647113F88A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Parents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 hours after taking an alien into custody under the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)), and prior to transferring the alien to a detention facility, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall request information from the alien on whether the alien is a covered parent and document the response.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA17A7A75794B4058AD636F4779A38E7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on detention</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that an alien who is in custody under the immigration laws is a covered parent, the Secretary shall release such alien unless an immigration judge determines that the Secretary has demonstrated, by clear and convincing evidence, that the alien poses an individualized risk to the safety of any other person or the community that cannot be mitigated through placement in a supervised release program.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB0F17147C5034C79B955E195E23E7EE5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safety risks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that a covered parent poses an individualized risk described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall determine the least restrictive placement for the individual, including placement in a community-based supervision program under section 236(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCB090087B1D44441AF86EFA8A342F790" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that an alien is in custody under the immigration laws, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall inquire about the parental status, or a change in parental status, of such alien during any interaction relating to the determination of the alien’s immigration status and no less than once each month.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HC5C4FEF1E3D84A22862135B818A29C59"><enum>4.</enum><header>Identifying detained parents</header> 
<subsection id="HDDE8C14C0A834751BA834B6959F484DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Detained aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered parent in the custody of the Department of Homeland Security shall be allowed to—</text> <paragraph id="H912BFB9E14D94A2C9B017A5511126DC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make telephone calls, without charge, to arrange for the care of each of their dependent children prior to any transfer, including in preparation for removal;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7CC6A91D9C343D0B7EA489D25FCECC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arrange regular in person visits with each of their dependent children; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H420D220D8BD2490E819D6264D47926B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make daily telephone and video calls to each of their dependent children, without charge.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H58DA5D22573541739A90355A1F5780C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on transfers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may not transfer a covered parent who is detained under the immigration laws to an area of responsibility of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement that is a different area of responsibility than the area in which the covered parent was initially detained or the habitual place of residence of the child of such parent, except in exceptional circumstances or if legally required.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H3445E8DFB928473A95A925B5CABA12BB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Attending court proceedings</header> <subsection id="H206F558A269C454CB351D860D6A18117"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that any covered parent has the opportunity to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE9205A351AFB425B89D0E6C83974F84A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">initiate or participate fully and, to the extent practicable, in person in—</text> <subparagraph id="H4A473AFB0A684AD6AF4B3AEEC37D6068"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any family court proceeding;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB9A3332ED01140D0878214B24B4EEA04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other proceeding that may impact the right of the individual to take custody of their dependent child; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7194C14E1D94F07B9A8E7E948FC0A12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any case planning activity;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CD215CEE7D64153BA1836B072A66FFF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make confidential telephone calls, without charge, to any legal counsel, relevant child welfare agency or applicable contracted entity or provider, community and family members, or family court as often as necessary to ensure that the best interests of such dependent child, including a preference for family unity whenever appropriate, may be considered in a child welfare agency or family court proceeding;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A331805988C44E6980640FE13F6F834" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fully comply with each family court or child welfare agency order impacting the custody of such dependent child;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2899794D4C454C0FABF4E31A35936BD9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit United States passport applications or other relevant travel document applications for the purpose of obtaining travel documents for such dependent child;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF41D0C305087431FBD26C3A278CC0D52"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have timely and free access to a notary public for purposes of applying for a passport for such dependent child or executing guardianship or other agreements to ensure the safety of such dependent child;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F47B8354DB24EB88B9281EDAD8A72C8"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have adequate time and opportunity before removal to obtain passports, apostilled birth certificates, travel documents, medical records, educational records, and other necessary records on behalf of such dependent child if such child will accompany the individual to the country of removal or eventually join the individual in such country;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC70872B96B24DC4ACF94C8076C980D1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have adequate time and access to any documents in the possession of the Secretary of Homeland Security that are necessary to make arrangements for the dependent child’s care, travel, or safety, including access to any identity document and passport of the covered parent;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE42CE298BCEA432AA1487A185EFE9EAD"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have adequate time and notice regarding their dependent child’s travel arrangements with respect to removal, including the time of travel, reporting location, manner of transportation, and who is facilitating such travel; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26E8C81E4A424ABBAFCA4EC363F0ADCA"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share information regarding such travel arrangements with his or her legal counsel, consulate, dependent child, child welfare agencies, or other caregivers before the alien departs the United States.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7EFF18366E304751A4FE3C440DEFE53E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Immigration court proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a proceeding before an immigration court the immigration judge shall, as the judge determines necessary, appoint counsel to a covered parent, at the expense of the Government, during family integrity custody review proceedings.</text> </subsection> </section> <section id="H7B885DEC0F75441CBB8821CC445EC0B8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Parental rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a dependent child is physically separated from a covered parent as a result of such parent’s detention under the immigration laws, and a State court has not made a determination that the parental rights of such parent have been terminated, there is a presumption that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H76A113914A1145EE809C5059E25A632A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the parental rights remain intact; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3075653D50BF4D999DB09BB18A6816CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such separation does not constitute an affirmative determination of abandonment, abuse, or neglect under Federal or State law.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H531F5E1F99964500BA39D02770DB94FA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Removal of detained parents</header> 
<subsection id="H7699F1B4F4E348EE9ADEE540EC2C42A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Request for removal with dependent child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide oral and written notice to each covered parent who is subject to a final order of removal, in each covered parent’s preferred language, that the alien may, in writing—</text> <paragraph id="HE8A8EC32B94F4A0496FD698A3EC89357"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">request removal from the United States with, and to the same country as, their dependent children; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD04892E464C84DBAB7A580440BFC2348"><enum>(2)</enum><text>amend a request described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5D06FAC25E2C47A8B1E1DB211B295251"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to give effect to any request under this section made under duress or any other coercive condition.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HC8F440914B604DEF8BA3BC2962F620B0"><enum>8.</enum><header>Training and National Coordinator</header> 
<subsection id="HF896C71D924D4D38BA98FBF3084E19AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the headquarters of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement an Office of Detained Parent Coordination, headed by the National Coordinator.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HABF1BC30FBCF42E392062F847F68D67D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Coordinator shall be responsible for the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H72F9B272EAB4415B9745C1F47EB7F78B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Serving as the primary point of contact and subject-matter expert for Enforcement and Removal Operations personnel of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement regarding State child welfare or guardianship issues related to detained aliens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H143F2AB35BC946EF8FD594EE42B50AAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Conducting data collection and analysis, including evaluating, on an ongoing basis, information collected from a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement records system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F70A2E8E48C43D6AF37E0D5DF60ACFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assigning and maintaining field points of contact for matters pertaining to detained covered parents.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H370515C9A6024FC9B7DD6C699F5CC093"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing guidance to each field point of contact assigned under paragraph (3) on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF7E4ABF7DEC842D68C29366D5ADE78F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participation in family court, child welfare, or guardianship proceedings for detained covered parents;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4A2AEAFD46D401F8A92E2C4F0839313"><enum>(B)</enum><text>visitation protocols for detained covered parents; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4A7DDE394074136B83202D54F4BD033"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitation of participation by detained covered parents in child welfare services and programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E412007E4E14F5EBA62F0669A0F07F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Ensuring that detained covered parents are provided the opportunity to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H46642195FD4749098FF3F61CF4AC06F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with counsel and consular officials;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9218EE8DEC1048418B0B03C0B89FB375"><enum>(B)</enum><text>communicate with family courts, child welfare personnel, and family members or friends to arrange guardianship or care, in accordance with sections 4 and 5;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D781A7C65154995A4B9A5635B9C0358"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain travel documents or make necessary travel arrangements, for the dependent child of such alien; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA27587A17BBD434ABAD429F9B0DB6CCD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>access necessary services to meet case plans, status and permanency goals in child welfare proceedings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7115AE84469444C8BE18B07BB5B09963"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordinating with relevant Enforcement and Removal Operations personnel, field office directors, State or local court or child welfare personnel, legal counsel representing covered parents, and consular officials to facilitate the timely response to any issue or complaint received by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement regarding the parental or guardianship interests of a detained alien.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D5D3C06906D4F91A823240A4C65C99D" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing and maintaining a national, publicly available designated mechanism through which family courts, child welfare agencies, legal counsel, and other stakeholders may provide the Secretary of Homeland Security with notice of family court proceedings, child welfare matters, case planning activities, or other proceedings affecting a covered parent's custodial rights or relationship with their dependent child, for the purpose of facilitating the parent's timely notice of and meaningful participation in such proceedings.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5A0C17038064CFF80A668B34B3B6BDB" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Facilitating the removal of covered parents with each dependent child, as requested.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D33B0D250174FA690A34F18FBA0C5DB" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assisting with obtaining travel documents for dependent children as needed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H962E71A21D874C06B4725FF32B539482" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Coordinating with Federal and State or local child welfare agencies, caretakers, foreign governments, or other appropriate stakeholders.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E9D24CC74754B44812CB8D5018AEBE6" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Establishing travel procedures (that do not use contractors) for a dependent child to travel and be conveyed safely to the detention facility in which the covered parent is located for reunification and travel prior to removal.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD64DE3EF72F74C60A855F9929526528D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with independent child welfare and family law experts, shall develop and provide training on the protections required under this Act to each employee of the Department of Homeland Security, including detention facility staff who interact with covered parents.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H37242D337AE94D94867819F0FF3E0B8B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of Detained Parent Coordination shall be staffed by not less than 8 full-time employees.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0799DA5331B04BB8A08AD511D4ECA90F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualification of National Coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Coordinator shall have not less than 10 years of experience in child welfare, family court matters, or guardianship matters.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H07D8F9AFD987466280DFCAC76F18E75B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Online detainee locator system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the online detainee locator system maintained by the Department, or any successor system, is updated to include information on whether aliens were referred by State and local law enforcement agencies prior to transfer into the custody of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H43C6F13074D74F1390955331D982DDC7"><enum>9.</enum><header>Community-based case management program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 236 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H627E63C4CD344BB29F95B4AE02757ABC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HB2E3F7CD6A454CA2B833415448EEFE05"> <enum>(g)</enum> <header>Community-Based case management program</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish, outside of the purview of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, a community-based case management program that—</text>
                    <paragraph id="H1508719D6F9F4ABD89B4A0DA1157EE97">
                        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>provides alternatives to detaining aliens; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEC95C751E694E689EE95A42D7BAC219"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>offers a continuum of community-based support options and services, including—</text>
                        <subparagraph id="H1620A31603C94D759B468BDD394D314A">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>case management;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F106EC81CB641208D051ED8BF150896"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>access to—</text>
                            <clause id="H515C0D64CF554CE7B2E1FFDD37BA8E44">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>social services;</text> </clause> <clause id="HE80217D18BA044A18E081FE3F74985C8"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>medical and mental health services;</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H85B39B96AA1F4DE2AF1A3CBF21B5483A">
                                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>housing;</text> </clause> <clause id="H7F20BF0A384A4A4397BA109B2EFB3ACC"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>transportation; and</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H3AAD7CB566AB4916AA21FB9174A3C977">
                                <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>legal services; and</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDFD733EC7BE24F7AA39FB1FAB7EC2F46"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>provides services in the appropriate language.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HC8A383A71B9F491B843F6BF3F37A82C0" commented="no"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H42EC2FA07AEE4A27B7541D39A5C2F05E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a quarterly basis, the Secretary of Homeland shall publish on the Department of Homeland Security website—</text> <paragraph id="H85023D03718C4E999F0FFBDABBCFBC7B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered parents that were—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF11784284B86461D82B5027344A02656"><enum>(A)</enum><text>detained by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF12F61119B8445248C99349B28993519" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transferred to the custody of the Department of Homeland Security from a State or local law enforcement agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7AECCBBC1094AEC84F22E1859B2D921" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supported by the Secretary to make custody arrangements for each of their dependent children immediately after being taken into custody; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B117E5A393B45D0B082F23EAA002DAC" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supported by the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to make custody arrangements while in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement custody;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H726C45017DF8497A86D05396B7876DB7" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of such aliens in any ongoing proceeding, disaggregated by type of proceeding including family court, child welfare, or guardianship proceeding;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6154FA2E7F9246579777627F8D0FC059" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of such aliens with respect to which U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement facilitated participation in such proceedings;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15EAA349AC50462F84F9F2F231718140"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the minimum, maximum, average, and median duration for which covered parents who are detained by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement are in the custody;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B468EA418E74541B1164E0D0EC58248" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the placement of dependent children whose parent is a detained alien, including placement in foster care; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD66BCB8E9CF949E58652EBE23D1BE927" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of dependent children removed with their parent, disaggregated by the citizenship status and age of such children.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAE3A6CE7C01E425785245BA15CE2A489" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header> <paragraph id="HCA943540E4E841F9A14EA9AC70871C0C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report that contains the information collected under subsection (a) for the preceding 180-day period to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCEACAA4F9F884C8B880953EF72503180" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary, Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA37662808A3F4DDA97C7C36274B832E5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary, Committee and Homeland Security, and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E1802EFBFE344B08575229B8B535F72" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>The initial report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include a detailed summary of the efforts of the Secretary to carry out this Act, including a description of the manner in which the Secretary plans collect and store the data required to be included in each report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7B6B44F95BE40799BA49D25CFBD90DF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text>Each subsequent report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, for the preceding 180-day period—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H881EC151D5314841A88B213418D33544" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number employees of the Department, coordinating entities, and detention facilities provided annual training under section 8; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B8D4478427147DEB50BB8807DC4A236" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of new employees of the Department, coordinating entities, and detention facilities who have been provided an initial training under that section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8AFB85D259954C119AFA152D2E1ABF29" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="H001FFF74BA544564AD586CBC783359A9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the methods for collecting information are consistent from year to year so as to enable the tracking of trends across years; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H133AE16AE1D4483B98029D03D6AE456C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>personally identifiable information is protected.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB100C8FD5F674149AEC5F4956DBF21D3"><enum>11.</enum><header>Remedies</header> <subsection id="H9D8B6C7F01FF4E66899F01765793EE78"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)), in the case of a covered parent described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="HABF05D14422540029B22CC84B601F6FF">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>if the parent desires reunification, facilitate the reunification in the United States of any dependent child with the parent in a community-based setting, at the expense of the Government, as expeditiously as possible, but not later than 2 months after the removal of the covered parent; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE28C8F51A9264981BF7BB4B470048B9A">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>facilitate, at the expense of the Government, the ability of the parent to make necessary arrangements for their dependent child to remain in the United States, including participation in any family court or child welfare proceedings.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD2ECD7AFBB644AAAF942731B582C680"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered parent described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered parent described in this subsection is a covered parent—</text> <paragraph id="HC25738C2DC044685B14152E7CBD6D530"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who was removed from the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA31F83617A5A4A0893F29FEF4F040B0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to whom the Secretary did not afford the protections required under this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F69DAA742B04F36A5A8DA54F371B2FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whose dependent child remained in the United States after the parent’s removal.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4BAEEABBECED44A4B505A511A1FCCF63"><enum>12.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to impede, delay, or limit the obligations of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, or the Secretary of Health and Human Services under—</text> <paragraph id="H55D98FE66AED47C5AF1520EFE1733E18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 235 of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4877FCC3AD949F99285E25A43C06338"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 462 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB81A24A62E6347D18B44E59B0A913709"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>the stipulated settlement agreement filed in the United States District Court for the Central District of California on January 17, 1997 (CV 85–10BUR26159 V3Y S.L.C.4544–RJK) (commonly known as the <quote>Flores Settlement Agreement</quote>).</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBCDBF58F1E944056AE833013335359DE"><enum>13.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H74D1FF6FA31B41CFAD50C1A5CCDE3A60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered parent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered parent</term> means an alien who is a parent of a dependent child, which child is physically present in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82A069DD8219470B87819DACFD9FD2C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dependent child</header><text>The term <term>dependent child</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="HD187DC480483406DA70963071BAF4B6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has not attained the age of 18; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE94FFEA629B54541A2831DF5537686FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is incapable of self-support because of physical, medical, or mental disability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE065EF480C604DBBA450BDA327474BEC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>parent</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCBD1EAF2054D4A28B1DE700E9DF9BBE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a biological or adoptive parent, or an adult otherwise recognized by the law of a foreign country as a parent, whose parental rights have not been relinquished or terminated under State law or the law of a foreign country;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B14E66B5D0E4B0C9CB3E2973EB832E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a legal guardian of a child under State law or the law of a foreign country; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A92A427707641F182AECCB6BAF0189E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a kin caregiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

