<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E7203FF30474CEA8696B532B6439978" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1402 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of Alzheimer’s and Brain Awareness Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1402</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000482">Mrs. Fedorchak</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of Alzheimer’s and Brain Awareness Month.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Alzheimer’s disease is a slow, progressive disorder of the brain that results in loss of memory and other cognitive function and, eventually, death;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alzheimer’s disease is the seventh leading cause of death in the United States and the fifth leading cause of death for persons aged 65 and over;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 7,000,000 Americans in the United States are living with Alzheimer’s disease, and this number may increase to 13,000,000 by the year 2050;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas almost two-thirds of those living with Alzheimer’s disease are women;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that 1 in 3 older Americans dies with Alzheimer’s disease or another dementia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the early detection and diagnosis of Alzheimer’s disease and other dementias can improve health outcomes and quality of life;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas recent research demonstrates that healthy lifestyle interventions can help protect cognitive health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the direct costs to United States society of caring for Alzheimer’s disease patients in 2026 is estimated to be $409,000,000,000;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 13,000,000 Americans provide unpaid care for people with Alzheimer’s disease or another dementia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 70 percent of Alzheimer’s disease and dementia caregivers rate the emotional stress of caregiving as high or very high;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 40 percent of family caregivers for individuals living with Alzheimer’s disease and other forms of dementia report symptoms of depression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas older Black Americans face nearly 2 times higher risk of developing Alzheimer’s disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas older Latinos face 1.5 times higher risk of developing Alzheimer’s disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders are at high risk for underdetection of dementia and Alzheimer’s disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every American is at risk for developing Alzheimer’s disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas stigma around having Alzheimer’s disease contributes to underdetection and failure to diagnose the disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas health disparities continue to exist for underserved populations, including Black, Latino, and Asian-American communities, in the care, caregiving, and research of Alzheimer’s disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June is Alzheimer’s and Brain Awareness Month;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Alzheimer’s Association established Alzheimer’s and Brain Awareness Month in 2014, and the inaugural Alzheimer’s and Brain Awareness Month was celebrated in June of that year; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Alzheimer’s and Brain Awareness Month is an opportunity to—</text><paragraph id="HE14D5CE5177E443B9C280F1E2811E095"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">raise awareness about Alzheimer’s disease and other forms of dementia;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6974625ED7748B7B06FFB7DF45087F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advocate for Alzheimer’s disease and other forms of dementia research, care, and support services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4501B06958B4329BCD297644F3614F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>offer support to individuals living with Alzheimer’s disease and other forms of dementia, their families, and their caregivers: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDAE0931E41034490B0608962979D778D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HEBE3BE6EDE2A40379366492FB4D5D8A7"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H25D4400772444C9392C2D5501E912C0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of Alzheimer’s and Brain Awareness Month; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E5D34684EE348DAA16C24215E843081"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages people in the United States to—</text><subparagraph id="H0369CFE3E460468B97D445D93D53818B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educate themselves about Alzheimer’s disease and other forms of dementia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H050931F231A74400BC463A13EEFB2722"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advocate for Alzheimer’s disease research, care, and support services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A1606B768F74DEEAD05E23AA2DA9569"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offer their support to individuals living with Alzheimer’s disease and other forms of dementia, their families, and their caregivers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

