<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25B90-874-2G-K74"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3423 IS: Lowering Egg Prices Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3423</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To make inapplicable to surplus broiler hatching eggs certain regulations relating to shell eggs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE6722A65D5E143ABA40ECA7D4C7D6AEF"><section section-type="section-one" id="H12CA7DB99D9549CD921E6F2FF76F3634"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lowering Egg Prices Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H33F70D32BA47400E91FA57FD3ECE31CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inapplicability of certain shell egg rule provisions to surplus broiler hatching eggs sold to egg breakers</header><subsection id="HB9C1150AA97A4CEF9BF093069DE6A529"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inapplicability of current rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date of the enactment of this Act, section 118.4(e) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) shall not apply with respect to surplus broiler hatching eggs that are intended to be sold to an egg breaker for purposes of processing such eggs as liquid egg products subject to regulation under the Egg Products Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1031">21 U.S.C. 1031 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H849B3490A80B46EB95661A5EDC2275A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revised rule required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall issue a rule revising section 118.4 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to allow for surplus broiler hatching eggs to be held at such temperature and for such period of time at such temperature, so as to be compatible with conditions for hatching chicks and to allow for the sale of such eggs to egg breakers for the purposes described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC9202DD6DCE842CCA31570277ECABC92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HADAC2EFF26B149E4AAC9171B63908F09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <term>egg</term> and <term>egg product</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Egg Products Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1033">21 U.S.C. 1033</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC900C517FA6A469BBBA3290E4F46E2EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>egg breaker</term> means a facility in the commercial sector that processes eggs by breaking the eggs out of their shells and selling the resulting liquid egg product in bulk to food manufacturers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7008262C96184A29B203D5C85938D460"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>broiler hatching egg</term> means an egg intended for use by broiler hatcheries for the production of baby chicks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8395C70B5694AC2B873570B51E1EBE0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>broiler hatchery</term> means a facility where fertilized eggs from broiler breeder chickens are incubated and hatched into day-old chicks, which are then raised on farms to produce meat as broiler chickens.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

