<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26779-0TR-XV-88L"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4405 IS: 287(g) Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4405</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize an increase in the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant allocation for jurisdictions that enter into a 287(g) agreement to enhance immigration enforcement.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idecf92b38d1e14c7a963d8f1f5bff01d1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>287(g) Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4a24db0fec148d596f840658b52dc19"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of increased Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant allocation for jurisdictions that enter into a 287(g) agreement to enhance immigration enforcement</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7943915c54248bea2bc0fa3e822fa5a"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applications for increased grant funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 505 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10156">34 U.S.C. 10156</external-xref>), any State or political subdivision of a State that has entered into a written agreement with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, in accordance with section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>) (referred to in this section as a <quote>287(g) Agreement</quote>), may submit an application to the Attorney General to receive an increased allocation under such section in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id46f38c66fd6b47329509f377c281f700"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increased allocation authorized</header><text>The Attorney General, in collaboration with the Secretary of Homeland Security, upon receiving an application described in subsection (a) and confirming that the applicant has entered into a 287(g) Agreement, shall increase the annual amount allocated for Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grants to such applicant by not more than 10 percent of the average annual amount allocated to such applicant during the 3 most recent years in which the applicant received such funding.</text></subsection></section><section id="id8081d1632b264bf4b3149992f8fed9b0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated, for each of the fiscal years 2027 through 2033, $20,000,000, which shall be expended to provide increased funding to States and political subdivisions of States pursuant to section 2(b).</text></section></legis-body></bill>

