<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE7E05164D674043AF5A1B3EFBCA7647" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6027 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for an annual increase in the rates of compensation for veterans with service-connected disabilities and the rates of dependency and indemnity compensation for the survivors of certain disabled veterans, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6027</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for an annual increase in the rates of compensation for veterans with service-connected disabilities and the rates of dependency and indemnity compensation for the survivors of certain disabled veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26BA1F8AC0F64FF0B38E55CAE2C3300B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE923740BF47E492BB3A2B45CDC7FF519" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Annual increase in rates of Department of Veterans Affairs disability compensation and dependency and indemnity compensation</header> 
<subsection id="HF48A6465DCE4412BA0437999E7A38889"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H7FD59F22AAB84970B387693564E275AD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H74DB3B4DE0E1433BAF5E0DB80EE36B92"><enum>120.</enum><header>Annual increase in disability compensation and dependency and indemnity compensation</header></section> <subsection id="H37E9D8A9978D429D94F4A48526ECCD25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rate adjustment</header><text>Effective on December 1 of each year, the Secretary shall increase, in accordance with subsection (c), the dollar amounts in effect on November 30 of that year, for the payment of disability compensation and dependency and indemnity compensation under the provisions specified in subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H49C5972D2E05424AA67FE69892AD3192"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts To be increased</header><text>The dollar amounts to be increased pursuant to subsection (a) are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H163827C2D84143D582D1544328032CCA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Wartime disability compensation</header><text>Each of the dollar amounts under section 1114 of this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H294CC89288E3476E88032EA71F764243"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional compensation for dependents</header><text>Each of the dollar amounts under section 1115(1) of this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50F2363D5EFF4FBEBC57D2162C8960FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clothing allowance</header><text>The dollar amount under section 1162 of this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC76C3D643AE9453D8560E56E1F5B64F7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dependency and indemnity compensation to surviving spouse</header><text>Each of the dollar amounts under subsections (a) through (d) of section 1311 of this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE235741B392C4067A06165AF17068213"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dependency and indemnity compensation to children</header><text>Each of the dollar amounts under sections 1313(a) and 1314 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H171C9252083E439899469A305200AEBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of Increase</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each dollar amount described in subsection (b) shall be increased by the same percentage as the percentage by which benefit amounts payable under title II of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>) are increased effective December 1 of such year as a result of a determination under section 215(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/415">42 U.S.C. 415(i)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H974328724C6C4BA098C857573DF93549"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>The Secretary may adjust administratively, consistent with the increases made under subsection (a), the rates of disability compensation payable to persons under section 10 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/857">Public Law 85–857</external-xref> (72 Stat. 1263) who have not received compensation under chapter 11 of this title.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H867208A664864BBB87BCC5B299425D35"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication of adjusted rates</header><text>Each fiscal year, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the amounts specified in subsection (b), as increased under subsection (a), not later than the date on which the matters specified in section 215(i)(2)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/415">42 U.S.C. 415(i)(2)(D)</external-xref>) are required to be published by reason of a determination made under section 215(i) of such Act during that fiscal year.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBBC17A1E97ED4F149B1E70D7AED3B86D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 119 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H4146EEEED57F4076910DF35DDA230080" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">120. Annual increase in disability compensation and dependency and indemnity compensation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAE93106F2B6B4D7FAF900B54E4F30184"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 120 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

