<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5FA64EEB4BD442178FBE1BC3641505EE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9435 IH: Ensuring Exclave Communities are Listened to And their Voices are Examined Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9435</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require consultation by agencies during rulemaking in the case of unique burdens on pene-exclaves.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA3C989EF5FAE46BD9A9D1804188463E5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H08A55FF7BFB64785A40ACA0FC878F864" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Exclave Communities are Listened to And their Voices are Examined Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>EXCLAVE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HBBEFA48021714EA6A81B28D6988B075F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consultation regarding unique regulatory burdens on pene-exclaves</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H4E27925AD45B4461AA11EB83A994EB51" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H030CD90B8FD74D2985B9C105C607DECA"><enum>(f)</enum> <paragraph id="H642331CAE90C45A8ABEE3848C0E7EF3E" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the agency determines, prior to the publication of the general notice under subsection (b) that a proposed rule may impose a unique burden on residents of a pene-exclave, the agency shall include in such notice a statement to that effect.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7D8C875DEB8469C8C3ACB6088958854" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the agency makes a determination under paragraph (1), or if, during the public comment period under subsection (c), the agency receives a comment from a resident of a pene-exclave alleging that the proposed rule would impose a unique burden on residents of the pene-exclave, the agency shall, not later than 30 days after making such determination or reviewing such comment (whichever is earlier)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEE5E4A8350FB416AA3D5148660290455"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hold a public meeting, exclusively for residents of a pene-exclave to submit written data, views, or arguments pertaining to the unique burden, that is reasonably accessible (including by using telecommunication equipment to allow remote participation) to each of those residents;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDEB9269FCBE46708109210B2B427CDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide notice of such meeting (including the date, time, and location of the meeting) not later than 30 days prior to such meeting to relevant State, county, Tribal, and local government officials; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD285010C59A547A8A014A99CFA5CCCEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>record all communications received that pertain to the meeting and record the minutes of such meeting (including the content of any comments made at such meeting by such residents), and publish all such records in the Federal Register by not later than 60 days after such meeting.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B3C13A47130421A9008EFB00EA74290" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the publication of the final rule, the agency shall include a response to each comment received or made at such meeting from a resident of the pene-exclave.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49B4416265274ECB814FB552801A89DB" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget shall establish a process for each agency to identify comments referred to in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22DCE62621394D1C8BB19006E15EF3F9" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H717DEC8C8A7B48CFAF94E4F4755C5E13"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unique burden</term> means, in the case of an individual who resides in a pene-exclave, any circumstance resulting from such residence that hinders such individual’s ability to—</text> 
<clause id="H1026262F313D49EAA9E4725203AFFEDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cross the border of the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H2EFF7EC4290845A486ED827889AC7510"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access emergency management services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAAA1A08265EC4B28B9B76B620EBDC0CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>access veterinary care;</text></clause> <clause id="HD3A5D5A7045643CCA1E60905289BC71B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>procure food, health care, or any other necessity of life; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA44ABE12CD984B27A098FFCC9F429400"><enum>(v)</enum><text>conduct any trade or business.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD216FCA9383F4467AAA7ED1F781C8137"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>pene-exclave</term> means any region of a State or territory of the United States that is generally accessible by land only by travel through the territory of a foreign country. For purposes of this paragraph, any such region that is geographically contiguous with any other part of the United States only by reason of impassable terrain may not be considered to be generally accessible by land. Such term may not be construed to apply to the entirety of a State or territory.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H65B91B3B506D4D3096057CDB12F0AB9E"><enum>3.</enum><header>OMB list</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall establish a list of pene-exclaves in the United States and the appropriate contact information for the relevant State, Tribal, county, municipal, and local governmental officials. Any organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code, that is domiciled in the pene-exclave shall be added to such list on the filing of such a petition.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

