<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H318500ACFB264FAEBFE056F025C89C86">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5829 IH: Leveraging Aerial Systems for Stewardship Operations (LASSO) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5829</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251024">October 24, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a grant program to support the use of unmanned aerial systems for the humane roundup and management of wild horses and burros.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HF4D6FDCD399D4D82AE7234E0AAEADB18">
<section id="HD57A86F63BEB4B17A3B5E77F3FA13C08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leveraging Aerial Systems for Stewardship Operations (LASSO) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF803F0F1A2FF41FBB15F2DB23EC7C4B0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Wild free-roaming horses and burros uas program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1338a">16 U.S.C. 1338a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HEEEFCA3FBEFC44D4A54114227A3602A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In administering this Act,</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H594F42A6E9404ECE9EABEB86BEFDAD6B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HEAE03D8312D94428A5E0AC22DF70ABDE"><enum>(a)</enum><text>In administering this Act,</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71B244A44D0E4905A6A2D8EDC632D1D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H90FD572741434229BE1CD5325AD3CFD0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H411CC3839A2E40B499ECC274C02B2807"><enum>(b)</enum><text>For each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030, from funds made available to carry out this Act, the Secretary shall allocate $100,000 for grants to support pilot projects that test whether unmanned aerial systems can be used to successfully and humanely gather and manage wild horses and burros. Grants issued under this subsection shall be awarded to organizations, including institutions of higher learning, with demonstrated expertise in drone technology, and a proven commitment to research which furthers equine welfare. Grants may also support pilot projects using unmanned aerial systems for humane fertility control application and related herd-health efforts. Reports with results from all funded pilot projects shall be made available to Congress and the public not later than 180 days after the conclusion of each study. Organizations receiving grants under this subsection shall also submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Department of Agriculture a report evaluating the potential uses of unmanned aerial systems for ranching, animal care, and environmental stewardship.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

