<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H84CFEBE94F9E45019CC5333B11668D7D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5934 IH: Major Thomas D. Howie Congressional Gold Medal</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5934</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional gold medal to Major Thomas D. Howie, in recognition of his bravery and outstanding service during the Battle of Normandy.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2C0FED2BE6964E6AAE4DEF781975996D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H41FA09D813944A8BA154DAC11F50F809" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Major Thomas D. Howie Congressional Gold Medal</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0A71E5AF5EB94C7F8C09CAD421222032"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H494F7908781042C7BFA2503B9277A583">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Major Thomas D. Howie was born on April 12, 1908, in Abbeville, South Carolina, and went on to both a storied academic and athletic career at The Citadel as class president, a star football halfback, and captain of the baseball team.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H171EAAFEC344422EAE26F34900836AB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Major Howie answered his nations call to service by accepting a commission as a Second Lieutenant in the Officers Reserve Corps in the Virginia National Guard upon graduation from The Citadel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4163204719074A14BDC11270248653B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Major Howie was commissioned into the U.S. Army Reserve and later transferred to the Virginia National Guard’s 116th Infantry Regiment in Staunton, Virginia.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H294F9C9FB6C74ABAA59FB272B89E88D3">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Major Thomas Howie valiantly served his country during the Battle of Normandy, demonstrating exceptional courage, devotion to duty, and skill in battle after landing on Omaha Beach on June 6, 1944.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCD2707EBBA0D495F9E04F0A4DB69287D">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Major Howie commanded 3rd Battalion, 116th Infantry Regiment, 29th Infantry Division on July 13, 1944, and shortly thereafter was tasked with rescuing the encircled 2nd Battalion, 116th Infantry Regiment.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70EA2737A0D74ACE93D8BFF5842750EA">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Major Howie was instructed by his commanding officer to take St. Lo on July 17, 1944, he decided to leave the battered 2nd Battalion behind to recuperate and proceed with only the 3rd Battalion. When questioned on this, he was overheard saying <quote>See you in St. Lo</quote> to Major General Charles Gerhardt, words which would serve as inspiration for his men in the coming battle.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9ED5E1E9DD9C44B88C50E08DFD13D2F7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>While giving his company commanders instructions for the attack, the unit came under fire from German mortars, and Major Howie was killed, a sacrifice for which he was posthumously awarded a Silver Star, Bronze Star, Purple Heart, French Legion of Honor, French Fourragere, and Combat Infantry Badge.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74F8AB73D90D4939A8F373CEDE420C6C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Major Howie’s men strapped his body to a stretcher, draped him with an American flag, and placed him on the hood of a Jeep so that he could be the first American to enter St. Lo. He was laid in the rubble of the St. Croix Cathedral, where fellow soldiers and French civilians paid their respects. From then on, he was known as <quote>The Major of St. Lo</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB1544A69B6B94084A68B82ADF58FD6C4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Major Howie’s leadership and unwavering commitment to his soldiers inspired bravery and determination among his troops, ultimately leading to the successful capture of St. Lo, a crucial strategic objective that directly led to Operation Cobra and the Allied Liberation France, Belgium, and the Netherlands from Nazi Tyranny.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B8436B34451418A80DF0EAE1D29366F"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Though his command of the 116th Infantry Regiment was short-lived, Major Howie embodied the extraordinary courage and valor that defined American soldiers during the Battle of Normandy. His sacrifice echoes through the halls of history to inspire Americans to this day.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED9093ADFE2D4784B90BA38C41F6CAC0"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The character of Major Howie was used as inspiration for the role of Captain John Miller, portrayed by Tom Hanks in the movie <quote>Saving Private Ryan</quote>. This brought attention to his remarkable leadership and sacrifice, thereby furthering public recognition of his valor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CEC36E8671649438048BFE6040B161B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Major Howie’s legacy extends beyond the silver screen. Monuments and markers commemorating his valor and leadership stand in Abbeville, Greenwood, and Charleston, South Carolina; Staunton, Virginia; Shelby, North Carolina; and Saint-Lo, Normandy, France. In 2003, South Carolina further honored him with a posthumous induction into the South Carolina Hall of Fame.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE47529B95DE74904949F3A64C4B3FE7C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Major Howie’s sacrifice and exemplary service symbolize the highest ideals of patriotism, integrity, and dedication to duty.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F66D2154B1F48D7BA7894772E4906E4"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Major Thomas D. Howie’s legacy continues to inspire future generations to uphold the seven army values of loyalty, duty, respect, selfless service, honor, integrity, and personal courage.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H8915E6A05DBD43108A414C779EB2E42C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header>
<subsection id="H78ABE31868F04F84AC219C7D4F256A26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous award, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to Major Thomas D. Howie, in recognition of his bravery and outstanding service during the Battle of Normandy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H85DF5493DF4749E6BE9B7C9004C98945"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purpose of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE4965E8F4F194E9FB7B48243AD32FE08" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Presentation</header><text>The gold medal referred to in subsection (a) shall be presented to—</text> <paragraph id="H811EDD39D2B546B6B44E2D883D199CE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the nephew of Thomas Howie, Tom Howie; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H017DF6AC226643278F4924A757533E77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if Tom Howie is unavailable, the next of kin of Thomas Howie.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1C1FB271E5B84154BBBBAFE2F5680C7B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Award of medal</header><text>Following the presentation described in subsection (c), the gold medal shall be given to The Citadel Museum, where it shall be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H57AA489302F24840A344D68F5F73B121"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs of such medals, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="H5FF43CBF63904632909065C64CCFEBE2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> <subsection id="HB5AF0B543A7A4BAA94115AEBFE32C25A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H53621BCC477347A48FB3ADC83100DBF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD3F6BC0937B44113981DCB9D1C071DEE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> <subsection id="HC8FE8D84CDAB401C90E2C6D21E2414E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDECFAFFF2F024F25BE21C112C03A5137"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>The amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

