<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE9442DC5B7D7427C8C5116FB45EAB118" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9728 IH: Protecting America’s Diplomatic Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9728</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to modify the requirements relating to reductions in force for Foreign Service officers and certain other Federal employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H40F1A6CE529F485B952C910EB2644C82" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H567E5F8B9DBF49A9BE30821F133B5AFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting America’s Diplomatic Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H00ECD7B72BE24261B576D8550BF2FBB9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improved transparency and justifications for significant reductions in force</header> <subsection id="HA1250D3DE385459687EFBF9FB7A2C0BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), during any 6-month period, a covered agency may not separate more than 50 employees from service pursuant to 1 or more reductions in force.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H738803BADC774803A89F989141CA04D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A covered agency may separate more than 50 employees from service pursuant to 1 or more reductions in force during a 6-month period only if, before carrying out the reduction in force that would cause the covered agency to violate subsection (a), the covered agency—</text> <paragraph id="HFE163E0FF196433AB273E02013FDFA9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 20 days before submitting a notice of the reduction in force to affected employees, submits to the appropriate congressional committees of jurisdiction a detailed explanation of the reduction in force that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF95319BA06014BB58DC25FA35628A60E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the steps the covered agency has taken to exhaust all other options before carrying out the proposed reduction in force, including whether the covered agency considered reassigning the employees to an equivalent position;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B0F981EF6E547F79F13629BDC4B7DC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the justification for the reduction in force;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H140D7FA75AFA434DBB1F7EF07D78319C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the proposed reduction in force will negatively impact the covered agency’s ability to carry out its mission and obligations required by statute;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE8B2F7747AF4DB7859B641C82902A09"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of how the proposed reduction in force will affect United States diplomatic presence and engagement and the United States ability to compete with adversaries; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD03A455C6FCF41B1AA99B6ABD00F8788"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with respect to employees in the civil service, information about how the covered agency has complied with—</text> <clause id="H48E8B4E51CAF40F5AE997E879A6BB528"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6C38E65277046368F0A744A89AD8A2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>part 351 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation); and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAFA90DB861554A4EA327FE5DF9F739EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>briefs the appropriate congressional committees of jurisdiction on the justification for the reduction in force and the other criteria described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H432D8E79CC9C47C28A5B7D12F478C0FE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Foreign service reduction in force procedures</header> 
<subsection id="H28F311F033D040D592369DDAAFF81AA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 611 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4010a">22 U.S.C. 4010a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA3475DECD3F048C193A290DB0C99E7BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H32306223BA9C4B95B0F846D0D9462620" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H1258EBCDB2EF43A886726DDFFA414551"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Secretary may conduct reductions in force for the separation of members of the Service holding a career or career candidate appointment under chapter 3 for reasons such as reorganization or shortage of funds.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AAC3681D4C7425B965EC8F5A46AD348"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) (as amended) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC458B8D566BB4616AB5131B6B67871B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block id="H3C8FB4BD1F4F48F491B502DDA587461C" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H26E6B7E4CB054E20AD14E7E9EC9F9271"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Competitive area</header><text>The competitive area for a reduction in force shall be worldwide, with employees of the same rank and cone or specialist competing against each other for retention.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD63859FB717475C9AE72987CBFFAF71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>Reduction in force procedures shall be designed to ensure that determinations are based primarily on performance as determined by previous selection board rankings. Tenure of employment, language capabilities, and military preference, subject to section 3501(a)(3) of title 5, United States Code, shall also be considered.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H065CEAE90A804B9C80EEC66EA828346A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Required notice</header><text>Absent unforeseen circumstances, members of the Service shall be given 120 days advance notice of separation. In no case shall members be given less than 60 days advance notice.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF78BB60CE2A64036BDBCAD8D3C961145"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Protections</header><text>Members of the Service shall be afforded the same protections afforded to career members of the civil service under section 3503 of title 5, United States Code, in the event of a transfer of function.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA25E2AA1FC0489C8F305737EBBC366B"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>in subsection (g), as redesignated by paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Grievances under chapter 11</quote> through <quote>of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>The Foreign Service Grievances Board shall have the same authority as the Merit Systems Protection Board to adjudicate reduction in force grievances.</quote>.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FA131BE5FF34030B729C895431B339A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management rights</header><text>Section 1005(a)(3) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4105">22 U.S.C. 4105(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, and to prescribe regulations for the separation of employees pursuant to such reductions in force conducted under section 611</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0084898F81A841788BE6A65E4962D5E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notice period required for reductions in force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The notice period for a reduction in force pursuant to section 3502 of title 5, United States Code, at a covered agency shall be 60 days.</text></section> 
<section id="H6594DF8A620548F4957FD84123FAC192"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prior consultation and briefing requirements for significant changes to the foreign affairs manual</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5318(c) of the Department of State Authorization Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2658a">22 U.S.C. 2658a(c)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting at the end of the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H224D3A94F6A54F35B43C0E8F82EFC134" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H50B10D04FB12429B81EEFA416F494126"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice; consultation; briefing</header><text>Before effectuating any significant changes in the Foreign Affairs Manual, the Secretary of State shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4EEB6CA40C414CBFB7070510A60F51AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide notice to, and consult with, the appropriate congressional committees in writing, not later than 30 days before such changes are scheduled to take effect; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA42CA87962B4B30B99A4BA7BC370F76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the proposed changes.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H0637D7A43CA74ED5B3CCC3D854099453"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HAAC49E53A4E64B2FA46CACB38E0BF603"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5406B80AB6C45BC89CDEF43248928D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <quote>covered agency</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC1B4D8C60144050ACC9F3D9DC051C9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84D4AFD2237B4E2BAC92C0614D1B05B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States Agency for International Development;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE9625E1C2834591B7D218A06B2490CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Millennium Challenge Corporation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB74A861613C44EC97FDD0A19F01E6D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74B4353BC2FD4182B42C0EA9F9B6BF7A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Peace Corps;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5D15683E6D64C7EB61C1E017CBDE433">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>the Foreign Agricultural Service within the Department of Agriculture;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3812D94F7174451BF58D1F9A353A707">
                    <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service within the Department of Agriculture;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCFBF65E56BDC43CEBE07D2FB1DD0895A">
                    <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>the Foreign Commercial Service within the Department of Commerce;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H758E6326A3204760A0B0FF305E9AC445"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the United States Trade and Development Agency; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DA779196ACC44F398074B6046502AF8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the United States Agency for Global Media and its networks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

