<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H70FF73DBCB5949D38086D799D4884AB7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6254 IH: Medicaid Staffing Flexibility and Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6254</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to allow States more flexibility with respect to using contractors to make eligibility determinations and redeterminations and conduct fair hearings on behalf of the State Medicaid plan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCFA486EE91364BA3B8E1D84A26FA431B"><section id="HA9DFBCAA51894C029B2B49049F101AFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Staffing Flexibility and Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H494FB1F152C948BC9C8425D93B83877A"><enum>2.</enum><header>State flexibility to use contractors to make eligibility determinations, redeterminations, and fair hearings on behalf of a state</header><subsection id="H40535AC220DC4774AE8B8C8176DF098F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements With Respect to Eligibility Determinations</header><text>Section 1902(a)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, but such determinations of eligibility may be made, at the option of a State, under a contract with another State or local agency or a contractor, so long as the contract does not provide incentives for the agency or contractor to delay eligibility determinations or to deny eligibility for individuals otherwise eligible for medical assistance</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE82EF9F438FE4F6799A7AC621B0C7CF7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements With respect to fair hearings</header><text>Section 1902(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, except that such fair hearing may be conducted, at the option of a State, under a contract with another State or local agency or a contractor, so long as such agency or contractor does not provide incentives to delay a fair hearing or to deny eligibility for an individual otherwise eligible for medical assistance</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC42C81BBDCCA46978FBA9DF8C871DEF7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting conflicts of interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State shall not use the flexibility provided under section 2 unless a contractor selected to conduct eligibility determinations or redeterminations pursuant to the amendments made by such section has no direct or indirect financial relationship with any Medicaid managed care organization (as defined in section 1903(m)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(m)(1)(A)</external-xref>)), including the network providers affiliated with such organization, that provides services to individuals entitled to medical assistance under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) pursuant to a contract with such State.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

