<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95F10111E1CB42D0AE1AFE5A5736D1BC" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1311 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 2026 as “Necrotizing Fasciitis Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 2026 as <quote>Necrotizing Fasciitis Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas necrotizing fasciitis is a rare but severe bacterial infection that spreads rapidly in the body’s soft tissue and can lead to significant morbidity and mortality if not treated promptly;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas necrotizing fasciitis is often caused by bacteria, such as Group A Streptococcus, though other pathogens may also be responsible;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas early symptoms may include redness, swelling, fever, and severe pain;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the infection can progress quickly to tissue destruction, systemic illness, and death;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas prompt diagnosis and immediate medical intervention, including antibiotics and surgical treatment, are critical to improving patient outcomes;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas increased awareness among the public and health care providers can lead to earlier recognition, faster treatment, and improved survival rates;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas survivors of necrotizing fasciitis often face long-term physical and emotional challenges, including recovery from extensive surgeries and rehabilitation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas advocacy organizations, health care professionals, and survivors work to educate the public about the risks, symptoms, and prevention of necrotizing fasciitis; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas designating a month for awareness would help promote education, encourage early detection, and support affected individuals and families: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H587F255C1D1442D4A34D95CC83DFE9E4"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H07CEB5AA43AB4DB9B32A953A4D9AA027"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F6AEBC01EC74D359CFE7117F50496FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Necrotizing Fasciitis Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FF34C69F1864164B6505CAF25A449E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages Federal, State, and local agencies, health care providers, and community organizations to promote awareness of necrotizing fasciitis; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H827918AACBD3494D8E3EDAC868F8DB44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges increased public education on the early signs and symptoms of necrotizing fasciitis to improve timely diagnosis and treatment; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB59D351064C4CBBB8788770B1E1D8B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses support for patients, survivors, families, and caregivers affected by necrotizing fasciitis.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

