<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD59950BF400547EFB44BE5593E343C2E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7469 IH: SNAP Online Access Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7469</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 authorize the use of benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program for online grocery purchases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4DCB7EE03C2342CF8B0D5549D22A87C5" style="OLC"><section id="H1151368F53D549C3A78A2D1918A01091" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SNAP Online Access Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC47E1D450C0E49C5B658852D2C4963F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Permanent authority for supplemental nutrition assistance program online purchasing</header><subsection id="H6806B05B30204445B3EAEDBB48948E60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2016">7 U.S.C. 2016</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H82ABF32B02B74292BAB207E374B3D107" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7C3E2AFB70994D2487B21E038A7BE394"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Online purchasing program</header><paragraph id="H39491200EC0244F78A8ADAFD78E0C660"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permanent authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the effective date of this subsection, the Secretary shall begin transitioning the supplemental nutrition assistance program online purchasing initiative from pilot or demonstration status to permanent nationwide program operations, with the completion of the regulations marking the end of the transition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0831B960B4374A29B379D162C9D37AD5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations and guidance as may be necessary to carry out paragraph (1), including provisions related to program integrity, consumer protections, and equitable access. Such regulations shall be issued not later than 2 years after the effective date of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67905E64B9394D96A052D24690E2F5DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholder consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a formal process for consultation with State agencies, authorized retailers, electronic benefit transfer processors, consumer advocates, and other relevant stakeholders to incorporate lessons learned from online purchasing operations during the period of 2014 through 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H004BD1D02084451E8D0AEFDA2C4E94CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the effective date of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing the consultation process and recommendations received.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

