<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B7E563F3AFB46AA9E79B1A56855E966" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9751 IH: Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9751</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employment Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to establish additional requirements relating to claims and appeals.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFADAA4AB52AD4F22A6DCD2C9C2CF3145" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5DAA3C3017C84B2E8060E515EDDD061D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF17D29A8EBAD4BFFB57DACA9FBAA670C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enforcement of claims procedure and external review requirements</header> <subsection id="H4AA3EE4655EA47FA9218E5B2471A4CDD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Equitable relief and penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 502(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0DB3F406E06E4C16869EFD95EE6283C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>or the terms of the plan</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB7B547E745248F58DA9E7CEFAF73F4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7AAB1C4814E9422981893182EB2C3999" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H183A4848AB8F4977AFBAE8417BC51B44"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the Secretary to collect any civil penalty under this title;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE3A5DE04C7764581B71F955BDDF69FBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty for claims procedure and external review requirement violations</header><text>Section 502(c) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2B4DD19E3445431D86299BD8A63AD6B7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HFDF2745610374B949F846DA844D2CF89"><enum>(14)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HE5A77D753CA24226A2B1A5CE589A5082" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Global and individual violations</header> 
<clause id="H83165C10EF194C4CBADBBC8429854D3F" indent="down1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may assess a civil penalty under subparagraph (B) against any person or entity (other than a plan) that materially causes (including through failure to perform required actions) a global violation described in clause (ii) or individual violation described in clause (iii).</text></clause> <clause id="H51C736681EBC47E0A66AB7F7D0B95BEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Global violation</header><text>It shall be deemed a global violation for a plan to fail to have—</text> 
<subclause id="HBD3E2E8171E94AB58836841D2D65FAD5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a claims procedure that complies (in writing or in operation) with—</text> <item id="H2CD4BF432BB74F02B6EA5367ED940946"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the terms of the plan; or</text></item> 
<item id="H139743E7620E48B781848D4DDABB7B5D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>section 503 (including the requirements of section 2560.503–1 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</short-title>); or</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H2F1F795313B9451A8832DE09ABE6D7E7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an external review process that complies (in writing or in operation) with—</text> 
<item id="HE2D7A309603F451FA52F7424C7D21C43"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the terms of the plan; or</text></item> <item id="H2C1BAEA4800B4559B8C67507A44B518E" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the requirements of section 2590.715–2719 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</short-title>.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HF11C57DCB69547DF923631A684385B92"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Individual violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be deemed an individual violation for a plan to fail to—</text> <subclause id="H0E3F9155955C4794826919843E85F71B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a required notification or disclosure to a participant or beneficiary that includes all required content;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8EC687D76DB4478791D190EAEA9EF763"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">respond to or decide a participant’s or beneficiary’s claim, appeal or request for external review in a timely manner; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H041851917BA742B8B92D104EC8884F49" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">respond to a participant’s or beneficiary’s communication or request for information with the requested information to which the participant or beneficiary is legally entitled;</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">in a manner that violates the plan’s written
                                    claims procedure, section 503 (including the requirements of
                                    section 2560.503–1 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as
                                    in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer
                                        Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</short-title>)), or the
                                    requirements of section 2590.715–2719 of title 29, Code of
                                    Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of
                                    the <short-title>Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement
                                        Act</short-title>).</continuation-text></clause> 
<clause id="HFED1065701FE431BA0B3CCA57A642332"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Separate violations</header><text>Each individual violation with respect to each participant or beneficiary shall be treated as a separate violation.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F680EEACE194B40A591EE8A027F4201" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalty Amounts</header> <clause id="HCBD17F92454940F2B46534441291D7B2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Global violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the penalty imposed under this paragraph for a global violation shall be no greater than the product of—</text> 
<subclause id="H60D72869B42E4B048381972E7ABE8C94"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each plan year in which such a violation occurs, $1,000, multiplied by</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA664BDF36FCC433EA1D2B3DB08F2A030"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of participants and beneficiaries in the plan at the start of each such plan year.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H6AC624E525A5428A8EF0AB0A3AC76E08"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Enhanced penalty for certain global violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A penalty for a global violation may be trebled if such violation is not corrected within 90 days after the Secretary gives written notice of the Secretary’s intent to assess such penalty to the plan administrator and each person or entity that the Secretary intends to hold liable for the penalty.</text></clause> <clause id="HC79F5D2F84F6437097433A6B8AA96A58"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Individual violation</header><text>The amount of the penalty imposed under this paragraph for an individual violation shall be no greater than $1,000 for each day beginning on the date on which—</text> 
<subclause id="H243D6F34D45C4E739E64BAFAA3B25100"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a participant or beneficiary (or such participant or beneficiary’s authorized representative) gives written notice of the violation to the administrator and the Secretary of Labor; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA558D8A0F5E4441A977145C18C8302C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary discovers an individual violation during the course of an investigation pursuant to section 504, the Secretary provides written notice to the administrator of such violation.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">and ending on the date on which the violation is corrected.</continuation-text></clause> 
<clause id="H42704E690C2E44A1BE35903EA9CF4BA9"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Enhanced penalty for certain individual violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The civil penalty described in clause (iii) may be trebled with respect to each separate and distinct violation of subparagraph (A)(iii) that is not corrected within the following periods beginning on the date on which the plan administrator receives notice described in subclauses (I) or (II) of clause (iii):</text> <subclause id="H40F8ABA4F31A482AB1DC73277882230E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">90-day period with respect to a violation pertaining to a plan that is not a group health plan.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDC0819DF68E94BD3AA6CFAF0C2EB32AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">30-day period with respect to a violation pertaining to a group health plan.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H20AE60FB87314C6C9C1C4FE69929D962"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">3-day period with respect to a violation of a claim involving urgent care as defined in section 2560.503–1(m)(1) of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</short-title>).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1378F541DE4E4A0EA083BDC73D0FCEDC" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Pattern or practice of individual violations</header><text>In addition to the penalties under clauses (iii) and (iv), in the case that the Secretary determines that a person or entity has engaged in a pattern or practice of individual violations, the Secretary—</text> <subclause id="HE558DB994F6B4C97ADAA49D71955FE61" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall provide notice to the plan of the intent to assess a penalty with respect to each individual violation that occurred within the 3-year period ending on the date that such notice was provided, unless each such individual violation has been corrected;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9D9ADDD11F884B08870C5C22D9A5279D" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to each individual violation, shall assess a penalty not less than $100 and not greater than $1,000 for each day each such violation during such period was not corrected following receipt of the notice by the Secretary; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1B67C17EF41843C8A60CD68DFA79B2A7" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>may waive some or all of the penalties if the plan corrects the violations within 120 days of receipt of the notice required under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8FC239EFAC1245C6AB2A5C914D09CD8B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Joint and several liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person or entity that materially causes (including through failure to perform required actions) a violation described in subparagraph (A) shall be jointly and severally liable for the payment of the appropriate penalty described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H670E33E0A98148E693C2D0E1E1D54D63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional penalty</header><text>Section 502(g) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HECA97CD06AD645FFBD24096EBC2619ED" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H7CC7958ED989421686F8C1EC5C4EAFC0"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HEE3D3F005D71410687823F7997316428" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In any action brought under subsection (a)(5) with respect to a violation of section 503 (including a violation of section 2560.503–1 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</short-title>) or a violation of section 2590.715–2719 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer Appeal Rights Enforcement Act</short-title>), a court may impose against any defendant (other than a plan), as additional relief, the penalties described under subsection (c)(14).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5AB7D38C83A4E39A538C9663DADB2B9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A court may not impose such penalties if the Secretary has previously assessed a penalty under subsection (c)(14) against such defendant for the same violation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H866784D5E3A74E4390F7E0C3A0EB8A87" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary may not assess any penalty under subsection (c)(14) against a person or entity if, in an action brought under subsection (a)(5), a court has imposed a penalty against such person or entity for the same violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDF0FF7BE0E874731824400D2D714DC91"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply beginning on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H37B442E9B2D4495C948FB6747AAEEAF9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Direct Enforcement Authority</header> 
<subsection id="H73D73026A00E4E57A4A3E33392830A19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 502(b)(3) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(b)(3)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H369020DBBC6C4464911BEE4A3F5165FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply beginning on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

