<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H600269D1535249BE8A925A67D3EC1059" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6634 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a refundable childhood education tax credit with monthly advance payments.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6634</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a refundable childhood education tax credit with monthly advance payments.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB52CC4B5771A4F5F8384F4FD12F21C26" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC6494B90B64D47D095A410DE0EF5306D" commented="no" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of refundable childhood education tax credit with monthly advance payments</header> 
<subsection id="H13DD249758F14466A5214562FBEE0291" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 24 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFFCAA6A99B3E45D4988A0D434F153F20" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HDD40B32362B849169AE952557E490A92" commented="no"><enum>24A.</enum><header>Monthly childhood education tax credit</header> <subsection id="HEEE885FB55DB45158FF85A3E5E25177E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year the sum of the monthly childhood education allowances determined with respect to the taxpayer under subsection (b) for each calendar month during such taxable year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H19DC92E1850D450081AAD6D12BBFBD9B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monthly childhood education allowance</header> 
<paragraph id="HF4FA493E17564BBC9FAA7C1293CCD2E5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>monthly childhood education allowance</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any calendar month, an amount equal to $667 for each specified child of such taxpayer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D7002D4F23E4524B53D9B2E1A671432" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation based on household income</header> <subparagraph id="H23832D61307D4DB083DFEA6D3307D49C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The dollar amount under paragraph (1) with respect to any taxpayer for any calendar month shall be reduced (but not below zero) by an amount which bears the same ratio to such dollar amount (determined without regard to this paragraph) as—</text> 
<clause id="H2724A5ED55064F15BCC75A0B205BCA4A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text> <subclause id="H22EAFA8BDAEA43258DB07C95474286B3" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s household income for the taxable year which includes such month, over</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA2DB60BEED344E469D2451DD6D46CE5D" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an amount equal to 300 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved for such taxable year, bears to</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H147B560B966043C4BB47DF4FCC287540" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to 100 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved for such taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE194725A92954FFC80D18911F2B59DF8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions related to limitation based on household income</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H35009720A47643119D9591099705EAD9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Household income</header><text>The term <term>household income</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, an amount equal to the sum of—</text> 
<subclause id="HEA9E44F18F194B0281BE7B650810ADA6" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the modified adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for such taxable year, plus</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAA05E898DA724A5196B334887B8285B4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the aggregate modified adjusted gross incomes of all other individuals for such taxable year who—</text> 
<item id="HA463010261FD4821A3B11E35A89C935A" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>were taken into account in determining the taxpayer’s family size under clause (iii) for such taxable year, and</text></item> <item id="H0E1DFED955314614BFC142F0CD20A0C5" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>were required to file a return of tax imposed by section 1 for such taxable year.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H45C8F77526AF461BAAD17CEED59783A6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text>The term <term>modified adjusted gross income</term> means adjusted gross income increased by any amount excluded from gross income under section 911, 931, or 933.</text></clause> <clause id="HA533E897919D408A95EE2E4E8C17671C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Family size</header><text>The family size involved with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall be equal to the number of individuals for whom the taxpayer is allowed a deduction under section 151 for such taxable year.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4FA58A0B347A41CF9A9B07927BFEF1F8" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Poverty line</header><text>The term <term>poverty line</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2110(c)(5) of the Social Security Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53D15E8E9BF040DEAA1E269A1BE466C0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any month beginning after December 31, 2025, the $667 amount under paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBBE57AB44B8742CEA0B737DA60B96FEC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8CA0AE163B84542B152C9D192F64FDC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage (if any) by which—</text> 
<clause id="H6EDB7CB3076C42FAA32AD934DEAD2B0F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the CPI (as defined in section 1(f)(4)) for the calendar year preceding the calendar year in which such month begins, exceeds</text></clause> <clause id="H84DCE0AE32F945DC9F3CC3650A5E9CDB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the CPI (as so defined) for calendar year 2024.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44102AEEB5F94A95AE7CB96C2C572FEA" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specified child</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H722F3F8B554843FE86B3DB93ED388F59" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>specified child</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any calendar month, an individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H50D076E9569A4312909BF310EF4B9638" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who has the same principal place of abode as the taxpayer for more than one-half of such month,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B56F545D9FB40C492A676F712DFA55D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who, as of the beginning of such month, will have attained age 2 and will not have attained age 5,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F61F15910A54223A681FD0C0D4A8ED0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who receives care from the taxpayer during such month that is not compensated,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA85A835C292842E580DBCC686D5040E5" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>who is enrolled in an early childhood education program during such month, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF0D6F2C4E3D45C78D79C1D14DA156B9" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>who either—</text> <clause id="H5A1E94C677F04B7A82F0CAC003DE28F3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a citizen, national, or resident of the United States, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8B66CCB15F954C4C9F737E2B969E2BBA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the taxpayer is a citizen or national of the United States, is a legally adopted individual of such taxpayer or is lawfully placed with such taxpayer for legal adoption by such taxpayer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DA29366DE764E9087E67D0E09B2F611" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, except that such term includes any private prekindergarten program licensed or regulated by a State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53BF043472874904AA17027A7FB1FFFD" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Care from the taxpayer</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC7156DD2188D4B4082AAC1CB044EE349" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, whether any individual receives care from the taxpayer (within the meaning of paragraph (1)(C)) shall be determined on the basis of facts and circumstances with respect to the following factors:</text> <clause id="H1BBC45899BAB4297BA15841343F5FE32" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The supervision provided by the taxpayer regarding the daily activities and needs of the individual.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB49AEA064BD34A69B018FC5D22DDE721" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The maintenance by the taxpayer of a secure environment at which the individual resides.</text></clause> <clause id="H5E09A760FF574D8B80D6F2389A2C3001" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The provision or arrangement by the taxpayer of, and transportation by the taxpayer to, medical care at regular intervals and as required for the individual.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6CD652DA90C54691B44D50F7C730D192" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The involvement by the taxpayer in, and financial and other support by the taxpayer for, educational or similar activities of the individual.</text></clause> <clause id="H1155FF9C45F149AA934A850EB0E777B0" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other factor that the Secretary determines to be appropriate to determine whether the individual receives care from the taxpayer.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98B2FE2C06FD41DFB96A9C146D5319A5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination of whether care is compensated</header><text>For purposes of determining if care is compensated within the meaning of paragraph (1)(C), compensation from the Federal Government, a State or local government, a Tribal government, or any possession of the United States shall not be taken into account.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED7496339C51472BBF60D9CB8EEAEE22" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application of tie-breaker rules</header> <subparagraph id="HEE833CFBCCCB4A6C967C986AAD5E08DE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (D), if any individual would (but for this paragraph) be a specified child of 2 or more taxpayers for any month, such individual shall be treated as the specified child only of the taxpayer who is—</text> 
<clause id="H7C7DDA2D4C5E4E7391F7C041573830FE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the parent of the individual (or, if such individual would (but for this paragraph) be a specified child of 2 or more parents of the individual for such month, the parent of the individual determined under subparagraph (B)),</text></clause> <clause id="H9DBDB7186AFD4872A97F2DE23D5432CA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the individual is not a specified child of any parent of the individual (determined without regard to this paragraph), the specified relative of the individual with the highest adjusted gross income for the taxable year which includes such month, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2BDE54E58AA44CD8B2A313CD2D7EF165" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the individual is neither a specified child of any parent of the individual nor a specified child of any specified relative of the individual (in both cases determined without regard to this paragraph), the taxpayer with the highest adjusted gross income for the taxable year which includes such month.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF86452455D345DAA0A93DD6649DDA3B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tie-breaker among parents</header><text>If any individual would (but for this paragraph) be the specified child of 2 or more parents of the individual for any month, such child shall be treated only as the specified child of—</text> 
<clause id="HE3194A857EDF47EB9851E6328AB796A8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the parent with whom the child resided for the longest period of time during such month, or</text></clause> <clause id="H543B344D59174546855B82142E6852F6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the child resides with both parents for the same amount of time during such month, the parent with the highest adjusted gross income for the taxable year which includes such month.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC554213BBC44B7FA0B2A9733456BB84" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Specified relative</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>specified relative</term> means an individual who is—</text> <clause id="HAE2D9AECBD6D47679C8E126FB03BFF37" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an ancestor of a parent of the specified child,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6F3E60895C04BAC9AEC323BCC748DAA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a brother or sister of a parent of the specified child, or</text></clause> <clause id="H9268512460914230B5C0C2990CD08374" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a brother, sister, stepbrother, or stepsister of the specified child.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9188089D7644F2B8358189EB9B98A97" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Certain parents or specified relatives not taken into account</header><text>This paragraph shall be applied without regard to any parent or specified relative of an individual for any month if—</text> <clause id="HB9585F7EF51F4F5BA47C7969C014D765" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such parent or specified relative elects to have such individual not be treated as a specified child of such parent or specified relative for such month,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDD65F85A38D7450DB717031D0B200AD8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a parent of such individual, the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer (with respect to whom such individual would be treated as a specified child after application of this subparagraph) for the taxable year which includes such month is higher than the highest adjusted gross income of any parent of the individual for any taxable year which includes such month (determined without regard to any parent with respect to whom such individual is not a specified child, determined without regard to subparagraphs (A) and (B) and after application of this subparagraph), and</text></clause> <clause id="H018AC05EC4CA491DAB2F014B28B43924" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a specified relative of such individual, the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer (with respect to whom such individual would be treated as a specified child after application of this subparagraph) for the taxable year which includes such month is higher than the highest adjusted gross income of any parent and any specified relative of the individual for any taxable year which includes such month (determined without regard to any parent and any specified relative with respect to whom such individual is not a specified child, determined without regard to subparagraphs (A) and (B) and after application of this subparagraph).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H070E594592644E49B19DE03CA8EDD99A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Treatment of joint returns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, with respect to any month, the adjusted gross income of each person who files a joint return for the taxable year which includes such month is the total adjusted gross income shown on the joint return for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32AC3954919D4BCAA451BAD98470F1B3" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Parent</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the term <term>parent</term> shall have the same meaning as when used in section 152(c)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1606084F59DC4068BEF8CD2BA2807AD3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of temporary absences</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in regulations or other guidance issued by the Secretary, for purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H0520B2B46893423A9903BF8BEAC2DFF2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any individual’s temporary absence from such individual’s principal place of abode, each day composing the temporary absence shall—</text> 
<clause id="H8A57E3BB3B6B449AA43AA43DC2C7EDCD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be treated as a day at such individual’s principal place of abode,</text></clause> <clause id="HD04C8AB8049A44A18C1709660E9BA995" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be treated as satisfying the care requirement described in paragraph (1)(C) for each day described in clause (i), and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H45681457735D43748C36B64307706C9C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not be treated as a day at any other location.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H696DFA0FA96B4EE2A5F1EF7CFBD7768B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Temporary absence</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), an absence shall be treated as temporary if—</text> 
<clause id="HBF9B9FB1D96440EEA5CD121976A111A1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the individual would have resided at the place of abode but for the absence, and</text></clause> <clause id="H5FDEDE87A40548F7952CB832C56F0FBF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under the facts and circumstances, it is reasonable to assume that the individual will return to reside at the place of abode.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3703E76201A4049806C598E3F4334C6" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rule for divorced parents, etc</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 152(e) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A59889A5B8345D6B4FFFD6E1F2063C1" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Eligibility determined on basis of presumptive eligibility</header> <subparagraph id="H0771D44F88C64AFE8ED1F16B81810979" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a period of presumptive eligibility is established under section 7527B(c) with respect to any taxpayer and child—</text> 
<clause id="H7B90969D76994EAEB0A7D4DC64FBC1C9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such child shall be treated as the specified child of such taxpayer for any month in such period of presumptive eligibility, and</text></clause> <clause id="HF32EB6A013B64A76A60A423D70AB1850" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such child shall not be treated as the specified child of any other taxpayer with respect to whom a period of presumptive eligibility has not been established for any such month.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC28DE33521FE4353AF9E9822A69041FA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ability of credit claimants to establish presumptive eligibility</header><text>Nothing in section 7527B(c) shall be interpreted to preclude a taxpayer from establishing a period of presumptive eligibility (including any period described in subparagraph (D) with respect to which payment could be made) with respect to any specified child for purposes of this section solely because such taxpayer affirmatively elects not to receive monthly advance childhood education payments under section 7527B.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB02AF6B3CD864124BFFC3BAE9AFAB97A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception for income-based tie-breaker rules</header><text>If a period of presumptive eligibility is established under section 7527B(c) for any individual with respect to any taxpayer and such individual is not the specified child of such taxpayer for any month in such period by reason of such taxpayer failing to be described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of paragraph (4)(A) for the taxable year which includes such month, subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to such month.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D4A253828A34B21BD86592CDC2BA9E5" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of certain retroactive payments</header><text>If any payment is made under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 7527B(f)(3) or paragraph (1) or (2) of section 7527B(g), with respect to any taxpayer and child for any period, such period shall be treated as a period of presumptive eligibility established under section 7527B(c) with respect to such taxpayer and child for purposes of applying subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A7A5341B511492198632F77ECAA9F11" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Fraud and intentional disregard of rules or regulations</header><text>If the Secretary determines that the taxpayer committed fraud or intentionally disregarded rules or regulations in establishing or maintaining any period of presumptive eligibility, the months with respect to which such fraud or intentional disregard relates shall not be treated as a period of presumptive eligibility for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17E6B7B9D06C445DB0F7AB4AF996B38C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credit refundable</header><text>If the taxpayer (in the case of a joint return, either spouse) has a principal place of abode (determined as provided in section 32) in the United States or Puerto Rico for more than one-half of any calendar month during the taxable year, so much of the credit otherwise allowed under subsection (a) as is attributable to monthly childhood education allowances with respect to any such calendar month shall be allowed under subpart C (and not allowed under this subpart).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9384BA7E627B4BC59497B0C10380F16D" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Identification requirements</header> <paragraph id="H0DA13DF0EFE6467F952187252A5AA007" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Specified child identification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section to a taxpayer with respect to any specified child unless the taxpayer includes the name and taxpayer identification number of such specified child on the return of tax for the taxable year and such taxpayer identification number was issued on or before the due date for filing such return.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D57DAF1E34A4F82A288971449CFAFB1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Taxpayer identification requirement</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section if the taxpayer identification number of the taxpayer was issued after the due date for filing the return for the taxable year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD51A3F53B5D645078FB8BA446E6A477E" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Restrictions on taxpayers who improperly claimed credit or improperly received monthly advance childhood education payments</header> <paragraph id="H6B6C9F00C7C842A4840936FE58E0780D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Taxpayers making prior fraudulent or reckless claims</header> <subparagraph id="H27721A71C85C43C0BCBD50E4D7DD6648" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section for any taxable year (and no payment shall be made under section 7527B for any month) in the disallowance period.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EA5FBFE5EB646F9B5648685FAE6D438" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disallowance period</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the disallowance period is—</text> <clause id="H1E191C5595394BB687C43F62E9657141" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the period of 120 calendar months after the most recent calendar month for which there was a final determination that the taxpayer’s claim of credit under this section (or payment received under section 7527B) was due to fraud, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4B41E4953C3F41199A8D934550D631BC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the period of 24 calendar months after the most recent calendar month for which there was a final determination that the taxpayer’s claim of credit under this section (or payment received under section 7527B) was due to reckless or intentional disregard of rules and regulations (but not due to fraud).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC056BA58C7C34658BEFC8C5617C6E6C2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Taxpayers making improper prior claims</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer who is denied credit under this section for any taxable year as a result of the deficiency procedures under subchapter B of chapter 63, no credit shall be allowed under this section for any subsequent taxable year (and no payment shall be made under section 7527B for any subsequent month) unless the taxpayer provides such information as the Secretary may require to demonstrate eligibility for such credit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H937D3A0F12EF4D2BB8426F7BD103E8C0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with possessions of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a taxpayer’s claim of credit under this section (or payment received under section 7527B) includes a claim of credit under this section of the income tax law of any jurisdiction other than the United States (or similar payment received under section 7527B of such income tax law), and a claim made or a payment received from American Samoa pursuant to a plan described in subsection (h)(3)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H82D7CA26059646CF8318C803CCAD433A" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reconciliation of credit and monthly advance childhood education payments</header> <paragraph id="H3E43CB6EE7E14714BB6E22FD22FEAD96" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount otherwise determined under subsection (a) with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate amount of payments made under section 7527B to such taxpayer for one or more calendar months in such taxable year. Any failure to so reduce the credit shall be treated as arising out of a mathematical or clerical error and assessed according to section 6213(b)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A8FC5F4FCE5419EA332FF7BF13AB189" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Increase in tax equal to excess advance payments in certain circumstances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the aggregate amount of payments made to the taxpayer under section 7527B for one or more calendar months in such taxable year exceeds the amount allowed as a credit under subpart C by reason of this section with respect to such taxpayer for such taxable year (without regard to paragraph (1) of this subsection), the tax imposed by this chapter for such taxable year shall be increased by so much of such excess as is attributable to one or more of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB7963EAEDA454CF3A52D0C07104BBFB0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Fraud, or reckless or intentional disregard of rules and regulations, by the taxpayer.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E30CF6A7530444F83048F8CE6D7B77B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Changes in the taxpayer’s household income that affect the application of the limitation imposed by subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D3CDD58909A400BB5B45B00CF04B856" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Payments under section 7527B which were made for months which were not part of a period of presumptive eligibility.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAA18CF51903F4BAA8EAD030B7063A2CD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A failure to be the taxpayer described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subsection (c)(4)(A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAD7F9087CED428ABC6DD17612A57C05" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A failure to satisfy the requirements of subsection (d).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2A5E973ED3644A8B56910E6A252B2EC" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A failure to satisfy the requirements of paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (e), except that a failure to satisfy the requirements of subsection (e)(1) shall not be taken into account under this paragraph if the taxpayer demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that it is reasonable to expect that the specified child will be issued a taxpayer identification number and that the delay in such issuance was due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76977628456E453095D6B8E26DC2E0CE" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other circumstances as the Secretary identifies for purposes of this paragraph to facilitate the administration and enforcement by the Secretary of section 7527B, to minimize the amount of advance payments made under section 7527B to ineligible individuals, and to prevent abuse.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59F38EDC3D7C4D8AB2B9E0BB89463187" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payments subject to treatment as excess advance payments after notice under section 7527B(j)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H183C067F6F7C464F966170CB267B970B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Joint returns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of an advance payment made under section 7527B with respect to a joint return, half of such payment shall be treated as having been made to each individual filing such return.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D073E311E45464693F593331940CA9A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination with possessions of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, payments made under section 7527B include payments made by any jurisdiction other than the United States under section 7527B of the income tax law of such jurisdiction, and advance payments made by American Samoa pursuant to a plan described in subsection (h)(3)(B). Any increase in tax imposed on a taxpayer by reason of paragraph (2) of the income tax law of a jurisdiction other than the United States shall be considered to reduce the aggregate amount of payments made to such taxpayer by such jurisdiction. In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with each possession of the United States to prevent any application of this paragraph that is inconsistent with the purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A6AEA19A71348198BD2874FFD64139B" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application of credit in possessions</header> <paragraph id="HED57F54ECCE54C818131497F85660DC2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mirror code possessions</header> <subparagraph id="H879C59D1F6004C5094911EA163A5A725" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall pay to each possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system amounts equal to the loss (if any) to that possession by reason of the application of this section (determined without regard to this subsection) with respect to taxable years beginning in calendar years after 2025. Such amounts shall be determined by the Secretary based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H68D7157E4EFD48CB928E750433C7A0DB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against United States income taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section for any taxable year to any individual to whom a credit is allowable against taxes imposed by a possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system by reason of the application of this section in such possession for such taxable year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91AD9A4F790B43418E59E0719FAF3D97" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>mirror code tax system</term> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CAA7E2AFD7E41A59E830728E19820CE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cross references related to application of credit to residents of Puerto Rico</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0668B49A1D05450DB141DFDF2FD2D26A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For application of refundable credit to residents of Puerto Rico, see subsection (d).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5E1B056708145498C7B91F79D833BC6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For application of advance payment to residents of Puerto Rico, see section 7527B(b)(5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5D1991A5F4C418C82E3AE180E958CB7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>American Samoa</header> 
<subparagraph id="H43C5827EC1D64976A1535AFFC0FBE1AF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall pay to American Samoa amounts estimated by the Secretary as being equal to the aggregate benefits that would have been provided to residents of American Samoa by reason of the application of this section for taxable years beginning in calendar years after 2025 if the provisions of this section had been in effect in American Samoa (applied as if American Samoa were the United States and without regard to the application of this section to residents of Puerto Rico under subsection (d)).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78B485639EE64B6EA4D63643D68E2315" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Distribution requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply unless American Samoa has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary, under which American Samoa will promptly distribute such payments to its residents.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48C23D05A5104BB4AAB8435F6A481B15" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against United States income taxes</header> 
<clause id="H49718CCBEB4F4537A8400E509DC8C8FA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxable year with respect to which a plan is approved under subparagraph (B), this section (other than this subsection) shall not apply to any individual eligible for a distribution under such plan.</text></clause> <clause id="H87FF1327ECF6448DBBCC1A10D9A8D741" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application of section in event of absence of approved plan</header><text>In the case of a taxable year with respect to which a plan is not approved under subparagraph (B), subsection (d) shall be applied by substituting <quote>, Puerto Rico, or American Samoa</quote> for <quote>or Puerto Rico</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35667FD661ED4138962DCF8AF488EC72" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1324 of title 31, United States Code, the payments under this subsection shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from a credit provision referred to in subsection (b)(2) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H129269FE74704026B9024DB517EC6D1E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance—</text> 
<paragraph id="H877A7FD8B4864E51B36A2D4824693E4B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for determining whether an individual receives care from a taxpayer for purposes of subsection (c)(1)(C), and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9167A4DE84254792AB3FF917A68B0A64" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to coordinate or modify the application of this section and section 7527B in the case of any taxpayer—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9CF99763ECDE47A1A67229D2CBFD9B14" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whose taxable year is other than a calendar year,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0656D77E9D842C293149642B3F061AC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose filing status for a taxable year is different from the status used for determining one or more monthly payments under section 7527B during such taxable year, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5DDD8B70D3E54A469B3B8F7D226275DA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whose principal place of abode for any month is different from the principal place of abode used for determining the monthly payment under section 7527B for such month.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC11B83921646462C9B6F2237228A88E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advance payment of monthly childhood education tax credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 77 of such Code is amended by inserting after section 7527A the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H044FFA7E67A84268A2E31313717DAA5B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H5F306357053841C096D1A60F22CD75EA" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7527B.</enum><header>Advance payment of monthly childhood education tax credit</header> 
<subsection id="H4E1C669EE32543019BC188F92D9A4824"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall pay to each taxpayer, during each calendar month which is during a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to the taxpayer and any child, an amount equal to the monthly advance childhood education payment determined with respect to such taxpayer for such month.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H107CD7C8E79D4CBFB79CB1597034A417"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monthly advance childhood education payment</header><text>The term <term>monthly advance childhood education payment</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any calendar month, the amount (if any) which is estimated by the Secretary as being equal to the monthly childhood education allowance which would be determined under section 24A(b) with respect to such taxpayer for such calendar month if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7A38181EB40E4ADDB14489466DE226D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the only specified children of such taxpayer for such calendar month are the specified children of such taxpayer for the reference month (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)),</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFD6E39184134B57A7C5165B5C2583ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ages of such children (and the status of such children as specified children) are determined for such calendar month by taking into account the passage of time since such reference month,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H601B9D7A546245F2A0192CC6F8798228"><enum>(3)</enum><text>each child is only taken into account as a specified child for such calendar month if such calendar month is during a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to the taxpayer and such child,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9776D15EC5694D80A2C4BB8375B1E6DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the limitations of section 24A(b)(2) were applied with respect to the reference taxable year rather than with respect to the applicable taxable year, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3931F87E9D7E44A7BB8A07EBC6FB3BC1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no monthly childhood education allowance was determined with respect to such taxpayer for such calendar month unless the taxpayer (in the case of a joint return, either spouse) has a principal place of abode (determined as provided in section 32) in the United States or Puerto Rico for more than one-half of the reference month.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF889BBE658C541589F61DCDAC0F8AD21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period of presumptive eligibility</header> <paragraph id="HA4861466497F4B698C9414B56F1A7A57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>period of presumptive eligibility</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer and any child, the period—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H393A8A17293C44F08046C0188C1617C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning with the calendar month following the calendar month during which the taxpayer provides the Secretary with sufficient information for the Secretary to—</text> <clause id="HC37A385D2AB2456A893431401F642FE4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine that such child was a specified child of the taxpayer for the reference month (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)), and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6E847DF782F343C589AB9C6C2D509943"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>estimate the monthly advance childhood education payment for such calendar month, and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8866CADDBAF54552BCADE82AC1BBA265"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ending with the earliest of—</text> 
<clause id="H9FC9846DE25E4C7891EAA7DC85AE6B98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the month beginning immediately after the month on which the Secretary sends the taxpayer a written notice that the taxpayer’s period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such child is being terminated by reason of information known to the Secretary (including a failure to provide annual information under paragraph (2)) which casts doubt on such taxpayer’s status as being allowed the monthly childhood education allowance under section 24A for such child (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)) with respect to one or more months following the reference month,</text></clause> <clause id="H823A02F7C5314CE08BCB2B2E7CD5F45C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any month with respect to which the taxpayer notifies the Secretary that such taxpayer is not allowed a monthly childhood education allowance for such month under section 24A(b) (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)), and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBBF2A055B4FD4FDBA9E7F29E0E5653AC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the month beginning immediately before the first month of a new period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such taxpayer and such child which is established on the basis of a reference month more recent than the reference month with respect to which such prior period was established (including on the basis of an annual renewal described in paragraph (2)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03B58F6237064FA3BCB44C0DFFE742F1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual renewal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall terminate a taxpayer’s period of presumptive eligibility with respect to any child under paragraph (1)(B)(i) unless such taxpayer provides information sufficient to establish a new period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such child (as described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii)) on an annual basis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58F4167D1B6E4D4A92F2DBAAC3ACBD3B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Presumptive eligibility based on certain government programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue regulations or other guidance to establish procedures under which—</text> <subparagraph id="HC0F210B1628542D1ADAF9E38345028F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>based on information provided to the Secretary by one or more government entities, a parent or specified relative of a child is treated as automatically establishing a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such child, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C5BE84542084C14AA194A3AB0C463A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the month for which such period begins, the month by which the first annual renewal described in paragraph (2) must be completed, and any additional circumstances under which such period will terminate, are determined.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AC7CAE0D6FE4819819387EC12A82184" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Taxpayer responsibility to notify Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that any taxpayer is not allowed a monthly childhood education allowance under section 24A(b) (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)) for any month in a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such taxpayer, such taxpayer shall notify the Secretary under paragraph (1)(B)(ii) at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68DE286A0F8841B78C56C4057DB6A4A5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text>With respect to periods of presumptive eligibility beginning during the first 6 months to which this section applies, the Secretary shall issue regulations or other guidance to establish procedures pursuant to which—</text> <subparagraph id="H9707ED2149504C6795AFAFA81C73E58A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>based on information known to the Secretary, including returns of tax for either of the last 2 taxable years ending before such month, a parent or specified relative of a child is treated as automatically establishing a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such child, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EE537C67F5B45188150FE105561375C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the month for which such period begins, the month by which the first annual renewal described in paragraph (2) must be completed, and any additional circumstances under which such period will terminate, are determined.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H81EB7061D2034E44885232C2D97FCA23"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determination of reference month and reference taxable year</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCC55E2E62C54474983B3C5AC1A5D3801"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reference month</header><text>The term <term>reference month</term> means, with respect to any calendar month in a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to a taxpayer, the most recent of—</text> <subparagraph id="H13DE152C1BCA41EAB8247C83D8E03D69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a taxpayer who filed a return of tax for the last taxable year ending before such calendar month, the last month of such taxable year,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED5AA500ABEA449F9666FB365CED4FC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a taxpayer who filed a return of tax for the taxable year preceding the taxable year described in subparagraph (A), the last month of such preceding taxable year, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7E011BB19D2430AABCA590B0C03E8E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a taxpayer who otherwise provides the information referred to in subsection (c)(1)(A), the month with respect to which such information is provided.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD78F90816900475B80E781CAA275F261"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reference taxable year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reference taxable year</term> means, with respect to any calendar month in a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to a taxpayer—</text> <subparagraph id="HE0B4B4D7B1304F3A8002942AA7BAD93E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the reference month with respect to such calendar month is determined under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1), the taxable year referred to in such subparagraph, respectively, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03CFD15096394ADB8E866AED395178D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the reference month with respect to such calendar month is determined under paragraph (1)(C), the last taxable year ending before such reference month.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H29F29D4789B342E5BDAF286A0B7CBD45"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Methods of providing information To establish a period of presumptive eligibility</header> <paragraph id="HB3B5681BDB674756A13F902066AB529B"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Secretary shall ensure the information described in subsection (c)(1)(A) may be provided on the return of tax for the taxable year ending before the calendar year which includes the month for which such period would begin, through the on-line portal described in paragraph (2), or in such other manner as the Secretary may provide.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H39D4C71721994CAE8AC93A0DF29C6A50">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>On-line information portal</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall establish an on-line portal (available in multiple languages) which allows taxpayers to—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H84CDFE76C6454218AC67071F1B1D8E17">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>subject to such restrictions as the Secretary may provide, elect to begin or cease receiving payments under this section, and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H65F2B488464C4E7C80C6622D81FD486F">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>provide the information described in subsection (c)(1)(A).</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H58100613A05B4A268302C7F7B0334C9C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Resolution of competing claims of presumptive eligibility with respect to same child</header> <paragraph id="H2CDF1DEB6A7044F3B5BCB44734623F80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If there is a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to any taxpayer and child (hereafter referred to as the <quote>original claim</quote>), a period of presumptive eligibility would (without regard to this subsection) be established with respect to another taxpayer and such child (hereafter referred to as the <quote>challenge claim</quote>), and the period of such challenge claim would overlap with the period of such original claim—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4C33EB95676A43EEB4597C930A659DCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such challenge claim shall not be taken into account under this section unless the reference month with respect to which the challenge claim would be established is at least as recent as the reference month with respect to which the original claim is established,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7485CCAA9DD470ABA7C4C69F5465B24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such challenge claim shall not begin before the original claim is terminated, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDAC2AAF7F46486B905F5C1D7EE5D038"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary shall establish procedures under which the Secretary expeditiously adjudicates such claims on the basis of the most recent feasible reference month.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78F202806B3940018DD4A263E576C706"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provisions related to adjudication</header> <subparagraph id="H8C02F57FAD7E4EA3988E3780B52B85B2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Challenge claim must relate to at least 3 months prospectively</header><text>The procedures established under paragraph (1)(C) shall require that the taxpayer establishing the challenge claim express a reasonable expectation and intent that such taxpayer would be allowed a monthly childhood education allowance under section 24A(b) (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)) for at least the first 2 months following the reference month referred to in paragraph (1)(C).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B2E924EED1F43D9ADD810DB467C885E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expedited process; appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The procedures established under paragraph (1)(C) shall include—</text> <clause id="H6B8827BF73ED4A69AC01CCACB81DEB23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an expedited process for taxpayers who meet such requirements as the Secretary may establish for such expedited process, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H907F358C141E433CAD3275904A428869"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>procedures for adjudicating an appeal of an adverse decision.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H552346FCEF97432D96852A9931EDD706"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information receipt and coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of obtaining information relevant to any adjudication under this paragraph, the Secretary may enter into agreements to receive information from, and otherwise coordinate with—</text> 
<clause id="H35F88F079B92416F9E00BD1E6F8907E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal agencies (including the Social Security Administration),</text></clause> <clause id="H4A990BBC09A548A98AFE772452412601"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any State, local government, Tribal government, or possession of the United States, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0B3E65EC97FA4E8697EAD3129E91D5F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other individual or entity that the Secretary determines to be appropriate for such purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE71F9A03C88946E5A9D63128F1019742"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Adjudication not treated as assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any adjudication under this paragraph shall not be treated as an assessment described in section 6201.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDE9DEB0071A4DA793A7B75F8E9B4DA7"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Adjudication not treated as inspection of taxpayer’s books of account</header><text>The inspection of a taxpayer’s books of account in connection with any adjudication under this paragraph shall not be treated as an examination or inspection of a taxpayer’s books of account for purposes of section 7605(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38C2BF6DB56E4DCA9EEC94B85B665C73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retroactive payments related to adjudication</header> <subparagraph id="H636A935068EC4F478D8EF3DAEEDFAA47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Delay in establishment of challenge claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the challenge claim is established pursuant to the procedures established under paragraph (1)(C), the Secretary shall make a one-time payment to the taxpayer with respect to such claim equal to the aggregate amount of increases in the monthly advance childhood education payments which would have been made to such taxpayer if such challenge claim had been allowed to take effect without regard to this subsection. Any payment under this subparagraph shall be in addition to any payment made under subsection (g).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35FE64FC26804781A6A539EC031EF72A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination and reinstatement of original claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, pursuant to the procedures established under paragraph (1)(C), the original claim is terminated under subsection (c)(1)(B)(i) and a new period of presumptive eligibility is subsequently established pursuant to such procedures with respect to the same taxpayer and child as for such original claim, the Secretary shall make a one-time payment to the taxpayer with respect to such claim equal to the aggregate amount of increases in the monthly advance childhood education payments which would have been made to such taxpayer if such original claim had never been terminated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H238BD3C276774C229A488AE789979F79"><enum>(g)</enum><header> Rules related to grace periods and hardships</header> <paragraph id="H20AE54B14B5646D28D55A0D833C594C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Automatic grace period</header> <subparagraph id="H12CD2A5505894ADD9FF1CBC74B2B9516"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a taxpayer establishes a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to any child, elects the application of this paragraph, and demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that such taxpayer would be allowed a monthly childhood education allowance under section 24A(b) (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)) for one or more of the 3 months immediately preceding the first month of such period, the Secretary shall make a one-time payment to the taxpayer equal to the aggregate amount of increases in the monthly advance childhood education payments which would have been made to such taxpayer if such months were part of such period. The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent that the Secretary determines that the failure to establish the period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such child for any such month was due to fraud or reckless or intentional disregard of rules and regulations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H704D080DDFB444DDA8E83693136CECF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to any taxpayer more than once during any 36-month period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BAAA61B1BB84F63A1244683B2B6A590"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hardship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a taxpayer establishes a period of presumptive eligibility with respect to any child, elects the application of this paragraph (and does not elect the application of paragraph (1) with respect to the establishment of such period), demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that such taxpayer would be allowed a monthly childhood education allowance under section 24A(b) (determined without regard to section 24A(c)(7)) for one or more of the 6 months immediately preceding the first month of such period, and the Secretary determines that the failure to establish the period of presumptive eligibility with respect to such child for such months was due to domestic violence, serious illness, natural disaster, or any other hardship, the Secretary shall make a one-time payment to the taxpayer equal to the aggregate amount of increases in the monthly advance childhood education payments which would have been made to such taxpayer if such months were part of such period.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC87D4591EA96422A9BD628DC95645986"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with retroactive payment for delay in establishment of challenge claim</header><text>For purposes of applying paragraph (1) or (2) with respect to any challenge claim to which subsection (f)(3)(A) applies, the period of presumptive eligibility shall be treated as including the period for which payment is made under such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H01F5A3AB9C4245F1AAB64D4EEAF9CA73"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Provisions related to form, manner, and treatment of payments</header> <paragraph id="H8CBD8D61FC4D42CD9D45B22F131D72AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of electronic funds payment requirement</header><text>The payments made by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be made by electronic funds transfer to the same extent and in the same manner as if such payments were Federal payments not made under this title.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD262377031F9447D8929CF73C1012F62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delivery of payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may certify and disburse refunds payable under this section electronically to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF98B4997EFF649BA8290C0DA6A47668D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any account to which the payee authorized, on or after January 1, 2025, the delivery of a refund of taxes under this title or of a Federal payment (as defined in section 3332 of title 31, United States Code),</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F2010648D1540AA8DCAF126971FA77F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any account belonging to a payee from which that individual, on or after January 1, 2025, made a payment of taxes under this title, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE694B18623EE4AF5BBB04E3731A8754F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any Treasury-sponsored account (as defined in section 208.2 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00FCFD9D75AA43988DF02B20936B3212"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver of certain rules</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3325 of title 31, United States Code, or any other provision of law, with respect to any payment of a refund under this section, a disbursing official in the executive branch of the United States Government may modify payment information received from an officer or employee described in section 3325(a)(1)(B) of such title for the purpose of facilitating the accurate and efficient delivery of such payment. Except in cases of fraud or reckless neglect, no liability under section 3325, 3527, 3528, or 3529 of title 31, United States Code, shall be imposed with respect to payments made under this paragraph.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85D5C5A6D6244FB09295A98F54104BC9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception from reduction or offset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any applicable payment (as defined in paragraph (5)(E)(iii)) shall not be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5FCEAD59DD744FC4B4F20030FD4AC6C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to reduction or offset pursuant to section 3716 or 3720A of title 31, United States Code,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF08D6390E4E04430AE8BF6085DA674F0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to reduction or offset pursuant to subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f) of section 6402, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7E05C4936D545B3874C60B2C3103DA4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduced or offset by other assessed Federal taxes that would otherwise be subject to levy or collection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14800A8767EA465FABAD909806E49B00" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Assignment of benefits</header> <subparagraph id="H9D4B86519A464592889313713AA3AA5D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The right of any person to any applicable payment shall not be transferable or assignable, at law or in equity, and no applicable payment shall be subject to, execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, or the operation of any bankruptcy or insolvency law.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05040A8A2937472683B00EF80E4E435A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Encoding of payments</header><text>In the case of an applicable payment described in subparagraph (E)(iii)(I) that is paid electronically by direct deposit through the Automated Clearing House (ACH) network, the Secretary (or the Secretary's delegate) shall—</text> <clause id="HA3D0D858707B4A5D9BA34D5C46DF32B5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issue the payment using a unique identifier that is reasonably sufficient to allow a financial institution to identify the payment as an applicable payment, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H982AD1C1D4F64625BFB748C53E8BF468" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>further encode the payment pursuant to the same specifications as required for a benefit payment defined in section 212.3 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEFFF6B71B06D4E16903F4F4211623D16" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Garnishment</header> <clause id="H2A0E8D196B3B4E27A8E29BB240729DCB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Encoded payments</header><text>In the case of a garnishment order that applies to an account that has received an applicable payment that is encoded as provided in subparagraph (B), a financial institution shall follow the requirements and procedures set forth in part 212 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, except—</text> 
<subclause id="H3B89195E654C491AB86E9B9544B3EFF4" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding section 212.4 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (and except as provided in subclause (II)), a financial institution shall not fail to follow the procedures of sections 212.5 and 212.6 of such title with respect to a garnishment order merely because such order has attached, or includes, a notice of right to garnish Federal benefits issued by a State child support enforcement agency, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H00621C08CA484C1F8CC6A52C8A9F8E44" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a financial institution shall not, with regard to any applicable payment, be required to provide the notice referenced in sections 212.6 and 212.7 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1DD0F2056866493786A04316F7681443" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other payments</header><text>In the case of a garnishment order (other than an order that has been served by the United States) that has been received by a financial institution and that applies to an account into which an applicable payment that has not been encoded as provided in subparagraph (B) has been deposited electronically on any date during the lookback period or into which an applicable payment that has been deposited by check on any date in the lookback period, the financial institution, upon the request of the account holder, shall treat the amount of the funds in the account at the time of the request, up to the amount of the applicable payment (in addition to any amounts otherwise protected under part 212 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations), as exempt from a garnishment order without requiring the consent of the party serving the garnishment order or the judgment creditor.</text></clause> <clause id="H6CB5A4267F6140B0B32E30CD73C0D893" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>A financial institution that acts in good faith in reliance on clause (i) or (ii) shall not be subject to liability or regulatory action under any Federal or State law, regulation, court or other order, or regulatory interpretation for actions concerning any applicable payments.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H984B1A4AB47245DE877B5DF86B8D6160" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No reclamation rights</header><text>This paragraph shall not alter the status of applicable payments as tax refunds or other nonbenefit payments for purpose of any reclamation rights of the Department of the Treasury or the Internal Revenue Service as per part 210 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEEB0FA9AC3864E95AFD79F1ECAADFA81" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> 
<clause id="H88708D852C504497B65990AA476D8F8C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Account holder</header><text>The term <term>account holder</term> means a natural person whose name appears in a financial institution’s records as the direct or beneficial owner of an account.</text></clause> <clause id="H6EE3CABF0A414B8498D7C7B5680D1277" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Account review</header><text>The term <term>account review</term> means the process of examining deposits in an account to determine if an applicable payment has been deposited into the account during the lookback period. The financial institution shall perform the account review following the procedures outlined in section 212.5 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations and in accordance with the requirements of section 212.6 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1472720AE8844D51B9654E192E2E2FCC" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicable payment</header><text>The term <term>applicable payment</term> means—</text> <subclause id="HF56C00CDAA8E453FAF9FB740F00123CA" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any payment made to an individual under this section (other than any payment made pursuant to paragraph (6)), and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3A4707C2BCF4444CAC712305D676D9EC" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any advance payment made by a possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system (as defined in section 24A(h)) pursuant to an election under paragraph (6)(B) which corresponds to a payment described in subclause (I).</text></subclause> </clause> <clause id="H638BC22A78BA46F39E07566FF4FB7D61" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Garnishment</header><text>The term <term>garnishment</term> means execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF4CFAF32BF7D404481E4E20551E2EC33" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Garnishment order</header><text>The term <term>garnishment order</term> means a writ, order, notice, summons, judgment, levy, or similar written instruction issued by a court, a State or State agency, a municipality or municipal corporation, or a State child support enforcement agency, including a lien arising by operation of law for overdue child support or an order to freeze the assets in an account, to effect a garnishment against a debtor.</text></clause> <clause id="H7522309A2C734ED59EB661B13CC71C2E" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Lookback period</header><text>The term <term>lookback period</term> means the two-month period that begins on the date preceding the date of account review and ends on the corresponding date of the month two months earlier, or on the last date of the month two months earlier if the corresponding date does not exist.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B8A0496B41E47189A42593F18EAB3A9" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Application of advance payments in the possessions of the United States</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAFF86E597B8144CE9B9799AAE579B77F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Puerto Rico</header> 
<clause id="H909BC149243440F09AE9AFEC72697C2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For application of monthly childhood education tax credit to residents of Puerto Rico, see section 24A(d).</text></clause> <clause id="H4B6EFD3FE03A4F5D8F7440E04C998472"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For application of monthly advance childhood education payments to residents of Puerto Rico, see subsection (b)(5).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B6A645DAC864876830AFB6FDD6D8D3C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mirror code possessions</header><text>In the case of any possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system (as defined in section 24A(h)(1)(C)), this section shall not be treated as part of the income tax laws of the United States for purposes of determining the income tax law of such possession unless such possession elects to have this section be so treated.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7BD638A527CC49D7A5065E350D6471C5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application of certain definitions and rules applicable to monthly childhood education tax credit</header> <paragraph id="H0FC1E5837D544C199DB5D9368A456486" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, terms used in this section which are also used in section 24A shall have the same respective meanings as when used in section 24A.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00E523563DF640DDA214632B640045F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of certain deaths</header><text>A child shall not be taken into account in determining the monthly advance childhood education payment for any calendar month if the death of such child before the end of such month is known to the Secretary as of the date on which the Secretary estimates such payment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44C5E50493B34A0090A5EBE02EB72BE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Identification requirements</header><text>Rules similar to the rules which apply under section 24A(e) shall apply for purposes of this section, except that such rules shall apply with respect to the return of tax for the reference taxable year or, in the case of information provided through the on-line portal or otherwise, with respect to the information so provided.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05B94F7515CF41D199162A30EB04DB82"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restrictions on taxpayers who improperly claimed credit or improperly received monthly advance childhood education payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For restrictions on taxpayers who improperly claimed credit or improperly received monthly advance childhood education payments, see section 24A(f).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6D7C496504E44FD08D15884FB3D5BDBF"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Notice of payments</header> <paragraph id="HB703A7D3FFFD4379AA564023AF8D7C05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 31 of the calendar year following any calendar year during which the Secretary makes one or more payments to any taxpayer under this section, the Secretary shall provide such taxpayer with a written notice which includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8E6D105BF3E449B89A0A8FA7E04219C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s taxpayer identity (as defined in section 6103(b)(6)),</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EE3ECB91691470FB453BACAD04790A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of such payments made to such taxpayer during such calendar year, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BA014D620834C00B4D855896C572878"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59D8AEB800C44906BD790A10AAC97BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain payments subject to treatment as excess advance payments</header><text>In the case of any payments made to a taxpayer which the Secretary has determined are subject to treatment as excess advance payments, the notice provided under paragraph (1) to such taxpayer shall include the amount of such payments.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5D5395803F0C4EAD83C830F91D7A68B2"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Notification of certain events</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any taxpayer receiving monthly advance childhood education payments under this section with respect to any specified child, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, provide reasonable advance notice of each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H36202140648B42C381E6955341A4AF0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any month with respect to which such monthly advance childhood education payment will increase (relative to the preceding month) by reason of an inflation adjustment under section 24A(b)(3).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB53F8D3658194A1C91CA9CD73A8DFD75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any month with respect to which such monthly advance childhood education payment will be reduced (relative to the preceding month) by reason of such child ceasing to be a specified child by reason of attaining age 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5965D8B8F4444B1E942B115BAE987542"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such other events as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE695234019BF40C2BE2F7F4221C6A69C"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H07BF48C3F0A54D5C87DDFC24932FB1B4"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Disclosure of information relating to advance payment of monthly childhood education tax credit</header> <text>Section 6103(e) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H91B9536668204F9395A4562DFF04B41F"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <paragraph id="H285A4F51EAE945B080680E8E61D8039E">
            <enum>(12)</enum>
            <header>Disclosure of information relating to advance payment of monthly childhood
              education tax credit</header>
            <subparagraph id="H3C8C2F2307B14335A3CE8DCF1A16CC86">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Joint filers</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any individual who is eligible for monthly advance childhood education payments under section 7527B, if the reference taxable year (as defined in section 7527B(d)(2)) that the Secretary uses to calculate such payments is a year for which the individual filed an income tax return jointly with another individual, the Secretary may disclose to such individual any information which is relevant in determining the monthly advance childhood education payment under section 7527B, and the individual’s eligibility for such payment, including information regarding any of the following:</text>
              <clause id="HDBF154432FBC4275846E7D04DAD66DC6">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>The number of specified children.</text> </clause> <clause id="H63AD0B54B6F54C318149DE979D412F0B"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>The name and taxpayer identification number of specified children.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H59CE9C1056424AD7A0FA1E51B72AEE3C">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Marital status.</text> </clause> <clause id="H6FBEAC9EA41146E98CE013E2D50593E0"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>Household income.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H0ABC6F35D0CE416EAE30891F183E14F8">
                <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>Modified adjusted gross income.</text> </clause> <clause id="HB6F6CF87193A4AF1A13FA5E351B85884"> <enum>(vi)</enum> <text>Principal place of abode.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H352B441593FD411D9681555D061F56C6">
                <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>Such other information as the Secretary may provide.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15FCF15315384CD5A4249CF2FFBB48AB"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Competing claimants</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any adjudication under section 7527B(f), the Secretary may disclose return information provided by the individual with the original claim to the individual with the challenge claim, return information provided by the individual with the challenge claim to the individual with the original claim, and any other information considered by the Secretary in such adjudication to either or both such individuals. Such information shall be limited to the items specified in subparagraph (A) and the following:</text>
              <clause id="H68C5F7FB6FDF4CBDBF7762D4E3182B17">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information received under any agreements or coordination the Secretary entered into with—</text>
                <subclause id="H428A64BA820749199854550B3F9E8C23">
                  <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>any State, local government, Tribal government, or possession of the United States, or</text>
                </subclause>
                <subclause id="HD123178B88984DD985297BFE1CC9475B">
                  <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>any other individual or entity that the Secretary determines to be appropriate for purposes of adjudicating claims under section 7527B(f).</text>
                </subclause>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HAEA7AD860F4C4558858380232FB84FD5">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>Information considered by the Secretary about where and with whom the specified child resided.</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H5763C2A7B66445F1A0641A958B68CCC0">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Information considered by the Secretary about expenditures made by the claimants to the extent such payments relate to the original or challenge claim.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E6729B502184FA2916A3D1FEA37B940"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="HCA18378BEEF04B5EA55971C1AB010048"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 26(b)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (Z) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF3A4AB090A2D42D58E61158002F70FFA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H159A3E20DC9D4053966689467EB59BC9"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 24A(g)(2) (relating to increase in tax equal to excess advance payments in certain circumstances).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8524CF4D501C45C2818C02700C2E3F11"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 152(f)(6)(B)(ii) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1621A2AF07A54E0892C7B8A250581E4C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HCB5D013083F04B43BC1EA93194FFD764"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credits under sections 24 and 24A, and the payments under section 7527B,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C33BC62DE284D54B43EA4BB9F2BB366"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 3402(f)(1)(C) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or section 24A (determined after application of subsection (g) thereof)</quote> after <quote>section 24 (determined after application of subsection (j) thereof)</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D86DE9597C64C03AC18726C3619C646"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6103(l)(13)(A)(v) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or section 24A, as the case may be</quote> after <quote>section 24</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E8C15E105C0444C86DEB33B0CD59EC7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6211(b)(4)(A) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>24A by reason of subsection (d) thereof,</quote> after <quote>24 by reason of subsections (d) and (i)(1) thereof,</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF566BDBE2B44168A09EC94DE881D3E8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 6213(g)(2)(I) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or section 24A (relating to monthly childhood education tax credit)</quote> after <quote>section 24 (relating to child tax credit)</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05706ACA88964C0E912F2789272C7511"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 6213(g)(2)(L) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>24A,</quote> after <quote>24,</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FD2F0D0FD8D4B7BA8F5A0EC6B40721B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Section 6213(g)(2)(P) of such Code is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC8BBF5C5315C461998424D57AFC9A455"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or 24A(f)(2)</quote> after <quote>section 24(g)(2)</quote>,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD45539994FF748569BA4FD08263F3DE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or 24A</quote> after <quote>under section 24</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF13C6115E89945F69BDF72D87E22582D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (g)(1) thereof</quote> and inserting <quote>section 24(g)(1) or section 24A(f)(1), respectively</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H120BF98F98C64078A459378644FDA93C"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6695(g)(2) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>24A,</quote> after <quote>24,</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B5C3FBFD2A54DE0966168F02F945AA0"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 1324(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>24A,</quote> after <quote>24,</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA356AABCC9384EBF8FF2DE7A00EC54AE"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 24 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6247C94C22D34D678BC92E07D9F6F765" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HFFCAA6A99B3E45D4988A0D434F153F20" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HDD40B32362B849169AE952557E490A92" level="section"><enum-in-header>Sec. 24A.</enum-in-header> Monthly childhood education tax credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6B5785199444063B5D054266983F985"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for chapter 77 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7527A the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE50FF554B8C142DCA32225905967F54B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H044FFA7E67A84268A2E31313717DAA5B" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="H5F306357053841C096D1A60F22CD75EA" level="section"><enum-in-header>Sec. 7527B.</enum-in-header> Advance payment of monthly childhood education tax credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H04225CD597254495886495E3C2FC457C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <paragraph id="H5673DD926FC74B2CA42FF8A40F08C4FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H878B3CF601474348A224994AA47222D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advance payment of monthly childhood education tax credit</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (b) shall apply to—</text> <subparagraph id="HABE48AA35B27451ABD0F807AF713E850"><enum>(A)</enum><text>calendar months beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED074BB537544A478CD6B9A937FAA361"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7527B">section 7527B(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to grace periods and hardships), calendar months beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49062EE6AAA946E28292F456C61991D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure of information</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (c) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

