<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0D6CF37C7C242C6B1036EBDF3041089" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6510 IH: National Military Civilian Medical Surge Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6510</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to establish the Military-Civilian Medical Surge Program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAAD3A0311A4F414DAD61B3B0C62D5838" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H137747ED99024C34AE74BC35DBA52D81" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Military Civilian Medical Surge Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text> </section> <section id="H6E4A02D6C1244E3A90F0AD74D2D00100"><enum>2.</enum><header>Military-civilian medical surge program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1096 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H079ECF77B844459A981CED62B16BD6C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by adding at the end the following: <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">; medical surge program</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H977148A91DA94D698E305A02722B3625"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HE2DB41277CC549EF88A5928FD7244D16" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H98C3D71A666D4C8EAD8AB59D67335818"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Medical surge program</header>
<paragraph id="HC85B67EDA3914C0EA3741CBEC129AF4D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall carry out a program of record known as the Military-Civilian Medical Surge Program to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9FA3F7FEFE4A4C33A4659C05F4FA8C4A" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support locations that the Secretary of Defense selects under paragraph (3)(B); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H03EA8C8B4EDD4F2BB1E8B4F7B9CE8A45" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhance the interoperability and medical surge capability and capacity of the National Disaster Medical System in response to a declaration or other action described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E92DA1F0CA64B9AA8CE2B304F0649EB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph id="HBF57C7E708664017B9D53BE989A7700E" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Institute for Defense Health Cooperation at the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences (or such successor center), shall oversee the management, staffing, and deployment of the Program, in coordination with the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the Director of the Defense Health Agency, and, for purposes of ensuring that the Program is carried out in a manner that is consistent with paragraph (6), the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H671F5E7541F14E1D8467BBB2C1C01658" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subparagraph (A) during a contingency operation, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the Program provides support, acting through the Defense Health Agency serving as a combat support agency, to the relevant combatant command.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAA458425B964F119C442D385FE338AD" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure the program is administrated in coordination with the military departments, the Joint Staff, the Defense Health Agency, and the Department of Health and Human Services through semiannual coordination meetings and quarterly updates. On an annual basis, one such meeting shall include the participation of partners specified in paragraph (3)(A).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAE6B4C54FB5E4E658257A1A92A4A8C7F" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary of Defense shall maintain requirements for staffing, specialized training, research, and education, regarding patient regulation, movement, definitive care, and other matters the Secretary determines critical to sustaining the health of members of the armed forces. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H077992669E2F498294CCD9484661679F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph id="H136684E9B9794A36AFFD7D9FFA723C96" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary of Defense shall establish partnerships at locations selected under subparagraph (B) with public, private, and nonprofit health care organizations, health care institutions, health care entities, academic medical centers of institutions of higher education, and hospitals that the Secretary and the Secretary of Health and Human Services determine—</text>
<clause id="H5D58ED7F530B47E08ADD1E7E75100457" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are critical in mobilizing a civilian medical response in support of a wartime contingency or other catastrophic event in the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE8735E0691EA4188B184453DA2F7C258" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have demonstrated technical proficiency in critical national security domains, including high-consequence infectious disease and special pathogen preparedness, and matters relating to defense, containment, management, care, and transportation.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1A7A94B12E3B4C92B8604B3DD85B0C4F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall select not fewer than eight locations that are operationally relevant to the missions of the Department of Defense under the National Disaster Medical System and are aeromedical or other transport hubs or logistics centers in the United States for partnerships under subparagraph (A). The Secretary may select more than eight locations, including locations outside of the continental United States, if the Secretary determines such additional locations cover areas of strategic and operational relevance to the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B677A3B26C14589AD3F22665B1BA948" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall ensure that the partnerships under paragraph (3)(A) allow for civilian medical personnel to quickly and effectively mobilize direct support to military medical treatment facilities and provide support to other requirements of the military health system pursuant to the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HFEEB9F04F2BF4BC0BF5C0590318E780C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A declaration of a national emergency under the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1621">50 U.S.C. 1621 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A3512B772F74205B24E5D5644906108"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A public health emergency declared under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H43D330E1566C4F30B1F99A90D94F3A9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A declaration of war by Congress.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86E5145BE7FC4DC48426C616E72E20F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A contingency operation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBE05ACD6A94E4A4BAB079CC89BD9D0EA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President’s exercise of executive powers under the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5F93AC90B0F418DBDAC9EC33518A13F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other emergency or major disaster as declared by the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7CDBA6A524CB4B7B9BAFCD6E1DC6BC7F" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the status, readiness, and operational capabilities of the Program. Each report shall include an assessment of personnel readiness, resource availability, interagency coordination efforts, and recommendations for continued improvements to the Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEEE5EB49101405A83C1F231B77EBBF0" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary of Defense to control, direct, limit, or otherwise affect the authorities of the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to the leadership and administration of the National Disaster Medical System, public health and medical preparedness and response, staffing levels, or resource allocation. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA44DBC889FE74A3C9810B3AEB2904E05" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H323E9CC554B74FE3880FCF6B1404FE8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> means a four-year institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB711096D0A4C41D6AB0A4E59E64EC334"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>National Disaster Medical System</term> means the system established under section 2812 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300hh-11">42 U.S.C. 300hh–11</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDFC865E70E647BC938DDE1023CED7B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Military-Civilian Medical Surge Program established under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

