<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HD9A07E9064124EB4A2496724B9DD6BEE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6555 RH: Enhancing Bank Resolution Participation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 459</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6555</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–534]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on December 10, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller of the Currency and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation to carry out a study on shelf charters and modified bidder qualification processes, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H69BAAC867BA64C3981E8192C2AA73199"><section id="HE2E1593D4EEB410D9A14E9A1E0D4A6CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Bank Resolution Participation Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H7730D1D944144876B11FDAF2B4899412"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on shelf charters and modified bidder qualification processes</header><subsection id="H738C1674CA4B4B30B94980A92A299BE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Board of the Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, jointly, carry out a study of—</text><paragraph id="H634197C6659446B3928E1978DE7F8497"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use by the Comptroller of the Currency of shelf charters, including all conditional or preliminary shelf charter approvals granted between January 1, 2008, and the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1811C1566CF7476397A824FD87D5217F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation of the modified bidder qualification process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA65655B946B04E3DB45A8EDDE6CE12F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841 et seq.</external-xref>) and section 10 of the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">12 U.S.C. 1467a</external-xref>) to shelf charter proposals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3595947F4A144FB68E9052E360D2D23D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether shelf charters and modified bidder qualification processes were considered or used in connection with the receivership of any insured depository institution for which the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation was appointed receiver in 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16110B75066B44EB89ECD996F33DB1FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to such receiverships, the extent to which greater use of shelf charters and modified bidder qualification processes could have—</text><subparagraph id="HCDE361FE25264857848BE2FE468DA897"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanded the pool of participants in the acquisition of the assets or liabilities of such failed insured depository institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6934116E70F498C8DFB3DC3B5EF198C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resulted in greater competition and diversity in market outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B440AA13414403B95E9D54B0A581813"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protected the Deposit Insurance Fund; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8305192437244E7BA7C89E42AE16F861"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthened financial stability and reduced the need for any emergency determination by the Secretary of the Treasury under section 13(c)(4)(G) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1823">12 U.S.C. 1823(c)(4)(G)</external-xref>) with respect to any such receivership;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F4FFB0F83554636933139876457E28C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the use of shelf charters and modified bidder qualification processes since January 1, 2008, including on financial stability, the safety and soundness of affected insured depository institutions, and the availability of financial products and services provided to consumers by such institutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85D2AF88ACDB4C9383D3EB91DD096A92"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any benefits and risks of private equity ownership of banks through the use of shelf charters and modified bidder qualification processes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15D22494F31348BE964B9D03E4454B88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Board of the Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, jointly, submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing—</text><paragraph id="HA644CBCB5FAC4861923BD122101918B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C62324D721149E79FC069D12D04DDB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of statutory or regulatory barriers to the use and effectiveness of shelf charters and modified bidder qualification processes in the resolution of failed insured depository institutions, including recommendations for legislative and regulatory changes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H378014D05445479CA023E4CF467618C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3C54618A3DB145D8B997473601BD1C9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Insured depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>insured depository institution</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB617BAF3E93344F5951CFE3CA3B05181"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modified bidder qualification process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>modified bidder qualification process</quote> has the meaning given such term in the press release of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation titled <quote>FDIC Expands Bidder List for Troubled Institutions Plan Allows Those Without a Bank Charter to Participate in the Process</quote> published November 26, 2008. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H676B020FA34D4A1F91CA1CB9F85AFC52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Shelf charter</header><text>The term <quote>shelf charter</quote> has the meaning given such term in the report issued by the Comptroller of the Currency titled <quote>Activities Permissible for National Banks and Federal Savings Associations, Cumulative</quote> published October 2017.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

