<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBBDFC2662D804287AB1B53A65F49FEB9" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1152 IH: Expressing appreciation and recognition for the contributions of the American cowboy and historic cattle trails in advancing American history in celebration of the Nation’s 250th anniversary.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1152</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260402">April 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing appreciation and recognition for the contributions of the American cowboy and historic cattle trails in advancing American history in celebration of the Nation’s 250th anniversary.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States is celebrating the 250th anniversary of the signing of the Declaration of Independence and the history of the Nation, culminating on July 4, 2026;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the American cowboy played a significant role in the history of the Nation, demonstrating the courage, strength, and independence of the American spirit;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the American cowboy tradition has roots going back centuries across the United States, Mexico, and Canada and reflects the significant contributions of Mexican, Black, Native American, and White cowboys who helped shape the cattle industry and culture of the American West;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the American cowboy as he is known today first became reality in the post-Civil War era of the great cattle drives, when cowboys moved millions of Texas longhorns to markets further north over historic trails such as the Shawnee Trail, Chisholm Trail, Western Trail (also known as Great Western Trail), Goodnight-Loving Trail, and more;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas those cattle trails and cowboys crossed the States of Kansas, Oklahoma, Texas, Missouri, New Mexico, Colorado, Nebraska, Wyoming, Montana, South Dakota, North Dakota, and beyond;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas those cattle drives helped rebuild the economy of the Nation in the post-Civil War era by meeting the emerging consumer demand for protein in growing cities and supplying breeding stock for burgeoning northern ranch operations, creating the truly national beef and cattle industry;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the cultural representations of the cowboy in museums and other attractions are a significant economic engine for rural and urban areas, encompassing agriculture, entertainment, retail, and tourism sectors with the impact felt across the entire Nation; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the American cowboy has become uniquely and globally recognized as a symbol of American courage, independence, spirit, and determination: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE1F9C4F3E0994E6995A7D3C426E40355"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H44B839D18409440991A7D31BB9179575"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives recognizes the valuable role of the American cowboy and historic cattle trails for their vital contribution to the Nation’s history and encourages local celebrations of such legacy as part of the Nation’s 250th anniversary.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

