<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H44D65920C80F4B0D9295EB0184E29187" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6371 IH: No Robot Bosses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6371</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain uses of automated decision systems by employers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF7C709DA4639428A9FDCA7F4C3EFB589" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB7681045307E4E69B01B6E0AC8383B8B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Robot Bosses Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD6F0CB9995014357BF296BB3B21C94A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HD21733332CCC4586AA9BE5A677117E45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Automated decision system</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5437A04AA4824082A77A738FA3512785"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>automated decision system</term> means a system, software, or process that—</text><clause commented="no" id="H7BAEBB4E2FB84E2FA713B53A25BF3170"><enum>(i)</enum><text>uses computation, in whole or in part, to determine outcomes, make or aid decisions (including through evaluations, metrics, or scoring), inform policy implementation, or collect data or observations, including such a system, software, or process derived from machine learning, statistics, or other data processing or artificial intelligence techniques; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H12EE794C3EB94A8794D083DCF2DB0C83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not passive computing infrastructure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4B2E2773647346B1B06DA1B330F0840B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Passive computing infrastructure</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>passive computing infrastructure</term> means any intermediary technology that does not influence or determine the outcome of a decision, make or aid in a decision (including through evaluations, metrics, or scoring), inform policy implementation, or collect data or observations, including web hosting, domain registration, networking, caching, data storage, or cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1596E9D114A4449DABE743B9D01E0F60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Automated decision system output</header><text>The term <term>automated decision system output</term> means any information, assumption, prediction, score, recommendation, decision, evaluation, metric, conclusion, inference, or profile generated by an automated decision system.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H023691764A5E4E588EC8BC7A5369B76F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Candidate</header><text>The term <term>candidate</term>, with respect to an employer, means an individual who applies, or applied, to be employed by, or otherwise perform work for remuneration for, the employer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5342716792F349DA9C6F913E5FD8C1FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term>, with respect to an employer, means an individual—</text><subparagraph id="HA946BC0A47D24C7793740DA101C4DAF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is employed by, or otherwise performing work for remuneration for, the employer, including such an individual who is—</text><clause id="HACBB58103371438F97466FE79344CBE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employer described in clauses (i)(I) and (ii) of paragraph (6)(A);</text></clause><clause id="HF7365CCC24AD4CA8B845E928A306CA4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an entity described in paragraph (6)(A)(i)(II);</text></clause><clause id="H5F84677694CF4848BCA0FDAAF15D77AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing office described in paragraph (6)(A)(i)(III);</text></clause><clause id="H393BF5501CF54A71BC9C4D0FD1052AB0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing office described in paragraph (6)(A)(i)(IV); or</text></clause><clause id="HE6491C7F5A3A4358BC1C810BA5437112"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any individual performing work for remuneration for an employing agency described in paragraph (6)(A)(i)(V); or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DA2C0611EC64E63BDEBBA093BECAED7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is a candidate with respect to the employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94601E4D2AB64E42B7AD4EB7E7E97796"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Employ</header><text>The term <term>employ</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H38916B6991FE4929921B288790471C9C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Employer</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8AFCA1207436471780059BF870562A2C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means any person who is—</text><clause id="H3C383259295C478A91EFE2A106E50615"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD61671885BFF41DAB801B2EE9541778A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a covered employer who is not described in any other subclause of this clause;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCE786524654847C5962485E4E9DBF4CC" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an entity employing a State employee described in section 304(a) of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16c(a));</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="H0D3A14A5B848437284461BC4FFB8C489"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an employing office, as defined in section 101 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="H2B9E58767EC34F9BA96AA311AF0184D2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an employing office, as defined in section 411(c) of title 3, United States Code; or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="HCFBE70E521A0436A8074A25ABACF4AA7"><enum>(V)</enum><text>an employing agency covered under subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7CEF3D8AADE442A689D6A17B136C0FE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engaged in commerce (including government), or an industry or activity affecting commerce (including government).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDDB258EA07664B68A636C6C9DECF7ED7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered employer</header><text>In subparagraph (A), the term <term>covered employer</term>—</text><clause commented="no" id="H725CB95EC83347ACB78B3B4D09A5CBCF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means any person engaged in commerce or in any industry or activity affecting commerce who employs, or otherwise engages for the performance of work for remuneration, 11 or more covered individuals;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HDBCABA840BEB445C985780B760192F52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H59549352A67D40D1B22A9BF1B489C752"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any person who acts, directly or indirectly, in the interest of a covered employer in relation to any individual performing work for remuneration for such covered employer;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H66C90AF639894ECDA1261778DAC1B4A8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any successor in interest of a covered employer;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HEDD61FA682684733A9C162EE7CE963D5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any public agency; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HBCB03A4EA4FF4B0CBACF529DA08078A4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBC09A1788748414AB9572284C9EBD6C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include any labor organization (other than when acting as an employer) or anyone acting in the capacity of officer or agent of such labor organization.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF52A81356D154C078EEF5D7DED2197EA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public agency</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, a public agency shall be considered to be a person engaged in commerce or in an industry or activity affecting commerce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3239493B6FE04E498E460A070A963884"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <term>commerce</term>, <term>person</term>, and <term>public agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9F46444A414B4583A63F8539CF503A0C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Employment-related decision</header><text>The term <term>employment-related decision</term> includes a decision by an employer with regard to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFE1589DA0C91422790C0A2E3F95D7D39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hiring a covered individual (including any decision with regard to recruiting, screening, interviewing, or selecting a candidate);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H36E1F38965D24DAC9651AE57BCE8CA13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>firing, retaining, taking a disciplinary action against, demoting, or reassigning duties of a covered individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1ABA7EECB5104632BE97AF2B50C61000"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other term, condition, or privilege of employment or work of the covered individual, such as relating to pay, scheduling, health care or long-term care coverage, benefits, or hours worked or promoting a covered individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H28BD95CB82A74E76AD8027EAE2C55619"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Government entity</header><text>The term <term>government entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFDFC9D422EE469D956D3A03156C8F1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal agency (as such term is defined in section 3371 of title 5, United States Code);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H93F6D5DA24A14B2782BB71F1C5179BD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State or political subdivision thereof;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBD513AC498F340E8A3A593C2082C2877"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any agency, authority, or instrumentality of a State or political subdivision thereof; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8082AD49A1C441DCBCBB8F8FC21983B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Tribal government or political subdivision thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H94CBC01C28EB4AC3939D4B44540F0095"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this Act pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BF3F75B403A46D6B5532F076B96535D"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2(5) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152(5)</external-xref>), except that such term shall also include—</text><subparagraph id="HF6B8334C227F47049880B5802C6563D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any organization composed of labor organizations, such as a labor union federation or a State or municipal labor body; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H675466FB28FD4B699BB18B8AFD576BA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any organization which would be included in the definition for such term under such section 2(5) but for the fact that the organization represents—</text><clause id="H5565C9ADD0BB4F7FAB5E273F01CAF44E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals employed by the United States, any wholly owned Government corporation, any Federal Reserve Bank, or any State or political subdivision thereof;</text></clause><clause id="H55AC7A119E244F9AAF6D66A244077D15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals employed by persons subject to the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="H9F6F00A4FFC443A4B09C2AD3BD2ACE0C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individuals employed as agricultural laborers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD540B5FFB5944232B0523AF23BE2F946"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Predispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75C65191F98448E6AD32F8E15137B58B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Predispute joint-action waiver</header><text>The term <term>predispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement, whether or not part of a predispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8D7266CBF75C434ABF609F9BBBEE9D49"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCCC81E321F9491A8A4BEC030A9E7A87"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4097A815F3B9446F91F7665D7AA0CD5A"><enum>(15)</enum><header>State attorney general</header><text>The term <term>State attorney general</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H98AE4119DF85456C9E62410910308C29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a State, the attorney general or chief law enforcement officer of the State, or another official or agency designated by the State to bring civil actions on behalf of the State or the residents of the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4214AF8BE6344089DF3CBEC276C5540" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a Tribal government, the attorney general or chief law enforcement officer of the Tribal government, or another official or agency designated by the Tribal government to bring civil actions on behalf of the Tribal government or the Indian Tribe of the Tribal government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H55D3664C1DBD4756B1A62B6AA5DBC804"><enum>(16)</enum><header>State privacy regulator</header><text>The term <term>State privacy regulator</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H82D5BD2DFDC0409AAC8F3CC1FF92A7C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chief consumer protection officer of a State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2F13060F1A5466AA7CA29B86CD2BA10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State consumer protection agency with expertise in data protection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8DD5FE595FD42649E5A7B063DE3F650"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDFD170857F824162BCE5D43668FFE086"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of an automated decision system by an employer</header><subsection id="H38659FFC858F4511A20B0A2F5FF5954D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employment-Related decisions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H871753B5389B41E2A3E9A1CA427A4E25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer—</text><subparagraph id="H6E25A3BB81F441CFA179CA385716BFCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not rely exclusively on an automated decision system in making an employment-related decision with respect to a covered individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86DBA35932DA4A0ABBD7218743C45D8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not use an automated decision system output in making an employment-related decision with respect to a covered individual unless—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35044907218844B8A3E4B4139A279BD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the automated decision system used to generate such automated decision system output has had pre-deployment testing and validation with respect to—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H046BE480543F43ADBD5F8962977673AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the efficacy of the system;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF315253A0D284F90A8270AA749125D30"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the compliance of the system with applicable employment discrimination laws, including—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E24272E87A840C68810C00DBE721335"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</external-xref>);</text></item><item id="HAE3BE01BAB9E463CA242C36D7FCF9AD0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/621">29 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8425C8147504077B28CCA5E3CC969F9"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">title I of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12111">42 U.S.C. 12111 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></item><item id="H22C009F15FDF4BC8A487A02192DAA256"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ff">42 U.S.C. 2000ff et seq.</external-xref>);</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B302452848640049425801C28A036FF"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>section 6(d) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206(d)</external-xref>);</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5CE2641024541408869402D0E0D2B7D"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>sections 501 and 505 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/791">29 U.S.C. 791</external-xref>; 793); and</text></item><item id="HC70E43E5D2284FD28AA86C76E5BC85C2"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>the Pregnant Workers Fairness Act (division II of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>));</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ECE4ACC632447CEA0A14A45A126F8B9"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lack of any potential discriminatory impact of the system, including discriminatory impact based on race, color, religion, sex (including pregnancy, sexual orientation, or gender identity), national origin, age, or disability and genetic information (including family medical history); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4441FFD72DA49FA90DD3D81655451AE"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the compliance of the system with the Artificial Intelligence Risk Management Framework released by the National Institute of Standards and Technology on January 26, 2023, or successor framework;</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ABBC1BE5D97405DAE8F92EA74B37472"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such automated decision system is, not less than annually, independently tested for discriminatory impact described in clause (i)(III) or potential biases and the results of such test are made publicly available;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B8EFE98A8DB434ABCE0410AAD843EA3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employer has provided the disclosure required under paragraph (2) with respect to such use of an automated decision system output;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45FBF642009D4F2C9DB2C4235F750999"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such use is designed for purposes of making such an employment-related decision;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97B3C8F0DDB54CF39401A355A3FFCD59"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the employer independently corroborates, via meaningful oversight by a human with appropriate and relevant experience, such automated decision system output;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H005C360AE0204DC896BBB53E506F0C0F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 7 days after making such an employment-related decision, the employer provides full, accessible, and meaningful documentation in plain language to such covered individual (at no cost to such covered individual) on the automated decision system output, including—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84F31477FC2742B0A7F7C0EF67CC0FFA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of the automated decision system used to generate such automated decision system output;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF742EEBCEE104E79A6E889532CB93F23"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description and explanation, in plain language, of the input data to such automated decision system used to generate such automated decision system output and a machine-readable copy of such data;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FFCC8D081B04095A01CBE014294DBC0"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description and explanation of how such automated decision system output was used in making such employment-related decision; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8A669849D9142728B262A360121D26D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasoning for the use of such automated decision system output in such employment-related decision; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF2FD6536321C4B4FADB06B00F3903501"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the employer enables the covered individual to, after receiving such documentation—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FAEFBD363164A1B931AB6A32620D213"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dispute (in a manner that is accessible and equitable and does not pose an unreasonable burden on the covered individual) such automated decision system output to a human with appropriate and relevant experience; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE26116BAE501494A83E7BF53F5CAF874"><enum>(II)</enum><text>appeal such employment-related decision to a human with appropriate and relevant experience who is not the human for purposes of the corroboration under clause (v).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC1479D44F024CA5945DFD35B9B320ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H588C2780086B4880A7B04A71AFF8DCB1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer that uses or intends to use an automated decision system output in making an employment-related decision with respect to a covered individual shall, in accordance with subparagraph (B), disclose to such covered individual—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52B7A963F16746D2AF1D20E2ECD04FC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the employer uses or intends to use an automated decision system output in making such an employment-related decision;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB132653734DC4C409FC8738EC632CDFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description and explanation of the automated decision system used or intended to be used to generate such automated decision system output, including—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB892556C56164B16A0B6DDBA17178D9C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the types of data collected or intended to be collected as inputs to the automated decision system and the circumstances of such collection;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D1981718D8D4194906010C24E360FD1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the characteristics that the automated decision system measures or is intended to measure, such as the knowledge, skills, or abilities of the covered individual;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BFF99CECADD4C1F974318C89BC57FC3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such characteristics relate or would relate to any function required for the work or potential work of the covered individual;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H961D92BC5FC146D895408AB04E42FD07"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the system measures or is intended to measure such characteristics; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2019EA288B044C8CB8D92641BEA7A8BD"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the covered individual can interpret the automated decision system output in plain language;</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F1937F6BE454C67AD9E6B1188506C53"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the identity of the individual or entity that operates the automated decision system that provides such an automated decision system output;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EBA0C581CC54F28862B0C217303FBCB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the employer uses or intends to use such an automated decision system output in making such an employment-related decision; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE48DC5DFDD24A61AB9A50BC4169DEB6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>how the covered individual may dispute or appeal an employment-related decision made with respect to the covered individual using an automated decision system output.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H321DAC7A2CD0441FA2EFED9FEDC88B00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing of notice</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9729611B641B4CB3AB59AA6440069FDF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employer shall provide the disclosure required under subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="HD7D4365F734948A1B0A8D8C3C1D1BD71"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a covered individual for whom an employment-related decision with regard to the hiring of the covered individual—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29D2752BCC55405996526136229297DB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was made before the date of enactment of this Act, to the covered individual not later than 30 days after such date of enactment; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2D7ECD660374F37A0AC6752A4E0F6D0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is made on or after the date of enactment of this Act, to the covered individual, except as provided in subclause (II), prior to making such employment-related decision; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HD181BF29AC7640C6A74ADDCF199C3986"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a candidate who applies to the employer on or after the date of enactment of this Act, prior to accepting an application by the candidate to be employed by, or otherwise perform work for remuneration for, the employer.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC63F97C995CE4D6E8D9D1D026AB03154"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent disclosures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after any information provided by an employer to a covered individual through a disclosure required under clause (ii) or (iv) of subparagraph (A) significantly changes or after any significant new information required to be provided in such a disclosure becomes available, the employer shall provide the covered individual with an updated disclosure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6753337E1B514FE9B7B1285817944166"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training</header><text>An employer that uses or intends to use an automated decision system output in making an employment-related decision with respect to a covered individual shall train any individual or entity that operates the automated decision system that provides such an automated decision system output or uses such automated decision system output on the use of such system, including on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B405FA3BBD14148916879E3E3DB4963"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the input information used by such automated decision system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCF0F597FF8C4A36B8E665BB60EAC4E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appeals process for such an automated decision system output;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD569B82D68844398A80855F56191D393"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">potential biases in automated decision systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCA07C3777C74903914A26433351E38E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any limitations of the automated decision system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAEF0EC43F6145359E376EB8B45FAE1F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any potential adverse effects to covered individuals due to the automated decision system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC881A131BF8E452482DA7303A68BC7E9"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any potential errors or problems related to the automated decision system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1A4CC9DFFD34610A2273365C72A2093"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examples of inappropriate uses of the automated decision system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52011D507E21472C8AABFE722489C4F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management by an automated decision system</header><text>An employer that manages a covered individual through an automated decision system shall enable the covered individual to opt out of such management and be managed through a human manager who is able to make employment-related decisions with respect to the covered individual.</text></subsection></section><section id="H27F6169BCF2E4821A4FDD19A093C1957"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Technology and Worker Protection Division</header><subsection id="H2A98C932636D4600B21891B7FC011807"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Department of Labor the Technology and Worker Protection Division.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36D9648CEF9A4113A74FFC769CE11C53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrator of the Technology and Worker Protection Division</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall appoint an Administrator of the Technology and Worker Protection Division to head the Technology and Worker Protection Division.</text></subsection><subsection id="H21E4E8CF16F147A6B200EDB906F479EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employees and advisory boards of the Division</header><paragraph id="HAA05DEFB870C4C2F81CDB11E99DC4098"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator—</text><subparagraph id="H6DE5A06E3B4D484092B4125394820EFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may select, appoint, and employ, without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3318 of title 5, United States Code, individuals, including technologists, directly to positions in the competitive service, as defined in section 2102 of such title, to carry out the duties of the Administrator under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04CD29B5C37742A497E5F37622B68C7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may fix the compensation of the individuals described in subparagraph (A) without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for such individuals may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37918A001C8D4AC69A9CA3922947D374"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory boards</header><subparagraph id="H2CFB2EC731C749B391C30E68FE264699"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish the following advisory boards to advise and consult with in the exercise of the functions of the Administrator under this Act and to provide information on emerging practices relating to the treatment of data by employers:</text><clause id="HEFED011A205C4DEFB089A90AC3044938"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The User Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of experts in consumer protection, privacy, civil rights, disability rights, labor organizations, and ethics.</text></clause><clause id="H78AC9A1D3D73474A8C87A64F6E193FAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Research Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of individuals with academic and research expertise in privacy, cybersecurity, computer science, innovation, design, ethics, economics, civil rights law, disability law, labor organizations and public policy and representatives of labor organizations.</text></clause><clause id="H4BD02A0B145147EB8E5449EB75E7503C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Product Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of technologists, computer scientists, designers, product managers, attorneys, representatives of labor organizations, workplace technology experts, accessibility experts, and other representatives of employers and employees.</text></clause><clause id="H7B36BCE318A849E6B5C7FD27F042025E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Labor Advisory Board, which shall be comprised of representatives of labor organizations and representatives of workers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B190F4132014FDEB9F0CC776B57460C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appointments</header><text>The Administrator shall appoint members to the advisory boards established under subparagraph (A) without regard to party affiliation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D48AC6FE3C14BB09189FF041FB97BE8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Representation from across regions and sectors</header><text>In appointing members to each advisory board established under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall ensure that the membership of such boards includes individuals who—</text><clause id="H796DAD4CD5A64C249A065F23D4243B29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>represent a range of geographic regions of the United States and its territories, including rural, suburban, and urban areas;</text></clause><clause id="H167C7FF4C6474203978A1D03724AB75B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide perspectives and expertise from employers of varying sizes, including small- and medium-sized businesses;</text></clause><clause id="H15ED7A4A3D1E45EE85026D24017D0A21"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>include individuals with scientific expertise relevant to the use of automated decision systems in the workplace; and</text></clause><clause id="H44E6586BC8174FEA9296DCB4D6970266"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>reflect experience from distinct sectors of the economy and worker protection fields to ensure that the advisory boards collectively consider the interests of employees and employers across all major industries and regions.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE133F44EAA444B55B90C0A681D591FBD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Each advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall meet—</text><clause id="H22985CF3C62248BF8D0B0F5CF8511587"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the call of the Administrator; and</text></clause><clause id="H0C0557AD8D794F768179257B6A5F0E76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 2 times annually.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8491310919CF454385D5D2DEE7DF33E3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Compensation and travel expenses</header><text>A member of an advisory board established under subparagraph (A) who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall—</text><clause id="H96FD63AA85494999B23511F543F116F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be entitled to receive compensation at a rate fixed by the Administrator while attending meetings of the advisory board, including travel time; and</text></clause><clause id="H5C097884EFCE4BBDA412D0F6AFCDC695"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H194AFE9F1CD14FB89C31898F0927E68A"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Exemption from the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>Each advisory board established under subparagraph (A) shall be exempt from <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C8488F593A343728545E32641B31CF4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of voluntary services</header><text>The Administrator may, as may from time to time be needed, use any voluntary or uncompensated services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8842D2566D8A4DCDA6951CC9ECE1CFFF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attorneys</header><text>Attorneys appointed under this subsection may appear for and represent the Administrator in any litigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01E61DEEA02D4229A0C1D8E5C2A3C345"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Offices</header><paragraph id="H805AC2C9689E487181257281965D274C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The principal office of the Technology and Worker Protection Division shall be in the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E07EA9BB379405C9146CECB12D915AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regional, local, and other offices</header><text>The Administrator may establish regional, local, or other offices.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDB02A148B655420D97027B4729A15ABB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Regulations</header><subsection id="HA7B4D16351EB4D60ADB8B59CF8AE08D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HFB73276F73EA4C1DAA6E296759DE5018"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><subparagraph id="HD54838A6D3A24A9999AD0A9B7015251C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A) (other than covered individuals described in clauses (iii) through (v) of such section) and other individuals affected by employers described in subclause (I) or (II) of section 2(6)(A)(i), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EE2EF9928F74FBA886C2BAF977C22F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In prescribing any regulations authorized under this paragraph, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, may consult with—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB08EF93FAF2444EB97B0911CBC77D4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over Federal privacy laws or expertise in privacy, including the Federal Trade Commission;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43B82333B2934F949A31E26B39DCD06D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over labor and employment issues, including the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the National Science Foundation, and the National Labor Relations Board; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H506FB78134324A58A19A0A2185844662"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal agencies with relevant expertise, including the United States Access Board and the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2806E2ADA95E4539ACAB4187F46E6FCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Government accountability office; library of congress</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress shall prescribe any regulations described in paragraph (1)(A) with respect to covered individuals of the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress, respectively, and other individuals affected by the Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37A1D6F60E59467E8E053577D60786F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employees covered by congressional accountability act of 1995</header><paragraph id="H3BB3B8FCAC774CC9B20CD5DCF9FC107D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance shall prescribe (in accordance with section 304 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1384">2 U.S.C. 1384</external-xref>)) such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A)(iii) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(6)(A)(i)(III), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5180B1568BB84B31A21D6E43F255F55B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H93168D7891BC4E97BB2D244D03EEF6AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, united states code</header><paragraph id="H6FE55C8D0E2B4ABD9A91E9D92B72E094"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the President (or the designee of the President) shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A)(iv) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(6)(A)(i)(IV), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52331FF901DA4FF3BA2EC29B1C837C1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the President (or designee) may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H685DBADCEB6E487099D4719A78810653"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, united states code</header><paragraph id="H72494537DB144716A2CD797F6129DBCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the Secretary prescribes any regulation under subsection (a)(1)(A), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act with respect to covered individuals described in section 2(4)(A)(v) and other individuals affected by employers described in section 2(6)(A)(i)(V), including individuals who are covered individuals described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to such employers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA86A18AE07874FB48E4740F83B57E62A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency regulations</header><text>The regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A) except insofar as the Director may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections involved under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8F75E299709E42E2BF99254EDC701AC0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No employer shall discriminate or retaliate (including through intimidation, threats, coercion, or harassment) against any covered individual of the employer—</text><paragraph id="HCB328DA6F2224C35972128848E893668"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for exercising, or attempting to exercise, any right provided under this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01C2DB68963E4D6FAB4F519BCB499A2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>because the covered individual (or another individual acting at the request of the covered individual) has—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0E733DC232B426B8E05FE0CAB06EE5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>filed a written or oral complaint to the employer or a Federal, State, or local government entity of a violation of section 3;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE518138A88E249DEB5D2A6FB6630D707"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sought assistance or intervention with respect to a worker privacy-related concern from the employer, a Federal, State, or local government, or a worker representative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2D61AF98208A46819602EE3559AD7713"><enum>(C)</enum><text>instituted, caused to be instituted, or otherwise participated in any inquiry or proceeding under or related to this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE387C59EE50F4B238B3E783DCABDDD83"><enum>(D)</enum><text>given, or is about to give, any information in connection with any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE2185A0BAD5E4782A5A0CE50E9927933"><enum>(E)</enum><text>testified, or is about to testify, in any inquiry or proceeding relating to any right provided under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H0A5098C3271A4E4F84757FBA27ECDEA9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="H8F789F40E55C4570838F77121A26E772"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HC0A4926EA995461AAE72CFB06EAAE3B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H00420D7AF62549258C87F03675AB316A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means a covered individual—</text><clause id="H8157D0DAC6C948B5B906769E17636BDA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in section 2(4)(A) (other than covered individuals described in clauses (iii) through (v) of such section); or</text></clause><clause id="HB1835C08F51E42BB9D900E057A130CB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66C35DAC2F2B42599085F2318A66BAFC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means an employer described in subclause (I) or (II) of section 2(6)(A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F95128C05A245DC84503816CCC7570F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Technology and Worker Protection Division</header><subparagraph id="H96BA32F66A3D4CC89F666B85D0EA4E28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Investigation</header><clause id="HBCD07F64FFBE4DB383A54C4700CED800"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure compliance with the provisions of this Act, or any regulation or order issued under this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED4B284CA83343CFB5FF98FEACE723C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may investigate and gather data regarding the wages, hours, and other conditions and practices of employment in any industry subject to this Act, and may enter and inspect any place or record (and make such transcriptions thereof), question any covered individual, and investigate any facts, conditions, practices, or matters as the Secretary may deem necessary or appropriate to determine whether an employer has violated any provision of this Act, or which may aid in the enforcement of the provisions of this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB124A15D2B254DE2BF266EC64D26E53B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may require, by general or special orders, an employer, to file with the Secretary, in such form as the Secretary may prescribe, annual or special reports or answers in writing to specific questions, furnishing to the Secretary such information or records as the Secretary may require as to the organization, business, conduct, practices, management, and relation to other corporations, partnerships, and individuals, of the employer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEBC7A883902843D69F58F980ACE29FEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reports and answers</header><text>An employer shall file the reports and answers (including information and records) required under clause (i)(II) in such manner, including under oath or otherwise, and within such reasonable time period as the Secretary may require.</text></clause><clause id="HDE832BA85B6C4264BBF67B047CB56492"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Joint investigations</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator, may conduct investigations and make requests for information, as authorized under this Act, on a joint basis with another Federal agency, a State attorney general, or a State agency.</text></clause><clause id="H54722DBA745A447DBC78F999419E5D3B"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Obligation to keep, preserve, and make available records</header><text>An employer shall make, keep, preserve, and make available to the Secretary records pertaining to compliance with this Act in accordance with section 11(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211(c)</external-xref>) and in accordance with any regulation or order issued by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EBDB8D01B724B8392F8895117CD779D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>With respect to employers and covered individuals, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall receive, investigate, and attempt to resolve complaints of violations of section 3 or 6 in the same manner that the Secretary receives, investigates, and attempts to resolve complaints of violations of sections 6 and 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 206 and 207).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73167663AB194796A798AEF1349C9EBC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Referral for criminal proceedings</header><text>If the Secretary, in the course of the performance of any act or duty under this Act, obtains evidence that any employer has engaged in conduct that may constitute a violation of Federal criminal law, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General for prosecution under any applicable law. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect any other authority of the Secretary to disclose information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE96001DCBA248B08CEAA0614EB2DF08"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Litigation</header><text>The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary on any litigation brought under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC0FC74402C4C4C8A2DB36B4163E582"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0DF92E9B1517425FAE147B6F341FC168"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause commented="no" id="HB2145369413D45ED9C7C575E2A4EF5D1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>Notwithstanding any action by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B), any covered individual adversely affected by an alleged violation of section 3 or 6, may commence a civil action against any person that violates such section in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HB3E3B48A4C8E4F6EAABCA48C8BA6D93D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>Notwithstanding any action by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B), any labor organization adversely affected by an alleged violation of 3 or 6 may commence a civil action against any person that violates such section in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0A5432BA9B14A33A0FF6A28DCCC1494"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header><clause commented="no" id="HE7C46E61F3CF40A89379B8F8F4D85543"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the covered individual or labor organization prevails, the court may award the covered individual or labor organization—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H2EBFDC8921C249C2A0A94D1D9F57150E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>damages of—</text><item commented="no" id="H0F041AE209B6444682B9FE7B0DD85BE3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an amount equal to the sum of any actual damages sustained by the covered individual; or</text></item><item commented="no" id="H1CA081DE364744C4AF015F0E74E3AF63"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not more than treble damages;</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H41A9F4BF345C4893893CEF8C1DCE0EA6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>statutory damages described in clause (iv);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA27ECB7E0DE24BC4947EF084B55CF598"><enum>(III)</enum><text>injunctive relief; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H6B3F7A8EA6374ABE966AE03553219266"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>equitable relief.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H077BC9505AD449DCAA267B8019FA2304"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Attorney's fees</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the covered individual or labor organization prevails, the court shall award the covered individual or labor organization reasonable attorney's fees and litigation costs.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H079FC44C4D0646FAAD0D8E963C0886A9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Temporary relief for whistleblowers</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) regarding a violation of section 6, the court may award the covered individual or labor organization temporary relief while the case is pending, including reinstatement.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H00E8490AF49746D5AD627BFDCB75209B"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Statutory damages</header><text>The court may, in accordance with clause (v), award statutory damages under clause (i)(II) against a person in the following amounts:</text><subclause id="H689596A118514B39990C89612D148093" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Using an automated decision system for prohibited activities</header><text>For each violation of section 3 by an employer with respect to a covered individual, the court may, subject to clause (vi), award—</text><item id="H1B8ADD36622F4CFB8370A0EDDEA78492" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>damages of an amount not less than $5,000 and not more than $20,000; or</text></item><item id="H2B13E15B169743B5A21EC567ECFB3C9F" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for any willful or repeated violation by the employer, damages of an amount not less than $10,000 and not more than $40,000.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB050311D082F4897BB8AD97E73D1CD36" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Retaliation on whistleblowers</header><text>For each violation of section 6, the court may, subject to clause (vi), award—</text><item id="H5C36BD3B84B6494FB63C2485DBFEBC74" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>damages of an amount not less than $5,000 and not more than $50,000; or</text></item><item id="HD06233B01E494B73B53E5E8FFAB8535C" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for any willful or repeated violation, damages of an amount not less than $10,000 and not more than $100,000.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H05B4F49875C74EAFB3EAE1CD81EDA85A"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Considerations for statutory damages</header><text>In determining the amount of statutory damages assessed under clause (iv), the court shall consider any relevant circumstances presented by the parties to the action, including—</text><subclause id="HEBE24099C24E4B0692149A68A112AFE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the nature and seriousness of the violation;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0C6C8298008C457FA8DCB3D4310F0097"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of violations;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF4A9264A92FF4EB7A6FAF031CCD3A7C0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the persistence of the misconduct;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDEEE11661F7D496F9D0883228CF762F5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the length of time over which the misconduct occurred;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2919328F20114F39A5002C4249AF3DDD"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the willfulness of the misconduct of the employer; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB671C2A9E1244E0382F05B8C91979422"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the assets, liabilities, and net worth of the employer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE1C09CDFE4B845DBBCE4D27EBD237079"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text>The dollar amounts referred to subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (iv) shall be increased annually, for fiscal year 2026 and every fiscal year thereafter, by the percent increase, if any, in the consumer price index for all urban consumers for the most recent 12-month period for which applicable data is available.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2BA5D7CA90574A428DAF89494AA1CA7E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rights of the Secretary and a State attorney general</header><text>Prior to an covered individual or labor organization bringing a civil action under subparagraph (A), such covered individual or labor organization shall, in writing, notify the Secretary and any relevant State attorney general of the intent to commence such civil action. Upon receiving such notice, the Secretary and State attorney general shall each, not later than 60 days after receiving such notice—</text><clause commented="no" id="H9CB0FA06487641AE889F9BBE92C6A7E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine whether to intervene in such action and, upon intervening—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HA79DA9AED53E4F61ADFACDFDE83EBC51"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in such action; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD1BF3C4B1AFD4E1596FE4BEC82334DFC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in such action; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBEA12E80884C4E3F8E9643EB20E99C58" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify such covered individual or labor organization.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11714D5C401540EC9DEFB6B9524C2831"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Remedies for state employees</header><clause id="H294B207E0DA241979B0F8048158F6BB8"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header> <text>A State’s receipt or use of Federal financial assistance for any program or activity of a State shall constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity, under the 11th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or otherwise, to a suit brought by a covered individual of that program or activity, or a labor organization representing such a covered individual, under this paragraph for equitable, legal, or other relief authorized under this paragraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5ACF143265BB4356A18190B26840A01C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Official capacity</header><text>An official of a State may be sued in the official capacity of the official by any covered individual or such a labor organization who has complied with the procedures under this paragraph, for injunctive relief that is authorized under this paragraph. In such a suit the court may award to the prevailing party those costs authorized by section 722 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">42 U.S.C. 1988</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H3AB6B14FF6A446358C25D845BF02AF8F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>With respect to a particular program or activity, clause (i) applies to conduct that occurs—</text><subclause id="HB73F10299F2B46CE8705DF4904BACC54"><enum>(I)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2464F2EAFCC8430A838179511EDC6264"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after the day on which a State first receives or uses Federal financial assistance for that program or activity.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA027A7E467CB408FB22A7197A2CF7C04" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definition of program or activity</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>program or activity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H159E0CAB34EE487EA106E167C90C36F5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Remedies for Tribal government employees</header><clause id="H6DAF5EE2CF73475583BA3AC9E62BB954"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header><text>A Tribal government's receipt or use of Federal financial assistance for any program or activity of the Tribal government shall constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity to a suit brought by a covered individual of that program or activity, or a labor organization representing such a covered individual, under this paragraph for equitable, legal, or other relief authorized under this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="H148CD705850B4B888F802F788E2D7F40"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Official capacity</header><text>An official of a Tribal government may be sued in the official capacity of the official by any covered individual or such a labor organization who has complied with the procedures under this paragraph for injunctive relief that is authorized under this paragraph. In such a suit the court may award to the prevailing party those costs authorized by section 722 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">42 U.S.C. 1988</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H62C2371916BF4A8A93E9582E54C7E6FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>With respect to a particular program or activity, clause (i) applies to conduct that occurs—</text><subclause id="H61C22FCFEB574AE9BA931FE0D331BC85"><enum>(I)</enum><text>after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H10E0ADC65F2143B1A54CFBC163AE65CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after the day on which a Tribal government first receives or uses Federal financial assistance for that program or activity.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2D92A1CB90814560B48355B120268839" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definition of program or activity</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>program or activity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 606 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE55C121901C44083A9FF81C9B1EECB3F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enforcement by the government accountability office and library of congress</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, in the case of the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress, the authority of the Secretary under this subsection shall be exercised respectively by the Comptroller General of the United States and the Librarian of Congress, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A183D242D3144FE9048360B540A72F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employees covered by congressional accountability act of 1995</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) to the Board (as defined in section 101 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>)), or any person, alleging a violation of section 202(a)(1) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1312">2 U.S.C. 1312(a)(1)</external-xref>) shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to that Board, or any person, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3 or 6 against a covered individual described in section 2(4)(A)(iii) or described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(6)(A)(i)(III).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3700F805A5D14734AED9016549D957C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, united states code</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code, to the President, the Merit Systems Protection Board, or any person, alleging a violation of section 412(a)(1) of that title, shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to the President, that Board, or any person, respectively, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3 or 6 against a covered individual described in section 2(4)(A)(iv) or described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(6)(A)(i)(IV).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1B17BA5AC60B449AAC3ED388CB95A34A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employees covered by <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, united states code</header><text>The powers, remedies, and procedures provided in title 5, United States Code, to an employing agency, provided in chapter 12 of that title to the Merit Systems Protection Board, or provided in that title to any person, alleging a violation of chapter 63 of that title, shall be the powers, remedies, and procedures this Act provides to that agency, that Board, or any person, respectively, with regard to an allegation of a violation of section 3 or 6 against a covered individual described in section 2(4)(A)(v) or described in section 2(4)(B) with respect to an employer described in section 2(6)(A)(i)(V).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1FC76E950BFA4111AFC15E3135F67023"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HBE8F9DE1726D4214A066729FBB29A40B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which a State attorney general or a State privacy regulator has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of a State has been or is adversely affected by any person who violates any provision of section 3 or 6, including a regulation or order prescribed under this Act, the State attorney general or State privacy regulator, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA952707C4E94421183CDA036E6966A53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin further violation of such provision by the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H13C3F86FE6154AEA9685E7BC3403306D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compel compliance with such provision;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC6221DEC64534658B0B1FEC698803BD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages (including statutory damages described in paragraph (4)), civil penalties, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of the residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H33E6EA4B24754C9DB32DF113CCA75FAF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain reasonable attorney's fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H92A2528D425042CE8CE8BA6799C5E1E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of agency</header><text>Before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the State attorney general or State privacy regulator, as the case may be, shall notify the Secretary in writing of such civil action. Upon receiving such notice, the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H85D3C1D5A29C445AB39A9B3DB93DF2D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intervene in such action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H513FB3C99C9A4EB8BED58C6F29D4CF35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text><clause commented="no" id="HA63CAD99C9024A48B7F3A93F304E9D68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in such civil action; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H7EBDBF77CD374FB5A87B4A8124669D0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in such action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB8C4FD460C404A6492A8CDA341F39147"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preemptive action by agency</header><text>In any case in which a civil action is instituted by or on behalf of the Secretary for violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act, a State attorney general or State privacy regulator may not, during the pendency of such action, institute a civil action against any defendant named in the complaint in the action instituted by or on behalf of the Secretary for a violation that is alleged in such complaint. In a case brought by the Secretary that affects the interests of a State, the State attorney general or State privacy regulator may intervene as of right pursuant to the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95FA5BE4DA5F4976B597709B6948E4BA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Statutory damages</header><text>In a civil action instituted under paragraph (1), a court may award statutory damages under paragraph (1)(C) against a person for a violation of any provision of section 3 or 6—</text><subparagraph id="H65A895E12AA64A1DB78AAEFE41593900" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in an amount not more than $50,000 for each such violation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA71E1BAC21FD40CCAD98C7945217EC65" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of such a violation that results in the discharge of an employee or other serious economic harm to an employee by such a person who has, within the preceding 5 years, committed another such violation resulting in such a discharge or other serious economic harm, not more than $100,000 for each such violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAD3AD86298744AB584DFAE1E39587ACA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Preservation of state powers</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), no provision of this subsection shall be construed as altering, limiting, or affecting the authority of a State attorney general or State privacy regulator to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCFA588DB62554BA59F36338918D20C49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bring an action or other regulatory proceeding arising solely under the laws in effect in that State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD57396A8087B43C6B9972D16F57B23EB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exercise the powers conferred on the State attorney general or State privacy regulator by the laws of the State, including the ability to conduct investigations, administer oaths or affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11E66C96935B4104B192E30A4D84B951"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Arbitration and class action</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no predispute arbitration agreement or predispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable with respect to any alleged violation of section 3 or 6.</text></subsection></section><section id="H929023AFD54C45DA803B015A151C4D2D"><enum>8.</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall coordinate with any appropriate Federal agency or State regulator to promote consistent regulatory treatment of automated decision systems.</text></section><section id="HDEF3ABBFB4894D51ABE683FD21E75160"><enum>9.</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as explicitly provided otherwise in this Act, nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt, modify, limit, or supersede—</text><paragraph id="H02C0175451304960B64D38E082A25301"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any provision of Federal or State law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DB12119F8964B06A6D29AA2C0B5B31C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of the Federal Trade Commission, Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, National Labor Relations Board, or any other Federal agency.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H29D4509530C747FEABB2CBBA00B766DD"><enum>10.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provisions of such to all other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

