<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON25529-KN4-07-SHF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3505 IS: Relief for Survivors of Miners Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3505</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Black Lung Benefits Act to ease the benefits process for survivors of miners whose deaths were due to pneumoconiosis.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Relief for Survivors of Miners Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id84389910F83A476E85A1A0724180C215"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to the benefits process for survivors of miners whose deaths were due to pneumoconiosis</header><subsection id="id90CEF5EB53AD4670B4367F5410920C68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumptions for a death due to pneumoconiosis</header><paragraph id="id9A915EBCCA7A418FB307F7F35EBF8EB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption for a deceased miner employed for not less than 10 years in a coal mine</header><text>Section 411(c)(2) of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/921">30 U.S.C. 921(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the second sentence and inserting <quote>The presumption under this paragraph may be rebutted only by establishing that no part of the death of such miner was caused by pneumoconiosis.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5EA6B243270842F7BABB64C5F277854F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption for a disability due to pneumoconiosis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 411(c) of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/921">30 U.S.C. 921(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="id5D8B099D5CF94CE880D44A02205287F3" act-name=""><paragraph id="id3BF3B6D97EE94E91968CFF9976365F44"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a deceased miner was totally disabled due to pneumoconiosis during the life of such miner and does not meet the requirements for an irrebuttable presumption under paragraph (3), there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the miner's death was due to pneumoconiosis. The presumption under this paragraph may be rebutted only by establishing that no part of the death of such miner was caused by pneumoconiosis.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idE1D84DEB30054534964DBD8ACFA426C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraphs (1) and (2) shall apply with respect to claims that are—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id604e0c48622d427d89fccbb17e4c909e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">filed under part C of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/931">30 U.S.C. 931 et seq.</external-xref>) on or after the date that is 5 years before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd877738a5d6c4a21bfb1c094f7054a34"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7d76ba2c70bc41d6bae7a98ec0f76b69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment regarding the term respirable</header><text>Section 411(c)(2) of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/921">30 U.S.C. 921(c)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2(a)(1), is further amended by striking <quote>respirable</quote> and inserting <quote>respiratory</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e2688d0e0954dcbafe0e1874120a235"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restoring certain pre-1981 provisions regarding total disability due to pneumoconiosis</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc03367aaaebd4a95b7c860ecb1de6a4e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Black Lung Benefits Act is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97b31cb33a7a4a6daf7f8f20da7c0739"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 401(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901(a)</external-xref>)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43101bf71c1543b985897c698ed8ad9b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>this disease;</quote> and inserting <quote>this disease or who were totally disabled by this disease at the time of their deaths;</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided466ad48ca64e41a21e0a4402c54942"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or who were totally disabled by this disease at the time of their deaths</quote> after <quote>such disease</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7f5d6248dfa473187698cdee1c4c09e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 411(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/921">30 U.S.C. 921(a)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>, except</quote> and all that follows through <quote>of 1981,</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id11ED0AE9826147D49AA01558D2561083"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to claims that are—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEDBD5EB3DFF641F4933CF28B342B4945"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">filed under part C of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/931">30 U.S.C. 931 et seq.</external-xref>) on or after the date that is 5 years before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE151C47106E2402489DD938806E8E9D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B0625965F1D49C183CA8E216830DCFC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees and medical expenses payment program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part A of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD728C884ED7A4A65A841A08C00B08C65"><section id="H9798B3B6AB834B2BBBA0F26DC608442C"><enum>403.</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees and medical expenses payment program</header><subsection id="H69BBAC50A60E47879AB5ACFCC253582E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program established</header><paragraph id="H7A4BF2B014F24BAFB7110710132AA57A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Relief for Survivors of Miners Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a payment program to pay attorneys’ fees and other reasonable and unreimbursed medical expenses incurred in establishing the claimant’s case, using amounts from the fund, to the attorneys of claimants in qualifying claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB74B785FE38D4C3EA2C4B4E5A23B7621"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualifying claim for purposes of this section is a contested claim for benefits under this title for which a final order has not been entered within one year of the filing of the claim.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEAF99F6619A49D8891E87393A013853"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of payments from the fund</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts in the fund shall be available for payments authorized by the Secretary under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H241AFECB124C4574B6726F37FED2911C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments authorized</header><paragraph id="H997D83F5115A43EEBE2EAF6D23554839"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees</header><subparagraph id="id7670ABABC5EE4F60B1B8E51C0641E544"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a claimant for benefits under this title obtains a proposed decision and order from a district director with an award of benefits for a qualifying claim, or an award for a qualifying claim before an administrative law judge—</text><clause id="idF0EB23E51770470DA7A8E6A54EEBCA12"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the district director may approve attorneys’ fees for work done before such director in an amount not to exceed $1,500; and</text></clause><clause id="idEAE30FC8675C44048341121EE834D555"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the administrative law judge may approve attorneys’ fees for work done before such judge in an amount not to exceed $3,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAE42D945EA1841F9A9A029AE03924CE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, through the program under this section, pay any amounts approved under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF8D2026A2AA4A46B6B2D20BF7044E85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medical expenses</header><subparagraph id="idC0331C0A092547399EB594BCA52A8AA5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a claimant for benefits under this title obtains a proposed decision and order from a district director with an award of benefits for a qualifying claim, or an award for a qualifying claim before an administrative law judge, such district director and administrative law judge may each approve an award, in an amount not to exceed $1,500, to the claimant’s attorney of reasonable and unreimbursed medical expenses incurred in establishing the claimant’s case.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57674BBDC7FB4C73B2BE57E3BFC204E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, through the program under this section, pay any amounts approved under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24113B35243D4250AEFCE79070C9266D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maximum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, through the program established under this section, shall for any single qualifying claim pay—</text><subparagraph id="idC818F92CC35C471EAC8AAD83F3B8AB0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than a total of $4,500 in attorneys’ fees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04A443094CFC4F53BD9679E628876A9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than $3,000 in medical expenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FF903A7CF784F25878D0A7204B687E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reimbursement of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which a qualifying claim results in a final order awarding compensation, the liable operator shall reimburse the fund for any fees or expenses paid under this section, subject to enforcement by the Secretary under section 424 and in the same manner as compensation orders are enforced under section 21(d) of the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/921">33 U.S.C. 921(d)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C58A28287AC4228A1285C5DF242B990"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional program rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall limit or otherwise affect an operator's liability for any attorneys’ fees or medical expenses awarded by the district director or an administrative law judge that were not paid by the program under this section. Nothing in this section shall limit or otherwise affect the Secretary's authority to use amounts in the fund to pay approved attorneys’ fees in claims for benefits under this title for which a final order awarding compensation has been entered and the operator is unable to pay.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEAA60C37314A45C3A8FF8900EA44B40D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No recoupment of attorneys’ fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any payment for attorneys’ fees or medical expenses made by the Secretary under this section shall not be recouped from the claimant or the claimant’s attorney.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="idA9533D5A6BCB46339D6072D4DE38643A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports by the Government Accountability Office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="id0A53F9BEAF09467BAD3483C8E97904E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out a review of interim benefit payments under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) for miners and survivors who have submitted a claim for benefits under such Act and are waiting for a final determination, including—</text><subparagraph id="id44E0F73D19844A7B9DB0BDC8C0E2E491"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an examination of the financial impact on beneficiaries of such payments in the case the claims of such beneficiaries are denied and the payments are recouped;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2FB08F75C8E449A9EFFF246E1FBA1FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a study of the impact that the stress caused by such recoupment, or the threat of such recoupment, has on beneficiaries of such payments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id614A1C9822284C78814603AC058EF6E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a study of the financial impact on the Federal Government and taxpayers of the process for recouping such interim benefit payments in the case of claims that are denied;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBECBDAE5EECC4A50B1EE756FC9553FDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carry out a review of benefit payments for miners and survivors under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>), including—</text><subparagraph id="idF79CC93EA2D9495C831C863F6A7B1E6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an examination of whether such payments are sufficient to meet the expenses of such miners and survivors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1B0DFE4D8EE4608989B008101962E03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an examination of the economic impact of a possible increase in the amount of benefit payments for such miners and survivors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD5F9070A3F4A4F2FB055BE85F210F426"><enum>(C)</enum><text>based on such examination, recommendations on the amount of benefit payments that such miners and survivors should receive;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8784D5CE5FE843C8B28102D01768B5FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carry out a review that examines the impact of a possible change to regulations of the Secretary of Labor to permit a survivor of a miner to, after a final determination of benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) is made with respect to such survivor, file a subsequent claim for benefits under such Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA51F90BD60144FCCB20373A9F0FE7FEE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submit to Congress reports on the results of the reviews under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

