<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26967-NJV-4R-9MT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4466 IS: Pathways for Advancement, Transition, and Hiring to the Foreign Service</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4466</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide a Foreign Service officer career pathway for former United States Agency for International Development officers.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HFC356B17B1004DF0B42B1F9CD59D3DA0"><section section-type="section-one" id="H7EBEE6A0C2D7433BB63C242C99E91264"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pathways for Advancement, Transition, and Hiring to the Foreign Service</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PATH to the Foreign Service Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H4503023677A94817979006C65456D3CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Foreign Service Officer career pathway for former USAID officers</header><subsection id="H9C9B913C400D42B39CE18DD66A6A90F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>USAID</term> means the United States Agency for International Development.</text></subsection><subsection id="H020EBFC36B534FE092DDC65920650B1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign Service officer career pathway</header><text>Former USAID Foreign Service members who are appointed to positions within the Department of State shall be eligible for appointment into the Foreign Service Officer career track at a grade and tenure status commensurate with their prior Foreign Service rank, time-in-service, and performance, subject to applicable suitability and security requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1BBC4CB0DA3F4BCB8161E441BB0B12FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Foreign Service officer test waiver</header><text>Former USAID Foreign Service members are not required to take the Foreign Service Entrance Exam, including any written or oral elements, as a condition of appointment or conversion or any hiring mechanism to the Foreign Service of the Department of State if such officers previously met Foreign Service entry requirements and served in good standing at USAID.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02CF0318CB6D49BDBA969F9360BE47DA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hiring preference points</header><text>The Department of State shall award hiring preference points or equivalent hiring credit to applicants for Department of State positions who have prior USAID service, whether in the Foreign Service or the Civil Service. Such preference shall be formally incorporated into hiring and selection processes and applied in a transparent and consistent manner.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2D2BAFAAD27D43A8AC89561164ECFA30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recognition of prior service</header><text>Prior USAID service shall be fully credited toward a Foreign Service Officer’s seniority, time-in-class, retirement eligibility, and other applicable career milestones to the maximum extent permitted by law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB394A45F7AC2432F86EC7565E5E04CDF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with appropriate officials of USAID and the Office of Personnel Management, shall issue guidance for the timely implementation of this section to ensure uniform application.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0897B63E57CA4D57B9F99A054F5CD028"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The provisions of this section shall cease to be effective beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

