<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B6F79E5829740119DB649770656FCD6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9334 IH: Workforce for AI Trust Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9334</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 to facilitate the growth of multidisciplinary teams that can advance the development and training of safe and trustworthy artificial intelligence systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H42C3C55676574543B48DD317A48E8171" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6CB622C78E3E4E1BBE79CF7ECAA8351A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce for AI Trust Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFEE935AA4217470A81162890759259E2"><enum>2.</enum><header>NSF artificial intelligence research and education; NIST artificial intelligence governance workforce</header> <subsection id="H08BDF8ACD38E495FBD4869DFF80A1227"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>; enacted as part of title LIV of division E of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>)) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB2D83FC239FC4FAF85CE6EF0DC423073" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H306CFDF1928744FE92562D6DF6FFDE12"><enum>(12)</enum><header>National laboratory</header><text>The term <quote>National Laboratory</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9644D55B5C954CE898151A3FF93E1E63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fellowships</header><text>Subsection (e) of section 5401 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9451">15 U.S.C. 9451</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD67FFEA5E9644776ADDC4992D447DC7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2FAE5E7A58542DBBD66ECBE9A951C0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">faculty</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5959E742CA7443CBAF0BC1C904E942CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H5E7918502C1041ECBEEAD08E3B34DF3A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC7E9374939CE47F9A143A264474B1D1C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interdisciplinary artificial intelligence fellowships</header> <clause id="H9BF2259F11AC4497AFAA2A6644B79202" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation may support graduate and postdoctoral research fellowships for students and postdoctoral researchers from across disciplines, including social science disciplines and the humanities, by making awards through eligible institutions of higher education for research and related activities related to the trustworthy design, development, training, deployment, evaluation, and understanding of artificial intelligence.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA0C90120215F4162959DA09688C0B514"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use of awards</header><text>An institution of higher education that receives an award under clause (i) to support graduate and postdoctoral research fellowships for students and postdoctoral researchers described in such clause shall use such award for any of the following, as the case may be:</text> <subclause id="HCCF3062E8AAE473EA591EE36C203B658"><enum>(I)</enum><text>For graduate fellowships, tuition, education-related fees, and stipends for up to three academic years.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2AC65AEE0F954BC5B03633BE22CB0812"><enum>(II)</enum><text>For postdoctoral fellowships, salaries, benefits, relocation costs, related conference travels, and research expenses for up to three years.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD8D4D6A7575B4E9F8EC8E42DA3D57384"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other expenses as the Director of the National Science Foundation determines appropriate.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1B69E0C4F9A44CECA713113D7EC3AB56" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under clause (i) to support graduate and postdoctoral research fellowships for students and postdoctoral researchers described in such clause, an institution of higher education applying for such an award shall ensure such students and postdoctoral researchers satisfy the following:</text> <subclause id="H6A333CAD75064C6C9DB36A282FE9F4AF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Are citizens, nationals, or lawful permanent residents of the United States.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2F85A77B61EE43DCBEB450B9E3629E5A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Demonstrate a commitment to a career in research into fields and research areas that will contribute to the development and deployment of trustworthy artificial intelligence systems, including in areas of security, safety, reliability, or other aspects of artificial intelligence trustworthiness as established by the National Institute of Standards and Technology pursuant to section 22A of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h-1</external-xref>).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H469F0D59DFE1446994EC1B0D92303227" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>For graduate fellowships, are—</text> 
<item id="H4BA95B1DA65946A1BBFC23104554D1DE" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">full-time students in an eligible program at the institution of higher education, as determined by the Director of the National Science Foundation; or</text></item> <item id="H9458ECB0D92F474E95DDB6CB1302A397" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>students pursuing a degree on a less than full-time basis, but not less than half-time basis, in an eligible program at the institution of higher education, as determined by the Director.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0F80B504332946529A580A514FC3427A" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>For postdoctoral fellowships, have a doctoral degree in an eligible program, as determined by the Director, have received such degree not earlier than five years before the date that such fellowship begins, and have a postdoctoral appointment at a host institution.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD925A0AE698E4F2FBA9DF6D2359DE39A" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An institution of higher education that seeks an award under clause (i) shall submit to the Director of the National Science Foundation an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may require. At a minimum, the Director shall require such an application to include a description of the following:</text> 
<subclause id="HF78E50E188D1431187B1975A4CED4594" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the proposed research and activities are designed to contribute to the development and deployment of trustworthy artificial intelligence systems, including ways to design, train, evaluate, and understand such systems.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3F2AC3D136314D6B8EB6E2CE241052DE" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the students and postdoctoral researchers described in clause (i) who are the subject of such application will be integrated with artificial intelligence researchers at such institution in a role consistent with being a member of an interdisciplinary or transdisciplinary team.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H42D1C49087464BA898CA11E386BB2954" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>How such institution plans to disseminate to the broader artificial intelligence systems research community any research findings, learned best practices, or technical solutions that are the outcome of such an award.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE6AE5E55D85540A9BBC0F000EF5C8878"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Administrative agreements</header><text>Fellowships supported by an award under clause (i) may include temporary artificial intelligence-related positions at Federal or State agencies, National Laboratories, private sector entities, institutions of higher education, the Institute, or other artificial intelligence relevant entities, as determined appropriate by the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD69729BEEC254853AFA89E424202333D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HE785B344999045E9BB34DF2DFF9ADEF3" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD1D02DA340E34719B623933B5865107B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence skills-based training across the National Science Foundation</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall seek to encourage the application of artificial intelligence systems to accelerate scientific discovery and technology development across all fields of STEM supported by the Foundation, including by supporting the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA0E42C0161254928B725A291EE5930B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training for undergraduate and graduate students and postdoctoral researchers through existing technical and skills-based training or certification programs, and, as appropriate, by providing for additional experiential learning experiences.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4BAA745C737A41318C218670E20E8EF8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Development and hosting of intra or inter-institutional workshops on the application of trustworthy artificial intelligence systems to new uses in research, development, demonstration, testing, dissemination, and evaluation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H57986368CA6B44B2B3FD5A1D3B4250F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Administrative and award supplements to existing research awards to support professional development experiences for graduate students and postdoctoral researchers who receive a substantial portion of the support of such students and researchers in connection with such research awards to learn how to apply artificial intelligence systems to the research of such students and researchers, as determined by the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE303323696394625AA6E653E773049F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Workshops</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 5401 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9451">15 U.S.C. 9451</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H52F347E287D84A92AA2D2716F0D4C91C" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HBD081525DBFA4F90BB1BB989AB06EA43" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Workshops</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation may make awards for the development and hosting of intra- or inter-institutional workshops to facilitate the growth of multidisciplinary teams that can advance the development and training of trustworthy artificial intelligence systems.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9DE297F6689C4B3B890853B6F6B7413E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Peer review panels</header><text>Section 5401 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9451">15 U.S.C. 9451</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8FAD73532A9D421A8191A8E2244443B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF849919DFC074D7299A644B7A85FA866"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF0BE1E059310485CAA328EE91CF80086" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H54577457345B49859AD933E485C22FD8" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Peer review panels</header><text>As practicable and appropriate, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall ensure any merit review panel convened to evaluate a proposal related to artificial intelligence systems research and related activities integrates perspectives from multiple and diverse research disciplines, including researchers from social science, technology ethics, normative ethics, legal, and linguistic disciplines.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HC300605251FC4B588782F75EFB036986"><enum>3.</enum><header>NIST activities to describe and support the artificial intelligence workforce</header> <subsection id="H5C54785C6B33411084C051F015420035"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorities to support workforce frameworks</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 2 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/272">15 U.S.C. 272</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0F3EE173D3204E659857E722F6DA1219"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD157E9381B454EE79AC0E022523426D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7388A8C41E4447F4BB210F893EA7F9BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HAD86DB7B9F804DB79ABB1654D532526B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC8EE01D903D24D1689387107B40BD017"><enum>(14)</enum><text>to provide industry, government, and research, nonprofit, and educational institutions with workforce frameworks for critical and emerging technologies and other science, technology, engineering, and mathematics domains for the purpose of bolstering scientific and technical education, training, and workforce development.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD51A18D47F5949B7908164EB38C71344"><enum>(b)</enum><header>NIST activities to support the artificial intelligence governance workforce</header><text>Section 22A of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H517AF08C900B4D0C8E2E0D6270347FFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9B7B1A9DAA974749A7E72006FDC33284"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (5) as paragraphs (4) through (6), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90BBE17E3C68491AB2BE7B9A95D7E752"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB0A9B9ECCA1646DFB1D71CDBF746C8CC" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HD5BD09220DAB45EB95610A67DBE932A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support education and workforce development activities to expand the artificial intelligence workforce, including careers related to helping organizations govern, map, measure, and manage artificial intelligence related risk, including testing, evaluation, verification, and validation of artificial intelligence;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA97428D9819A4726BF0F830245E00FDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H9450E08B6D394402B4248CDA269AAC5A" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H00BA70EF8A4A430AB6CD24647599A006"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB2053F2621F249669B332D323B685FA2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence workforce framework</header> <paragraph id="H56CBE8AB908C421B8F02D9161F2DAF95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title LIII of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9441">15 U.S.C. 9441 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD7A40B7AE91A4CD4BFAC5387F4511667" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H82AA9B7FE6374ACBA829B0ECD08A9ED8"><enum>5304.</enum><header>NIST activities to categorize the artificial intelligence workforce</header> 
<subsection id="H1097376A0F1B40CAAA349891C41A7480"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall develop fundamental reference resources for describing and sharing information regarding work related to artificial intelligence to address workforce gaps.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H746C2ED9D5B2489F8F1BB3A3220A0DAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header> <paragraph id="H3AC82737C1BA46C0BF9654BDF92EB982"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall carry out the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3C87AB36C09145C38C92ED36A6F5C898"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop and periodically update an artificial intelligence workforce framework, which shall include the following components:</text> <clause id="H7DDA96A56C5C4A46A35C05D1C4A5E021"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A common, consistent lexicon to describe artificial intelligence employment-related activities by work role, competency area, or other categorization, as appropriate.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H63228BAE1F9A46C786E8DFE33C4129A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the tasks, knowledge, or skills that are needed to perform artificial intelligence work.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0543939B3CB45FEA4D88938945DD781" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Support interoperability and avoid unnecessary duplication of the such components of such framework with components in other workforce frameworks, including the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education Cybersecurity Workforce Framework or successor framework.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFDC07860E9A4FFC85CE1A4073ED3EDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Develop guidelines regarding how to use the artificial intelligence workforce framework under subparagraph (A) for different aspects of workforce development, education, and training purposes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE3D06CD6E3641448F66DD5AAFE4107E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Support external use of such framework, including relating to the following:</text> 
<clause id="H1F96F29B8E0446D7A3BC1E9C586A90E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The development of technical guidelines and best practices related to the artificial intelligence workforce, or dissemination of existing related guidelines, as appropriate.</text></clause> <clause id="HB23A38D8E6584EE6953FBCA3621F88C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Outreach and dissemination to artificial intelligence programs at all education levels of such framework to prepare and improve a skilled artificial intelligence workforce for the public and private sectors.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76D75A9C3FFC4141B3826B8DDA61A2CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stakeholder input</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall seek input from the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H9179843C1FB347C8A06E7E8E3963FAA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal departments and agencies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DC8744195F449AC90A8331B248A13ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DE83A4A71A94B4F88BC06E9EF686DA4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Industry.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H63EFBCFE989C4E98B25905839762D3BF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H221EA517388B4EDC91BC4DB85276D97E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>National Laboratories.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F068E3E6D434D6FB25D8979AEDBBB7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Labor organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE28966EA2F7B4C60B1CC53463A44046D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Non-profit organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H31782108BDF64DD7A0A60485C1ED96CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supporting efforts to identify and address Federal artificial intelligence workforce gaps</header><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall use the artificial intelligence workforce framework under subsection (b)(1)(A) to provide technical assistance to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7E9896E50DFA408D9AD0796007B82004"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation, in developing criteria to designate qualified institutions of higher education for the Federal AI Scholarship-for-Service Program under section 10313(d) of the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18993">42 U.S.C. 18993(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H584EB5BE4BE94639AD99400F4674A209"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management, to align the appropriate roles, knowledge, skills, abilities, and tasks specified in such framework with the activities described in section 105 of the AI in Government Act (title I of division U of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC4CA0C0F1BC643EAB847BE1344FEEAAC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than one year after the development of the artificial intelligence workforce framework under subsection (b)(1)(A), the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate such framework and make such framework publicly available on the website of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E3006FF56C04630A7C22CE6FD9E1763"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H05F6ACFE9B4548A2BFD334BCF663D779"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence system</header><text>The term <quote>artificial intelligence system</quote> means any data system, software, hardware, application, tool, service, or utility that operates in whole or in part using artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B16A840122B48C691331CDF3CCD32BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <quote>labor organization</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2(5) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152(5)</external-xref>), except that such term shall also include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H758E16E1D19344B588D29C28A3155EEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any organization composed of labor organizations, such as a labor union federation or a State or municipal labor body.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A94CEF0065F45D59C21FDFA81AF7BB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any organization which would be included in the definition for such term under such section, but for the fact that the organization represents individuals—</text> <clause id="HB350EA48626241F39ECDA10129C231F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employed by the United States, any wholly owned Government corporation, any Federal Reserve Bank, or any State or political subdivision thereof;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3703C89CE28C4A34848DAD3712ED40F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>employed by persons subject to the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></clause> <clause id="H42E4437C54D04EF183B9F47D1B43AD24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employed as agricultural laborers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD869281E10B74C51B0F9498548364D35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-profit organization</header><text>The term <quote>non-profit organization</quote> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7B4CB3F444E4EDBA2191FA1C9813448"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical standard</header><text>The term <quote>technical standard</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 12(d)(5) of the National Technology Transfer and Advancement Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/272">15 U.S.C. 272</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6832A2081E504BFA85FD3810DDA4F10F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Workforce framework</header><text>The term <quote>workforce framework</quote> means a common taxonomy and lexicon for any given domain that includes the building blocks of tasks, knowledge, or skills that can be structured to form work roles or competency areas.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93731CBB640B470CBE19E945E69D2332"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The tables of contents in section 2(b) and title LIII of division E of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 are amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5303 the following new item: <quote>Sec. 5304. NIST activities to categorize the artificial intelligence workforce.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

