<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2CA2C0643ED340628557E5A012BEA024" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7492 IH: Michigan-Canada Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7492</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Federal interference with the opening and operation of the Gordie Howe International Bridge.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H98D58AADF8F74D1DBD4BF1F913592F24" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2B4F598B66474BBCA85639EDF004A716" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Michigan-Canada Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H24F82CE9CB404F3AB84576F6BEE67C50" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1E39AC4063884700BD9693F48E98672F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Gordie Howe International Bridge will be a critical piece of United States transportation, trade, and national security infrastructure connecting Detroit, Michigan, and Windsor, Ontario, and linking the economies of the United States and Canada.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A61A61F562F4E85B89AD130BAF1DFF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Detroit-Windsor crossing is the busiest commercial land border crossing in North America, facilitating the movement of passenger vehicles, freight, and supply chains essential to manufacturing, agriculture, and energy production in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90C21E3E4D13472EAF30AF97CD110813"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Trade between the United States and Canada supports hundreds of billions of dollars in annual economic activity, including a substantial share of U.S. automotive, advanced manufacturing, and agricultural trade that flows through Michigan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11C6CC04DE174FE09BCBD84D901DF20E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Michigan and Canada are longstanding economic partners, particularly in the automotive sector, where integrated supply chains depend on reliable, secure, and efficient cross-border infrastructure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4067127D4A7A44BD8A69721192C99953"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2012, the State of Michigan and the Government of Canada entered into a bilateral agreement to advance construction of the Gordie Howe International Bridge, under which Michigan and Canada share ownership, with Canada financing construction without direct cost to Michigan taxpayers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06D03BF475BC45FAB783FA73FC5F9B38"><enum>(6)</enum><text>That agreement was executed under Republican Governor Rick Snyder and with the cooperation of Democratic President Barack Obama, reflecting bipartisan recognition of the crossing’s importance to American workers, manufacturers, and national competitiveness.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9856FD11FC5049C3A518108C67D67C6C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Construction of the Gordie Howe International Bridge began in 2018 and has proceeded pursuant to valid Federal approvals, permits, and authorizations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F1BDE0610294ED19AA49E74E1B9B274"><enum>(8)</enum><text>During his first term, President Donald Trump publicly acknowledged the importance of the Gordie Howe International Bridge through a joint statement with Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau that said they <quote>look forward to the expeditious completion of the Gordie Howe International Bridge, which will serve as a vital economic link between our two countries.</quote></text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22F4A8FC43174311845082C5F1D24755"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Gordie Howe International Bridge will enhance resiliency and increase capacity at the northern border by complementing existing crossings, improving freight reliability, and reducing congestion and economic risk associated with reliance on a single crossing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82A8014E9029420FBAD320802D9B96B3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Any unilateral Federal action to interfere with the opening or operation of the Gordie Howe International Bridge would harm American workers, manufacturers, farmers, and consumers, disrupt integrated North American supply chains, and undermine the longstanding partnership between Michigan and Canada.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06F1DC8C52F0427A8911602A801C9BCD"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Congress has an interest in ensuring that the Gordie Howe International Bridge is opened and operated in a timely manner consistent with existing agreements, valid permits, and the national economic and security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB848CDCBD2914A83BF2F5D1F7F2298D0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <subsection id="HCD68E3D7865A4809BACC23BCC1972129"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Prohibition on interference with the gordie howe international bridge</header> <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal officials, including the President, shall by any means impede the opening of or attempt the closure of the Gordie Howe International Bridge and its associated port of entry unless approved by an Act of Congress or requested by the Governor of Michigan.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H088E5811896B4EC9A2A5C76F67ADAB89">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Affirmative duty To facilitate operation</header>
 <text>Federal agencies with jurisdiction over the Gordie Howe International Bridge or its associated port of entry shall take all actions necessary to ensure the timely opening and continuous operation of the bridge and port of entry.</text>
        <paragraph id="HF5CF2BC8683C4B4C9ECD7ED4B2D2A9D1">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Continuous operation</header>
 <text>For purposes of this subsection, <quote>continuous operation</quote> means in accordance with the staffing and operational models required by relevant Federal agencies, including the U.S. Customs and Border Protection Workforce Staffing Model.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H65BABEFB01354E09AB315EE7745FE87C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibited delay tactics</header><text>No Federal official may impede, delay, condition, or otherwise interfere with the bridge or port of entry through action or inaction, including by failing to take timely and necessary steps to carry out Federal responsibilities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H61E8EF2B58864C4DB9CC9C173C788FB4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>The State of Michigan or any affected local government may bring an action in a United States District Court to compel compliance with this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

