<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H84C1A57E5D0B4F239E4BE30E144346A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7130 IH: McCarran-Ferguson Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7130</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260116">January 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To eliminate the Federal Insurance Office of the Department of the Treasury and to establish a United States Insurance Representative within the Department of the Treasury, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6CE89B1BBCB24E3CBF7F3D9872F90A1A" style="OLC"><section id="H6CEDDF633F8F4238A9EE77E30CA6DDC3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>McCarran-Ferguson Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HCD18EED3CE274318B89238C12839D4D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of Federal Insurance Office</header><subsection id="HF9ACBCE2E71F4BA1876BE4B53D0D8E0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Insurance Office of the Department of the Treasury, and the position of the Director of the Federal Insurance Office, are hereby eliminated.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4B2F289F842848FCBA99BAE97AFBC7A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treasury authority</header><text>This section may not be construed to repeal or otherwise limit any authority of the Secretary of the Treasury with respect matters relating to insurance.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA277FC7B77E34ABDB328DC1423DB3338"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of United States Insurance Representative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9BDEC5F8BE7A44D2A294409F3C92A67B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the table of sections for subchapter I of chapter 3, by striking <quote>Federal Insurance Office</quote> and inserting <quote>United States Insurance Representative</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D260531E3E6472B85F83C2B9981F01C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending section 313 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H3674FE75A5FB4C8CB4AE285894432C0D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H2AAA64C36726418284183582C31E8409"><enum>313.</enum><header>United States Insurance Representative</header><subsection id="H37A3F4DF8CCB4ED2BCBBD6166F640E7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, for the purpose of carrying out this section—</text><paragraph id="H55DB37CA90D54D09B9DBBE8DF5E34A8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appoint an United States Insurance Representative; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H152164A38FEE471185090C23489BC12B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hire and retain individuals with expertise in matters related to insurance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD55F7D55CD15439580284A2C72468CD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The United States Insurance Representative shall—</text><paragraph id="H026962AE3E784004B284CEAC99EA79FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate Federal efforts and develop Federal policy on prudential aspects of international insurance matters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01C9D1664CAF44E1952F2AF6A96A3EC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">represent the United States Department of the Treasury, as appropriate, in the International Association of Insurance Supervisors (or a successor entity);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F1B150548E44BFB94ADB6DD2C463DF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assist the Secretary in negotiating covered agreements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD2B82A50AA64090BC699FEBB9C86F5B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether State insurance measures are preempted by covered agreements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12C7D3BC2D09446E87BE4192E6786D32"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist the Secretary in administering the Terrorism Insurance Program established in the Department of the Treasury under the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6701">15 U.S.C. 6701</external-xref> note);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H092FF71231FF42A2B93EC4BCEE08C0A5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the States (including State insurance regulators) with respect to insurance matters of national importance and prudential insurance matters of international importance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAA1F625D9714DABAD234172FD1E444D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the Secretary on prudential international insurance policy issues.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H533F509E1C294806B9855196D8C3BAAD" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the United States Insurance Representative shall extend to prudential aspects of all lines of insurance offered in the United States, except—</text><paragraph id="H94B2249E10234BD999093768F1CC121B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">health insurance, as determined by the Secretary in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services based on section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6791410707794CBCB554E9C609414026"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">long-term care insurance, except long-term care insurance that is included with life or annuity insurance components, as determined by the Secretary in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and in the case of long-term care insurance that is included with such components, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services in performing the functions under this paragraph; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB35D21BC3C4A4848A2A559FECAA09B11"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">crop insurance, as established by the Federal Crop Insurance Act (7 U.S.C. 1501 et seq).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C7EB9CD0CDF467C801DDAD6579AC51F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preemption of State Insurance Measures</header><paragraph id="H048B715A179542369CD004995B4441E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State insurance measure shall be preempted pursuant to this paragraph or section 314 if, and only to the extent that the United States Insurance Representative determines, in accordance with this paragraph, that the measure—</text><subparagraph id="HCF4D8752B3ED4B34BCEE08A1152D2532"><enum>(A)</enum><text>results in less favorable treatment of a non-United States insurer domiciled in a foreign jurisdiction that is subject to a covered agreement than a United States insurer domiciled, licensed, or otherwise admitted in that State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A7EE1B57574C51804DA98C86EE68C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is inconsistent with a covered agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H806C69B148A34BC58934AE9BD73D259F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><subparagraph id="H3CC37511F89147D389235B11869EB133"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice of potential inconsistency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before making any determination under paragraph (1), the United States Insurance Representative shall—</text><clause id="H0AD6E0913E6942098A0A8E5B539863DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notify and consult with the appropriate State regarding any potential inconsistency or preemption;</text></clause><clause id="H15E78323CE81432D8DED62FE688AA93D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify and consult with the United States Trade Representative regarding any potential inconsistency or preemption;</text></clause><clause id="H6A3CC532AA574FC4B30C9C3681633390"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>publish in the Federal Register a notice of the potential inconsistency or preemption, including a description of each State insurance measure at issue and any applicable covered agreement;</text></clause><clause id="HE1BB58B6087C49A4AC17E3FF4DD5C88D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide interested parties a reasonable opportunity to submit written comments to the United States Insurance Representative; and</text></clause><clause id="HF96C71B3D1854D858956519662BD5C7F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>consider any comments received.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93EC572BCA814B1E89422107E9D777E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, any determination of the United States Insurance Representative regarding State insurance measures, and any preemption under clause (i) as a result of such determination, shall be limited to the subject matter contained within the covered agreement involved and shall achieve a level of protection for insurance or reinsurance consumers that is substantially equivalent to the level of protection achieved under State insurance or reinsurance regulation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38BEC41DA955414AB80DC495159D63FF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice of determination of inconsistency</header><text>Upon making any determination under paragraph (1), the United States Insurance Representative shall—</text><clause id="HF1426C7E809B43238908134647BEB9B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notify the appropriate State of the determination and the extent of the inconsistency;</text></clause><clause id="HDBF5B08DC1ED4EE7A29D974376CEEB58" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish a reasonable period of time, which shall not be less than 30 days, before the determination shall become effective; and</text></clause><clause id="HAD53FE38FE97480F9F22BFB04B05979C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>notify the Committees on Financial Services and Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Finance of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF73DC25E5BF24319898A58AE475BAC62"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of effectiveness</header><text>Upon the conclusion of the period referred to in paragraph (2)(C)(ii), if the basis for such determination still exists, the determination shall become effective and the United States Insurance Representative shall—</text><subparagraph id="H91EA2817AD904CEBB53607EB57510275"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish a notice in the Federal Register that the preemption has become effective, as well as the effective date; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE917C3289124CE386E65CAED647857E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the appropriate State of the preemption of the State measure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70876D2929444BF78776632029C83DAA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No State may enforce a State insurance measure that has been preempted under this subparagraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA932E89FD87B463E89520252C409223F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability of Administrative Procedures Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determinations of under subsection (d) shall be subject to the applicable provisions of subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (relating to administrative procedure), and chapter 7 of such title (relating to judicial review), except that in any action for judicial review of a determination of inconsistency, the court shall determine the matter de novo.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB15C675BC33540EEA5E1BAAB5032334E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations, policies, and procedures</header><text>The Secretary may issue orders, regulations, policies, and procedures to implement this paragraph.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEC84B374DCAF446897D97F32E50A4D7F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The United States Insurance Representative shall consult with State insurance regulators, individually or collectively, to the extent the United States Insurance Representative determines appropriate, in carrying out this paragraph.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8374004B0F454945BF61321E78A3C518"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph or section 314 shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H6FA0794E18E449CAB21DF955FD108DBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">alter, amend, or limit any provision of the Consumer Financial Protection Agency Act of 2010;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE166D38456334041ACC878B7CBBA7020"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect the preemption of any State insurance measure otherwise inconsistent with and preempted by Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC945942C1F054A6190B8FAF0BF014F55" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>preempt—</text><subparagraph id="H6AD5AA3928574D89BD34CDAF4CB36334" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any State insurance measure that governs any insurer’s rates, premiums, underwriting, or sales practices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD849393CE6704967A367104EECF7E61F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any State coverage requirements for insurance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53A749C607EB4FC99B7B68579763A264" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the application of the antitrust laws of any State to the business of insurance; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0F0ECAFF9B94B62913F0305970EC4DC" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any State insurance measure governing the capital or solvency of an insurer, except to the extent that such State insurance measure results in less favorable treatment of a non-United States insurer than a United States insurer;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8F7BAAB91D748E49F9A9AE938F58D12"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide the United States Insurance Representative or the Department of the Treasury with general supervisory or regulatory authority over the business of insurance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97BBD7B425994CE280E09385FA44B201"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit the authority of any Federal financial regulatory agency, including the authority to develop and coordinate policy, negotiate, and enter into agreements with foreign governments, authorities, regulators, and multinational regulatory committees and to preempt State measures to affect uniformity with international regulatory agreements; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19D5E2CDD531489FB9B50FE9B8A01839"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect the authority of the Office of the United States Trade Representative pursuant to section 141 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2171">19 U.S.C. 2171</external-xref>) or any other provision of law, including authority over the development and coordination of United States international trade policy and the administration of the United States trade agreements program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D84359ABACF4DFCACD3F4B3DE7981D3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><paragraph id="HE750B5C49EB54CEDA3C3DBA3B9D8BDB5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preemption reports</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, and annually thereafter, the United States Insurance Representative shall submit a report to the President and to the Committees on Financial Services and Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Finance of the Senate on any actions taken during the preceding 1-year period by the Representative pursuant to subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CB27002F4624BD7B4F15001BBE5ACE0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>International insurance reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the United States Insurance Representative shall conduct a study and submit a report to the Congress that describes—</text><subparagraph id="H7A5662D7238F40E6846911EBEF842A01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any international coordination of insurance regulation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB0FDE4CE87E40448DEBF9C4A2B3BF75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the international competitiveness of United States insurers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30570F1EFE3E44D883EBEA8984D3322D" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Use of Existing Resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this paragraph, the United States Insurance Representative may use personnel, facilities, and any other resource of the Department of the Treasury that are available to the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBB9A6791FCB541B7888E2FBCEC387019"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph and section 314, the following definitions shall apply:</text><paragraph id="H81D21C2F139144CFABFED4DA16B27722"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered agreement</header><text>The term <term>covered agreement</term> means a written bilateral or multilateral agreement regarding prudential measures with respect to the business of insurance or reinsurance that—</text><subparagraph id="H7EA4B6557994490FB454ADFCB1F5C28A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is entered into between the United States and one or more foreign governments, authorities, or regulatory entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FB0BFDDDCA24D89B626756C2BD692BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relates to the recognition of prudential measures with respect to the business of insurance or reinsurance that achieves a level of protection for insurance or reinsurance consumers that is substantially equivalent to the level of protection achieved under State insurance or reinsurance regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H590366DD71404924B808DE1FDA041D8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insurer</header><text>The term <term>insurer</term> means any person engaged in the business of insurance, including reinsurance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H745EE914AAAF411DA73AAF34E615232B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal financial regulatory agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal financial regulatory agency</term> means the Department of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, or the National Credit Union Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A2D5576350F43F6AAD6248BB2EBADEB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-united states insurer</header><text>The term <term>non-United States insurer</term> means an insurer that is organized under the laws of a jurisdiction other than a State, but does not include any United States branch of such an insurer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DAFF34E770D43D7BA58D1EB6CDD6DA8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State insurance measure</header><text>The term <term>State insurance measure</term> means any State law, regulation, administrative ruling, bulletin, guideline, or practice relating to or affecting prudential measures applicable to insurance or reinsurance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65083F1FCFF842FD8DB4F3BC291300E6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State insurance regulator</header><text>The term <term>State insurance regulator</term> means any State regulatory authority responsible for the supervision of insurers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H522082783C764B029B281AFBABA59623"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Substantially equivalent to the level of protection achieved</header><text>The term <term>substantially equivalent to the level of protection achieved</term> means the prudential measures of a foreign government, authority, or regulatory entity achieve a similar outcome in consumer protection as the outcome achieved under State insurance or reinsurance regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66BED54CF490410A974CB1018A318108"><enum>(8)</enum><header>United states insurer</header><text>The term <term>United States insurer</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H3C5AAAAC20704D78B534931D71E9C495"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an insurer that is organized under the laws of a State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9027E8C95A1A474D9EF87EF015688658"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a United States branch of a non-United States insurer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H20B6126A9B6B478F97E48D750EE0EDE2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Related amendments to elimination of Federal Insurance Office</header><subsection id="H213198AD3C724FF1A7A599B39BEED6B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H45ABEA90F3DA49689A8CC1DD44422A8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 165(i) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5365">12 U.S.C. 5365(i)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H0D9FEE4597BE42ACA0FDF620FAFE8036"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>and the Federal Insurance Office</quote> and inserting <quote>and the Secretary of the Treasury</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F5239F8B75F4C9482360EA9917FF036"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(C), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>and the Federal Insurance Office</quote> and inserting <quote>and the Secretary of the Treasury</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA10D91259FB942C0992CAD3D19C1B4C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 203(a)(1)(C) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5383">12 U.S.C. 5383(a)(1)(C)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Director of the Federal Insurance Office</quote> in each place it appears and inserting <quote>United States Insurance Representative</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC36E371A10E4E318F2967591B8A33A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 211(a) of the Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/313">31 U.S.C. 313</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HABA9EEB25249436A84FD86CF9C83932D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the Secretary of the Treasury, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and Director of the Federal Insurance Office</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>the Secretary of the Treasury and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H390B2037F1FA4A178EFF080C8C0E1BDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the Secretary of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Director of the Federal Insurance Office</quote> each place that term occurs and inserting the following: <quote>the Secretary of the Treasury and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H36352A61509D4B908AD1D9243F8D2D34"><enum>5.</enum><header>Financial Stability Oversight Council membership</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE4FD05392134434CA6FC1BAF91D7BE8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 111 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5321">12 U.S.C. 5321</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H962DE230962F4C11AE2D0C8B1A8376D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H29C33FC3C0D94991917B9B5E935B52AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="H03B85A0D420448FDA7FCC27C2AF7D428"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEF78EA9E2DC54497BD74501DEEC7381C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H98F43FA328454F948DD470C22FBBA558"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H50CEFF663CD34A44BAF43B88A8A85725" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HF2E47EBBDA2E488A846CC7A5225A9DA2"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State insurance commissioner appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, as described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="H9A09D526F584424C93422B49CB1F730A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subclause id="HF48292A4269941FE839A5170586FB838"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H658941AD4B6341BF828746EE90221211" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD3C0B546CAD941598D36E6415453E7DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Insurance Representative;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="H0346479EB9CC4C18832DED2C65DAAD37"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDFDC8E8C3EEC4EB7B50092D9224FAF03"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D) and (E) as subparagraphs (C) and (D), respectively; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H29F850583CE04E61B4B9052436243E8E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1B6155030D6D4304B0C62E4CFA49C785" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H1D56083C3CFB4373B4A8D073AC10019E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appointment of State insurance commissioner</header><subparagraph id="H19F71C543C4B4EC7B77F53FA0390033B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before making any appointments pursuant to paragraph (1)(K), the President shall request a list of recommended candidates from the States through the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, which shall not be binding on the President.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10570CE0ABBF40F5B41708EDDE2339AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure of list submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the National Association of Insurance Commissioners fails to submit a list of recommendations not later than 15 business days after the date of the request, the President may make the requisite appointment without considering the views of the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFA12BC55DE3407D94025E293E4B9B44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="HC7F1CD8215F74097B85986945E003C67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="H4EC87B8A89A443C6A8A3F593E1964778"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, the State insurance commissioner shall serve a term of 4 years</quote> after <quote>6 years</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5D271BB1186143FCA2B6750917530046"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(C), (D), and (E)</quote> and inserting <quote>(C) and (D)</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEB3CC1C893B84F70B449474BC18B98A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H97E7D54FB92B4D1F8CEE84F72233ECAE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE1AF7CB047EF4C23B35F36B9E8FBD4EF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Acting State insurance commissioner may serve</header><subparagraph id="HEDD08E5B6B2A4CDFB1593C4D5D4C4DFF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3345 of title 5, United States Code, in the event of a vacancy of the State insurance commissioner of the Council or during the absence or disability of the State insurance commissioner of the Council, an acting State insurance commissioner of the Council shall serve as a nonvoting member of the Council until a successor is appointed and confirmed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBD3450A13574040A3BB25D97ED7267E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection of acting State insurance commissioner</header><text>The acting State insurance commissioner described in subparagraph (A) shall be selected through process determined by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD149D2CBB5BA46DFAE3E69EAABD72CFE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Term of State insurance commissioner</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if a successor to the State insurance commissioner of the Council is not appointed and confirmed by the end of the term of service of the commissioner, such member may continue to serve until the earlier of—</text><subparagraph id="HB9CFCFEF95D94C288B657D43B92703FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>18 months after the date on which the term of service ends; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A4ABBB833FF46AAAA500763D9B4FE09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which a successor to the commissioner is appointed and confirmed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFC72A46845B4F8AAA8CBD2FA078AC4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 112 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5322">12 U.S.C. 5322</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H0A839E7EB0F145379D34F5F86025EF52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(A), by striking <quote>member agencies, other Federal and State financial regulatory agencies, the Federal Insurance Office</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>member agencies and other Federal and State financial regulatory agencies</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H716EE0223D4546039DF9BD84696C887C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><clause id="H8A23E070056446EE8D75DC148C1AD64C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>the Office of Financial Research, member agencies, and the Federal Insurance Office</quote> and inserting <quote>the Office of Financial Research and member agencies</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H25B641524CF843279B13528BCCC7A803"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>, any member agency, and the Federal Insurance Office,</quote> and inserting <quote>and any member agency</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

