<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1002A11F61704866A082132F8E592DBB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6823 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a pilot program to facilitate the development of certain traumatic brain injury diagnostics for members of the Armed Forces.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6823</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a pilot program to facilitate the development of certain traumatic brain injury diagnostics for members of the Armed Forces.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H31F5C6E7604842589FA21715138EC881" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3ABB16D041034F679A2029114BA5C68A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Pilot program to facilitate development of certain traumatic brain injury diagnostics for members of the Armed Forces</header> 
<subsection id="H80DC822ECA8D465081B7842D10245FC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs, shall establish a pilot program to—</text> <paragraph id="HFA3D42A2F217477FAC0873BC970B1B1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the feasibility of providing support to eligible entities engaged in the research, development, test, evaluation, or production of covered diagnostic technologies that may be procured by the Secretary and used in the diagnosis of traumatic brain injuries among members of the Armed Forces in connection with operational deployments, including in combat zones;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07E7AE6037DD4BE2BB03F3F50FCBF0D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess covered diagnostic technologies to determine—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B32EC400ACE45868D3344BABBD45A22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether such technologies are capable of distinguishing mild traumatic brain injury from moderate or severe traumatic brain injury;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F0C5867F47849D992059550A5079248"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how such technologies may be used with other diagnostics or diagnostic aids for traumatic brain injury (including neuroimaging biomarkers used in computed tomography, magnetic resonance imaging or molecular imaging, blood-based biomarkers, electrophysiological biomarkers, oculomotor tracking systems, and environmental sensors);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB15505D81C6A4D31A681E52BB5970188"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how such technologies may be integrated with the detection of other indicators of physiological deficit, to enhance the health, survival, and long-term prognosis of members of the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9429B03FCD24476DBD7401088921E268"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such technologies may improve military readiness through the improved brain health of members of the Armed Forces; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97A77593F9164EF3B8DAE5AE3C11DA26"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which such technologies may address concerns regarding the growing medical burden of traumatic brain injury by more accurately assessing and quantifying acute exposure; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF050AAC7B9704015BDFA2E56380DE554"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the research, development, test, evaluation, and production of safe and effective covered diagnostic technologies, including by facilitating the research and development of new or updated manufacturing processes for such technologies and the transitioning of such technologies from the prototyping phase to the production phase.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H86E0E6CBCED648389E8FF551465B0804"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pilot program established under subsection (a) shall be known as the <quote>Warfighter Traumatic Brain Injury Diagnostics Project</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>pilot program</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7C298A9EC104C34B3AFF1D646E20F89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The pilot program shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HDD7F72E653F94504AD8C9A5A8BA40F4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conduct of research studies to make the assessments specified in subsection (a), including studies conducted by, or in consultation with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H21CF1270350645ECAFEBF8C546C7D3DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trauma, primary care, and traumatic brain injury experts of the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50BB6A0175BC46399B5DA913A5D85E57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emergency medical technicians of the Department;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDEB0C0A097814E73B0B7A1EB88E862A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>members of the Armed Forces diagnosed with traumatic brain injuries; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E104957A3D14D55816F90038C8509AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>personnel of the Department who are experts in the covered diagnostic technologies assessed under such studies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H386864D159E340CDAD39AC45E014106D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such activities as the Secretary determines may be necessary to incentivize participation in such studies by military medical treatment facilities, units of the United States Special Operations Command, civilian level one trauma centers, and such other entities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H51E0475E25FA40099B6FBA038471CC77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants</header> <paragraph id="HE8601D4146C549AF8E6E5CB81A6028DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Award of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary of Defense may award a grant to an eligible entity engaged in the research, development, test, evaluation, or production of covered diagnostics, consistent with subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC794A12FDF8435AA096F5A91F944E06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority of awards</header><text>In awarding grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give preference to an eligible entity that the Secretary determines meets one or more of the following criteria:</text> <subparagraph id="H07BBDA4054E94875B7A90BC964A552CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The eligible entity has a demonstrated history of researching, developing, testing, evaluating, or producing a covered diagnostic technology.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3FDEEB030704C3882AD23E6A6C71E61"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity has a demonstrated history of researching, developing, testing, evaluating, or producing a covered diagnostic technology or other related capability in the national technology and industrial base (as such term is defined in section 4801 of title 10, United States Code).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H574B3FD2AE904AE892F963C9D15C0747"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The covered diagnostic technology researched, developed, tested, evaluated, or produced by such eligible entity provides modularity to support diverse applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A959D56637F4250BE8E2426D86A3121"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity awarded a grant under paragraph (1) may only use such grant amounts to carry out one or more of the following activities:</text> <subparagraph id="HA3FFFC919316456ABD1A43C4728F0425"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting research, development, testing, or evaluation activities to validate a covered diagnostic technology (including through experimentation, prototyping, or adapting such technology), to determine or improve the potential operational use to the Department of Defense of such technology, or to integrate such technology with other technologies and systems, including with respect to new or existing pathways of care.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6391FFA306764A758D9B752170A2C99F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Addressing manufacturing or other production challenges relating to a covered diagnostic technology.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B54B596BD95473EAA29AB2691991634"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing commercially available covered diagnostic technologies to any Secretary of a military department, or commander of a combatant command, to support use assessments or other testing by members of the Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAB8283CB784457BBADEDAB103831562"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Building or strengthening relationships with nontraditional defense contractors in the technology industry that may be capable of providing unused or underused solutions to specific operational challenges of the Department relating to traumatic brain injury diagnostics technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H49794A0A1ED646E6B60D9C5A655AFD7D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (g), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the results of the pilot program. Such report shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H31959C7C4283418DA8CCE2E44267542F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the results of the pilot program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5611E2BF87E4893B463E37308DD2095"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a determination of the Secretary regarding whether to procure and adopt covered diagnostic technologies in addition to tools already used by medical providers of the Department of Defense to screen for traumatic brain injury at the point of injury; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0ED479D74EA49C6A307DCCB03DC9801"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Secretary regarding necessary steps to promote the use of covered diagnostic technologies that meet the needs of the Armed Forces, including any legislative solutions that may be necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H42C528097D874BBAB57D43B57E16045F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 to the Secretary of Defense for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7B3ACB66A3B24FD28F23DEC8B727BD6B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to carry out the program shall terminate on September 30, 2029.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9EBFC5DF2F09438FB9666EFBDE21FD2E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9A4D8667D45B4A9E8B7EE3E97A21A31D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0754DA9204F4AE594E09A3C3A341407"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered diagnostic technology</term> means a device that aids in the diagnosis of traumatic brain injury, including by assisting clinicians in making such a diagnosis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8261F53AF7424B65BA7FDA58E269AC28"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>civilian level one trauma center</term> has the meaning given that term in section 708 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1071">10 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0B10D7AC17540248DB61A8C02002CDE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA4CDB65E6C7A42FC892F5899FEECA4FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1758A3F92F8144A7970C97E806ED59BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any entity that is owned by an entity described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57001F8C994C47B38BC78C8281EF3412"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>nontraditional defense contractor</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3014 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

