<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT26532-T03-2C-CLY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4892 IS: Strengthening Manufactured Appliance Requirements towards Thoughtful Energy Efficiency Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4892</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act with respect to regional standards for furnaces, central air conditioners, and heat pumps.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H28C1D043DE944747B3006D79211B8079"><section section-type="section-one" id="H86765B744F9243FA85852C508553794C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Manufactured Appliance Requirements towards Thoughtful Energy Efficiency Standards Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SMART Energy Efficiency Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H83DCB87B21444D2AB0C867F056259E37"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regional standards for furnaces, central air conditioners, and heat pumps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 325(o)(6)(E)(ii) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6295">42 U.S.C. 6295(o)(6)(E)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>shall apply to any such product installed on or after the effective date of the standard in States in which the Secretary has designated the standard to apply</quote> and inserting <quote>shall apply, in States in which the Secretary has designated the standard to apply, to any such product that is manufactured or imported into the United States on or after the effective date of the standard</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

