<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95746CFC447C4061B913E35534678F4C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6452 IH: Executive Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6452</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States code, to require certain officials to provide an annual briefing to certain congressional committees.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H49475578007C4848B2BEA8E58271E71A" style="OLC">
<section id="HC3185BDE9EA44111BA1D0A8EFE3570FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Executive Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFA8E326CC36C4E1BBE2EB837660A45C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual briefing to Congress</header> <subsection id="H39A443BE88E54E7AAC5206B0C3AD151A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual briefing to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/29">chapter 29</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HDB58D4DF121D4CD1A99B6561ACC75F22" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="HE9C9D90BC2ED45E280DECB6DBD1AFE68"><enum>2955.</enum><header>Annual briefing to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following officials shall provide an annual briefing, in such form and manner as the applicable committees may require, to the corresponding congressional committees:</text> <paragraph id="H2CEF1E0628EC44F8B701DC57087B3D57"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H345ECB61724D42019777F2ABC7110D94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64F2F9A9A08B4D2E94B8A296BD4A0AAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDE9C4A45D8A84F748264EDBBDC4B8E54"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Attorney General; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1EC51552E324D09BAF2B69E4CB70024"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADBBA3DB71C24917AE5B9EC549EAB6DE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H585A4DA88E8443FF9B6547F757F0D0C0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC993E4E8AF124493BF23EC6F7C671641"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C48CF41A2234174AACAE5A7E4F5127A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58B9DE8F846E4ACE8360AC1747532C9D"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB92D2443E3B241A2A7547BE0625306EC"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD76E2AA5F01E4716B146106046D830A4"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1D79976E1754BE8A2983133CFC61D96"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE563B374217340C5AA2829ED74265F3E"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23DD1896D82648F39E887D7EC6DAB9CC"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H517CC4D87CB64B289F4992529071883C"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0853AF761A2A44DC978211FC163C3774"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC99A1FE6E2FB4C898C431F292445C3E6"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget; the Committees on Appropriations and the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H252E9663840C4099AE831E7852D90578"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD1835DF2024A489081FF4FE220EAC19B"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF95BA282734A4069BE4B0B550BC44169"><enum>(21)</enum><text>The Chair of the Federal Reserve Board; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3866EF3BC7864875B5661219F30ECEFE"><enum>(22)</enum><text>The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAD72C6F79124C8E857784EDC0F57202"><enum>(23)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigations; the Committees on Appropriations and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H902FF27D0C39444B9A7B5596C335FDC7"><enum>(24)</enum><text>The Chair of the Securities and Exchange Commission; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FE94C53B4C74B678CA07A313E3D6BB1"><enum>(25)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8DB98B0F886B4E2DB5094082C7FA1555"><enum>(26)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA01A6A3351B94E89B15E11ED09E395A4"><enum>(27)</enum><text>The Chair of the Federal Trade Commission; the Committees on Appropriations and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H600D7446BB874B478A9A87370A05AC6B"><enum>(28)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41DA87AB023D46D0AFA5E18085037DF8"><enum>(29)</enum><text>The Chair of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H75CB6E8573E04973B2AAF0DF915ABD1B"><enum>(30)</enum><text>The Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service; the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H8F05CE64CDDA4847A3D3900F60D4E7C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for subchapter II of chapter 29 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H82A616C2A59E4499918859965903CAB5" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">2955. Annual briefing to Congress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>


