<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H29D6A37ECEE4419A9E00598F7218C686">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7702 IH: Death Penalty for Child Rapists Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7702</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to authorize capital punishment for certain sexual abuse offenses against children.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HBDCE711D9D02408F9F6455297E2FBACF">
<section id="HFE7C9CD45BBF428FBD63EFE2E1C03078" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Death Penalty for Child Rapists Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC6767C9FEE354E1D85A6076D50ACF7DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of death penalty for certain sexual abuse offenses against children</header> <subsection id="HA739B17FF17142D598FDA4CD16C23720"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Aggravated sexual abuse</header><text>Section 2241(c) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>shall be fined under this title and imprisoned for not less than 30 years or for life</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be punished by death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life and by a fine under this title</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H66DB79F4C26C41F687A52BBB121BE4D8">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Sexual abuse of a minor</header>
 <text>Section 2243(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 15 years, or both</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be punished by death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life, by a fine under this title, or by both</quote>.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="HEFCA2EB2F28349BD861F4B2FCBDAE623">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Abusive sexual contact</header>
 <text>Section 2244 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3CF8664E39904336AEF16D35B8EDB44A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in paragraph (a)(3), by striking <quote>shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than two years, or both</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be punished by death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life, by a fine under this title, or by both</quote>;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H9A0AE27003924B67984DAE9E70D6DBC2">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (a)(5), by striking <quote>shall be fined under this title and imprisoned for any term of years or for life</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be punished by death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life, by a fine under this title, or by both</quote>; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2154083C620542D6AC063F8F685262C9">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (c), by—</text> <subparagraph id="H6FA3840B65AA4E4A99974ACE4A46CAD8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>striking <quote>(other than subsection (a)(5))</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H73186A92339C49319CAAA7F5DDECCCE7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>striking <quote>maximum term of imprisonment that may be imposed for the offense shall be twice that otherwise provided in this section</quote> and inserting <quote>maximum punishment that may be imposed for the offense shall be death or imprisonment for any term of years or for life</quote>.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="HCA681CE7949B41D6A44CA709230D26FF">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Sentence of death</header>
 <text>Section 3591(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9D4548B17E2B499CAC719B42A6BD019A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6588578D7C034CB48EE1743782AC0513">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD70B439384B2409396BD3304888E054A"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text>
                    <quoted-block id="H5382EBC773C248188B50DBAA873BA21E" style="OLC">
                        <paragraph id="H58F7C174965A4C4F91C49C99B196D43D">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>an offense described in section 2241, section 2243, or section 2244 against a child; or</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section>
<section id="H2DF61C9C592B436B90AE2FB17A55A15E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of death penalty for offense of rape of a child under the uniform code of military justice</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 920b(a) of title 10, United States Code (article 120b(a) of the Uniform Code of Military Justice), is amended by inserting <quote>by death, or such other punishment</quote> after <quote>shall be punished</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H08F424C42D834A7295F454C2AC5B5842"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or any amendment made by this Act, or the application of a provision of this Act or an amendment made by this Act to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provision or amendment to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected by the holding.</text></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


