<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H9CA42A593693488FBBB697272FB4D19C" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 962 IH: Original Resolution Honoring Harriet Tubman</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 962</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring Harriet Tubman’s extraordinary courage, unyielding opposition to the institution of slavery, and lasting contributions to American history.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas this resolution may be cited as the <quote>Original Resolution Honoring Harriet Tubman</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Harriet Tubman, born Araminta Ross, was born enslaved and escaped slavery through the Underground Railroad abolitionist network;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Harriet Tubman later became a conductor on the Underground Railroad, leading 13 missions that rescued approximately 70 enslaved people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Harriet Tubman acted as a scout, spy, and nurse for the Union Army during the Civil War, becoming the first woman to plan and lead a United States military operation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Harriet Tubman’s leadership in the Combahee River Raid led to the liberation of 700 enslaved people in South Carolina; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Harriet Tubman continued fighting for human rights and women’s suffrage after the war and throughout her life;</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body id="HADA2E7F9BE5A44719ABABB5258F5449E" style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause"><section id="H7F2422285D564AFF9C2A08120E4FBAFD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Original Resolution Honoring Harriet Tubman</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H59A325327E4D444FB3861472B40DE75B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Honoring harriet tubman</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HE39EF1CF7DCA4C0A84647EAE016A3847"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acknowledges and honors Harriet Tubman’s extraordinary courage, unyielding opposition to the institution of slavery, and lasting contributions to American history.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

