<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26435-PJJ-LM-228"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4133 IS: 21st Century Entrepreneurship Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4133</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to encourage entrepreneurship training in after school programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Entrepreneurship Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD21E96EA3F504E158DE21FE388122C00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="idec479db146df4f55ab8fe98b670a5d5c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entrepreneurship creates new jobs, grows the economy, increases productivity, and significantly improves the quality of life of the people of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf913b09bbc0a48dd90f4ad2e2b1ece1b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>entrepreneurship rates in the United States have declined substantially over the last several decades;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5cac3db4d8624177b7204611d47ba8a7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>children from disadvantaged communities are less likely to become entrepreneurs and inventors, hampering economic growth and harming communities most in need;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6541bb6d19b8442f8cc4e0fbbb2effa9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>studies show that children with mentors in entrepreneurship and inventorship are more likely to pursue these fields in adulthood; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb489add9ef264ec6a53459aea7302d3e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in order to promote growth in disadvantaged communities, increase entrepreneurship rates, and improve the economy, volunteer mentors with the SCORE program should be encouraged to engage with children in community learning centers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idDBC701588A6C41FDB8667DB0552BF0DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id47B058AE45D8497DA6EC0A75C56B7396"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration; Administrator</header><text>The terms <term>Administration</term> and <term>Administrator</term> mean the Small Business Administration and the Administrator thereof, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ff0f55e36164c57bfb97b4e593c57dc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community learning center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community learning center</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4201(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">20 U.S.C. 7171(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDBA2A960988F4262B926A51E746A3A3B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inventorship</header><text>The term <term>inventorship</term> means the activity of creating, designing, or otherwise originating a new product or service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6BE7CB3551814390AD49631A80438042"><enum>(4)</enum><header>SCORE program</header><text>The term <term>SCORE program</term> means the Service Corps of Retired Executives described in section 8(b)(1)(B) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e19699d1eae4e9fbe8f8735c28bd5ed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small business development center</header><text>The term <term>small business development center</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idD9F06E3DAD8A4A89A2CC60727B2F1188"><enum>4.</enum><header>Entrepreneurship education for disadvantaged youth</header><subsection id="id28643AFB909E48C190299D184712573F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="id575403e7497549ffa1f4781f4b66a35e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a curriculum for volunteers with the SCORE program to teach female students, minority students, English learners, children with disabilities, students from rural areas, and low-income students who are often underrepresented in critical and enriching subjects about entrepreneurship and inventorship through community learning centers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86b3e6f5e5be4c408a5701d79565f912"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and implement a strategy to encourage partnerships between the SCORE program and community learning centers to teach the curriculum developed under paragraph (1) to the students described in that paragraph through community learning centers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3B977D1BE44C4755B372373703BE67B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in developing the curriculum required under paragraph (1), collaborate with education specialists, entrepreneurship groups, business groups, and groups with experience serving underrepresented children.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id72B4935E54F64545A8F39158DA5CF1D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration with other programs</header><text>In carrying out the partnerships under subsection (a)(2), volunteers with the SCORE program are encouraged to collaborate with other entrepreneurial development programs of the Administration and other agencies, including—</text><paragraph id="id4207D64BD3C24660BB401391B871DC1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>small business development centers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE9D128D2B6F44B4793ECEE32E9281A90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>women's business centers operating under section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53CA8FCAA4CC499281A790D37C02787D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>centers overseen by the Minority Business Development Agency of the Department of Commerce; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC3DC0EAF01514A41B52B100916383B03"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Growth Accelerator Fund Competition of the Administration carried out under section 24 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3719">15 U.S.C. 3719</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCF8C40E4E00243AA9C11133FC0F5A4B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>SCORE program</header><text>Section 8(b)(1)(B) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended, in the first sentence, by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>and to carry out entrepreneurship and inventorship programs under section 4(a) of the <short-title>21st Century Entrepreneurship Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idFCF10C1871254095AB473EC7A81208E0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Community learning centers</header><text>Part B of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">20 U.S.C. 7171 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idC745BF875A724420B654A56E0099E890"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 4201(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">20 U.S.C. 7171(a)(2)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>entrepreneurship and inventorship (as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>21st Century Entrepreneurship Act</short-title>) programs,</quote> after <quote>apprenticeship programs,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4C1575E8418E4633BED3158B55D974B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 4205(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7175">20 U.S.C. 7175(a)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="idC442D9F3DC4A46CD99A53EB6BC61CD2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id316A8A9FC1A647CA896BDEE66CFC10CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1E036E77E13A42919F991BDA066D34EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56A41A43CC6F416F8B878834C01771A8"><paragraph id="id040A71728099441E83B8E5C9114EE703"><enum>(15)</enum><text>entrepreneurship and inventorship programs described in section 4(a) of the <short-title>21st Century Entrepreneurship Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3F142CC2819F4CFC9ABB84EB913129F1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><paragraph id="id8cc348758bbd4c2a9cac7e0aa6a41307"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies each partnership between the SCORE program and a community learning center during the preceding 2-year period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB0DD9DDE550C420EB6D45CB958EB38B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>documents the use of funds by the SCORE program, and adherence by the SCORE program to contract award and procurement procedures, relating to the implementation of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB82C91CB117A45BBA4BF602F7B38BA52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>documents any training or guidance provided to SCORE program chapter leadership on properly using funds provided to carry out this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4bb16f20613846d885f16125bbb93de7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>estimates the number of students who were reached through the entrepreneurship curriculum developed under subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b596ff8bf634b67ac4ba2c9c5ee9b9a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identifies any barriers to reaching additional students; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idddf217251b4a4d72b240af35fff35741"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identifies any plans for improving the curriculum or implementing the strategy developed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7BA0F70BA22646989BF4B2FCD23CF087"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="id23D0B230215E4213A1F480F016806497"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $2,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0689042DF8E6430A9C9F318321E8CEB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>Of amounts made available to the Administrator to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act, the Administrator may transfer any portion of those amounts to the SCORE program to carry out such provisions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

