<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81E2F9A1DCE74247851F90CB41447FE1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9442 IH: Artificial Intelligence Data Center Moratorium Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9442</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose a moratorium on the construction of new data centers until legislation is enacted that safeguards the public from the dangers of artificial intelligence.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5617A7C3779D4B58AF87ED893A39024A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5E52CC51B8FC483EAF87FBADBDD62114" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence Data Center Moratorium Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF20EBF52FDB5483EAD6D2C383788796B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H23C38430F10F4814943E6537A4B3F0A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>leading experts and industry leaders have warned about catastrophic consequences from unchecked artificial intelligence development and deployment, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H006D2B9440D54BC99E12AD23E07726D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Elon Musk, the wealthiest person alive, and worth $826,600,000,000 as of the date of introduction of this Act, who stated that <quote>AI and robots will replace all jobs. Working will be optional.</quote> and that artificial intelligence is akin to <quote>summoning the demon</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF520D95B84FF419086685E468B48A118"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Dario Amodei, the CEO of Anthropic, who predicted that <quote>AI could displace half of all entry-level white collar jobs in the next 1 to 5 years.</quote> and that <quote>humanity is about to be handed almost unimaginable power, and it is deeply unclear whether our social, political, and technological systems possess the maturity to wield it.</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H984C59EE873844229967ED4052416EEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Demis Hassabis, the head of Google’s Deepmind, who stated that the AI revolution will be 10 times bigger than the industrial revolution and 10 times faster;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H30AEBD6F614042B5BE28E5620A54BD73"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Jeff Bezos, the fourth-richest person in the world and worth $233,000,000,000 as of the date of introduction of this Act, who has reportedly pushed his staff for years to think big and envision what it would take for Amazon to fully automate its operations with plans to replace at least 600,000 warehouse workers with robots;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC974E4B53E9043CE9EA2E5A2D177FEBE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Bill Gates, worth $101,000,000,000 as of the date of introduction of this Act, who predicted that humans <quote>won’t be needed for most things,</quote> such as manufacturing products, delivering packages, or growing food over the next decade due to artificial intelligence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAD4C83306C44D219BAE25CBB5054284"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Mustafa Suleyman, the CEO of Microsoft AI, who said that most white-collar work <quote>will be fully automated by an AI within the next 12 to 18 months</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01527AFA272247D69F9F82F414F50FFD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Jim Farley, the CEO of Ford, who predicted that artificial intelligence will eliminate <quote>literally half of all white-collar jobs in the U.S.</quote> within the next decade;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H808554B65A46454395D36C4761D2F6C3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Larry Ellison, the sixth-richest person in the world and worth $203,000,000,000 as of the date of introduction of this Act, who said that there will be an artificial intelligence-powered surveillance state where <quote>citizens will be on their best behavior, because we’re constantly recording and reporting everything that is going on.</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E31A88B5DD94DDDAE8C26FDF40C869B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Dr. Geoffrey Hinton, considered to be the <quote>godfather</quote> of artificial intelligence, who stated that he believes there is a <quote>10 to 20 percent chance [for artificial intelligence] to wipe us out.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5040FC6083814F97B82A9F8492FB194C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Mark Zuckerberg, the fifth-richest person in the world and worth $214,000,000,000 as of the date of introduction of this Act, is building a data center in the State of Louisiana that is the size of Manhattan and will use 3 times the quantity of electricity that the entire city of New Orleans uses every year; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54C74E4596A44588AF72B1A4B41C44D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leading experts and the heads of the major artificial intelligence companies have called for regulation and reasonable pauses to the development of artificial intelligence to ensure the safety of humanity, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1FD04ECE7C0C486894F4690D2A1C1A2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Elon Musk, the head of xAI, who stated—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01B52A1B5DE4481A97BAFD89E454ABD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 2018 the following: <quote>Mark my words. AI is far more dangerous than nukes. So why do we have no regulatory oversight? This is insane.</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C6B305C8AB54393823BC780C939BD4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 2025 that he had <quote>a lot of AI nightmares</quote> and would <quote>certainly slow down AI and robotics</quote> if he could;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC27356266F484C22BFD1306CD20DCE22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Demis Hassabis, the head of Google’s Deepmind, who said in 2026 that he would support an AI pause if he knew other countries and companies also paused development;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA26C502628E54EA4AB54F7AD73D2A10D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Dario Amodei, the head of Anthropic, who said in 2026 that he would be <quote>absolutely in favor of trying</quote> to slow down AI development if other countries also slowed down;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87714817FC5F4392A3C3CF4EE27B9766"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Sam Altman, the head of OpenAI, who, in 2023, wrote that <quote>we need some degree of coordination among the leading development efforts to ensure that the development of superintelligence occurs in a manner that allows us to both maintain safety and help smooth integration of these systems with society</quote> and that <quote>an effective global regulatory framework including democratic governance</quote> is needed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H34FDD69CB13D409AB7AAD44F27D5BB01"><enum>(E)</enum><text>more than 1,000 business leaders in the Big Tech industry, prominent scientists, and artificial intelligence researchers and academics, including Elon Musk, Steve Wozniak (co-founder of Apple), and Evan Sharp (co-founder of Pinterest), who, in March 2023, cosigned an open letter entitled <quote>Pause Giant AI Experiments</quote> which stated the following: <quote>We must ask ourselves: Should we let machines flood our information channels with propaganda and untruth? Should we automate away all the jobs, including the fulfilling ones? Should we develop nonhuman minds that might eventually outnumber, outsmart, obsolete and replace us? Should we risk loss of control of our civilization? Such decisions must not be delegated to unelected tech leaders…Therefore, we call on all AI labs to immediately pause for at least 6 months the training of AI systems more powerful than GPT-4. This pause should be public and verifiable, and include all key actors. If such a pause cannot be enacted quickly, governments should step in and institute a moratorium.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14AB8E1DCBC144869740981BFC2F8642"><enum>(F)</enum><text>artificial intelligence pioneers Geoffrey Hinton and Yoshua Bengio and other technology leaders, who have called for <quote>a prohibition on the development of superintelligence, not lifted before there is broad scientific consensus that it will be done safely and controllably, and strong public buy-in</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H0F7487D677D04F9BB279E6F45759229A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Moratorium on construction of new artificial intelligence data centers</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1757C0510DCB48D18D6D29F1E208309F"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of artificial intelligence data center</header><text>In this section, the term <term>artificial intelligence data center</term> means all the buildings, equipment, structures, and other stationary items, such as server racks, that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB470EC8F460445E6B605C6D8B3F3DA4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are located on a single site or on contiguous, adjacent, or otherwise connected sites;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FB8A87EA148498A873C50F3CB798974"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are owned or operated by the same entity or by any entity that controls, is controlled by, or is under the common control of that entity, regardless of whether the site is a single-occupant or multi-occupant facility; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC2EDE7686814F2CA2B971203FBA66D7"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H63BF1D00475941DCB3708DF07590C80D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are used for the development or operation of artificial intelligence models at scale; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC21C632259D74B7F970A3817FEB25DDA"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB3E6C7EDC7C34AB79B5D694DB5AE9AAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have a maximum rated power capacity or total peak power load in excess of 20 megawatts; and</text></clause> <clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBF18E1A3CAB4D76B0E852121A003687"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are designed or equipped—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H157D7E45B89D439CBBEDA676BC9685C1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to deliver 20 kilowatts or more of electrical power to a single server rack; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H249A80B03AEA495F8E14D29EC9609DB7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to utilize cooling systems that circulate liquid to individual hardware components or submerge electronic hardware in liquid.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD3FFB6080F6493389CC42B23C75974B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Moratorium</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the construction or upgrading of new or existing artificial intelligence data centers may not commence or proceed until—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64FD05143CDB4F3683F7AD8C5DAE66FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more laws are enacted that ensure that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA78ABA0643DB40DFB31367745350B2FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Government shall review and approve artificial intelligence products before those products are released, for the purpose of ensuring that those products are safe and effective and do not threaten the health and well-being of working families, privacy and civil rights, and the future of humanity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9F87D07048742E182B0076EE1C52032"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the economic gains of artificial intelligence and robotics will benefit workers, not just the wealthy owners of Big Tech companies, including by—</text> 
<clause id="HFAA8D90B3B56424BAFEEA65EFE36E519"><enum>(i)</enum><text>putting policies in place to prevent job displacement due to artificial intelligence; and</text></clause> <clause id="H11FC9C48B7174218B0AF6D58CD947280"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring the wealth generated by those companies is shared with the people of the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0418BB378D6E45CF938A39EF8FB9186C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to any artificial intelligence data center built or upgraded after the termination of the moratorium under this subsection—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B90E59FB66D4C1F8F1E97E71919474C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the artificial intelligence data center does not increase utility or electricity bills of consumers;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAD45DF1622E43F1B8D523E310161AA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the artificial intelligence data center does not exacerbate the threat of climate change or harm the environment;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53ACC024FF83431EB6BB590F54F0D21D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communities that would be affected by the artificial intelligence data center are empowered to approve or reject the construction or upgrading of that artificial intelligence data center;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB148B3B52B0343B2A62AD6BCE2748878"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no government subsidy is provided for the construction, upgrading, or operation of that artificial intelligence data center; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD30E1696EF004AF28DB80BB00855144F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the artificial intelligence data center creates union jobs with strong labor standards, including payment of prevailing wages and use of registered apprenticeship programs and project labor agreements; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9123F5BA4B214E0EA1A40C0B047F7E10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a provision in the 1 or more laws described in paragraph (1) expressly terminates the moratorium under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD919EE9C0B4F4692B213E8D6DFB31B95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="HA8FE3CDD7827445ABD94207C191A55EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Energy shall—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEC2529220764BD1875BD2083F177F77"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress quarterly reports on artificial intelligence data centers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5312E4D7606C41279DBD271A4B0861AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make those quarterly reports publicly available on the website of the Department of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F30AA06975847BAB80CD3A459FC330F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A report submitted by the Secretary of Energy under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, for the period covered by the report and with respect to each artificial intelligence data center—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD72D90A9B8284E03B4FB92DF19D71C96"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all financial vehicles involved in the operation of the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H498CF4E8CEAA47B2B458D01BCCB12A4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the water usage of the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB44F68EDB37645A4B05E65DF97F9887E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the energy usage and infrastructure needs of the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAA9577635184261B000A7942776655E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the on- and off-site greenhouse gas emissions of the artificial intelligence data center, including the results of fenceline air quality monitoring;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9948FAC092C4F2F8743EC32F3B87CD1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the wastewater discharge and thermal outputs of the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99EBD3CE0D0741529EA056AFFB3B88C3"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cooling chemicals used at the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C5D2077B3DC426DBC0E6BD495484074"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the noise levels at the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BA754D52C764A4A871D1E2A217DE942"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on wages and benefits provided to workers at the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FC76F2CA93A4B6F9F0F9278E6D8F917" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of temporary and permanent jobs created at the artificial intelligence data center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD98DDEB2A71B4DFFA5205A9ACD9161FD"><enum>(J)</enum><text>agreements entered into by the artificial intelligence data center relating to land acquisitions, utilities, or government entities, if any; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D0CF9B7DBF247DD93EDAB7EFD5D47E3"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that the artificial intelligence data center has not utilized any Federal, State, or local subsidies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EA87F48D37B4BE49385DF9778F26AEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>The Secretary of Energy may obtain and verify information relating to the moratorium under subsection (b) and reporting requirements described in paragraph (2), including by—</text> <subparagraph id="H9920C4943E4F4FF8A90CB2300980B740"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issuing subpoenas;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC608EF1551F438EAF2A6F177ADC9F13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requiring written interrogatories;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B13140B5D574050A5F339ECD115555B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducting inspections; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4CDBE8B049C74C5AB0C6F98D48685356" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conditioning future permitting on compliance with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD16B5BB11DC7423FB83685B61821C06F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Export controls on computing infrastructure hardware</header> <subsection id="HC11220B54ED14E58A20AD80FDA12B774"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F657A11912A4F518CD29F6000626E33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Computing infrastructure hardware</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>computing infrastructure hardware</term> means semiconductors, integrated circuits, and products containing integrated circuits, including computers, networking equipment, and data storage systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E1C8B5F312143E188E60E3F581FA85D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Export; in-country transfer; reexport</header><text>The terms <quote>export</quote>, <quote>in-country transfer</quote>, and <quote>reexport</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 1742 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD41196F486E246AEA2DA419B80B426E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Export controls</header><text>On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall prohibit the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of computing infrastructure hardware for an end-use described in subsection (c)—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF1ECD0560654B1EBC51AC6EC0DC1A75"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to or in any country that does not have in effect statutes or regulations that are comparable to the laws described in section 3(b)(1); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB3E414EDB3A4B028602B60593A09B56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to any person in a country described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE911A3F3CD7B485FA5DFA1E716DB8DF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>End-Uses described</header><text>An end-use referred to in subsection (b) is use—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H050A270A62524701A08B16C661323EC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an artificial intelligence data center; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF4A15ADA19246DE829F1F37770C1D9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise in the training or deployment of artificial intelligence models at scale.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

