<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26081-J73-JX-KS0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3676 IS: American Decade of Sports Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3676</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a sports diplomacy strategy to strategically leverage the major sporting events being hosted in the United States during the next decade to enhance United States soft power, diplomatic relationships, and global leadership, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H8B023FB077F246D3A8D16288999B0EA5"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4C597C2BE04B4B979351480713162205"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Decade of Sports Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD19CED00632B48A1AED046DAC041918F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08295d4e777547ceaa44abf844e69715"><enum>(1)</enum><header>American decade of sports; mega-decade of sports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>American decade of sports</term> and <term>mega-decade of sports</term> mean the major international sporting competitions hosted in the United States between 2024 and 2034, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00b27570989a48bba1fa7f675805d58e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2024 Copa America;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9a40def444c4eb8ba6f0becff431c08"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2025 Club World Cup;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8b0668f1ee749b9817852f9cdcb19c2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2026 FIFA World Cup;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1212b4bfa07248ee85c9ff0925414d6c"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2028 Summer Olympics and Paralympics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id340a1706484b46bcbef86717e6aed475"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2031 Men’s and 2033 Women’s Rugby World Cup; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d8835d61b694faa8840ef166e7a15d6"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 2034 Winter Olympics and Paralympics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12c903435b2749fbba081b69355ce39e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id332573f0835d4c76bb72a641e67c263c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16a9b84660a54b3391a1a5f20cb938dd"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H033BC1C9992444349773A526F5348608"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mega-Decade Sports Diplomacy Strategy</header><subsection id="H05C65F62CC374F669821EF043DAAFD43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than 5 years after such date, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a 5-year sports diplomacy strategy to strategically leverage the major sporting events being hosted in the United States to enhance United States soft power, diplomatic relationships, and global leadership.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA23CA483D40B4E59BC4F6BEAA5CDEF9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Both strategies required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HCA6E8A3B41D34E3A9EEE84D11CD5138B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the Department of State’s diplomatic objectives and metrics of success related to the mega-decade of sports;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D884AFE4E6A4E57BAF599500E00A3A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan to partner with local host cities, diaspora communities, creatives, athletes, the sports industry, private sector entities, human rights organizations, and civil society stakeholders surrounding the competitions for the purpose of showcasing United States national strengths and forging new diplomatic connections;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FF6C7B3C5B240E4B0A988BF25484289"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to coordinate internally within the Department of State to leverage sporting events to advance various diplomatic lines of effort, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H96AAD3DFCEC843428439C9A19A8235D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrating sports diplomacy into regional bureaus’ bilateral engagements and efforts to pursue new areas of cooperation with foreign partners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BCB0279451D4F7DAF680816E2F620E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrating sports into public diplomacy to reach new foreign audiences that might not otherwise engage with United States embassies abroad; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF0B5427029C459883E426DBF345BD24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>leveraging sports diplomacy to advance commercial diplomacy;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92122549D4184E18963C509D8E50400D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan to ensure an expeditious and secure visa process for athletes and their families and support staff and eligible international visitors planning to travel to the United States to attend major international sporting events, including reducing visa appointment wait times;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B8457A948E24B12BC5D14ADBA0FBE9A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of the financial and personnel support needed to implement the 5-year sports diplomacy strategy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79E23C8E92BE4914A0E51EBC1BE363D7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any plans to deploy domestic public diplomacy resources, such as the Cultural Unit and Foreign Press Center established during the 1984 Olympic Games, to enable foreign visitors to engage with American culture and values.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H837CD5F7AB7B451B868D45319C410560"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategies required under subsection (a) shall be made publicly available on an internet website of the Department of State not later than—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90578b3e361f4df8a379e6914d13d87d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, with respect to the first 5-year strategy; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd429b80d54cf46289d0f4a8ce5062570"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5 years after the date described in paragraph (1), with respect to the second 5-year strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFF8E948727D4CF98F2AADFE2CC9301B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id627fa826ed9749ed99a5706d4dbf80af"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the appropriate congressional committees regarding the elements of the strategy required under subsection (a) before submitting either strategy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id420d00c6d5494b2db78d52bcaaf47a5f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide information regarding the implementation of the most recently submitted strategy every 180 days during the period beginning on the date of such submission and ending on December 31, 2034.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H313207C69DF347649C6B69EA7D72C179"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement for the Office of Sports Diplomacy to carry out the Mega-Decade of Sports Diplomacy Strategy</header><subsection id="H838F9589E18E479AAD2F3260D729039A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall rename the Sports Diplomacy Division in the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs as the Office of Sports Diplomacy (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>). The Office shall be under the general supervision of the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Professional and Cultural Exchanges in the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23315d33465f4c399164bc3592811076"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall manage sports diplomacy exchange programs and implement each strategy required under section 3(a), including by coordinating with internal Department of State and interagency stakeholders—</text><paragraph id="HDC78B6F2B5524EF9B31D5FDF220BB9B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate the implementation of the strategy across relevant bureaus, directorates, and offices of the Department of State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90120DE6AF0C4867ACCEE9B779DF22A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to work with host cities and their social, political, and economic partners to identify new avenues for engagement with foreign entities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53C34EE386EB4ADBA0CAB63C76A85B98"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to engage local diaspora communities to deepen people-to-people connections with foreign visitors and officials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53C195D8556A4C20AD76338DDE74C191"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to partner with the United States sports industry, major sports leagues, and individual athletes to promote new international sports partnerships and sports diplomacy programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4652FA797FD047E9BA0860B4A2284060"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to collaborate with host cities’ international trade and tourism offices to deepen economic and commercial ties with foreign nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFDE8D866CC544DC84BB3F28F44764CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to elevate American arts, film, and music creators to promote cultural exchange and connection with foreign visitors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52A89185BFA04E3CA1A93EBFCF78B1A8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to coordinate with internal Department of State and interagency stakeholders to ensure efficient and expeditious processing of visas for eligible international visitors, broadcasters, athletes, and support staff interested in attending major international sporting events in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA08ECE1A8823447F9B623B8C626A1E7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Full-Time equivalent employees</header><text>During the period beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on December 31, 2034, the Secretary of State shall assign to the Office not fewer than 3 additional full-time equivalent staff dedicated exclusively to implementing each strategy required under section 3(a). These staff shall be assigned to the Office by considering mechanisms, including—</text><paragraph id="HBB32CF5B4F4E45EE969CEDB4C85C39E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use of existing flexible hiring authorities, including Domestic Employees Teleworking Overseas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA8849CF4E1846F68FC47A889FF58991"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the realignment of existing personnel.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1AB12D0CB7D64F3693191F1D979CCAF3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementation reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the submission of the first strategy required under section 2(a), and annually thereafter until December 31, 2034, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees describing the progress made toward achieving the objectives of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

