<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B9753479E6D409F9CBA5B9085082846" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1407 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the current design concept for the National Global War on Terrorism Memorial fails to adequately honor the profound sacrifice of members of the United States Armed Forces, and demanding a redesigned monument that clearly and unmistakably honors the valor, combat reality, and distinct sacrifice of post-9/11 veterans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1407</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the current design concept for the National Global War on Terrorism Memorial fails to adequately honor the profound sacrifice of members of the United States Armed Forces, and demanding a redesigned monument that clearly and unmistakably honors the valor, combat reality, and distinct sacrifice of post-9/11 veterans.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on September 11, 2001, the United States of America was attacked by radical Islamic terrorists, triggering the longest continuous military conflict in the history of the Nation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, for over 20 years, more than 2,700,000 brave American men and women voluntarily deployed into harm’s way across the globe, including Iraq, Afghanistan, Syria, Somalia, and the Horn of Africa, to protect the homeland and eliminate terrorist threats;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this multigenerational conflict resulted in the tragic loss of over 7,000 members of the United States Armed Forces who made the ultimate sacrifice, left tens of thousands more with permanent visible and invisible wounds of war, and profoundly impacted Gold Star families who carry the heavy burden of that sacrifice every single day;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a national military memorial on the National Mall in the District of Columbia must serve as an enduring, sacred testament to the raw courage, unmatched lethality, and deep physical sacrifice of the warrior class;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas military monuments of past generations, such as the Marine Corps War Memorial (Iwo Jima), the Korean War Veterans Memorial, and the Vietnam Veterans Memorial, are revered precisely because they explicitly portray the service, faces, names, and concrete realities of the men and women who fought;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the initial design concept unveiled by the Global War on Terrorism Memorial Foundation on June 10, 2026, relies heavily on abstract architectural features, natural landscaping, and interpretive water elements; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an abstract, landscape-centric concept falls short of the enduring tribute that the post-9/11 generation of veterans earned through blood, sweat, and tears, and fails to adequately communicate the stark, unyielding reality of their 20-year fight against global terrorism to future generations of Americans: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3C93893AB3EF4A5C8361E5505810B85A"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H79FC7B406E5940F1B8548053E74AC749"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB67C677E078047D48D0E368D0E5830AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the current abstract design concept for the National Global War on Terrorism Memorial fails to deliver the proper honor that Global War on Terrorism veterans and Gold Star families rightfully deserve;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67445046C24F4B7B90EC435A7EF5D169"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a national war memorial must not prioritize passive artistic reflection over the explicit, unmistakable depiction of military service, valor, and combat sacrifice;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H102D58321BDA47A29CE7E878D85E68F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Global War on Terrorism Memorial Foundation, the Commission of Fine Arts, and the National Capital Planning Commission should reject or substantially modify any design proposal that obscures the warrior ethos in favor of contemporary landscape architecture; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6E58405304845638217B5C8078566AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the final design of the Global War on Terrorism Memorial must clearly, powerfully, and visibly showcase the tremendous physical sacrifice, combat gear, and collective efforts of the brave men and women who fought the Global War on Terrorism, ensuring their legacy is preserved with the dignity and historical clarity it commands.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

