<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24D47B5A869643F98EA26B1A93EAD765" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7465 IH: Federal Investment in Grants for Health Transportation and Flu-vaccination Local Units Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7465</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration program to award grants to States to improve the provision of recommended immunizations for children, adolescents, and adults through the use of mobile vaccination units, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5C12B0A54D7B42B99623501FC133677E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCFF1304300EB4BF1BAD5C43EC2DD03E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Investment in Grants for Health Transportation and Flu-vaccination Local Units Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB9FFCA8E57D246B59E6C7151FA18FB99"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration program To award grants to States for mobile vaccination units</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 317 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b">42 U.S.C. 247b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7DDEDB77A1054B3A8AF9855A6CF0DDD6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HD71787F896734726BEE36435D6E894BF">
          <enum>(o)</enum>
          <header>Demonstration program To award grants to States for mobile vaccination
            units</header>
          <paragraph id="HD21265C587DA419D91C44DD44BAE4466">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a demonstration program to award grants to States to improve the provision of recommended immunizations for children, adolescents, and adults through the use of mobile vaccination units.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H107F862410DD4E88AE66968D153178D4">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Applications</header>
 <text>To be eligible for a grant under the program, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H4100870C30834CB5A679684988DC4506">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Use of funds</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds received by a State under a grant under this subsection shall be used to—</text>
            <subparagraph id="HFED916CED1BB43C0A57EDAFF0E3D8FDA">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish or expand mobile vaccination units in the State; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="HAE827719A06C457A87D880403F0F8AF3">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist in covering the costs associated with the mobile vaccine units, including acquiring vehicles, equipment, and vaccines.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HA81AE64C95564797B0E72BD386376097">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Report to Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2027, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of the demonstration program established under this subsection, together with recommendations on whether to continue and expand the program.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HACB79C5821B644B8B69FC0922E62E589">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2027.</text>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

