<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H3E891F2D7038410696970C9A44A04355"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 858 IH: Impeaching James E. Boasberg, United States District Court Chief Judge for the District of Columbia, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 858</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251104">November 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</sponsor> (for himself,
                    <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs
                    of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr.
                    Ogles</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>)
                submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching James E. Boasberg, United States District Court
            Chief Judge for the District of Columbia, for high crimes and
 misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body id="HBA6DC14FB75A427688B6160F47C61586" style="traditional"><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="resolved" id="H6BAAB83F59EA4EC1BDD89F86C549BB72"><text>That James E. Boasberg, Chief Judge, United States Court for the District of Columbia, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following article of impeachment be exhibited to the United States Senate.</text><subsection id="H0CABE85D231040D19C459943241E623F"><enum/><text>Article of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against James E. Boasberg, who was appointed, duly qualified, and commissioned to serve, during good behavior in office, to be United States District Judge for the District of Columbia on March 14, 2011.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA76C04A328314B8FA03908F1440099B9" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><header>Article I: Abuse of Power</header><subsection id="H50A0A8669F084D2CBB97265D4E45FAE1"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ignoring his responsibility to wield the power of his office in a constitutional manner, Chief Judge Boasberg granted Special Counsel John L. Smith authorization to issue frivolous nondisclosure orders in furtherance of the Federal Bureau of Investigation project codenamed ARCTIC FROST. These nondisclosure orders covered Members of Congress who were acting in accord with their legislative duties and privileges guaranteed by article 1, section 6, clause 1 of the U.S. Constitution. Chief Judge Boasberg authorized the issuance of frivolous nondisclosure orders covering at least Senator Marsha Blackburn, Senator Ted Cruz, Senator Lindsey Graham, Senator Bill Hagerty, Senator Josh Hawley, Senator Ron Johnson, Senator Cynthia Lummis, Senator Rick Scott, Senator Dan Sullivan, Senator Tommy Tuberville, and Representative Mike Kelly. These illegitimate and frivolous nondisclosure orders and subpoenas threaten Members of Congress by imposing undue legal scrutiny for fulfilling their constitutional duties. Chief Judge Boasberg signed an order prohibiting AT&amp;T from informing Senator Cruz of his subpoena for at least one year. Chief Judge Boasberg expressed that there were <quote>reasonable grounds to believe that such disclosure will result in destruction of or tampering with evidence, intimidation of potential witnesses, and serious jeopardy to the investigation.</quote> Chief Judge Boasberg had no clear reasonable basis to make this finding about Senator Cruz, which accused him of being willing to destroy evidence and intimidate witnesses in violation of both the law and Senator Cruz’s ethical obligation as a member of the Bar.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9E5ED1A9A134C9AAA1C194052688969"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 United States Code § 6628 states <quote>the Office of the SAA, any officer, employee, or agent of the Office of the SAA, and any provider for a Senate office that is providing services to or used by a Senate office shall not be barred, through operation of any court order or any statutory provision, from notifying the Senate office of any legal process seeking disclosure of Senate data of the Senate office that is transmitted, processed, or stored (whether temporarily or otherwise) through the use of an electronic system established, maintained, or operated, or the use of electronic services provided …</quote> Chief Judge Boasberg does not appreciate basic statute and contributed to the legal inquiries that violate the law indicating he is unfit to serve as Chief Judge.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA19A319FF7F84707BBECD438662AF9E1"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is unclear if Judge Boasberg facilitated the frivolous subpoenas issued by Special Counsel John L. Smith which covered conservative nonprofit organizations, including but not limited to Conservative Partnership Institute, America First Policy Institute, Women for America First, and Center for Renewing America. Many of these same organizations had been outspoken in opposition to various radical Biden Administration policies. It appears that these subpoenas were intended to silence political speech.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD51E4F79C58441A3990856216059B21D"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition, these frivolous subpoenas covered conservative activists and patriotic Americans, including Jeffrey Clark, John Eastman, Rudy Guiliani, Edward Corrigan, Mark Meadows, Cleta Mitchell, Amy Kremer, Kelli Ward, Jenna Ellis, and Wesley Denton. The weaponization of the judiciary compromises the separation of powers found in the U.S. Constitution, and Chief Judge Boasberg’s impropriety in participating in the undue investigation of Members of Congress casts doubt on his ability to execute his office with good behavior.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD39D36C5A1E146E5ABC38A37CB229673"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Chief Judge Boasberg is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution>


