<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN26426-WW7-J5-JGV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4473 IS: China-Africa Mining Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4473</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of State to annually issue a list of People’s Republic of China-origin entities carrying out mining involving forced labor or causing environmental harm in African countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>China-Africa Mining Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6f0b404983049339eea0c1174771353"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual list of PRC entities carrying out mining involving forced labor or causing environmental harm in African countries</header><subsection id="id9bbd0c56f9784c9aad4e5a917020b3e2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id8d5d6e9faa364390b2b9fbfb53b130b5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artisanal and small-scale mining</header><text>The term <term>artisanal and small-scale mining</term> means a form of mining common in the developing world that—</text><subparagraph id="id7c0360d2f8e74914bb7825f94760caa7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>typically employs rudimentary and low-cost extractive technologies and manual labor-intensive techniques;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40c1650d2edb4694aa6d388c3423814f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is frequently subject to limited regulation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b2fa9406a95430dbcc2b236496fe117"><enum>(C)</enum><text>often features inhumane, harsh, and dangerous working conditions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id33192cee82044a8c8fdff88203627bc2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term> has the meaning given that term in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab84f92f3aeb4c808b766d18b90a4726"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental harm to a protected area</header><text>The term <term>environmental harm to a protected area</term> means damage to the environment of a protected area, such as—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2119318abb5c41518ca85ac1ed37f65c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contamination of water resources, streams, rivers, lakes, or other bodies of water, including wells, aquifers, or soil;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf60b3ef6b7ac409092c70ae51142674f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">soil degradation or erosion; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95c58ce04b14427795ed6bedf70748a3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">degradation of aquatic or terrestrial ecosystems or biodiversity loss.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0637a1c61ff4c5e99a533097ab7756b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Forced labor</header><text>The term <term>forced labor</term> has the meaning given that term in section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87b17195977e47998f8e5a9a41b6a26d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Large-scale mining</header><text>The term <term>large-scale mining</term> means capital-intensive, usually highly mechanized, typically industrial-scale mining carried out by large commercial entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9a39a6268973487189a559c126d8defe"><enum>(6)</enum><header>PRC entity</header><text>The term <term>PRC entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idefb500b39ace49c3976b72387f96f2f3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity under the ownership, control, or influence of—</text><clause id="id84bd490ae5cc41769367f95322558007"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China;</text></clause><clause id="idb2010eb3b03441e9812d104fa6dcef0a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party; or</text></clause><clause id="id48d2a7faafdb49b2a01e36f8d9ee4250"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a military, intelligence, or paramilitary entity of the Chinese Communist Party or the People’s Republic of China;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71f224f1e0704922a85730c581409ca7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity that is organized under the laws of, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, the People’s Republic of China (including Hong Kong and Macau);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e24f59d202e42749969b860ccc3e9af"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity majority-owned, majority-controlled, or majority-financed by an entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1859ddcf42e74532a8a9dd14b24d8111" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a parent, subsidiary, affiliate, or contractor of an entity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C), including a joint venture in which an entity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) holds a controlling interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6467761e9184dc1ae9124c3c10a58ff"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Protected area</header><text>The term <term>protected area</term> means any area that has received protected status in the country in which the area is located, such as a national park, game refuge, ecosystem reserve, or other nature preserve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfffe3c7fb3134f6691238ce3c0ec7c06" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id680cb8b725234cd2b92ff00c9d029881"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the relevant congressional committees, and make publicly available, including on the internet, a list of—</text><paragraph id="id846a79ed73804978815abaf0e48658ef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each PRC entity that the Secretary reasonably assesses is carrying out mining, including large-scale mining or artisanal and small-scale mining, of critical minerals, gold, or iron in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Nigeria, Guinea, Zambia, South Africa, Zimbabwe, or any other country in Africa—</text><subparagraph id="id6b7a3ec2fc3d46f28c43f2d5379ae824"><enum>(A)</enum><text>using forced labor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf75f6c37aa6449d9a4704f39996dc403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a manner that causes environmental harm to a protected area in the country concerned; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f7564c6df01423b8de0c3f3f0de00c1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each mine, mining zone, or concession at which such mining is carried out.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1082497bb625443fa2448c75540061b5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development of list</header><text>In developing each list required by subsection (b), the Secretary of State shall—</text><paragraph id="id335b2fe06b5a43dd8900420199ae870d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use open-source information, including from press sources and academic, non-profit, and other non-state research organizations or individual researchers, and information received, collected, or otherwise obtained by United States embassies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf722497d6e2470ebd26275da7b17372"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with the Secretary of Labor, through the Bureau of International Labor Affairs of the Department of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Director of National Intelligence, and other heads of Federal departments and agencies, and the foreign country counterparts of such individuals in the countries specified in subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb241e52ba0974925873527ba73d55fee"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each list required by subsection (b) shall be made publicly available and submitted to the relevant congressional committees in unclassified form, but the version submitted to the relevant congressional committees may include a classified annex, if warranted.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

