<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26219-PPK-DK-86S"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 641 IS: Recognizing Girl Scouts of the United States of America on its 114th birthday and celebrating its legacy of providing girls with a supportive and inclusive space where they can explore their world, build meaningful relationships, and have access to experiences that prepare them for a life of leadership.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 641</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing Girl Scouts of the United States of America on its 114th birthday and celebrating its legacy of providing girls with a supportive and inclusive space where they can explore their world, build meaningful relationships, and have access to experiences that prepare them for a life of leadership.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas March 12, 1912, Girl Scouts of the United States of America (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Girl Scouts</quote>), was founded with a mission to <quote>build girls of courage, confidence, and character, who make the world a better place</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas reflecting upon the 250th anniversary of the signing the Declaration of Independence, Girl Scouts is an important part of the story of the United States as it launched a girl-led movement that celebrates girls’ independent spirits and encourages them to embrace their unique strengths and forge their own opportunities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Girl Scouts, at its core, embodies a commitment to community through service and civic engagement, and Girl Scouts members are active across the country every day, showing up to serve, lead, and make a difference in their communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Gold Award Girl Scouts are trailblazers who collectively dedicate hundreds of thousands of hours to tackle the most pressing challenges facing their communities and beyond with measurable, long-lasting, and far-reaching results;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Girl Scout Leadership Experience offers girls 21st-century programming in science, technology, engineering, and math, the outdoors, entrepreneurship, and beyond, encouraging girls to make meaningful connections and develop invaluable life skills along the way;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks the 100th World Thinking Day, an annual celebration hosted by the World Association of Girl Guides and Girl Scouts and celebrated by Girl Scouts in its 153 member organizations, that uplifts international friendship, reflects on our global Girl Scout movement, and celebrates girls’ voices on important issues that affect girls and young women across the world; and</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas, in July 2026, Girl Scouts will host <quote>the 58th National Council Session and the Girl Scouts Unite event: Celebrating all the ways that Girl Scouts make history</quote> in Washington, DC, a convention where more than 10,000 Girl Scouts members, alums, and supporters will gather to explore, celebrate, and reflect upon the history of the Girl Scout movement alongside fellow changemakers, dreamers, and doers: Now, therefore, be it</text>
 </whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idfdbd081988224224922c928f4456ae5b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Girl Scouts of the United States of America for 114 years of providing girls with the skills necessary to navigate life with purpose and joy, by offering unique experiences, and the support girls need to discover their interests, build self-confidence, and become agents of change as global citizens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd2f67759079424798ac1178d233f718"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates all Girl Scouts members who earned the Gold Award in 2025; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6762f453bf7e4f758a64ca620100e4bf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages Girl Scouts of the United States of America to continue to champion the ambitions, nurture the creativity, and support the talents of future women leaders.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

