<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HC63EEAFA61C542588CDB8A91526A801D" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5729 : North Rim Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5729</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize direct emergency acquisition flexibilities for the National Park Service for the purpose of retaining, vetting, approving, and expediting contractor approval for the clearing, rebuilding, maintenance, and improvement of the Grand Canyon grounds that have been impacted by the Dragon Bravo Fire.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HA37E570A8BC84B36AD4284845277AC98"><section id="HA5D19EEB54F74580AD97C46DAAF79AD8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Rim Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCC40F559F6B34FA99B14E43CB1689D25"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7978AE1F4F674D399484A6D06E53B1A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered Area</header><text>The term <term>covered area</term> means the areas within Grand Canyon National Park impacted by the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B4A945C94CF49B89444745028FF27BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4ACEFC92433742F684EB84AB2E6956BB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Emergency contracting authority</header><subsection id="HD2A36DCF392D4003A9C97D8F91F1BE49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any requirement for a Presidential emergency or disaster declaration, the Secretary is authorized to use the emergency acquisition flexibilities under part 18 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations (and any successor regulations), including the increased micro-purchase thresholds, simplified acquisition thresholds, and other higher-level emergency flexibilities, in contracting for the following services within the covered area:</text><paragraph id="HF1B4B1D858C943F9B3D44D81D21E7850"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Forest management or restoration activities carried out in response to the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA607E8D7E57E4C31BEE319D45B125A5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rebuilding, planning, development, and design of structures affected by the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30265F55E2CC4EF3BB43B366FEAE0353"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improvements to the grounds and structures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13EECBBC62B14C1F931E9409C14D444C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recovery efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H134FBC9AED584F0DAF34CD2495ACE6FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any activity listed in section 4(a). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFCA4F7D9F61402EAF76C8ADBF916B67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process for other services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided by law or regulation, the authority granted under subsection (a) does not apply to contracts for services other than those described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAD760A3DA8BA467D89B9E0F81346EE12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Secretary begins to use the authorization under subsection (a), and every 180 days thereafter until the date that is 180 days after the date described in subsection (e), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Natural Resources and Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on all expenditures related to the recovery efforts for the Dragon Bravo Fire, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H384483A6E0A049C99F78B8CF4055FED9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expected cost of recovery efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5A8F69F001542FA9746647DE98C29CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cost expenditures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1146C8994C654A6EA9142BB9D7A158D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Cost overruns.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A71EE3B014540339437DEDDBA80B9F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identification of contractors preforming the work associated with the recovery from the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB246D2EAE414A05842FCCC01886F3CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any affiliations or conflicts of interest between the contractor and the contracting office at the Grand Canyon National Park or the National Park Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD0A8FCB85604ED9BF266AD70A4DC894"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any waste, fraud, or abuse detected during the recovery efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9450D9B20EF6424ABCD090030C0DE3E2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any contracts that came in under expected expenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B787371D1A4826B1B55A621F62C9E0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An estimated time of completion for all projects and full recovery efforts related to the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE08347D106E94997811020C808B98CAE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>If an extension is needed for this authority to complete projects associated with the Dragon Bravo Fire.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDE9576BDD31415081677D95DDB5101D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If, after the date of the enactment of this Act, a new wildfire ignites within the covered area and impacts recovery efforts related to the Dragon Bravo Fire, the Secretary may request a 12-month extension of the authority granted under subsection (a), subject to congressional approval.</text></subsection><subsection id="H06835F56BE4D449EB10CC6497B37FF55"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>The authority granted under subsection (a) shall expire on the date that is the earlier of the following:</text><paragraph id="H52A6758E8FF94BF58E581F7A78899E35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94218796816E427C8B72D50732DF621D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The date on which projects and recovery efforts within the covered area are completed, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9BECC552BD5047178009F2A3E13AECAF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limited sole-source procurement authority</header><subsection id="H652447FE1EB242FD92D3C7EDB2B70CA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, or any other provision of law relating to the use of competitive procedures for the procurement of services, supplies, or construction materials and services, subject to a determination made by the Secretary under subsection (b), the Secretary may enter into one or more contracts, on a noncompetitive basis, for the planning, design, repair, construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, stabilization, replacement, or operation of assets supporting the recovery and reopening of the Grand Canyon National Park North Rim, including—</text><paragraph id="H3953CE98C3244C7B9396D7DC87A8E66A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>employee housing and related facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC9E089D16F44A68BC3D555868DB1E6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>water, wastewater, power, communications, and other utility systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2330BEA51284C05B9B1BDE26D35B1DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>visitor-facing facilities and infrastructure, including lodging, food service, retail, transportation, and associated public-use facilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H126328DD50924AF996E20EAD065B92FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>maintenance, administration, and other back-of-house assets necessary for safe and continuous operation of North Rim services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF702D0D6C1BB4DF188913E2BD1440C04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text>The Secretary may utilize the authority provided in subsection (a) if the Secretary determines, in writing, that—</text><paragraph id="H950411DE36A34F0A96C67B2C24481CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the concessioner currently holding a valid concession contract for operations at the North Rim of Grand Canyon National Park on the date of enactment of this Act is uniquely positioned to execute one or more procurement contracts identified under subsection (a) due to the concessioner’s current operational responsibilities, site access, integration with existing concession infrastructure, or continuity needs essential to expedited North Rim recovery; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H470ED37CB33D4AF3B12D0D5D7128BE82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>use of noncompetitive procedures under subsection (a) with this concessioner is necessary to ensure public health and safety, protection of park resources, or continuity of essential services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5ECEDD1015F4BD28AD48B7D797A8320"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>The authority granted under subsection (a) shall expire on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE3E553384DE84C159D4E12CB65384C01"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship to existing concession contract</header><text>Any procurement action conducted or contract awarded under this section shall be considered separate from, and shall not modify, amend, or extend the duration of, or provide any leasehold surrender interest or other benefit, under a concession contract issued under section 101913 of title 54, United States Code, or related authorities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF5FEDD5737154B4593094E528ED43B63"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="HF58BB8014C0A4D42907F61AF9A9E34DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorize the award of any concession contract or lease without full compliance with applicable concession contracting law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE601AFF15C20423B918731D11FCDD068"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent the Secretary from using competitive procedures if the Secretary determines such procedures to be in the best interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260316" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 16, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

