<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C3577EA5986493889DDAC77AB497759" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6528 IH: Tracking and Restricting Adversarial Circumvention of Embargoes Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6528</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require a report on the purchases of Iranian oil by the People’s Republic of China, support from entities and individuals in the People’s Republic of China for Iran’s ballistic missile program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HDBC37945F60C446599DF7CF52214D4B9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4633C77729F945BA9DED1630C1A1FFE5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tracking and Restricting Adversarial Circumvention of Embargoes Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H36F1E803E1644879AEEBBD4F0EF87F0D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header> <subsection id="HFA16D1018229438EB3E929AC0A2921A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and Secretary of the Treasury a report analyzing oil and ballistic missile-related transactions between the People’s Republic of China and the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAF5C6E692754E93873B1BAF31ED24FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H314E0601B55E4EF6803FBE9AA38B011A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the purchases of Iranian oil by the People’s Republic of China since 2020, including an assessment of the use of transshipment points and shell companies as methods to insulate the People’s Republic of China from sanctions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EECA07213784D3BB1AF1F68FB21947F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of significant financial transactions by entities in the People’s Republic of China related to the sale, supply, or transfer to Iran of chemical precursors and other materials that may support the ballistic missile program of Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1B6BDE7886F84861B1A34A59C5EE3D50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1278B8ACEB294E5F85322C863048CA81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52448BD1BC9C4A75934FC20E53510E36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H864380DBD752473F8A6A916EB64AD0F1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the submission of the report required by section 2, the Secretary of the Treasury shall determine whether the People’s Republic of China is conducting any sanctionable activities and report such determination to Congress. </text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

