<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC2F1312C178451BA5F6D6DB42952A78" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1157 IH: Commending the American Chemical Society on the occasion of its 150th anniversary and recognizing its many years of service to the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1157</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending the American Chemical Society on the occasion of its 150th anniversary and recognizing its many years of service to the United States.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas, on April 6, 1876, 35 chemists convened at the College of Pharmacy of the City of New York to found the American Chemical Society (ACS), establishing what would become one of the world’s foremost scientific organizations;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, for 150 years, the ACS has advanced the chemical enterprise by supporting American innovation, fostering research, and disseminating scientific knowledge through its internationally respected publications and programs;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the American Chemical Society was incorporated by an Act of Congress on January 1, 1938, thereby affirming its national importance and mission of promoting the broader chemistry community;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas chemistry, as the central science, connects and informs countless disciplines and plays an essential role in addressing challenges that affect every aspect of daily life;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas global challenges in public health, national security, and emerging technologies increasingly demand collaborative, science-based solutions, with chemistry providing a critical foundation for such advancements to ensure continued American leadership in science and innovation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the science of chemistry has the power to improve lives, strengthen communities, and make meaningful contributions that address critical societal and global issues;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas innovations in chemical research and development continue to generate economic growth and employment across numerous industries and sectors;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas chemists and chemistry professionals serve as catalysts for positive change—advancing discovery, expanding educational opportunity, and inspiring the next generation of scientific leaders; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the American Chemical Society has demonstrated long standing leadership in promoting innovation, environmental stewardship, and scientific advancement for the benefit of the United States and the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4E0F09CCD0044F639EB64544A70C5882"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HAACAEEF1C86042619D0DACDC84A4C0A6"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HA86A184F176D435A8BD0A2CDBBD231EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the American Chemical Society on the momentous occasion of its 150th anniversary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5073EF5EF66E4B4F9AEC44466D7F903C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the American Chemical Society for its enduring contributions to the scientific, educational, and economic strength of the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1026C82690DE46CAAD58EF32B3D5471A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms the importance of promoting science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education, expanding opportunities for students to pursue chemistry and related fields, and encouraging youth from all communities to pursue careers in these disciplines; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA6121279A7A4D03AECC58E5567F7320"><enum>(4)</enum><text>requests that the Clerk of the House of Representatives transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H32907950420F4318BDC18118A596E197"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President of the American Chemical Society, Rigoberto Hernandez;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4370DC10DB2042AF8659C8ACBD8AE955"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chief Executive Officer of the American Chemical Society, Albert Horvath; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H11B8FEF9961F42CBB09C13663455E0D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Chair of the Board of the American Chemical Society, Wayne Jones.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

