<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E2179F77C914A9381E085013C72A307" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1053 IH: Honoring Sweet Briar College on the 125th anniversary of its founding.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1053</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring Sweet Briar College on the 125th anniversary of its founding.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas February 9, 2026, marks the 125th anniversary of the founding of Sweet Briar College;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Sweet Briar College, in Amherst, Virginia, has been educating, inspiring, and empowering women for 125 years, since its founding in 1901;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Sweet Briar College has advanced the ideals of both the liberal arts and the sciences, its alumnae proving themselves a valuable resource to the Commonwealth, the United States, and the world;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Sweet Briar College’s many excellent programs, from a unique women's core leadership curriculum, to its ABET-accredited engineering program, to its working and academically immersive greenhouse, to its nationally recognized equestrian program, train and equip women to be consequential citizens and leaders;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Sweet Briar College’s 22 buildings on the National Register of Historic Places make the campus an architectural gem, and the leadership of the College stands foursquare for steady economic development in the region, for robust civic participation, and for sustainable environmental stewardship;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Sweet Briar College remembers its past, recalling the vision of Indiana Fletcher Williams as she endowed the College as a perpetual memorial to her daughter Daisy in institutional perpetuity, as well as Meta Glass and the other great leaders, faculty, and staff of the College, and the brilliant women schooled there, even as the College acknowledges the Monacan Indians at a special monument on campus and memorializes, in a sacred grove, the Enslaved Persons who are also part of the Sweet Briar story; and</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Sweet Briar College strides purposefully into the future, gracing the Commonwealth, the Nation, and the world with talented alumnae who remember their alma mater with graceful pride, even as they go forth to great things: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF6C45967ABD046C2941307C9189F26B8"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE4B186F0DA2B499CB2CF650F0E137864"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H06FC10867AEA41B8AECEAC89448A21D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hereby commends Sweet Briar College on the occasion of its 125th anniversary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B7E33EFA2E443BBAA47B5C60C9FC9E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the designation of Sweet Briar College Charter Day in honor of such anniversary;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9D7B2A5708C424293A075FF9DCC3AB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reminds this and future generations of the relevance and importance of Sweet Briar College’s vital mission and its enduring commitments to educating our female leaders of tomorrow; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H874F55DAC4CB4D1EA5E16686B07EB636"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes Sweet Briar College’s innumerable contributions to the Commonwealth of Virginia through its commitment to education, its numerous distinguished alumnae, and its enduring mission to maintain a community where women lead, making it undeniably a Category of One.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

