<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H995AAFD7C06F495FA4A231EEF82552EA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>87 HR 7021 IH: Critical Mineral Mining Education Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7021</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260112">January 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a new educational exchange program to strengthen domestic mining education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9FC0F4ACB6224F8AB7A9DA56AD40AF12" style="OLC"><section id="H1E4466C6129848DA8770CDC791A48C9F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Critical Mineral Mining Education Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB285324C3BCF4D80B0550C609BA8DB7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the United States mining industry and, more broadly, mining and mineral processing and refining, is widely reported as facing a significant personnel shortage. This shortage is driven by an aging workforce, declining numbers of graduates entering mining careers, and difficulty recruiting and retaining skilled workers. Fifty percent of the current mining workforce is expected to retire within the next 5 years. In 2023, only 14 United States universities and colleges had mining and mining engineer programs. Downstream segments, such as ore processing, refining, and metallurgy, are affected by the same workforce trends. Institutions and personnel from allied countries with mining expertise can share their knowledge and experience with the United States workforce through education exchange programs.</text></section><section id="HBF2AFD026D1442639FC70D8DC0CCB414"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/87/256">Public Law 87–256</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2451">22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 101 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFEDE2C95E0747B1BACF73CDA4EC48A4"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H29E80FC9D9C149F6B436A19783B542A1"><enum>101A.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HEB018BDB3D1049DEA3B87A59C55A36DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced degree</header><text>The term <term>advanced degree</term> means a degree from an institution of higher education that is a master’s or doctoral degree.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FDD78797E2A437B8E2227B454956092"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H574C5D35094F4121941BF704F78BED55"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given such term in section 7002(a)(3) of the Energy Act of 2020 (division Z of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)(3)</external-xref>); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D0D9D6492C64EFAB830DD9C9B9B4DBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes gold, and copper, and any other mineral or mineral material the Secretary of State determines—</text><clause id="H3E8C0E20ECB44879BB696C405E862135"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be essential to the economic or national security of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HE746CDD240544DCDA133EBA678A6CB72" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a supply chain vulnerable to disruption.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3697C9C5B89E43709FF45BEF1284236B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excess foreign currencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>excess foreign currencies</term> means foreign currencies, which, if acquired by the United States—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B9489FDFFB84978874118CF4DBD15D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would be in excess of the normal requirements of departments, agencies, and embassies of the United States for such currencies, as determined by the President; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5ED6AE674DCA45C0BA084C07E7C80753"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would be available for the use of the United States Government under applicable agreements with the foreign country concerned.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98E39367C6A24C23B70355100EE9031E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal employee</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0A6A060245A4352B610D83816D08EF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any employee described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of section 7342(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79E43DDD8D0E4F12BFB524A434492E73"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a person described in subparagraph (G) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88719D1B3DD0401C8F5D1F52F9DFCC5E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Government-sponsored international exchanges and training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Government-sponsored international exchanges and training</term> means the movement of people between countries, financed wholly or in part with United States Government funds—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D1C3D35C958440485FF1B9336BFE0F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to promote the sharing of ideas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EE3C47B3B6A4E7BB93C841A283B62B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop skills; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H372052F367D8475D8460A02B6E363C94"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to foster mutual understanding and cooperation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD430B7797922405D9CB20E1CC1694317"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93F40F1A943A4B2E8DF855400D139F44" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Historically black college and university</header><text>The term <term>historically Black college and university</term> has the meaning given the term <term>part B institution</term> in section 322(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CE6532435D34719AE7CF064809460E9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Mining education program</header><text>The term <term>Mining Education Program</term> means an academic program related to the mining industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17C8554A8B114423A7C944DF0A20074B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Mining industry</header><text>The term <term>mining industry</term> means the mining industry of the United States, which consists of activities related to naturally occurring metal and nonmetal critical minerals, including—</text><subparagraph id="H05323AD2B64744D2962437FC533CB062"><enum>(A)</enum><text>geological mapping, geophysical surveying, geochemical sampling, and management of geological data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H640A16A13144480E8B2C7C5941AB78A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mineral system analysis, exploration, and resource delineation, including exploratory drilling and resource estimation and classification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE92F492164CD4C85AEC41A1769282650"><enum>(C)</enum><text>project development, feasibility studies, financing, and permitting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19EAADF68E924B9DB2022922E770171F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>mine construction, extraction, and operational support activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6ADA5EC0FEBA4107AA2CCA13D350FE05"><enum>(E)</enum><text>mineral processing, beneficiation, smelting, refining, chemical conversion, and separation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01387A36F71E4C90A011A152EB8A03F2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>material conversion and advanced materials manufacturing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFF68917323D45DBAD380CFF7AE6E61A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>transportation, logistics, and handling of intermediate and finished material products; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26A8ADAC52A34207820EC6B5B5ACBC5F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>reclamation, remediation, reuse, recycling, and recovery of materials from primary and secondary sources, including mine waste and end-of-life products. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H642EBB6CFC4F4F61AD56EF4C0E7D8BCA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Mining profession</header><text>The term <term>mining profession</term> means the body of jobs directly related to the mining industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFB9EBBEC7174491BA5848954F4590F6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Minority serving institution</header><text>The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means an eligible institution under section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE18E394042FF413C9CD2FD8BD593884B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Critical Mineral Mining Fellowship Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35A7FA4ACEE940219259105647150F12"><section id="HC73D04EBBEB3453395654AEC857DA534"><enum>116.</enum><header>Critical Mineral Mining Fellowship Program</header><subsection id="H32574780D8E546B184B9FEE8108622CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized to be established the Critical Mineral Mining Fellowship Program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fellowship Program</quote>) within the J. William Fulbright Educational Exchange Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD036D74CAFF4416B8A4EA6F42DF56B9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Fellowship Program are—</text><paragraph id="HF7F0EC9AC23D47F6838D5FABFBEA24A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to advance foreign policy priorities of the United States by promoting studies, research, and international exchange in the mining industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC7829AFB84E42F7961ADA4F7E6F24B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to send United States students to mining institutions abroad to build the capacity of the United States mining workforce;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52FEBC78672442988E838D0B5F443B9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to develop a robust and skilled workforce that can support and fill the gaps of the United States’ growing domestic critical mineral supply chain; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24AF753B81BB47C69F9BE8059D3C17D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to reduce dependency on foreign energy and critical mineral supplies and enhance competitiveness of the United States within the global critical mineral marketplace.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EC9BAE7CD824DB2BE32C5651692E831"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Education and Cultural Affairs of the Department of State (referred to in this section as the <quote>Bureau</quote>) shall administer the Fellowship Program in accordance with policy guidelines established by the Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board (referred to in this section as the <quote>Board</quote>), in consultation with binational Fulbright Commissions, mining industry leaders, institutions of higher education, foreign governments, and United States embassies in eligible countries.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B6E8C0BA47845D693C14A59492E59B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of fellows</header><paragraph id="H6DBEDF37790D4BE28C5A24E86E4FF3F4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Bureau shall determine the number of fellows selected for the Fellowship Program each year. The Board shall select qualified individuals to participate in the Fellowship Program. In selecting the fellows, the Board should ensure geographic representation to ensure region-specific specialties are developed.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FDB6257C0A9442E94F02357D06B3402"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>All fellows shall meet one of the following criteria:</text><subparagraph id="H4BC67D71D8804994B3852E2D01BD0CA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Have a conferred bachelors degree, or equivalent degree, before the start of the Fellowship period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE505D40656949FC9BE8F705C0D146E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Be a student who is currently enrolled in a United States institution of higher education completing an advanced degree in the field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics or a field related to the mining industry.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6C4B2E9BE264F448848133EB9162FD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Have had a conferred postdoctoral degree during the 5-year period immediately preceding the Fellowship period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46B5520D21C64002B78AAAD22AB503DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required intent</header><text>Upon completing the Fellowship Program, each fellow shall demonstrate their intent to seek employment in a mining profession that directly benefits the growth, progress, and development of the United States mining industry—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03F3173C06E74FD2A26677C03C08FCEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the United States Government; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD5F25716AB34DCBB0C7899D05F8EB0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at a United States-based nongovernmental organization, academic institution, private sector company, or other organization that has been approved by the Bureau.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FFD548A1F214083BD9DC1DA55361067"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible universities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States students shall attend universities approved by the Bureau, in consultation with the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, that have a mining program and are located in a foreign country. To the extent practicable, the Bureau should prioritize enrollment in higher education mining programs in—</text><subparagraph id="HDE3584455E574430A94C4FF184882C01" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>member countries in the Minerals Security Partnership; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52F76B66B96C4F40833AAC49F8FE23EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any additional countries identified by the Bureau, in consultation with the congressional committees referred to in this paragraph, as containing sufficiently qualified mining programs .</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H573EA2F5ACF14BA0997397B4F84309CC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Bureau shall conduct outreach at United States undergraduate and graduate higher education institutions the Bureau determines are likely to produce a range of qualified applicants to be sent abroad.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEA565EABF004498952E975CEED082DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Structure</header><paragraph id="HB303CC2BEA834D419E3EC76CCD176755"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Work plan</header><text>To carry out the purposes described in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HC058404D04F64A58B10B3E69F835BAE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each fellow selected pursuant to subsection (d)(1) shall be encouraged to arrange placement in a mining education program at an eligible foreign university; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31352C74EA994566A21C0D02FD82EFAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each fellow shall—</text><clause id="H3F6A1E78F60C4842B13A86F19245A453"><enum>(i)</enum><text>participate in advanced coursework, research projects, and practical training opportunities, including internships, offered by the host institution;</text></clause><clause id="HBB25FCBE44E645C5B7234DA38EA785B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engage with faculty advisors and industry partners to gain hands-on experience through internships, laboratory work, and field studies relevant to the mining industry;</text></clause><clause id="HE6E816C0A14D42F98773D2B9A223042D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>serve as a cultural and academic ambassador of the United States by fostering mutual understanding within the host country’s academic and professional mining community;</text></clause><clause id="H3CA50D3F871C415A925307B7A9BA7CFC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>participate in professional development activities, such as conferences, workshops, and seminars, to expand knowledge of global best practices in mining engineering and related fields; and</text></clause><clause id="H4ED8CB73CD7947DEB47E70E59D8043DC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>build and strengthen networks with international peers, faculty, and industry professionals to facilitate ongoing collaboration and knowledge exchange; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H722E1D45FCA1487C93F5B363B108747B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Bureau shall, for each fellow, approve a work plan that identifies the target objectives for the fellow, including specific duties and responsibilities relating to such objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF813EF4BA5274634B8926D98064487FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fellowship period</header><subparagraph id="H6262418A82BB44B0BF2CD8AFBD295D49"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each fellowship under this section shall continue for a period determined by the Bureau, which, whenever feasible, shall not be shorter than 1 year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB9DCAD5D119443E9CD0687786E43A42"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau may grant a renewal for a second year, in consultation with the relevant United States embassy or the Fulbright Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B78DF2F2688414DB1C833BB9B9CA955"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Fellowship award</header><text>The Bureau shall provide each fellow under this section with an allowance equal to the amount needed for the fellow’s reasonable costs during the fellowship period, including—</text><paragraph id="HC877474C5CFA4AF59BF9D694A9C84934"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mandatory university fees, including tuition, associated with his or her studies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBCE18DD68184D84B87249EC0DED95B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>living expenses, including housing, basic food costs, and daily transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H922A60949C074F50A958A764CBD3FAAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>essential textbooks and other academic materials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5491B1FBDE440948DF965E678B8DD8F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>mandatory visa application, immigration fees, and other essential pre-departure requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FB5D181A496432794803E929854EBC5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>relocation expenses, including travel by air or by rail;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD22F5E25C3AF4539A4EF1DF52088A1C4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a research allowance, including essential travel to field sites and laboratory work; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A969A8979F04DFE86EF803C2C184566"><enum>(7)</enum><text>other reasonable costs approved by the Bureau.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13D3FD9F2E554C04A494FBF265C7AEB0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the completion of the Fellowship Program by the initial cohort of fellows selected pursuant to subsection (d), and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes information regarding the implementation of the Fellowship Program, including—</text><paragraph id="H14B7E271E60A439DA35D85C8AA1E9557"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the demographics and geographical origins of the cohort of fellows who completed a fellowship during the reporting period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8271E6D0BCB44513B94E324CE41C6D88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of academic placements selected and their relation to the development of the United States region-specific specialties under the Fellowship Program, including participant feedback on program implementation and lessons learned; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F19F6606F6D4AEEBB5D7028544297D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan for factoring lessons learned and acquired skills based knowledge into future programming.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H9F0D9C4DDE624D2D970911B09A1D69AE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Visiting Mining Scholars Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, as amended by sections 3 and 4, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB13841A4DCA40B5B5A0D83E4422F728"><section id="H712B02CF2BD94BBD8B2AEC81C821B76A"><enum>117.</enum><header>Visiting Mining Scholars Program</header><subsection id="H1B7DD9B3494246318012C7DFCEAF7D1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized to be established the Visiting Mining Scholars Program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Visiting Scholars Program</quote>) within the J. William Fulbright Educational Exchange Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H65B11BE5227047AB8CE73D971C6AD91B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Visiting Scholars Program is to bring mining academics and professionals to the United States—</text><paragraph id="HCD667EEAFA4E43BCB591BCC44ED9BC5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to build and expand United States mining education programs at higher education institutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF5CC2C1783496E8BB4ABA5B60CDAA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to bolster workforce development programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1847C7D1613946CABA5E243035697877"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to advance research and development initiatives in the mining industry and adjacent fields.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDD97A455E1443F8A704849F03A474FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs of the Department of State (referred to in this section as the <quote>Bureau</quote>) shall administer the Visiting Scholars Program in accordance with policy guidelines established by the Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board (referred to in this section as the <quote>Board</quote>), in consultation with binational Fulbright Commissions, mining industry leaders, higher education institutions, foreign governments, and United States embassies in eligible countries.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB6E0D77FD54F4D4FA26A642E93F4FED9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of Visiting Mining Scholars</header><paragraph id="HC5B8DAA8744D4701BBB902253CFE07C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall select qualified individuals to participate in the Visiting Scholars Program, who shall be foreign nationals—</text><subparagraph id="H935862A8EF394D49B2A8845989C569B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>currently employed as mining professionals, practitioners, or operators outside of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21B70F7D5F9541F3A32B8A3DFABBCD8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>currently employed as academics working at institutions of higher education in foreign countries with mining education programs, as approved by a Fulbright Commission or United States embassy, in consultation with the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H244CE818167B4461A4645A5B4EE44846"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Number of Fellows</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall determine the number of fellows selected each year, which, whenever feasible, shall be not fewer than 10.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E29808EF89245CEB6CD74583905E15E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Critereia</header><text>Visiting mining scholars shall be foreign nationals—</text><subparagraph id="HBECC264E8E344E23A15E657BD08B72AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of a country in which an existing Fulbright Foreign Student Program operates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AB02CC3E5F249079AAC573769372EC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>of a country that has expertise, specialized knowledge, or engages in practices that could benefit the United States mining industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAAB414BE3D048DDB48D3A470D7BD3E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preferred Countries</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Board should prioritize selection of visiting mining scholars who live or work in—</text><subparagraph id="HFCBCFF2C99BF430ABF229D5E7A449217"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member country in the Minerals Security Partnership; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H195F6F5104AF4399AFEB04F56627811C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any additional country identified by the Bureau, in consultation with the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, as containing individuals who have academic expertise, specialized knowledge, or engage in practices that could benefit the United States mining industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46061D57D4B34A129FBB5DAE87DB1E75"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Bureau shall conduct outreach in coordination with appropriate United States embassies, mining industry leaders, and mining institutions abroad that are likely to produce a range of qualified applicants to come to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD3CDC9F069644EEA416CEC65EF87D9D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Structure</header><paragraph id="H61D9EC2E9961428F9816A43B7F797EA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Work plan</header><text>To carry out the purposes described in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H97C698B3C3A24BD8B9857BD24A84145B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each individual selected pursuant to subsection (d)(1), and who is coming to the United States as a visiting mining scholar—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H849966E807E94C4AA177BD0CDC69F13E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall arrange placement in a United States academic institution approved by the Bureau; and</text></clause><clause id="HA427A24AA41F4687B3417E4C744DAB47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>should—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2C92CE15F8A4D8AA265A71D6E77F6CC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with faculty members to provide technical assistance on how to develop or expand a mining education program at the host institution of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="H838B13605EFC4C1F9108704A54FAFA52"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assist in the development and review of mining education curricula, including course syllabi, laboratory modules, and fieldwork components;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3116556154E3448FBEB3E501419B10FF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>participate in collaborative research projects with faculty, students, and third-party research institutions focusing on innovative mining technologies, sustainable mining practices, and resource management;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFB1A032CAED346149211FE6BB36ECE30"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>facilitate partnerships between the host institution and mining organizations, government agencies, and other institutions to foster academic exchange, research collaboration, and workforce development;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8782C8F2004842058126E9BDD6B2AEA2"><enum>(V)</enum><text>mentor undergraduate and graduate students interested in mining education, offering guidance on academic projects and career development; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC5EC723A96964526A08277F097DC0B09"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>contribute to the development of outreach programs aimed at increasing awareness of the mining industry as a career path and to increase awareness of the types of mining professions available; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AE1537C219F4EE18B1980650B7CC88D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Bureau shall, for each scholar, approve a work plan that identifies the target objectives for the scholar, including specific duties and responsibilities relating to such objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16CDD08BD1414D7A967B0E5141C661AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible united states institutions</header><text>Visiting mining scholars shall be placed in a higher education institution approved by the Bureau that—</text><subparagraph id="HA1CABE8AE5DB4E95B60D5DF479E4F5FF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrates a commitment to develop or expand academic programs in the mining industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AF2ABA9C88C4D43AF3AA6CBCE8CC3C7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>possesses existing faculty expertise or research activity in the mining industry or related extractive fields;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H108BA1CF57EB41ABBDDD5CC3B3B0238C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides institutional support and resources, such as laboratory facilities, field sites, or equipment, relevant to mining education and research, including in geology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DDEC9A88A2D479A86C11207F2CC6485" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrates a commitment to integrate the visiting scholar into curriculum development, faculty training, or workforce pipeline initiatives in mining;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE63C7FADADE9473D83047AEEE1FBE9B3" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>demonstrates a plan for sustaining mining or critical mineral resources programs beyond the duration of the visiting scholar’s placement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11F5CBC1947E4208B256EF7DF5CA61D3" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>shows evidence of student interest or regional workforce demand for mining education programs or training; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B4EBF83DAF4457A9DCF831E7DBD9185" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>agrees to provide mentoring, administrative support, and opportunities for the visiting scholar to engage with students, faculty, and local industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC80B84F8D8C445DF89B8E52F305BC780"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scholarship Period</header><subparagraph id="HA226CFE6993242D4A172AA283913124D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The duration of each scholarship period under this section shall be determined by the Bureau and shall, whenever feasible, be not less than three months and not more than one year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61ABCC028FB74939BED0043FD529CFAF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Any exception to the duration of the scholarship period described in subparagraph (A) shall be submitted by the visiting mining scholar to and approved by the Bureau before such exception takes effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95E156D5875B455E81DA3B391B4F0688"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Scholarship award</header><text>The Bureau shall provide each visiting mining scholar under this section with an allowance to cover the scholar’s reasonable costs of living during the scholarship period.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FDE46286A524C82B2ABA4C0772A67E2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the completion of the Visiting Scholars Program by the initial cohort of scholars selected pursuant to subsection (d)(1), and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes information on the implementation of the Visiting Scholars Program, including—</text><paragraph id="H1223B551671C4629B70BAFFCAFF30F03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the demographics and geographical origins of the cohort of scholars who completed a Visiting Scholars Program during the reporting period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BCFC9B3CE274102B023D287AC673E90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States universities at which visiting scholars were placed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H236987D7EB9B4AC19766FA7AD272FDE7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the foreign universities or other post-graduate institutions from which the cohort of visiting scholars were chosen;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFDEDFF6FC434FDC96D9A43B4B68021C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of academic placements selected under the Visiting Scholars Program, including participant feedback on program implementation and lessons learned; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E364F8839C14F2C8441679A17CC869B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a plan for factoring lessons learned into future programming.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H82C49C80FE094CA9B273FCEDA7781C24"><enum>6.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments to the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/87/256">Public Law 87–256</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2451">22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H21DC83A9A7CD48DBBD56472F109B7DDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 104(g) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2454">22 U.S.C. 2454(g)</external-xref>), by striking paragraph (5);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA138F6CE52C4E9FAE4756D1561F4B38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 108A(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2458a">22 U.S.C. 2458a(a)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF4A5BEA89C64323B5AE0E713788702B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(1)</quote> before Congress;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7F954C4AB8E413D92FABBCD8125A08E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC72B33D721EE4095BE98B26B00FDD048"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) as paragraph (1), (2), and (3), respectively;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9038BB1F3DEC47AEBC598DD86B7DF829"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 112 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2460">22 U.S.C. 2460</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H007C822E6E084634B058E5D8BC523E19"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3E1A36DA9F84DC2BDB65976553368FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="H9A25F9422AF645A497195E5E01D17C10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the first paragraph designated as paragraph (10), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="H7652F9DB13A044D2B661740E9A664AC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the second paragraph designated as paragraph (10)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H828068ED86F544CF9B2879C6A91363CA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(10)</quote> and inserting <quote>(11)</quote>; and </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83CC04E97EA14ABFBF0EFB2D21EA1A5D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE4057C6820E9452084A0515EF3367A7C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9356E278D4774F2F88EDAEB88C190299"><paragraph id="H095428CF01B6414D83A8933523DE837C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the Critical Mineral Mining Fellowship Program established under section 116, which provides funding for studies, research, and international exchange for students seeking or completing advanced degrees from United States higher education institutions in self-arranged placements with universities with mining education programs in foreign countries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC9D24B8137A4F22B7F9086FB6463D34"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the Visiting Mining Scholars Program established under section 117, which provides funding for international mining academics, practitioners, professionals and operators in self-arranged placements with universities in the United States.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53180FAF6A13426CB9EB4D0F2D75C6A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H608ACD1DBE98433CAB71F3057E4876CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (2);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26B4D4F14F324651A9AB30C7D7462632"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (11) as paragraphs (2) through (10), respectively; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C0990DFAFFD4BA6A29EFC054B3606B9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), as redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (5)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7EC0F01C0D44A0E9CB7B7D0D6C15A41"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 115(d)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2465">22 U.S.C. 2465(d)(2)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FA5697A29D94A0F915AC71FD72FAAA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81EB35A1549C463489CCAF51BA77F449"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7ADC321FC70A4957A69479605AC3FB1C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>(A) <header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">In general</header-in-text>.—</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CE769156AB147A1B789F14CE58317DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), and moving such clauses 2 ems to the left.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HBAD8AA189A5842F690BF8D19D749B35C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2035 for the purpose of carrying out the Critical Mineral Mining Fellowship Program and the Visiting Mining Scholars Program established under sections 116 and 117 of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, as added by sections 4 and 5.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

