<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GOE25891-8HY-C1-JGG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3347 IS: Flight Delay and Cancellation Compensation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Department of Transportation to require airlines to provide consumers experiencing significant flight disruptions or cancellations cash compensation, free rebooking, and reimbursement for amenities, such as meals, lodging for overnight delays, and transportation to and from lodging.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flight Delay and Cancellation Compensation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7050acdada7e43d9941055f7c7ceb2f6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Flight Delay and Cancellation Compensation</header><subsection id="id665ea0754cf04749bb4ddc2e9bad0b7e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Aviation rulemaking committee</header><paragraph id="ida7b88c388ca34259bf077830b00b2586"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish an Aviation Rulemaking Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to review and develop recommendations regarding the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2386ea2a4fa2415e8c17d3690d1d8256"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation of the requirements of section 512 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (49 U.S.C. note prec. 42301), as amended by subsection (e) of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff69a7226d1a475aa845e1730b0c5b86"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring that air carriers and foreign air carriers provide passengers with the following when a flight operated by such air carrier or a foreign air carrier is cancelled or significantly delayed and such cancellation or delay is directly attributable to such air carrier or foreign air carrier:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4899ca3bb7c5411a8d4d9e716e463ec6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cash compensation of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73886f796d2249979e49619a7342ca93"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least $300 for a delay of more than 3 hours but less than 6 hours; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd8490ae69ee4da3a1660c30da5fc162"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least $600 for a delay of 6 hours or more.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7195dd6d7731496ba8a136c1cad1a4c3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Free rebooking.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida50b57901a7f444e8b8cc4a4505f998c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Committee shall consist of members appointed by the Administrator, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="id97c2ac410b674d3cbf2db5a84e806e3e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Air carriers and foreign air carriers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39ecfb0b4d29478c974f91f1c1dfc7ae"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Airport operators.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id401cc17b596e4f969894982bb5740871"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Representatives of consumer protection organizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69df3aafb42f404a9bf579e9985c289c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Representatives of the Office of the Secretary of the Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id908c62604c2a411cb5b91ec71dac7581"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Representatives of the Federal Trade Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id534886617bfd47bfabccf62f79d0ee98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to the Administrator and the Secretary</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Committee shall submit to the Administrator and the Secretary a report detailing the consensus findings and recommendations of the Committee. Such report shall include recommendations regarding each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id2cab5feedad84016a0d9ff0d5f00c9dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A requirement that air carriers and foreign air carriers provide cash compensation to passengers impacted by cancelled or significantly delayed flights comparable to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48f76e365f1f4b46aa0871ed724a815c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Canadian Transportation Agency (CTA) Air Passenger Protection Regulations, including a requirement that the minimum cash compensation is $300 for a delay of more than 3 hours but less than 6 hours and $600 for a delay of 6 hours or more; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2eb87f1a04347d58bd39d58412e7e0f"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulation (EC) No <fraction>261/2004</fraction> of the European Parliament and of the Council.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1be5cbd6faa4b5fbaa048a2238ba576"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A plan to implement the requirements of Article 19 of the Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Carriage by Air (Montreal Convention).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f88e1a342034f37bad29cc50e43f2c2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A requirement that air carriers and foreign air carriers cover the costs of amenities, such as meals, lodging for overnight delays, and transportation to and from lodging, when a flight is cancelled or significantly delayed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98d8c43028da4669a570c1d89c22a075"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A process for determining whether a cancelled or significantly delayed flight is directly attributable to such air carrier or foreign air carrier.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide418a6010abc40ce87154622e6630e08"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The development of an educational process to ensure that passengers receive the correct information from the air carrier or foreign air carrier in a timely manner regarding the compensation and reimbursement options they are eligible to receive in the case of cancelled or significantly delayed flights.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1de9a1db2bb8460cb4779018ccb126ed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>How to ensure that the process for passengers to receive cash compensation and reimbursement for amenities for cancelled or significantly delayed flights is clear, simple, straightforward, and prompt.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ab2e16060bf457ab2b2db59b2cb35cb"><enum>(G)</enum><text>How to ensure that the process for passengers to receive cash compensation from an air carrier or foreign air carrier for provable direct or consequential damages resulting from the disappearance of, damage to, or delay in delivery of a passenger's personal property, including baggage, is clear, simple, straightforward, and prompt.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a4b4c1f3c234b0683a4fd000adceadf"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Other recommendations determined appropriate by the Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4810d49decc443be83da62ea49bcc3fc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id141fb239fb374004948453606b9c81c1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of proposed rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Committee submits the report under subsection (a)(3), the Secretary, taking into account the recommendations of the Committee included in such report, shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to implement—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e103256b3044f97a6f44ad620f7fb36"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirements of section 512 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (49 U.S.C. note prec. 42301), as amended by subsection (e) of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cb27f41e3c8422d82062faf2bd5d56d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the matter described in subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa2b55bb484a4bc5bc2abd7f6beb1f3f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other recommendations of the Committee as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4430d0ec62ce41749580470c0b11850f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of interim final rule until effective date of final rule</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02aed9179b574190ad20dcd5f91ff3ed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate an interim final rule that, at a minimum, includes the following requirements when a flight operated by an air carrier or a foreign air carrier is cancelled or significantly delayed:</text><clause id="idfcea47671e884e8dbda1cc5297682c47" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The air carrier or foreign air carrier shall provide $750 in cash compensation to any passenger impacted by such cancellation or delay if such cancellation or delay is directly attributable to such air carrier or foreign air carrier.</text></clause><clause id="id980c73565d1e45038ebacb9628bcaf5d" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The air carrier or foreign air carrier shall find a seat on another flight offered by the same air carrier or foreign air carrier or another air carrier or foreign air carrier or on an alternative means of transportation at no additional cost to the passenger, at the earliest available opportunity, if the passenger so chooses, for any passenger impacted by cancellation or delay if such cancellation or delay is directly attributable to such air carrier or foreign air carrier.</text></clause><clause id="idb82585a3db6d4ac49310c2890d43226b" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The air carrier or foreign air carrier shall provide a meal or meal credit to any passenger impacted by such cancellation or delay.</text></clause><clause id="idbf59eb57c801460cb5b171826ad3d92a" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>In the case of a passenger affected by an overnight flight cancellation or significantly delayed flight, the air carrier or foreign air carrier shall provide the passenger with—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6ff04e9197c4bc685d2d22f6bc64d84"><enum>(I)</enum><text>each of the requirements described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91f0de9c4c374525b710abf29b37b6ee"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complimentary hotel accommodations or reimbursement for lodging costs; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf03ed19127ed421aa81887bed483aaa1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>complimentary ground transportation to and from the hotel.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef22e699f9754c6fbeb25c863556e909"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interim final rule promulgated under subparagraph (A) shall be effective during the period beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this section and ending on the effective date of the final rule described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4825bc5a06ba4e6a80cea27396b7bb4f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, and every 6 months thereafter until the Secretary promulgates a final rule under subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the status of the rulemaking under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), including the development of the requirements for air carriers and foreign air carriers.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9a976ad7743140e396007728386bc4bd"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id349b25d19a2044878e77a7199ed97848"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idace6645aae1a453aa1ed9b05874aa041"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Air carrier</header><text>The term <quote>air carrier</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 40102(a) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3af91ed86b834377b3c1c490803ed881"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idb2a4c17cc2cb42a3a132315b0c724ead"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id825d7f365ae54ef287c45f40f4490bd3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef6a0d11fe35450a9c18c0b58b226ef5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc0cb35e3e396463badd32f969200f41a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f438821404546d199e281eb02ce72e4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign air carrier</header><text>The term <quote>foreign air carrier</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 40102(a) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d17144e5ff64e9a93e0295e0b8d0730"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Significantly delayed</header><text>The term <quote>significantly delayed</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 512 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (49 U.S.C. note prec. 42301).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2bf7fd09a49a4a55a693358ec56b378a"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb6c5a5f78b524f79b60a63c1497330b2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 512 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (49 U.S.C. note prec. 42301) is amended by striking subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="idba2ad6851e364eaf83044843f8cbc1ad"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>For the purposes of implementing this section and such section 512, the term <term>air carrier</term> under such section 512 is deemed to include foreign air carriers.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

