<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25G32-7GS-3L-SGY">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3130 IS: Veterans TBI Adaptive Care Opportunities Nationwide Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3130</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251106">November 6, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on
                    Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a program to award
            grants to eligible entities to develop, implement, and evaluate approaches and
            methodologies for prospective randomized control trials for neurorehabilitation
            treatments for the treatment of chronic mild traumatic brain injury in veterans, and for
            other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4224EE1E808549F4A701BAE5CDE84340">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="HBD57AEE4F6824411A4EA590B4459F306">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans TBI Adaptive Care Opportunities Nationwide Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="H205CD40C5BA64129BA7213E43E1A3200">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Department of Veterans Affairs grant program for supplemental
                neurorehabilitation approaches to chronic mild TBI treatment</header>
            <subsection id="H9B99E823067C47CC85779E16D248A7B1">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a grant program (to be known as the <quote>TBI Innovation Grant Program</quote>) to award grants to eligible entities for the development, implementation, and evaluation of approaches and methodologies for prospective randomized control trials for neurorehabilitation treatments for the treatment of chronic mild TBI (in this section referred to <quote>mTBI</quote>) in veterans.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H459DDE28234A4141865999E0DF87B021">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Duration</header>
 <text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out the grant program under this section shall terminate at the end of the three-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H9B84F1C4B60447F2BCDBD2A7720CD95C">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Use of funds</header>
 <text>An eligible entity in receipt of a grant under this section shall use amounts awarded under such grant to support activities that include—</text>
                <paragraph id="H9AEF8F42FE044462B044231DBE5714EA">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>designing and testing novel or integrative treatments for mTBI that prioritize patient-centered care, including non-pharmacological therapies;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H94B75FA3321744C5B0122AD40CC46D92">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>conducting clinical studies and assessments to measure the effectiveness of funded approaches—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H1084D3FF2D6640B2BCB0CE54FCC9A88A">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>to improve mental health outcomes among veterans;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CEA6C6099224CF4BD73F0D202E4814F"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce suicidality and common risk factors for completing suicide, including depression and substance use disorders among veterans; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HEE6922358C594B09A2A361DB3E35F7E4">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to mitigate long-term effects of mTBI;</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CDFFD4A54CD428887C349F602EF825D"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>providing training for clinicians and outreach to veterans and their families to improve awareness and accessibility of innovative mTBI treatments; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H36443F3EEFC54D90A96408ED475E0400">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>establishing partnerships with community organizations, academic institutions, and health care facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs to implement and evaluate best practices.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H119B918810CC47A0B424AF88273F8F8D">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Limitation on grant amount</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not award an eligible entity a grant under this section in an amount that exceeds $5,000,000 per fiscal year.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H4ABEC42D69844399A6C869696C46C34F">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Priority</header>
 <text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that the Secretary determines have demonstrated experience in delivering or researching effective treatments for mTBI.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H67110FEAE3D5485A810A319F847BB762">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Program administration</header>
                <paragraph id="HC48AABEF73254072BB19883AA24081C3">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Applications</header>
 <text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary determines appropriate, including a detailed description of—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H24511D8E7D91455FB5BF71BF059C89D1">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>proposed activities;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFB396927CEB44FFB321AD7332CAD952"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>expected outcomes; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HF1A5DC76ABE14E34B1E119E70011ECB1">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>plans for evaluating effectiveness.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4655327D816B4D4E8F43CBF8D4F50897"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Periodic reports</header> <text>An eligible entity in receipt of a grant under this section shall, not less frequently than annually, submit to the Secretary a report that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H83DDE40659D9464981588E2F7747438F">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a description of how the eligible entity used such grant;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H368D5A94F36C486E9C90038D4C179BD0"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>a summary of the progress of activities funded with amounts from such grant; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HC682C23DE0094590B9410D537D79DFE2">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>measured outcomes relating to such activities.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D6E309342114E7D885C569C7B39662E"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Oversight; annual evaluations</header> <text>The Secretary shall—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H9853656F32154E3E8F3DDF54AB34B39A">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>ensure rigorous oversight with respect to the grant program under this section; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H9C51F87E49714BD1B2AF29D049C9CAE2">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>on an annual basis during the period in which the authority to carry out the grant program is effective, evaluate the efficacy of activities funded with a grant awarded under such program.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="H0D589DF2CB404E3DBFF978A367830D43">
                <enum>(g)</enum>
                <header>Coordination with mental health services of Department of Veterans
                    Affairs</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the grant program under this section aligns with the Staff Sergeant Parker Gordon Fox Suicide Prevention Grant Program of the Department under section 201 of the Commander John Scott Hannon Veterans Mental Health Care Improvement Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/171">Public Law 116–171</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1720F">38 U.S.C. 1720F</external-xref> note)—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H5E868FA0791A481EBDB0210C8CC9EB94">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to provide for cohesive and comprehensive support for veterans with mTBI and associated mental health conditions; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H01CF963908434B1B988F73F0EB128D39">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>to increase research and development on integrated mTBI and mental health interventions outside of the scope of traditional pathways, interventions, programs, procedures, and pharmaceuticals of the Department.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id693a4439438346169d5bcbc5a3ee9e47">
                <enum>(h)</enum>
                <header>Annual review</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than annually during the duration of the grant program under this section, the Secretary shall review the effectiveness of such program to determine the potential of such program for continuation or expansion.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HA8ECB59A41764C4E80F2FE4BC091A77D">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
                <header>Reports to Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text>
                <paragraph id="HE5F6D55F66B7456C980EB20BBF6B5882">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the findings of the activities reported under subsection (f)(2); and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H89DAA2A273D742BE9358E06EEA712CD7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the recommendations of the Secretary with respect to policy and programmatic improvements to services of the Department of Veterans Affairs to treat TBI among veterans.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H1030622F54BB46CB9C6CBA762BD7886A">
                <enum>(j)</enum>
                <header>Regulations</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection commented="no" id="H42B0F407E5AB4F649372063B065E7C37">
                <enum>(k)</enum>
                <header>Funding</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H5BB1693ACA9843D0A8234C1F4FC810FB">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Available amounts</header>
 <text>The Secretary may carry out the grant program under this section using amounts available to the Secretary for general mental health care programs.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H2AC00A577D8B4BC4AF3D82E75487B75F">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $30,000,000 for fiscal years 2026 through 2028 to carry out the grant program under this section, which shall remain available until expended.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H46D91076F65748C1B760E868F02D6E88">
                <enum>(l)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE82E6E0602104EF0A35167AB85B75908"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Eligible entity</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means any of the following:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H60C8D7AB807E4C069B8E1357565F240F">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>A nonprofit organization.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAACADDDAC7F42299F891AA9AE3BB93D"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>An academic institution engaged in research with respect to TBI.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H6064F2D495F34647B831A8494CC4E47C">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>A non-Department of Veterans Affairs health care provider with expertise in neurorehabilitative therapies.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HD1EEA5F3901A4DE6AB096F58962CC8AA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>An entity the Secretary determines appropriate for an award of a grant under this section.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" id="H092C9DF74E9B4CCD8343877D9586BE4C">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>TBI</header>
 <text>The term <term>TBI</term> means traumatic brain injury.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D6FDCEFD608458E99882D6717097060"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Treatment</header> <text>The term <term>treatment</term>, with respect to TBI, means clinical interventions, therapeutic devices, or rehabilitation care provided directly to a veteran with TBI.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB84643181F774722A9103E6F70CAE75D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Veteran</header>
 <text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

