<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HAAE3C392B1C641A1B88EFF497434661C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7574 EH: ELO Realignment and Strategic Engagement Reform Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7574</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide for the reorganization and realignment of the Engagement, Liaison, and Outreach Office of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HC7CE0CBE9AEA4A448BCE9185D0AA8CF0" style="OLC">
<section id="HBB5C0A19A364402BA2B559959D243D0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ELO Realignment and Strategic Engagement Reform Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H689073D1AA0F471A9DD0D42266C0A075"><enum>2.</enum><header>Plan for reorganization and realignment of DHS Engagement, Liaison, and Outreach Office</header> <subsection id="H361E5C6786964A0F8E5867292891035C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a comprehensive plan to carry out the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HF5C387100153471DA8484E50B531D1F7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of redundant or non-essential positions, programs, or functions within the Engagement, Liaison, and Outreach office, including how reorganization of the Office will address such redundant or non-essential positions, programs, or functions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FFA18E3C3CC43B1BB35CE7F71EC3714"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Realign the essential functions and personnel of the ELO Office within the Partner Engagement directorate of I&amp;A.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE41B45159C214C56BF3F7AD81EC4F4C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improve the management and coordination of strategic relationships with priority law enforcement agencies, including by carrying out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H605EBEC0AB374D7786DDE3DBDAB33142"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establishing clear communication protocols.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5CF5540CB3242E9AFA9B0650B2F1F64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Centralizing points of contact for law enforcement engagement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H143274B8F7234246844D2B1214C18963"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Enhancing information-sharing mechanisms.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF2AB01ACE21940F8A8D7F23D578EF016"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Reducing duplication of outreach across Department of Homeland Security components.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59D8FE9561034951A60D751922584E59"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Improving accountability and performance metrics related to stakeholder engagement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H59A68A7A753F47028B053F4798CEE3D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan requirements</header><text>The plan required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9E6CC621F6374940A457AFB0A18EBD69"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Organizational analysis justifying the reorganization and realignment, including cost-benefit estimates, under paragraph (1) of such subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED058069289343F993B270410EBAEC56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Detailed staffing proposals, including reassignment plans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FFE810180BA4C14B74C7273738A9731" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A transition timeline for implementing the realignment within the Partner Engagement directorate of I&amp;A, in accordance with paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H187FECC119DF464FA109B3BA3B305283"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Internal oversight mechanisms to monitor implementation of such plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BA3A6CBA41C478FB36A55090D87315C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recommendations for future engagement models that reduce redundancy and improve efficiency in managing law enforcement and homeland security partnerships with priority law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H353C46B271EB4B0591926D8158DC2601"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assurance of continuity of intelligence support and convenings currently being provided to SLTT entity partners through the ELO office, including relevant HSIN-INTEL access.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDEAEDE36AE824C3587DB223F4655FC24" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a certification not later than 60 days after commencing implementation of the plan required under subsection (a).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2095795AB6754BD5818397EE84F43295" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on expansion</header><text>Until such time as the Secretary of Homeland Security submits the plan required under subsection (a) and certifies commencement of the implementation of such plan under subsection (c), the Secretary may not—</text> <paragraph id="H5455ED7F4012408195431B4314FAFE96" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expand the staffing, budget, or programmatic scope of the ELO Office; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H340DA3934A1B41FAAEF5EEFB5BC43FB4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish new offices in the Department duplicating the mission of the ELO Office or the Partner Engagement directorate of I&amp;A without specific congressional authorization.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7F3DA1DA59AD4635AB94EEB42E1B5403"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H56FAE81FF3964DFFA86992ADA4DD1B67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB7C80B67BBC4FC69C6AD291B345B59B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ELO Office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>ELO Office</quote> means the Engagement, Liaison, and Outreach office within the Office of Intelligence and Analysis (I&amp;A) of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0173DCB71896471997E130F9FEFCCA08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>I&amp;A</header><text>The term <quote>I&amp;A</quote> means the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H189BAB1A98234C53A2A18135F2CF7232"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD052CAFB33A543788045C2684C3DE7D4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>SLTT entity</header><text>The term <quote>SLTT entity</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2200 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/650">6 U.S.C. 650</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D93AD1CF41C448C828EEF3B3DC6C64D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Priority law enforcement agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>priority law enforcement agencies</quote> means Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies identified by the Secretary as key partners for national security, counterterrorism, emergency response, or other mission-critical operations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260713" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 13, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


