<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9CE1F1E576B14A75825AD6DFB1EF9144" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9733 IH: Interagency Council on Affordable Housing Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9733</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Federal Interagency Council on Housing Affordability and Preservation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA67FDEFC2BE44A148EC21BE58ACD7722" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCFC326F864B749A1AA4BCD4F4E32448D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Interagency Council on Affordable Housing Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H10139405A1CC47D4991573C5DB8DEFA3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established in the executive branch an independent establishment to be known as the United States Interagency Council on Housing Affordability and Preservation, whose mission shall be to develop Federal policy designed to preserve and increase affordable housing supply and increase fairness in the rental market and further the principles of fair housing and create a national partnership at every level of government and with the private sector to carry out such purposes.</text></section> 
<section id="HDBD1DA63BA3041A2B66F6B80FBD75383"><enum>3.</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<subsection id="HC81E917A654246ABA73E73300E76A4C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Council shall be composed of the heads of the following agencies or offices, or the designee of such agency or office head:</text> <paragraph id="HF13FD9A914654CACB4F7A529A61EC266"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48D9B8C7F3954E54BC71F1610EB2FE34"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Department of Justice.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FFB768672BC4F1C8C20867C6A97210F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Department of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD4E0A9D7DAA4CD7861F91D54A65BAD6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD252FE1BD341435BA98D3C28D24AD062"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA4318919D3047DD84773F9381F90C4A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AE3D74DEE564AA984EC6085FA051455"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Department of Education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H407CB4A95628443CAFB8229CDBC816B1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A8CEDAF1FE6402399F4AC2D43F8E5A6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3845655375404D8FAD0C55C9A51EFCC9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BEFA04FA81940B79FB1C45AA41E9EF8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Department of Defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBADB68E221349DBA5DCACCCB8885ECA"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE114F9C614B647DF9977AED70C0D31E0"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E8D30F147FF4453B09DC472B0362937"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Department of Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H511368A6903E4C6AB12744803E00596D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7768B2B071644F779517A5F82496CDBF"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Corporation for National and Community Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65F92526488F4616AB3B11234C728FAC"><enum>(17)</enum><text>General Services Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90E5DC8B14424598B39344B4E1A5DE90"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1C59987A2F74DFC9B0E2CACA3CE5F44"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Social Security Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58134FB4BBF849B19D11386BBE13E03C"><enum>(20)</enum><text>United States Postal Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B86C01A8B40412782B6D00BA12FE1F0"><enum>(21)</enum><text>White House Office on Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48603AAAAB784380ACFA73ADBBAFDA29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall elect a Chairperson and a Vice Chairperson from among its members. The positions of Chairperson and Vice Chairperson shall rotate among its members on an annual basis.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC19C1D8D1666459AB350BFD5716A245A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall meet at the call of its Chairperson or a majority of its members, but not less often than four times each year, and the rotation of the positions of Chairperson and Vice Chairperson required under subsection (b) shall occur at the first meeting of each year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H192F0622EFB44F889F7590263BEF0C85"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition of additional pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Council shall receive no additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Council.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC301E80E070543B49561D7E2B1F9F852"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Executive Director of the Council shall report to the Chairman of the Council.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H46CD5B213A4B45838B9B75EE589792E9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Functions</header> 
<subsection id="H3992F81AB40E40BBBC4D9864AF33A770"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="H36A0446AFD11428E9027C3D36299E79B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, develop, make available for public comment, and submit to the President and to the Congress a National Strategic Plan to Preserve Affordable Housing, and shall update such plan annually;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FF92A4FA2E4436FB5BEAD02CF0D6EC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review all Federal activities and programs relating to public housing, affordable housing production, affordable housing programs, and housing voucher programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08310E4161F14A999717C75E796F8BCE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>monitor, evaluate, and recommend improvements in programs and activities to assist affordable housing production conducted by Federal agencies, State and local governments, and private voluntary organizations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21D6C50F134E4286A3B10EEE45827376"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide professional and technical assistance (by not less than 5, but in no case more than 10, regional coordinators employed by the Council, each having responsibility for interaction and coordination of the activities of the Council within the 10 standard Federal regions) to States, local governments, and other public and private nonprofit organizations, in order to enable such governments and organizations to—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FD03355E2C549E9B46A166DEF871073"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interpret regulations and assist in the application process for Federal assistance, including grants;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3FED19758DD439BB975255DBABD5EDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide assistance on the ways in which Federal programs may best be coordinated to complement the objectives of this Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D3D59156E374DA4923EAA6F49ED26A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop recommendations and program ideas based on regional specific issues in serving homeless and low-income populations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06B1C7C5B1B548D382CED4B361DCFC06"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish a schedule for biennial regional workshops to be held by the Council in each of the 10 standard Federal regions to further carry out and provide the assistance described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) and other appropriate assistance as necessary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A5A1C8C5978400C9003735A092CAA2A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourage the creation of State Interagency Councils on Affordable Housing and the formulation of jurisdictional 10-year plans to end homelessness at State, city, and county levels;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8AE9906929A144068352CF8905511FFC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>annually obtain from Federal agencies their identification of consumer-oriented entitlement and other resources for which individuals may be eligible and the agencies' identification of improvements to ensure access; develop mechanisms to ensure access by persons and families to all Federal, State, and local programs for which the persons are eligible, and to verify collaboration among entities within a community that receive Federal funding under programs targeted for persons experiencing homelessness, and other affordable housing programs for which persons and families are eligible;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0C5BAF4988A494693258952C4BA516F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>conduct research and evaluation related to its functions as defined in this section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3537AD4D079C434492DF5CE551F5E6AB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>develop joint Federal agency and other initiatives to fulfill the goals of the agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B043C18ABD741D88839AE874DCA03AC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>collect and disseminate information relating to low-income individuals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BDE5C72D5794D86A9AEC9421ED80F07"><enum>(10)</enum><text>prepare the annual reports required in subsection (c)(2);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6F02BA484AC4E768AE7CE3DFD0F1936"><enum>(11)</enum><text>prepare and distribute to States (including State contact persons described in section 7(a)), local governments, and other public and private nonprofit organizations, a bimonthly bulletin that describes the Federal resources available to them to assist with affordable housing; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1A0DEB97C8D44559A9054E6A786703C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after completion of the report, convene a meeting of representatives of all Federal agencies and committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate having jurisdiction over any Federal program to assist affordable housing programs or production, local and State governments, academic researchers who specialize in homelessness, nonprofit housing and service providers that receive funding under any Federal program to assist homeless individuals or families, organizations advocating on behalf of such nonprofit providers and persons receiving housing or services under any such Federal affordable housing program, and persons receiving housing or services under any such Federal program, at which meeting such representatives shall discuss all issues relevant to the council’s jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H102709B70EAB449BB6653A6EEB5048DC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Council may—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5F99956AB68D41BBB7F2AB585882FB99" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>arrange national, regional, State, and local conferences for the purpose of developing and coordinating effective programs and activities to assist in carrying out the mission described in section 2 and pay for expenses of attendance at meetings which are concerned with the functions or activities for which the appropriation is made; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E2F96CD430F406494B44EA43F767C2F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish a newsletter concerning Federal, State, and local programs that are effective in carrying out such mission.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H73985E597D2A4A2EA959CE2FD04925F2" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H651C5349046C491186D1CB8D5B7EA865" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>By agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the head of each Federal agency that is a member of the Council shall prepare and transmit to the Congress and the Council a report that describes—</text> <subparagraph id="HFFF5AE37A1EE4C66A314F5172EF9EE87"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each affordable housing program administered by such agency and the number of individuals served by such program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDAABEE9AEE64505BD31716D2045EB5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impediments, including any statutory and regulatory restrictions, to the use by individuals of each such program and to obtaining services or benefits under each such program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H294A9D6A1D1E4AABAF6F255A97156635"><enum>(C)</enum><text>efforts made by such agency to increase the opportunities for individuals to obtain permanent housing, supportive services, and access to legal services in regards to housing matters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB8D7F1B31A64064B6ACD4647C07530F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>By Council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall prepare and transmit to the President and the Congress an annual report that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE0B2E511467F4B69A1D3922A42921158"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assesses the nature and extent of the problems relating to affordable housing and the needs of low-income individuals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD68572909CD443A912AB74BED486437"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides a comprehensive and detailed description of the activities and accomplishments of the Federal Government in resolving the problems and meeting the needs assessed pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92F687A57669435582F1DFF49DAD4C91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describes the accomplishments and activities of the Council, in working with Federal, State, and local agencies and public and private organizations in order to preserve and expand affordable housing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H51042527C04F4997AE21A59269597517"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assesses the level of Federal assistance necessary to adequately resolve the problems and meet the needs assessed pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H156D9FBA9D4843F69D2F6711088BB39C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>specifies any recommendations of the Council for appropriate and necessary legislative and administrative actions to resolve such problems and meet such needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H66BEEB9B1902462DBEE08CC5456E4AE7" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification of Other Federal Agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, in monitoring and evaluating programs and activities to assist in carrying out the mission described in section 2 conducted by other Federal agencies, the Council determines that any significant problem, abuse, or deficiency exists in the administration of the program or activity of any Federal agency, the Council shall submit a notice of the determination of the Council to the Inspector General of the Federal agency (or the head of the Federal agency, in the case of a Federal agency that has no Inspector General).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H627B6BF01BF44C01886F1AB2462B9CB0" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program Timetables</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency or office that is a member of the Council and responsible for administering a program to assist in carrying out the mission described in section 2 shall provide to the Council a timetable regarding program funding availability and application deadlines. The Council shall furnish such information to each State (including the State contact person described in section 7(a)).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0E5F77788B8644FF8F2428FB5C0A0EAF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Director and staff</header> 
<subsection id="H296F3370DBD84E8B8433ED54C0A4B946" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall appoint an Executive Director, who shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed the rate of basic pay payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code. The Council shall appoint an Executive Director at the first meeting of the Council held under section 3(c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H710A0221F7724F1BB96071D7B0C3E679" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With the approval of the Council, the Executive Director of the Council may appoint and fix the compensation of such additional personnel as the Executive Director considers necessary to carry out the duties of the Council.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B9947EBA7A843708DC3AD6F8A97A018" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Details From Other Agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request of the Council, the head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of such agency to the Council to assist the Council in carrying out its duties under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBE80406FB63A4FAAA431D682C8EEA8F1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative Support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall provide the Council with such administrative and support services as are necessary to ensure that the Council carries out its functions under this Act in an efficient and expeditious manner.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9574926E3A941F8ADCD0BE2E8C3E19C" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Experts and Consultants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With the approval of the Council, the Executive Director of the Council may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5F9FE35DA84141B39C976806B5EE44F8" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Powers</header> <subsection id="H28817E8FFADA4B22A9F6E51BA462C6B0" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of carrying out this Act, the Council may hold such meetings, and sit and act at such times and places, as the Council considers appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1B0438CED9643AF83C7E47124B6D1FB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delegation</header><text>Any member or employee of the Council may, if authorized by the Council, take any action that the Council is authorized to take in this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H45F31914606549E18E1802FF073DE891" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Council may secure directly from any Federal agency such information as may be necessary to enable the Council to carry out this Act. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Council, the head of such agency shall furnish such information to the Council.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1BC5D8F8EA04456AA2D2514F9259A9EE" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>The Council may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property, both real and personal, public and private, without fiscal year limitation, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Council.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H61E705DD917A4B73B7B3E763E58DA895" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Mails</header><text>The Council may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other Federal agencies.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDF3DFB9FE6EB4662B58B756400B9D4E5" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Encouragement of State involvement</header> 
<subsection id="H88650DC550254494BE75DAD601B73D34" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State Contact Persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall designate an individual to serve as a State contact person for the purpose of receiving and disseminating information and communications received from the Council.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1F524346842F422DA320A74EC0A69072" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State Interagency Councils and Lead Agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State is encouraged to establish a State interagency council on housing affordability and preservation or designate a lead agency for the State for the purpose of assuming primary responsibility for coordinating and interacting with the Council and State and local agencies as necessary.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDD0178DF4A5C4DB2A6B1229C93FFBC4D"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="H2087266D13BF48699C75F1B81B3B4EAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Council</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Council</term> means the United States Interagency Council on Housing Affordability and Preservation established in section 2.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFD6FA433D004C91A1288C01A81BD2C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>agency</term> in section 551(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF8142900E5364B38A2F17EFFDEE358D7"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $4,800,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. Any amounts appropriated to carry out this Act shall remain available until expended.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

