<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV26690-5DG-HK-7S2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 172 IS: To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran that have not been authorized by Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 172</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260413">April 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</sponsor> introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran that have not been authorized by Congress.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="id007afcf404494e1391fd4f7cdc788ba3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="idaaf1c48b840c4974be1e0a51e2a71a4a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8, clause 11 of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1501a56fdb9c4cd8b535a30c1c37e24a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war upon Iran or any person or organization within Iran, nor enacted a specific statutory authorization for the use of military force within or against Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b9105608c094581ac6039697d2c9b43"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>The purpose of the War Powers Resolution, as stated in section 2(a) of such resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541(a)</external-xref>), is to <quote>insure that the collective judgment of both the Congress and the President will apply to the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id544ad2619cde44e5a5c3ada36c973ee5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 3 of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1542">50 U.S.C. 1542</external-xref>) states, <quote>The President in every possible instance shall consult with Congress before introducing United States Armed Forces into hostilities or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id389f1f4891c44876b40c6e2f6d9d4679"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On February 28, 2026, the United States launched Operation Epic Fury, introducing the United States Armed Forces into hostilities as part of a military campaign against the Government of Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf05ee08a79664665bd484332e1f3ada3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As of April 8, 2026, 13 members of the United States Armed Forces have been killed and at least 380 have been wounded, and President Donald J. Trump has suggested there will likely be additional American lives lost.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4f0e360a2874a23802c4404c76c6675"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Following the initiation of combat operations on February 28, 2026, the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) effectively closed the Strait of Hormuz to all vessels, resulting in a precipitous drop in maritime traffic and worldwide economic disruption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32bb8f11462b46458aaa1dfc3b3ba568"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On March 24, 2026, the Department of Defense ordered additional United States military forces to the region in preparation of a further escalation of the military operations consistent with the President’s statements acknowledging the possibility of using ground forces against Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe7165b658eb43c6b379b03036dd5c0d"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A ceasefire between the United States and the Government of Iran took effect on April 8, 2026. Following an initial round of negotiations, the United States announced a blockade of the Strait of Hormuz to be implemented by the United States Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27d340184f734eae9a8201687467ef96"> <enum>(10)</enum> <text>The use of military force within or against Iran constitutes the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities within the meaning of section 4(a) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1543">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph><paragraph id="id115c859bf0494b2a9d803781a6be76d0">
                <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) provides that any joint resolution or bill requiring the removal of United States Armed Forces from imminent engagement in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures under section 601(b) of the International Security and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id89033dbcead24cdba486836536aaa636"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>), and in accordance with section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>), Congress hereby directs the President to remove the United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Iran, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or a specific authorization for use of military force.</text></section><section id="id2512b6f6cbe540f6a4c79e6fb4e13e35"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this resolution may be construed to prevent the United States from—</text><paragraph id="id049148d87cad4a6780f7864913a90641"><enum>(1)</enum><text>defending against an attack on the United States or its personnel or facilities in other nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04c0a878374842efab91a63edbe1b429"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collecting, analyzing, or sharing intelligence, including United States partners and allies such as the State of Israel, and international organizations as appropriate, related to threats from Iran or its proxies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb78645b260414b4ba2e6cc61af4c2f78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assisting partner countries who have been attacked by Iran since February 28, 2026, and other nations—</text><subparagraph id="id98599cf134da473c82a6fbe945ac4a2f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in taking defensive measures to protect their territory from retaliatory attacks by Iran or its proxies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63bb9801448144cd87b044b570a4f2d6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by providing defensive materiel support for such defensive measures; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id544bb343963549e0853c41de70a0ff4d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing assistance for the security, departure, and evacuation to United States citizens affected by the hostilities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

