<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE5C2FB4766CB40B48C4F38E13F4CDB6E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8841 IH: Veteran Scam Victims Foundation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8841</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish the Veteran Scam Victims Foundation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1531C0FF88474273B4090241B4E013B7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H467220D7B46E41B89A75C0FE7699FE26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Scam Victims Foundation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H873CAB7C736946E88AD39D70C6505029"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veteran Scam Victims Foundation</header> 
<subsection id="HDA41F828E2254F3CA76423BA9328AB37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 83 the following new chapter:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H60C69EF0E99B4EE3AF09D3976284C9B9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <chapter id="H01DB8F0AC2FA426F9935FF585E2827AA"><enum>84</enum><header>Veteran Scam Victims Foundation</header> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H60C69EF0E99B4EE3AF09D3976284C9B9" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="H01DB8F0AC2FA426F9935FF585E2827AA" level="chapter">Chapter 84—Veteran Scam Victims Foundation</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA513285F1F1B433BB7ECB9E89BFE4F82" level="section">8401. Establishment and purposes of Foundation.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2C48802F1ED04A659E2DFD63600E7ED6" level="section">8402. Board.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H48C9806BF582497DA7BFDF83C6B0D799" level="section">8403. Gifts, devises, or bequests.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HCF72ECE2ECFE4E76B9C713B45C565E4B" level="section">8404. Disposition of property or income.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HCFCF7E8469744B79A05DE3B38038E49A" level="section">8405. Corporate succession and powers and duties acting as trustee; personal liability for malfeasance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2735515BBFB14F0D8389DB0266DBB650" level="section">8406. Corporate powers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HFC67C3F163AA47D299D8CA025A3CDDB6" level="section">8407. Authority of Board.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HF6CDCCA198214228AE8F5A89B8CF83B6" level="section">8408. Tax exemptions; contributions toward costs of local government; contributions, gifts, or transfers to or for use of the United States.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HF6E5277315B941599C4ACBF11C538652" level="section">8409. Liability of the United States.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H476C5D4C63FB45F89183C3A29738B847" level="section">8410. Annual report.</toc-entry> </toc> <section id="HA513285F1F1B433BB7ECB9E89BFE4F82"><enum>8401.</enum><header>Establishment and purposes of Foundation</header> <subsection id="H213828055E8240D399CDA14CF8D6EFE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Veteran Scam Victims Foundation (in this chapter referred to as the <quote>Foundation</quote>). The Foundation is a charitable and nonprofit corporation and is not an agency or establishment of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H67F4581C3D4346F99B3A1F3B4DC0EC52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the Foundation shall be subject to, and have all the powers conferred upon a nonprofit corporation by, the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H09EDFEBCA943440C956E9E4236E2979F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purposes</header> <paragraph id="H82882253AFAC4F86BB42FF53F48F7F36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the purposes of the Foundation are—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC68E5AE91E464E42B9B2C70E77A3B95D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to encourage, accept, and administer private gifts of property for the benefit of, or in connection with, the activities of the Department, to prevent veterans and their beneficiaries from becoming the victims of scams; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73CE2FC789EF4FF6BA8CC1D76D093158"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to undertake and conduct such other activities as will protect veterans and their beneficiaries from scams, such as to educate veterans and their beneficiaries about scams and support them when they have become victims of scams.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC602526C12042AE80CC4F60C30D65A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation not included</header><text>The purposes of the Foundation do not include providing compensation to veterans or their beneficiaries for monetary losses in connection with scams.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H2C48802F1ED04A659E2DFD63600E7ED6"><enum>8402.</enum><header>Board</header> <subsection id="H77F547EEEB524D329B13922473C55079"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation shall consist of a Board having as members the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5B93115915294C24B3292AC92D90E4B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs (or the Secretary’s designee).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BD721F682774140998B63BB384A6A06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Six private citizens of the United States, of which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD472898F9E704A53B4E3F60379F206CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2900C16D474B485D9E6D50A1D191BD2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C350382C9DE4FA69388DD4451B95A9C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>one shall be appointed by the Attorney General;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CFB6B0C449747AD896E2130DC5965CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>one shall be appointed by the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A30FCCC72AC4ADC870BD1177A4D3B27"><enum>(E)</enum><text>one shall be appointed by the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01C419BDEA854485AC1348A4C7E8AE0F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>one shall be appointed by the Administrator of the Social Security Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8673415B9B44129BF4A5CEE1043B888"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Up to three members as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers appropriate, each of whom shall be a private citizen of the United States appointed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4A514F36BC404E13B585FFB5A7886602"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Term of office and vacancies</header> <paragraph id="H30391A9018AF4AB69C161FF46C953935"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term of the private citizen members of the Board is six years. If a successor is chosen to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of a term, the successor shall be chosen only for the remainder of that term.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02A9CC6BC63D48938C8F5E72F03671BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The initial terms of the first private citizen members of the Foundation shall be staggered so that—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E937DE3ADA84D268B5307A841CA09E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the first members appointed under subsections (a)(2)(A) and (B) serve initial terms of six years;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H64313F827DC54B45B47FB9902C9C5D38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the first members appointed under subsections (a)(2)(C) and (D) serve initial terms of four years;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76940A228E64428EAF79314CF65CAEAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the first members appointed under subsections (a)(2)(E) and (F) serve initial terms of two years; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE94ADC428784528A858FA71427AE19B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the first members appointed under subsection (a)(3), if any, serve initial terms of six, four, or two years, as determined by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (or the Secretary’s designee), except that no more than one in every three such members may serve an initial term of six years and no more than one in every three may serve an initial term of four years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H60ECC5D8DAC345F888A446EB41F03E83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairman</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs (or the Secretary’s designee) shall be the Chairman of the Board.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8009B828A0F541F8A8CB4FA2C4430F57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Board membership not an office</header><text>Membership on the Board shall not be an office within the meaning of the statutes of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5A56179DE61F49F0870DC2B7C6D2FA34"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Board serving at any time shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5D71DE59DD043B1A3D7BD960C42C649"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Seal</header><text>The Foundation shall have an official seal selected by the Board, which shall be judicially noticed.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9403DE02858242A2A9EAA8E9F677C9F7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Board shall meet at the call of the Chairman and there shall be at least one meeting each year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9561715E8FE3433F81EFC40E0893D08E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Compensation and reimbursement</header><text>No compensation shall be paid to the members of the Board for their services as members, but they shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary traveling and subsistence expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties as members out of Foundation funds available to the Board for those purposes.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H48C9806BF582497DA7BFDF83C6B0D799"><enum>8403.</enum><header>Gifts, devises, or bequests</header> <subsection id="H6B38A3DB3B3941DF890F0349DD759202"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Authority To accept gifts, devises, or bequests</header> <paragraph id="H6B72279D42D64AE4A7210D9C0945FD81"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Foundation may accept, receive, solicit, hold, administer, and use any gifts, devises, or bequests, either absolutely or in trust of real or personal property, or any income from, or other interest in, the gift, devise, or bequest, for the benefit of, or in connection with, the Department, its activities, or its services.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H0D8BEAD11DA9482BB570688A24AFBC48">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Coordination with Department</header>
 <text>Activities of the Foundation under paragraph (1) shall be undertaken after consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that those activities are consistent with the programs and policies of the Department.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD7022580319742DCB3735970240BB737">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Gift, devise, or bequest that is encumbered, restricted, or subject to
                    beneficial interests</header>
 <text>A gift, devise, or bequest may be accepted by the Foundation even though it is encumbered, restricted, or subject to beneficial interests of private persons if any current or future interest in the gift, devise, or bequest is for the benefit of the Department, its activities, or its services.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D39DC55E2E74CDDB1BE349647FD1A2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>When gift, devise, or bequest may not be accepted</header><text>The Foundation may not accept any gift, devise, or bequest that entails any expenditure other than from the resources of the Foundation.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HCF72ECE2ECFE4E76B9C713B45C565E4B"><enum>8404.</enum><header>Disposition of property or income</header> <subsection id="H4CC1140C80514003B719A95A7D2F7FC6"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Authority To dispose or deal with property or income</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise required by the instrument of transfer, the Foundation may sell, lease, invest, reinvest, retain, or otherwise dispose of or deal with any property or income from the property as the Board may determine.</text>
              </subsection> 
<subsection id="H257E13E76E0540AFAFD49B4C227B442F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>The Foundation shall not engage in any business or make any investment that may not lawfully be made by a trust company in the District of Columbia, except that the Foundation may make any investment authorized by the instrument of transfer, and may retain any property accepted by the Foundation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC54D6B285DA94CF4BB6283752EDC628B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of services and facilities of the Department</header><text>The Foundation may utilize the services and facilities of the Department, and the services and facilities may be made available on request to the extent practicable with or without reimbursement. Amounts reimbursed to the Department shall be returned by the Department to the account from which the funds for which the reimbursement is made were drawn and may, without further appropriation, be expended for any purpose for which the account is authorized.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HCFCF7E8469744B79A05DE3B38038E49A"><enum>8405.</enum><header>Corporate succession and powers and duties acting as trustee; personal liability for malfeasance</header> 
<subsection id="H2751250BD2CD472CA296D6F23444AF5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Perpetual succession</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation shall have perpetual succession.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD0BC8320A1A6474A869957996C57AD51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers and duties of trustee</header><text>The Foundation shall have all the usual powers and obligations of a corporation acting as a trustee, including the power to sue and to be sued in its own name.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1012A1FB21094882B319737A73495B7B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Personal liability of board members</header><text>The members of the Board shall not be personally liable, except for malfeasance.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H2735515BBFB14F0D8389DB0266DBB650"><enum>8406.</enum><header>Corporate powers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Foundation shall have the power to enter into contracts, to execute instruments, and generally to do any and all lawful acts necessary or appropriate to its purposes.</text></section> 
<section id="HFC67C3F163AA47D299D8CA025A3CDDB6"><enum>8407.</enum><header>Authority of Board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this chapter, the Board may—</text> <paragraph id="H4AC23BDD12004533BD42B5F5ACD19053"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adopt bylaws and regulations necessary for the administration of its functions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBA01C27AC25438FBFCFB55A8BA934D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contract for any necessary services.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF6CDCCA198214228AE8F5A89B8CF83B6"> <enum>8408.</enum> <header>Tax exemptions; contributions toward costs of local government; contributions, gifts, or transfers to or for use of the United States</header> <subsection id="HA2DDCC899AD941D39336CB8BD90A200B"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Tax exemption</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation and any income or property received or owned by it, and all transactions relating to that income or property, shall be exempt from all Federal, State, and local taxation.</text>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="HF54D61840AF3477F9163D292346C7DC9">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Contributions in lieu of taxes</header>
 <text>The Foundation may—</text> <paragraph id="HCF338633B4AE4A6A8B1106063F0B66D2"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>contribute toward the costs of local government in amounts not in excess of those which it would be obligated to pay that government if it were not exempt from taxation by virtue of subsection (a) or by virtue of its being a charitable and nonprofit corporation; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H23CF4D2CAA3747E680BA57F501720A0D">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>agree to contribute with respect to property transferred to it and the income derived from the property if the agreement is a condition of the transfer.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H0C9D1F4304B648119C399048EF300C53">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Transfers deemed To be to or for the use of United States</header>
 <text>Contributions, gifts, and other transfers made to or for the use of the Foundation shall be deemed to be contributions, gifts, or transfers to or for the use of the United States.</text>
              </subsection>
            </section> 
<section id="HF6E5277315B941599C4ACBF11C538652">
              <enum>8409.</enum>
              <header>Liability of the United States</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States shall not be liable for any debts, defaults, acts, or omissions of the Foundation.</text>
            </section> 
<section id="H476C5D4C63FB45F89183C3A29738B847"><enum>8410.</enum><header>Annual report</header> 
<subsection id="H5411BC6C8B594E0EA4D747BBD6F69927"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foundation shall, as soon as practicable after the end of each fiscal year, transmit to the appropriate congressional committees an annual report of its proceedings and activities, including a full and complete statement of its receipts, expenditures, and investments.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8391D5E2E2B942BB844F550F05BD3CCE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8693C6733D0E4D2B9100CC44D2951865"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C1FE4024B37477CB2E8A1C003FDC50F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE05C3252C6FB425AB1BF4D8618E05385"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The tables of chapters at the beginning of title 38, United States Code, and of part VI of such title, are each amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 83 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HBE865878826D4A8BA1567DBCE1688173" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <multi-column-toc-entry level="chapter"><toc-enum>84.</toc-enum><level-header level="chapter">Veteran Scam Victims Foundation</level-header><target>8401</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

