<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB08938DD5F2F4FCBB5B29F1BD09E9960" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1147 IH: Recognizing the United States legacy of dismissed pain and denied autonomy in women’s health care, and affirming the Federal Government’s duty to protect individual dignity and advance patient-centered care in women’s health.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1147</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260330">March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the United States legacy of dismissed pain and denied autonomy in women&#8217;s health care, and affirming the Federal Government&#8217;s duty to protect individual dignity and advance patient-centered care in women&#8217;s health.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas for generations, women in the United States—especially Black, indigenous, immigrant, LGBTQ+, disabled, and low-income women—have endured a system that too often treats their comfort as secondary, their pain as exaggerated, and their autonomy as negotiable;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the field of gynecology, while ranked high in patient trust and satisfaction compared to other medical disciplines, was historically built in part on the exploitation and sterilization of Black, enslaved, Puerto Rican, indigenous, immigrant, and disabled women without their consent, and remains a relatively under-researched area of medicine;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this history also includes the coercive testing of contraceptive pills on women and girls in Puerto Rico;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas countless women continue to experience their pain being dismissed or minimized, contributing to delayed diagnoses, untreated conditions, and unnecessary physical and psychological suffering that could have been prevented;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas American history is marked by laws and medical practices that have required spousal or State approval for women to make choices about their own bodies and private medical decisions, like whether to access contraception, undergo sterilization, or terminate a pregnancy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas recent escalation of rollbacks on reproductive rights, including on the constitutional right to abortion, have only worsened access to care for women’s health conditions, endangering reproductive health outcomes and directly causing preventable medical emergencies not seen in over half a century; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the future of women’s health care must center justice, bodily autonomy, and empowering patients to make informed decisions about their reproductive, sexual, and menstrual health: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC05327C8BAFE47E7A1302A3B3D156FA2"> <section id="H3F7E7879774440E4A36EF834EC212908" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB86E4B67DC284622B6AFFC13CEA47AA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the historical and ongoing injustices that deny women the dignity, seriousness, and respect they deserve;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6322731D98445F2A0B99E99D1C0BA21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the women, especially marginalized women, who have been denied agency over their bodies and suffered due to systemic neglect and bias;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H869FD12D6C034536AF0BBE56F54D7119"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms the need for shared decision-making and patient-centered approaches to gynecological and reproductive care, including patient education, procedural transparency, and expanded research on women’s health conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD2C487157E14988B5A53F7FFA924683"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commits to expanding access to reproductive and gynecological health care, strengthening protections for bodily autonomy, increasing Federal investment in women’s health research, and holding institutions accountable for bias and harm; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE3E8E5ED24A4EFEBF14FB2B1E2AB1B8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emphasizes the need to end the normalization of pain and address the implicit and structural biases within reproductive and gynecological care.</text></paragraph> </section> </resolution-body></resolution>

