<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H26E6496204114A17876C60486DBE5FC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9186 IH: Controlled Substances Act Clarification in Sciences Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9186</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00"> Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to more closely align the Act with modern medical knowledge, terminology, and practices, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H122FE2CCC2BB418CB0796F71CB8D79C3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCEB37B26D5A4464EBDBC640AC12F8AB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Controlled Substances Act Clarification in Sciences Act of 2026</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HA3AE0E9787B94C2DA994895C0A80AC18"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to Controlled Substances Act</header> <subsection id="H83ABD6959070490C890ABCFCFC092510"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H604BAE7559714FA4A3352A21E9F6C810" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HE99B7DCA1C8A41AE8EBA66D3D9FBEA89" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(61)</enum><text>The term <term>accepted medical use</term> means the use of a drug or other substance—</text> <subparagraph id="H159B31DA1C1C462693579FA782DAE7EE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with an approval under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or licensure under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H800A281E70FB41F2B1DCEEB991CB132F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conduct scientific research to advance the understanding of human biology, develop new therapies, or research animal or human models of disease, syndrome, or disorder; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFAF53CE74E4E493A9535D3EF585D5EE3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with a recognized legitimate medical use if—</text> 
<clause id="H77DF528A77F24ED89A305E69AA323988" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a jurisdiction has authorized the drug or substance for medical use;</text> </clause> <clause id="HBB9099DB57BE40E6BBDCFDBE7D7C8D9A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the drug or substance is widely used in such jurisdiction by health care practitioners; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC9AAEB37B49F4CDA84DC2F51A616463C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such legitimate medical use is recognized by the entities that regulate the practice of medicine in such jurisdiction through evidence-based scientific evaluation that employs rigorous and generally accepted methodologies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46464BF7635B492591A49B17FED52B31" indent="up1"><enum>(62)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>dependence liability</term> means, with respect to a drug or other substance that could contribute to a substance use disorder, the actual propensity for physical dependence or psychological dependence to the drug or substance.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF550E881A09F4DF4AA1E0923286D1059" indent="up1"><enum>(63)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>physical dependence</term> means, with respect to a drug or other substance, a state that develops as a result of physiological adaptation in response to repeated, chronic use of the drug or substance, manifested by withdrawal signs and symptoms after abrupt discontinuation or a significant dose reduction of the drug or substance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54A61AECA6084263932DFCCFE6BA050E" indent="up1"><enum>(64)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>psychological dependence</term> means, with respect to a drug or other substance, a state in which an individual’s use of the drug or substance is compromised by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF614BA8990BC46FE9F4005804466C995"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rewarding effects of the drug or substance, thus increasing the likelihood of chronic use; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE5EAAD8CAAC4F8098924D329931541F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">psychological distress (including craving) that occurs in the absence of the drug or substance and contributes to compulsive drug seeking, regardless of whether such use is indicative of abuse or misuse of the drug or substance.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA6C3EDF259C4A4C9246D50FAC515B0B" indent="up1"><enum>(65)</enum><text>The term <term>lack of accepted safety for use of the drug or other substance under medical supervision</term> means, with respect to a drug or other substance, that based on the accepted medical use of the drug or substance, a reasonable health care practitioner would determine that the potential risk of death or significant and irreversible harm to the user would clearly outweigh any medical benefit to the user.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H74AFC9BB915545DFBFC0CA98BE1E3AAD" indent="up1"><enum>(66)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>abuse</term> means, with respect to a drug or other substance, the intentional use of the drug or substance in a manner that will lead to a substance use disorder.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47B212C0C40D4E058F167DA59438B27D" indent="up1"><enum>(67)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>potential for abuse</term> means, with respect to a drug or other substance, the relative likelihood that use of the drug or substance will result in abuse of the drug or substance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5FCEA5A9311F4173B0187E5E71C0E44D" indent="up1"><enum>(68)</enum><text>The term <term>misuse</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCB5CEEF6128C47EE807BA55B3EF6A739"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use by an individual of a drug or other substance that is not intended for human consumption (determined in the same manner as such a determination would be made under section 203); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51FB40AA041D4D59B84EA5D06B8FF641"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use by an individual of a drug or other substance in a way—</text> 
<clause id="H8D6169B3D8E5445791660A9928B5A41D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that was not directed by the individual’s health care practitioner; or</text></clause> <clause id="H629FBF73E2AC4B1984DD1F9FE794EE71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is not in accordance with the instructions for use on the labeling of such drug or substance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5233686A8D174C54BD12A4D894B61EAA" indent="up1"><enum>(69)</enum><text>The term <term>potential benefits to society</term> means, with respect to a drug or other substance, any medical, scientific, or other use of the drug or substance that may improve public health or quality of life.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H49FCC532A8404A54A17E0F8C2047BE52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of roles in scheduling</header><text>Section 201(a) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before <quote>Rules of the Attorney General</quote> the following: <quote>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall (1) defer to the Secretary’s scientific and medical evaluation of a drug or other substance, and (2) add or transfer a drug or other substance to a schedule only if such schedule best corresponds to controls reasonably tailored to protect public health and safety (including the potential for abuse and dependence liability of the drug or substance) while preserving access for accepted medical uses, and recognizing the potential benefits to society, of the drug or substance.</quote>. </text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


