<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H37407CE4538A4CCFB8BC6A7EEA23ACB9" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1148 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of April as “National Language Access Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1148</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260330">March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of April as <quote>National Language Access Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas over 71,000,000 individuals ages 5 and older in the United States speak a language other than English at home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 25,700,000 individuals in the United States have limited English proficiency (LEP) and rely on translation and interpretation services to access vital public services and institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas studies show that 47 percent of all immigrant adults in the United States have LEP;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to a 2017–2021 Bureau of the Census estimate, at least 500 individual languages and language groups were spoken in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas about 30 percent of Asian-American adults, 12 percent of Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander adults, 32 percent of Hispanic adults, 3 percent of Black adults, and 1 percent of White adults reported having LEP;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 9 percent of the United States population are individuals with LEP, with some States and territories having even higher rates including—</text><paragraph id="HA5949144C2A7416998343F9FD9356D49"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">54 percent of residents in American Samoa;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15D2F38C90524FA1B27CD48906D89FC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>20 percent of residents in California;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0309E8ED81B44470803E62BFCCDD602D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>14 percent of residents in Texas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC648D083D744129A53BB425E7474B60"><enum>(4)</enum><text>12 percent of residents in New York;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6C5F88459834E38B54C96413E6D6335"><enum>(5)</enum><text>12 percent of residents in Florida; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFF0E24A4FAD4651886E23E38E73A065"><enum>(6)</enum><text>9 percent of residents in Puerto Rico;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the term <quote>language access</quote> means the provision of culturally competent and effective language services to an individual with LEP designed to enhance that individual’s access to, understanding of, or benefit from the services, activities, and programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas uneven coverage and implementation of language access contribute to significant disparities for individuals seeking—</text><paragraph id="HCE7B72B9D40947BE8A67CE027CF800E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>employment services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB80C9B001EE5469A9ACD094BB121D659"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transportation services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96739606FAB84B08B1A56FE16422929A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>financial services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A99474E9EA54807AA433524B44FDA57"><enum>(4)</enum><text>health services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DD7C89CC7AD4E7083157F2878E89296"><enum>(5)</enum><text>housing services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A7605D9C5594D739913DEBEDF245482"><enum>(6)</enum><text>legal services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5B68619639744E0BEE631A61703D549"><enum>(7)</enum><text>other services;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 31 percent of immigrants with LEP report that language barriers interfere with their ability to access health care services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 29 percent of immigrants with LEP report that language barriers affect their ability to find or maintain employment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 25 percent of immigrants with LEP report difficulty applying for government financial assistance for food, housing, or health coverage;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 22 percent of immigrants with LEP report that language barriers have made it difficult to report a crime or seek assistance from law enforcement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas existing legislation protecting language access has served as an integral part to accessing federally funded programs and policies for all Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) prohibits recipients of Federal funding from discriminating based on national origin;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), originally the Food Stamp Act of 1964, requires that State agencies utilize bilingual personnel and appropriate printed materials when there are a large number of low-income households that speak a language other than English;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency to account for needs of people with LEP in disaster planning and prohibits discrimination on the basis of English proficiency in provision of assistance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>) prohibits discrimination based on nationality and requires language assistance in the 15 most common languages for health-related programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas section 203 of the Voting Rights Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503</external-xref>) requires certain counties and jurisdictions to provide bilingual voting assistance in communities with large numbers of language minorities and LEP citizens;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for nearly 25 years, both Republican and Democratic Presidents have affirmed the importance of language access through the implementation of Executive Order 13166, <quote>Improving Access to English Services for Persons with Limited English Proficiency</quote>, which required Federal agencies and grantees to examine the services they provide and provide individuals with LEP <quote>meaningful access</quote> to agency services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the California Department of Education recognizes April as National Bilingual/Multilingual Learner Advocacy Month;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many States and local governments, including the States of New York and Hawaii, recognize April as Language Access Month; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the purpose of Language Access Month is to increase awareness and celebrate the importance of language access to ensure equitable access to public services and programs for all Americans, including individuals with LEP: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFBD9FB908DA745C6A1EB33012970CDF2"><section id="H9E4B5E919FBF4395B58AEEC6F96D4A9C" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HDB06BC1A285641FBB99CEFC88DC520D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the recognition of <quote>National Language Access Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FCE9E7BE905478A8777AE21ECC8C9C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirms the importance of meaningful language access in ensuring equitable participation in Federal programs and services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F703FAF125D487BAC3D30481E543796"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages Federal agencies, States, local governments, and community organizations to promote awareness of language access rights and resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE741F331F91B4433A10C444614E57BDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe National Language Access Month with appropriate ceremonies, programs, and activities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

