<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD746A31DCD74FB69CA444DD33599250" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7957 IH: Preserve the Traditional Cultural Place Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7957</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To preserve the Traditional Cultural Place of Chi’chil Bildagoteel Historic District listed on the National Register of Historic Places, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB0CAD70F501743AB8859E58A33C5A8AD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H49DBD35FC91D4D289344984499B8D3DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserve the Traditional Cultural Place Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H32B9C825121A4C70A6695EED5E8482C0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBE890BEEFBB7488DAB28FC536C35A3E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Chí’chil Biłdagoteel, meaning <quote>a broad flat of Emory oak trees</quote> in Western Apache, and known as Oak Flat in English, is part of the ancestral homelands of Native Americans forcibly removed at gunpoint by the United States Army during the 1880s and held as prisoners of war in concentration camps until the early 1900s.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3510DA3B50AA4D3284512546CECDAC2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Despite being forcibly removed, Western Apaches and other Native Americans have maintained their deep connections to Chí’chil Biłdagoteel and continue to conduct religious ceremonies, gather medicines, water and other items for ceremonies, gather acorns and other foods, pray, and honor ancestors buried there as they have since time immemorial.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64D9414535FC42E796DAF2CF470A2EC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The National Historic Preservation Act was enacted in 1966 to help preserve the historical and cultural resources of the United States and authorized the National Park Service to establish and maintain the National Register of Historic Places <quote>to identify the Nation’s cultural resources and to indicate what properties should be considered for protection from destruction or impairment (36 CFR 60.1)</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5CC824AC5544CD58ED7DF88666F1941"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The National Park Service has established specific criteria for the evaluation of nominations to the National Register of Historic Places, including for traditional cultural places.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDB7B226CAEF43F2919E1FC5262581FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2012, the Tonto National Forest initiated the formal process of nominating Chí’chil Biłdagoteel to the National Register of Historic Places given its status as a known traditional cultural place.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3533DB69D5394AEF94A8BF877DBA6327"><enum>(6)</enum><text>From 2012 to 2014, as part of the nominating process, Tonto National Forest staff engaged in government-to-government consultations with Arizona Indian Tribes, made numerous site visits, compiled oral history and archival research, and worked with the Arizona State Historic Preservation Officer and the Pinal County Supervisor and incorporated their suggestions, comments and feedback, and this process resulted in the Forest Service formally nominating Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District to the National Register of Historic Places.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2369D78510654C36A0EFF57E31D14B10"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District encompasses thousands of acres located in the Tonto National Forest and includes Apache Leap, Ga’an or Devils Canyon, Queen Creek Canyon, and the previous Oak Flat Withdrawal Area issued under President Eisenhower’s Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H416654999F294F12A18628FB194AEEBE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 2014, despite bipartisan opposition, congressional allies of Resolution Copper inserted the Southeast Arizona Land Exchange Act as a closed-door, last-minute rider in the Carl Levin and Howard P. <quote>Buck</quote> McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 to give away approximately 2,422 acres of land within the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District to Resolution Copper.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFACA2E14988F4FA0B02881784CC8AFA0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 2014 and 2015, under the Southeast Arizona Land Exchange (Section 3003 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/291">Public Law 113–291</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/539p">16 U.S.C. 539p</external-xref>), the Forest Service supervised an ethnographic and ethnohistoric study in accordance with the National Historic Preservation Act and found that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1E3F6589E4649EA8A005561739A0064"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Chí’chil Biłdagoteel is a sacred place for Western Apaches and an important traditional cultural place for at least 9 Tribes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C06A4CBF8AB497FB45639308D03B01F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there are hundreds of traditional cultural resources, including ancestral archeological sites, petroglyph sites, Apache camps, and named landforms and resource collection areas within Chí’chil Biłdagoteel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF453C220465C41FFB7DFA9E499D9B90B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>there are 46 known springs that are culturally important to Western Apaches in Chí’chil Biłdagoteel and the surrounding area; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE8FB1E9D4BD4E2AA77880FE5A8F15EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>there are dozens of plants, minerals, and animals that possess traditional cultural significance to Western Apaches located in Chí’chil Biłdagoteel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89CE4A82A688450391AC28EB90C1BEBD"><enum>(10)</enum><text>On March 4, 2016, the National Park Service listed Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District on the National Register of Historic Places.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC5C552D7FF8421FA5FC30A8D1BF3661"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Southeast Arizona Land Exchange Act does not require Resolution Copper to smelt, refine, or sell the copper it extracts from beneath the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District in the United States, nor is there any requirement that this copper, derived from public land, benefits United States consumers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB78C5A0549EE41F5AE5C5AD339C57371"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Resolution Copper is a joint venture of the world’s two largest foreign mining entities, Rio Tinto (55 percent stake) and BHP (45 percent stake), and these foreign corporations formed Resolution Copper to acquire public land within the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District to extract United States copper located beneath it primarily for export to the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB894E9724831498FABB1A12821D5752C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Rio Tinto’s largest shareholder is Chinalco, a company wholly owned by the People’s Republic of China, which owns 14.56 percent of Rio Tinto, 4 times more than the next largest shareholder, and Rio Tinto generates over 57 percent of its revenue through the export of minerals to the People’s Republic of China, while BHP generates over 62 percent of its revenue through the export of minerals to the People’s Republic of China, making the People’s Republic of China the largest market for Rio Tinto and BHP.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33650064B40E402F8FBC4AAC917F90BA"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Rio Tinto has a long record of human rights violations and environmental devastation, harming communities around the world, including in Australia, Papua New Guinea, Madagascar, Indonesia, Mongolia, and Namibia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30E523EAB53343249283D74B2F8AEF78"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In 2020, Rio Tinto intentionally blew up an area sacred to the Puutu Kunti Kurrama and Pinikura peoples in Western Australia, including the Juukan Gorge Rock Dwellings, which have evidence of human habitation dating back 46,000 years, because it was the cheapest way to access ore, resulting in immeasurable cultural and spiritual loss and pain for indigenous communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A055788E3504843920B1A6F3E91DA18"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Resolution Copper Mine will result in the destruction of most, if not all, of the 2,422 acres of the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District transferred to Resolution Copper, including the collapse of the surface, resulting in a 1.8-mile-wide crater 1,000 feet deep, and fracturing and dewatering of local aquifers, which will drain ground water and springs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0486235F277340318AB9E1A8C3AB8D2F"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Resolution Copper Mine proposes the development of significant mining-related infrastructure throughout Tonto National Forest, including large parts of the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District that were not transferred to Resolution Copper under the Southeast Arizona Land Exchange, for the construction, operation, and maintenance of—</text> <subparagraph id="HE51CDD4567404E058E38BA32E16AB1F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a 19.6-mile pipeline corridor to slurry 1,370,000,000 tons of toxic waste to a dump site that will require drilling a tunnel through a mountain called King’s Crown Peak and constructing a pipeline bridge to span Ga’an Canyon in the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35291456C9004624909B7BEF7006F246"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 3.6-mile long high voltage power line corridor and a 16.9-mile power line through the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District to provide power to the toxic waste dump; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF362BC695F7E48068401C3F88CD248F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>new roads in the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District for servicing of the pipelines and power lines and the conversion of various Tonto National Forest service roads to commercial use by Resolution Copper.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84EB1993D7904135A21F043E35D5271A"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Resolution Copper Mine will have enormous impacts on the region, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DE02D824F3340A7923FC6295D710EEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consuming over 250,000,000,000 gallons of groundwater over the 40-year life of the mine, which is enough water to support 180,000 people annually for 40 years, resulting in over 4 feet of land subsidence over large swaths of the East Salt River Valley due to decreases in groundwater levels, in some areas by nearly 200 feet; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA1E173B4A48421AA061802A2BFA3B1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the construction of a toxic waste dump to store 1.37 billion tons of toxic waste in perpetuity that will measure nearly 500 feet high and span approximately 15,000 acres in an area called Skunk Camp in the Gila River watershed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD4FA1D64EFC4A33B031CA5AC3D8D7CC"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District should be preserved and protected instead of allowing foreign-owned Resolution Copper to destroy it, resulting in permanent and irreplaceable religious and cultural loss to Native Americans while jeopardizing the health and safety of downstream communities due to inevitable future breaching of the toxic waste dump.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H962B7E82AB5D4229966DC086E6A0F0B4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H4F8BBE20328041E88CBFB0AEC46B1C80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District</term> means the traditional cultural place listed on the National Register of Historic Places located on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H71B11E89D17B4AA1B56820A029352E78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tonto National Forest land in southeastern Arizona; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H014E873B5FC241518A2CA1850B3D1252"><enum>(B)</enum><text>what was previously National Forest System land but transferred to Resolution Copper on or about March 13, 2026, in the Tonto National Forest in southeastern Arizona.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C5BADF16FE94F1D8A8DDCDE9BA636CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB142E5ED2B9842618CB6FDE8D5C03E4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Forest System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>National Forest System</term> has the meaning given the term in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE06D74C733904A2DB9493ECE8A23D205"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Resolution Copper</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Resolution Copper</term> means Resolution Copper Mining, LLC, formed by foreign mining entities Rio Tinto and BHP, to acquire 2,422 acres of the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District to extract and monetize American copper located beneath it.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H869195CFD7CB447A9CEB08027DB463A7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3E3FECC3C2E4CBDA598357F9C2327C2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Traditional cultural place</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>traditional cultural place</term> means a place eligible for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places based upon its associations with cultural practices and beliefs of a living community that are rooted in that community’s history and important in maintaining the community’s continuing cultural identity.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HED6A90E5BD994422855F2783B9B772F5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Forest System land located in the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District is withdrawn from all forms of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H92F7771F52604CFBB986960E94E9406E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70501437DEDE44D7929F0FBE70C2698D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B898698A28F48FFB49F42B9EC324411"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H459FC90B225442778449C0208E7EB271"><enum>5.</enum><header>Preservation of a historic place; prohibitions on use; consultations and cooperative agreements</header> <subsection id="H3FFDCBE3F3914D88AA8BB2F4BBEF8ACB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preservation of a historic place</header><text>The Secretary—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC840DD219A744ECE9860683B23302A8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall preserve the natural condition of the National Forest System land in the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District as a traditional cultural place;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF020C89B106542DB9945ED482423BDCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not carry out any activity that would adversely affect the physical or cultural integrity of the National Forest System land in the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDF53800967344BABAA0F257159339E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall prohibit any activities that could adversely affect the landscape or other natural structures, water resources, wildlife, flora, or ecosystems of the National Forest System land in the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB5D74AE44D2B4EF3B0C38E0E1989E508"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Prohibition of mining-Related activities</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other law, all activities related to mining and mining-related activities, including rights-of way, toxic waste pipelines and related infrastructure, electrical and other utility development, waste disposal, and road development and road expansion, are prohibited on the National Forest System land in the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDF266557363B40BDBF6E6EBE12898DDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultations and cooperative efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall engage in government-to-government consultations with Indian Tribes with ties to the Chí’chil Biłdagoteel Historic District and shall enter into cooperative agreements requested by these Indian Tribes to ensure access to the National Forest System land for traditional activities and preservation of sacred and cultural areas.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

