<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H81E64D223EF64A7499EA5AB0DE8F92A2" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3679 : Small Business Artificial Intelligence Advancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3679</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc> Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to develop resources for small businesses in utilizing artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HEC3EE6D08625492DA209AE2CDCE28C13"><section id="HD954B954458F460CBEBCD8740E0B407C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Artificial Intelligence Advancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD03A765AD70A4F17868493AE36DD213C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Resources for small businesses to utilize artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 22A of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278h-1">15 U.S.C. 278h–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H72C2F73C45A54866AFDE24C021F5D2B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0F5118895CF42EF9D6D373E73B97AF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H1047141FAD1D4446BDE7A0E0E896E1AB" style="OLC"><subsection id="HC16DE6768CCD46A9B72040E787E00BED"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Development of resources for small businesses in utilizing artificial intelligence</header><paragraph id="H9CFBFF33CA874D20B7A32EE789CD3307" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Director shall, in carrying out subsection (a), develop or identify, and disseminate (in accordance with paragraph (4)), resources for small business concerns (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)) relating to artificial intelligence. Such resources may include technical standards, best practices, benchmarks, methodologies, procedures, or processes for the understanding, adoption, or integration of artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72DA4A32CA6E4BA4BA082F933A9151B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Director shall ensure that the resources described in paragraph (1) satisfy the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD7C9817364F44552803AAE2B5F278C6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Are generally applicable and usable by a wide range of small business concerns.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50EDE7CCE0BD4E3EA3E405C96C6E2F7C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Include elements that promote basic understanding, identification, and adoption of proper use cases of artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA88D0B88AE44D389BF26628193F2049"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Include case studies of practical application across a range of business sizes and types.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B93E60FF5104D699A128B1AD30369BD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Are technology-neutral and relevant to technologies that are accessible and suitable for small businesses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DE4E4479EDD4AE98313B50E6FDE1588"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Are based on international voluntary standards as applicable, and are consistent with the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3701">15 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H487886EF3FB342398FDC65EEC44DB19A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Include recommendations and references to existing Federal educational resources, including the risk management framework under subsection (c), privacy and cybersecurity risk management frameworks established by the Institute, and activities relating to the national cybersecurity awareness and education program under section 303 of the Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7443">15 U.S.C. 7443</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17D430785B2F4DDDA0CE316C0F67475F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review and update of resources</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this subsection and not less frequently than once every two years thereafter, the Director shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF9912D543290484E9F12E6028CAE7F5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Review the resources described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H758158060B31403BB2ABDC31ED3420DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Update such resources as the Director considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA52A52AD36344977BA2BE2965F85535E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dissemination and use of training resources</header><text>The Director shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration regarding the distribution and use through the resource partners of the Small Business Administration of the resources described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1299B995F7A4224B8A1A7EA93C3E8EA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Voluntary resources</header><text>The use of the resources described in paragraph (1) shall be considered voluntary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50D5E30D2402490E8A3C0EF8EB6F4BB4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="H1D97E5B686674186B73802E201A5BA4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than four years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the development, identification, dissemination, and use of the resources described in paragraph (1), including updates made pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE820350318348A2B0AAAF13A7388336"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text><clause id="H4E11EDE82E3E416E9F33145D622B8008"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A list of the resources described in paragraph (1), including updates made pursuant to paragraph (3).</text></clause><clause id="HCB298809BC8C4990984BCBB6229993CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Relevant feedback from recipients of such resources, and disseminators of such resources pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></clause><clause id="H318B2257F5A5447795068C6E6EA266F0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Recommendations to Congress for further actions to help with the utilization of artificial intelligence by small business concerns.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260223" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 23, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

