<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC94840A8CAF5408B848EA2246DABC7CD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1301 IH: Supporting the designation of May 29, 2026, as “Mental Health Awareness in Agriculture Day” to raise awareness around mental health in the agricultural industry and workforce and to continue to reduce stigma associated with mental illness.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1301</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of May 29, 2026, as <quote>Mental Health Awareness in Agriculture Day</quote> to raise awareness around mental health in the agricultural industry and workforce and to continue to reduce stigma associated with mental illness.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas, according to the 2022 Census of Agriculture of the Department of Agriculture, 3,370,000 producers, less than 2 percent of the population of the United States, provide high-quality food, fuel, and fiber to the United States and abroad;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Economic Policy Institute, there are approximately 1,600,000 farmworkers in the United States;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Rural Health Association, the rate of suicide among farmers is 3.5 times higher than among the general population;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Mortality-Linked National Health Interview Survey, the rate of suicide among farmworkers is 1.4 times higher than rates across all other occupations;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the month of May is National Mental Health Awareness Month; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the stigma surrounding mental and behavioral health persists and acknowledging this public health crisis and creating awareness is as important as ever: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEAE02DDE6D4046FCA6BD0E8AB1921FF5"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H96C48B4F052C4AF69ABA9592007FF5A8"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H57CE0A94E0CC464A9EFD922D53EF244F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Mental Health Awareness in Agriculture Day</quote> to raise awareness around mental health in the agricultural industry and reduce the stigma associated with mental illness;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H636EB09F4C084DF68BC86A98A00879EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the important role of individuals in agriculture as providers of high-quality products to the United States and the world;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F1E9AD7D597401C8896CEC286AE5513"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seeks to create awareness for the unique challenges agricultural producers and workers face, such as weather unpredictability, labor intensity and shortages, farm succession, and fluctuating commodity and market prices;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBAFA4A220DB5495CBAD6A76A16F6103F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>highlights the resources available through the Farm and Ranch Stress Assistance Network of the Department of Agriculture in connecting agricultural producers and workers to stress assistance programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB61161B040C84B0B9229F50D85BF1079"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages all to observe Mental Health Awareness in Agriculture Day as an opportunity to promote mental well-being and awareness for current and future agricultural producers and workers.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

