<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7F43D0FDBBE468AADDEA6ED9025FC24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7384 IH: Preventing Mass Casualties from Release of Hydrofluoric Acid at Refineries Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7384</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit the use of hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) at petroleum refineries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H719B0DE57DB04EF8BA757D8AE5B72643" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBF1C9A64F3634DABBC78855CE6D6910E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Mass Casualties from Release of Hydrofluoric Acid at Refineries Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H2E3D8E9B22B347B2A8033F9E01ED0096" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4EA5A5A987F74A5B8659FFC4C10A9833" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) is an exceptionally hazardous chemical, which is used in large quantities in approximately 40 petroleum refineries in the United States to refine petroleum in order to produce high octane gasoline.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC50C6DBA728F435895F7C38676C83FAD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Petroleum refineries are vulnerable to accidents, natural disasters, and intentional subversive acts, which could result in the release of a large quantity of hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8378D5F9439F48BD805B09FE154E3AE0" commented="no"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>The release of a sufficient quantity of hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) from a petroleum refinery has in the past, and could in the future, caused immediate injuries or deaths to refinery workers who are exposed.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAF7CC04D5CB64D7EB083421A8BD3354C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The release of a sufficient quantity of hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) from a petroleum refinery could cause a mass casualty event in the surrounding community, resulting in immediate deaths or permanent injuries to thousands of people living, working, or traveling within a radius of up to 25 miles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9624936594034037B83D8BAAE580C07C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">More than 14 million people are at risk of death or permanent injuries as a result of living in communities surrounding petroleum refineries that use hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid), and many of these at-risk communities are disproportionately impacted by environmental burdens.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEF49E8901AAA4C49B26FBD5813AA8C3F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alternative technologies are available that would enable petroleum refineries to convert from the use of hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) to a vastly safer, commercially proven alternative method for refining petroleum to produce high octane gasoline, and these alternative technologies are already used in the majority of refineries in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37C4B895AA104D58A971917B4B371C9D" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">New petroleum refineries should not be allowed to use hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) to refine petroleum, and petroleum refineries that currently use hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) should be required to convert to a safer alternative.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HEC2C549C675845FF9B0BFDEDB37A0709"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of hydrofluoric acid at petroleum refineries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2605">15 U.S.C. 2605</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7E7D6560256640A0B660DA71D8EE3C80"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (k); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5F30D8526694143852DA83D475517EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (i) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB401665F6B334A4E8857F5DB6A245B3A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H4B0C70605A0D4B4BB311038E46AE8EDF"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of hydrofluoric acid at petroleum refineries</header> <paragraph id="H0AEDB6208C7A4EE38D92E1AE6C697FD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New refineries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person may use hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) to refine petroleum at a petroleum refinery that begins operating on or after the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5030385814A04D9881B2EC499E896C7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing refineries</header>
<subparagraph id="H5AE73E89CD9D47ECAA3795A17E80FC07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, no person may use hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) to refine petroleum at a petroleum refinery that began operating before the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF86141F97479472C9304C5B319AF6875" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the first sentence of section 16(a)(1), the amount of a civil penalty under such first sentence for violating a provision of section 15 with respect to a requirement of this paragraph shall be $37,500 for each such violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBC4A540868C245EFBCBDD6EC9CEA5D8C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 22, the Administrator may not issue a waiver under such section with respect to the prohibition on the use of hydrogen fluoride (hydrofluoric acid) at a petroleum refinery under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

