<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCEF64836A3B4489DB54AC142D4261320" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1391 IH: Impeaching Linda M. McMahon, Secretary of Education, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1391</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Linda M. McMahon, Secretary of Education, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H60090DE5B79A4723B4423844E2FF137C"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6566CD2DE4E44BA88A3F6FCB8D95820E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Linda M. McMahon, Secretary of Education, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following articles of impeachment be exhibited to the United States Senate:</text><subsection id="HE9C26D7CD5384EC09696F8E31B51FF1F"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Articles of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Linda M. McMahon, Secretary of Education, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against her for high crimes and misdemeanors.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8762FCF4249F4056A0FFF50122CBBF8F" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article I: Willful and systemic refusal to comply with the law</header><subsection id="H680EF50EF3C3438C9ECD50CB7D6E1A1C"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Constitution provides that the House of Representatives <quote>shall have the sole Power of Impeachment</quote> and that civil Officers of the United States, including the Secretary of Education, <quote>shall be removed from Office on Impeachment for, and Conviction of, Treason, Bribery, or other high Crimes and Misdemeanors</quote>. In her conduct while Secretary of Education, Linda M. McMahon, in violation of her oath to support and defend the Constitution of the United States against all enemies, foreign and domestic, to bear true faith and allegiance to the same, and to well and faithfully discharge the duties of her office, has willfully and systemically refused to comply with the laws of the United States, in that:</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1E86BCFAA934EBF95E96B44FC5ED121"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During her tenure as Secretary of Education, Linda M. McMahon has violated Federal law by illegally transferring the operations of 6 offices under the Department of Education to other Federal agencies. These actions fundamentally obstruct the ability of the Department of Education to conduct statutory oversight and disburse Federal funds appropriated by Congress through its authority under article I of the Constitution of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC93C2740EB0D48A58E012B9C6CA1BBDC" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 204 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3414">20 U.S.C. 3414</external-xref>) states that <quote>There shall be in the Department, an Office of Elementary and Secondary Education, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Elementary and Secondary Education appointed under section 202(b). The Assistant Secretary shall administer such functions affecting elementary and secondary education, both public and private, as the Secretary shall delegate. There shall be within the Office of Elementary and Secondary Education and directly under the supervision of the Assistant Secretary for Elementary and Secondary Education, an Office of Migrant Education, which shall be responsible for the administration of programs established by part C of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 and by subpart 5 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6EC26DAA82EA4B12BC6ABD3A0E863B81"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 30, 2025, Linda M. McMahon approved an interagency agreement moving the provision of several essential programs and services under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to the Department of Labor’s Employment and Training Administration. This action represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF55776E0D3B24383B9A649EFED521D2E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 20, 2026, Linda M. McMahon approved another interagency agreement moving the provision of additional programs and services under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to the Department of Health and Human Services. This action represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4A33B4DD9FAF4ACE8CDB4BA2595296D5"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3415">20 U.S.C. 3415</external-xref>) states that <quote>There shall be in the Department, an Office of Postsecondary Education, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education appointed under section 202(b). The Assistant Secretary shall administer such functions affecting postsecondary education, both public and private, as the Secretary shall delegate, and shall serve as the principal adviser to the Secretary on matters affecting postsecondary education.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD63207023665489993CFE4F1CCA135C8"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 30, 2025, Linda M. McMahon approved an interagency agreement moving the provision of several essential programs and services under the Higher Education Act of 1965 to the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor. This action represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AFDC9C072864F94BFD68AFBFB52ED80"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 20, 2026, Linda M. McMahon approved another interagency agreement moving the provision of additional programs and services under the Higher Education Act of 1965 to the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs of the Department of State. This action represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD51BFBDCE3AE446DAB77DDFAA9D0232D"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 206 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3416">20 U.S.C. 3416</external-xref>) states that <quote>There shall be in the Department, an Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education appointed under section 202(b). The Assistant Secretary shall administer such functions affecting career, technical, an adult education as the Secretary shall delegate, and shall serve as principal adviser to the Secretary on matters affecting career, technical, and adult education.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H19DD50E3AE204509AC48F55C29C9F93E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On May 21, 2025, Linda M. McMahon approved an interagency agreement moving the provision of essential programs and services under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor. This action represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1626AA3C479749C0B51F95F2EA73196E" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 207 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3417">20 U.S.C. 3417</external-xref>) states that <quote>There shall be in the Department an Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Special Education and Rehabilitative Services appointed under section 202(b). Notwithstanding the provisions of section 412, the Secretary shall delegate to the Assistant Secretary all functions, other than administrative and support functions, transferred to the Secretary under sections 301(a)(1) (with respect to the bureau for the education and training of the handicapped), 301(a)(2)(H), and 301(a)(4).</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98AA2F12FB5C436B8FA7EE24364C5042" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On June 15, 2026, Linda M. McMahon approved an interagency agreement moving the provision of essential programs and services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (formerly the Education for All Handicapped Children Act) and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to the Department of Health and Human Services. This action represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BC92ED80DF240398DB933586EB8EA89" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3413">20 U.S.C. 3413</external-xref>) states that <quote>There shall be in the Department an Office for Civil Rights, to be administered by the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights appointed under section 202(b). Notwithstanding the provisions of section 412 of this Act, the Secretary shall delegate to the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights all functions, other than administrative and support functions, transferred to the Secretary under section 301(a)(3).</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H272E092093F6404EAFB022735005BE61" commented="no"><enum/><text>On June 15, 2026, Linda M. McMahon approved an interagency agreement moving the provision of essential programs and services under the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Education Amendments of 1972, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, and the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 to the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice. This represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7106203FE53C4844B2E265A54457D190" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 215 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3423c">20 U.S.C. 3423c</external-xref>) states that <quote>There shall be in the Department an Office of Indian Education (referred to in this section as <quote>the Office</quote>) in the Department of Education.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB680820F05643E0B5F0AA6633AF0457" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 30, 2025, Linda M. McMahon approved an interagency agreement moving the provision of essential programs and services related to American Indians under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, the Higher Education Act of 1965, the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006, the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (formerly the Education for All Handicapped Children Act), and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to the Department of the Interior. This represents a willful violation of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF4C355828F6D4A1C9B0C634CAB49D3D8"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although the Department of Education has framed these interagency agreements as <quote>partnerships</quote>, Linda M. McMahon has publicly made statements referencing her plan to dismantle and eliminate the Department of Education, demonstrating a willful intent to violate the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>), including—</text><paragraph id="H9E12F0790F42488BB4BAB19929238DDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in a Fox News opinion editorial, Linda M. McMahon stated, <quote>I took office as Secretary of Education with a mission unlike any of my predecessors: to oversee the responsible and permanent closure of the very department I now lead</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4661E88E10B3476BABF8CF41ECF0DE49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a USA Today opinion editorial, Linda M. McMahon stated, <quote>The Trump administration will succeed where President Ronald Reagan and other conservative leaders did not . . . The Schumer shutdown underlined just how little the Department of Education will be missed</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABB745DCDCAF448495F9072036FB290E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These statements represent a willful intent to unilaterally dismantle and eliminate the Department of Education without approval by Congress. As a Federal agency established by Congress in the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.</external-xref>), the Department of Education cannot be dismantled, nor can statutory functions be reassigned to another Federal agency without an Act of Congress. Therefore, Linda M. McMahon’s actions have violated Federal law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C7C8DCDF09F4DC09BE6D4F5F250D048"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore Linda M. McMahon, by such conduct, has demonstrated that she will remain a threat to the Constitution if allowed to remain in office, and has acted in a manner grossly incompatible with her duties and the rule of law. Linda M. McMahon thus warrants impeachment and trial, removal from office, and disqualification to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust, or profit under the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="H238DA72B967148928CBFDF1F7C0EAAD1" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum/><header>Article II: False Statements Before Congress</header><subsection id="HC891ACCCC8CD4904BCFCF67E2901AF9C"><enum/><text>The Constitution provides that the House of Representatives <quote>shall have the sole Power of Impeachment</quote> and that civil Officers of the United States, including the Secretary of Education, <quote>shall be removed from Office on Impeachment for, and Conviction of, Treason, Bribery, or other high Crimes and Misdemeanors</quote>. In her conduct while Secretary of Education, Linda M. McMahon, in violation of her oath to support and defend the Constitution of the United States against all enemies, foreign and domestic, to bear true faith and allegiance to the same, and to well and faithfully discharge the duties of her office, has made false statements during testimony before the United States Senate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0B857DB0EC340B2B6F06DA277A34471"><enum/><text>On February 13, 2025, Linda M. McMahon testified before the United States Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. During her testimony, McMahon made several deceptive and false statements, willfully misleading Congress and demonstrating her willingness to violate Federal law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC08A3E8908FF42ACAF5E76FCE57E81D5"><enum/><text>Linda M. McMahon repeatedly stated in her testimony that, under her leadership, the Department of Education would disburse all congressionally appropriated dollars in accordance with statute.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBB6FB2695208405D9BEC2EABF1885CA3"><enum/><text>Senator Murray asked Linda M. McMahon <quote>if confirmed, do you commit to getting every dollar we have invested in our students and schools out to them?</quote> and McMahon responded, <quote>well, the appropriated dollars and those monies that are passed by Congress, yes</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB3286C915B047DF91DDE2C2AFA2A582"><enum/><text>Senator Murray asked, <quote>what will you do if the President or Elon Musk tells you not to spend money Congress has appropriated to you?</quote> and McMahon responded, <quote>We will certainly expend those dollars that Congress has passed, but I do think it is worthwhile to take a look at the programs before money goes out the door</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCD70044294B94ECD80EC37DDB2CE129D"><enum/><text>Senator Hassan asked a question about the President’s attempt to cut all Federal funding to New Hampshire. McMahon stated, <quote>Let me just object to one point, and that is that the residents in the State of New Hampshire should not be concerned that Federal funding is going to be removed from their schools. How they get that Federal funding may change</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6D095BC4CD2A411DAC992BEC2FD37F04"><enum/><text>Senator Markey asked, <quote>Ms. McMahon, can you commit today to not cutting funding for public schools in this country?</quote> and McMahon responded, <quote>Well certainly what I’ll commit to, sir, is that funding for schools is appropriated by Congress and that funding should continue</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5912E2CD53064DA596089F29C35467A5"><enum/><text>Senator Alsobrooks asked <quote>If you are confirmed, would you support any directive from the President to freeze funds that have been appropriated by Congress, including funds that students and families rely on to pay for college?</quote> and McMahon replied, <quote>If they’ve been appropriated by Congress, those funds should be disseminated</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD8C1266E23E64BEA8BC6FB4764E0D20B"><enum/><text>Despite repeated assurances that all congressionally appropriated funding would be spent in accordance with the statute authorizing such funding, and pledging to disburse this funding as Secretary, McMahon has repeatedly contradicted these statements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H37B014456C264508BD95109691B5F0A3"><enum/><text>Since taking office on March 3, 2025, McMahon has made no effort to reinstate the Institute of Education Sciences contracts that were illegally canceled in February 2025, and has instead defended these cancellations in both previous and ongoing lawsuits. Examples of these canceled contracts include—</text><paragraph id="HDBA35592C40548A39123D64D850240D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">10 contracts for Regional Educational Laboratories, which are congressionally authorized under the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9501">20 U.S.C. 9501 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB43FD13E2D17417DBB0DE0CAA0CCDAAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a $500,000 contract to conduct studies for the congressionally mandated evaluation of career and technical education under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9FF00EEB0F64F728D95DB0DEB3321B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a $22,739,370 contract to conduct a National Assessment of Adult Education as part of a report provided to Congress; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF91334E99B34489CAC4E7ED3625C3EF1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">18 grants totaling $226,000,000 awarded under the Comprehensive Centers Program authorized under the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9601">20 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3EEB3C90BD54DCC8CD73EE2A326E30A"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Linda M. McMahon has canceled or discontinued hundreds of Federal grants, including $1,000,000,000 in grant funds for student mental health under the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act and $168,000,000 in Full-Service Community Schools grants under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Congress authorized these grants with bipartisan support and McMahon terminated them without congressional approval.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD0166BC2502245EAB5E20BE782C7AB4E" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In June 2025, the Department of Education notified colleges and universities across the country that they would not receive funding for the College Assistance Migrant Program, authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) and funded by Congress under the Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/83">Public Law 118–83</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD88096B5FE934245A7CDA5EA15882A33" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In September 2025, the Department of Education rejected or canceled approximately 100 TRIO grants authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) and funded by Congress under the Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/83">Public Law 118–83</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7E0F0E0EA474A02A33D426B7B69E284" commented="no"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 10, 2025, Linda M. McMahon halted $350,000,000 in Federal grant funds authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) and funded by Congress under the Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/83">Public Law 118–83</external-xref>) for the following programs:</text><paragraph id="H4D9155A67CAB41409259ACE66933BEB7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Strengthening Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian-Serving Institutions (authorized under part A of title III of such Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02F281319D8E407685E43118F87C916C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening Predominantly Black Institutions (authorized under part A of title III of such Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03A7D6525BE44CCE81169D526632E987" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-Serving Institutions (authorized under part A of title III of such Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FAF89417DCB433E9514A8D5C44331E1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening Native American-Serving Nontribal Institutions (authorized under part A of title III of such Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF75704A99C774E4A82D43BE4F5F3DC81" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Minority Science and Engineering Improvement (authorized under part E of title III of such Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9E2AA008E144123902A57461085FEB4" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing Hispanic-Serving Institutions (authorized under part A of title V of such Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5833D881EF0742C99BD5530C4C625D5A" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promoting Postbaccalaureate Opportunities for Hispanic Americans (authorized under part B of title V of such Act).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07FBCB342C6848939C28F62D60A49328"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Linda M. McMahon’s actions to cancel congressionally authorized grant funding since taking office on March 3, 2025, demonstrate that the statements made during her February 13, 2025, testimony were knowingly, willfully, and materially false.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C952BC1A4004DEAA0ACA0CC3EC8B71A"><enum/><text>Wherefore Linda M. McMahon, by such conduct, has demonstrated that she will remain a threat to the Constitution if allowed to remain in office, and has acted in a manner grossly incompatible with her duties and the rule of law. Linda M. McMahon thus warrants impeachment and trial, removal from office, and disqualification to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust, or profit under the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="H288416C7F89C442C8D51D526ABEBAB56" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article III: Breach of Public Trust</header><subsection id="HC79ADDE775A44EBBB8A0AB90630C77B4"><enum/><text>The Constitution provides that the House of Representatives <quote>shall have the sole Power of Impeachment</quote> and that civil Officers of the United States, including the Secretary of Education, <quote>shall be removed from Office on Impeachment for, and Conviction of, Treason, Bribery, or other high Crimes and Misdemeanors</quote>. In her conduct while Secretary of Education, Linda M. McMahon, in violation of her oath to well and faithfully discharge the duties of her office, has breached the public trust, in that:</text></subsection><subsection id="H736E6D5F92734BEB90C92DB3A5BCC824"><enum/><text>Linda M. McMahon has terminated the employment or overseen the departure of approximately 2,000 employees at the Department of Education, affecting roughly half of the Department of Education’s total workforce.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD90A3E02D71E4A61B48D4A58205C1FBE"><enum/><text>On March 11, 2025, Linda M. McMahon announced a reduction in force (referred to in this article as a <quote>RIF</quote>) to cut the Department of Education’s workforce in half. The RIF included the termination of 1,378 employees without cause, including hundreds of employees in the Office for Federal Student Aid and the Office for Civil Rights.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1AEA83D608BC4A1590DF2A005901490C"><enum/><text>Later that year, the Department of Education failed to disburse congressionally authorized funding in a timely manner, creating significant delays that affected educational programming at elementary and secondary schools and institutions of higher education across the country. These delays in disbursement affected the following programs:</text><paragraph id="H623DE4F25C0548DEB36DDD9E54C391C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Migrant Education grants authorized under part C of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6391">20 U.S.C. 6391 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD454BAD02CE44757834B0833ECA43668"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Supporting Effective Instruction State Grants authorized under part A of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6611">20 U.S.C. 6611 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF143B35FEA1740E68288B7C03BCA2DEA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">English Language Acquisition State Grants authorized under part A of title III of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6811">20 U.S.C. 6811 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E8115C6BD9B4DA8A99DA94219345C6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Student Support and Academic Enrichment Program grants authorized under part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA27C083A9C024551948F460B54F6AC02"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nita M. Lowey 21st Century Community Learning Centers grants authorized under part B of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">20 U.S.C. 7171 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H654BB4F3A51947A8B9F679AD336EF279"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal TRIO Programs grants authorized under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5EC0FA1220E4E5FA291BFF879D77243"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs grants authorized under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36CBFD0A127472B82AF41BBB91F8BB6"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">College Assistance Migrant Program authorized under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71A346D040BA49068314B95BFBE39ED7"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">High School Equivalency Program authorized under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA10D911F74A245CE9316295EFC8C8E6C"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Adult Basic and Literacy Education State Grants authorized under title II of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3271">29 U.S.C. 3271 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19B2F015815F40359D995FCBAB87CEEE"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Integrated English Literacy and Civics Education State Grants authorized under title II of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3333">29 U.S.C. 3333</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B7DB30A52F14B88BDD596ED3A2757C2"><enum/><text>In October 2025, Linda M. McMahon initiated another harmful and unnecessary RIF and terminated an additional 465 employees without cause. Although a continuing resolution later reversed these terminations, the move was another chaotic and destructive attempt to undermine the work of the Department of Education.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC96CE638566A4D0EBD672BD7DE162760"><enum/><text>Linda M. McMahon has decimated the Department of Education’s capacity to fulfill its statutory responsibilities and created a culture of fear and chaos that has already disrupted and harmed critical educational programming. These actions have breached the public trust in the Department of Education and in Linda M. McMahon as its leader.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9022A9377D9D41909B7F944A44B47FF5"><enum/><text>Wherefore Linda M. McMahon, by such conduct, has demonstrated that she will remain a threat to the Constitution if allowed to remain in office, and has acted in a manner grossly incompatible with her duties and the rule of law. Linda M. McMahon thus warrants impeachment and trial, removal from office, and disqualification to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust, or profit under the United States.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

