<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9C0C21018334019A18A8AEA9AF5A56A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9013 IH: Fireworks Trafficking and Money Laundering Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9013</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260522">May 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide that unlawful interstate transportation of fireworks is specified unlawful activity for purposes of laundering of monetary instruments.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H84BF0BB958DF4EE893E54DE8B336533F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3869319C544B4301B8976C405E221EB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fireworks Trafficking and Money Laundering Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2401E64A2A5C4C3796DFB2161ADE3F1F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H54190B878C7D46358B4128149CB73619"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Illegal fireworks trafficking is a multifaceted criminal activity involving the transportation, distribution, and sale of explosive materials in violation of Federal and State laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06FF3EFA10BD4B73891349822B0A1591"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Law enforcement actions across the United States have demonstrated that individuals engaged in illegal fireworks trafficking frequently participate in related financial crimes, including money laundering, and may accumulate substantial illicit proceeds and assets subject to forfeiture.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6EB63AFE0CB044BB970E0392FE5B333F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Investigations have revealed that illegal fireworks are often transported across state lines and sold at significant markups, creating highly profitable black-market operations that can persist over many years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FE9E26DD80E44FF9EABBC573EFFED4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The use of illegal fireworks has resulted in numerous incidents causing serious injuries, mass casualty events, and fatalities, including some of the deadliest explosions and accidents in recent history.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC97B32AC69FC425C914AF8C080101739"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Fireworks-related injuries place a significant burden on emergency response systems and healthcare infrastructure, with thousands of individuals requiring emergency medical treatment each year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C3449A873E44A7CAB64A7A9925558F5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Illegal trafficking of fireworks poses substantial risks to public safety, as such explosives are often manufactured, transported, stored, and used without proper safety standards, increasing the likelihood of fires, explosions, injuries, and deaths.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF656C42239D74B84913C6CEDD5F4FE60"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Illegal fireworks trafficking is frequently linked to broader criminal activity, including drug trafficking, financial crimes, and organized criminal enterprises, which may use fireworks distribution networks to generate revenue, launder money, and evade law enforcement oversight.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3A98ED857534AD48E121CE1585FA68D"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>The investigation and prosecution of illegal interstate fireworks trafficking are often constrained by the limited statutory penalties, which provide for a maximum term of imprisonment of one year, thereby reducing the prioritization of such offenses relative to more serious Federal crimes, and providing an insufficient disincentive to engage in illegal activity especially as compared to the large financial incentives to do so.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H289F1EF115CB42C3B7BFD3FA66ECF22E">
        <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text>Designating illegal interstate fireworks trafficking as a specified unlawful activity for purposes of laundering of monetary instruments will strengthen law enforcement efforts by authorizing the application of Federal money laundering statutes to the proceeds of illegal fireworks trafficking, thereby enhancing investigative tools, disrupting criminal financial networks, and increasing the maximum term of imprisonment to up to twenty years.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H52ED4CA88A7A4F9AA1EB4B2F39B772AF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unlawful interstate transportation of fireworks to be considered specified unlawful activity for purposes of laundering of monetary instruments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1956(c)(7)(D) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>section 836 (relating to interstate transportation of fireworks),</quote> after <quote>section 831 (relating to prohibited transactions involving nuclear materials),</quote>.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

