<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F6AE00AAFBC466189CFA9EA6ADB5FAD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9368 IH: Voter ID Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9368</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require the provision of identification as a condition of casting a ballot in an election for Federal office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF4478739A07746E8A59559DA337B0B03" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9CCE98928A7440F49A6C57200210E1B9" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voter ID Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H274AD51FE86B419E9D7DAB1ED7686159"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring voters to provide photo identification</header> <subsection id="H4158A19A4FF542CB9843CB972E718289"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement to provide photo identification as condition of casting ballot</header> <paragraph id="HFCB606C65CDC4D89A8775D9F7D0191E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 303 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CD71806C4D64CFABFF97DCCCA9A1421"> 
<section id="HDA4F0385CCA745B18C680B00C36B019C"><enum>303A.</enum><header>Photo identification requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H86CB1F6860A14A4A9BF3DEAB8B8B8BD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of identification required as condition of casting ballot</header> 
<paragraph id="H2DB63E04E63D4C51B51E8E0AEA1E8AD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals voting in person</header> 
<subparagraph id="H71FB1FD89C484CF09EAE0A7A992D095F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement to provide identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subparagraph (B), the appropriate State or local election official may not provide a ballot for an election for Federal office to an individual who desires to vote in person unless the individual presents to the official a valid physical photo identification.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H736B54D294BD4B618E6400C7051A813E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of provisional ballot</header> <clause id="H75E14DF4242F4487BD094D2BB55B6B59"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual does not present the identification required under subparagraph (A), the individual shall be permitted to cast a provisional ballot with respect to the election under section 302(a), except that the appropriate State or local election official may not make a determination under section 302(a)(4) that the individual is eligible under State law to vote in the election unless, not later than 3 days after casting the provisional ballot, the individual presents to the official—</text> 
<subclause id="H12C1035763974398BAFBB31AFEB4D3B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the identification required under subparagraph (A); or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H26E474EA883D4C1FB6A775CE3B45CD49"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an affidavit developed and made available to the individual by the State attesting that the individual does not possess the identification required under subparagraph (A) because the individual has a religious objection to being photographed.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H7E354500AB224F89930DA95AC245547A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No effect on other provisional balloting rules</header><text>Nothing in clause (i) may be construed to apply to the casting of a provisional ballot pursuant to section 302(a) or any State law for reasons other than the failure to present the identification required under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D6345C846B64F8689A200C6FCE9919F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals voting other than in person</header> <subparagraph id="H5B198466ED5F48259920707FEC2927AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subparagraph (B), the appropriate State or local election official may not accept any ballot for an election for Federal office provided by an individual who votes other than in person unless the individual submits with the ballot—</text> 
<clause id="HDF028C13AFB441528656901C8EF3B58A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of a valid photo identification; or</text></clause> <clause id="H5320F70D2BF249BA9CF1A723D038ED72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the last four digits of the individual’s Social Security number and an affidavit developed and made available to the individual by the State attesting that the individual is unable to obtain a copy of a valid photo identification after making reasonable efforts to obtain such a copy.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3B28D8D57044C96914D8079051F6C90" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) does not apply with respect to a ballot provided by—</text> <clause id="H57316715D4FE4997A164C8804BEC2116"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an absent uniformed services voter, as defined in section 107(1) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20310">52 U.S.C. 20310(1)</external-xref>); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1543EC573C494CBA8E8945F92C010382"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual provided the right to vote otherwise than in person under section 3(b)(2)(B)(ii) of the Voting Accessibility for the Elderly and Handicapped Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20102">52 U.S.C. 20102(b)(2)(B)(ii)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4F29C33822EC4194995C7F004CB5E3E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Providing public access to digital imaging devices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each State, the appropriate State or local government official of the State shall ensure, to the extent practicable, public access to a digital imaging device, which shall include a printer, copier, image scanner, or multifunction machine, at State and local government buildings in the State, including courts, libraries, and police stations, for the purpose of allowing individuals to use such a device at no cost to the individual to make a copy of a valid photo identification. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H997A4A42045945A8B9D56A40E930A123"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification of identification requirement to applicants for voter registration</header> 
<paragraph id="H5EC996C20C814548AF15B4EECD86F38D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall ensure that, at the time an individual applies to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State, the appropriate State or local election official notifies the individual of the photo identification requirements of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E4902FC3385428AAF6850B97891408A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for individuals applying to register to vote online</header><text>Each State shall ensure that, in the case of an individual who applies to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State online, the online voter registration system notifies the individual of the photo identification requirements of this section before the individual completes the online registration process.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H122A2BC8958C44579E92883B4EA028FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Valid photo identification defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a <quote>valid photo identification</quote> means, with respect to an individual who seeks to vote in an election for Federal office, any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9F94814883CD400AAC55030307457EE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A valid State-issued motor vehicle driver’s license that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29D0932446454CA9A5BF72A45F57F586"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A valid State-issued identification card that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date issued by a State motor vehicle authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C3CFF700DA44DEF8F49C1714A951100"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A valid United States passport for the individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E0E6D9F876E44D88846A66B9031648B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A valid military identification for the individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4617DED4CDB49BEA15BFE4763807D69"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A valid identification document issued by a Tribal government that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date. </text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C9232E5AEDA468FBF53D7E798EC9D26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 303 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3033AA307B3D48C1AD345189F39589A2"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 303A. Photo identification requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC83125283DB442BB90DF2479C44DB771"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to voluntary guidance by Election Assistance Commission</header><text>Section 311(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21101">52 U.S.C. 21101(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA16B683FEBE440B187FC4F86002C124B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (2);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4859735B0AF40FA83FF44F046B564F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75156F86691247898ED02E84218A19C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9470D8A64E7644CBA50C8E669B3F9B0F"> <paragraph id="H72221B5F8AD04BC7A0C9430CDED6D035" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the recommendations with respect to section 303A, the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Voter ID Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8AC7398325D4D7BA191075CB25A4671"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sections 301, 302, 303, and 304</quote> and inserting <quote>subtitle A of title III</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H74ABFDA5C2BA4662B333F00F80494FAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0BC4A5E21FDA42FFAC97EB0EDCE90ECE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program for provision of State and Tribal identification</header> 
<subsection id="H596866D2BCCF40DEA04739321B23670F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of title II of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/252">Public Law 107–252</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21001">52 U.S.C. 21001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD65D56D701784B7CAF28F28F768FFE4A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <part id="H0521A34C11F2419999E2F3333347C700"><enum>7</enum><header>Grant Program for Provision of Identification</header> <section id="HE69126238B264E80A114C660C3D36ACF"><enum>298.</enum><header>Grant program for provision of identification</header> <subsection id="HD057805C1C5E4989931D670294B92DF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants to States</header> <paragraph id="HC0FE51053CBD48CA9CCD12D1F669BA98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall make grants to each State that provides identification described in paragraph (2) without charge to any individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1FA259B5A9444BECBBFBCD6A647F99A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is eligible for such identification; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H05656276F102421E892F9C87255C1380"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides an attestation under penalty of perjury that the individual cannot afford to pay the fee otherwise charged by the State for the provision of the identification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA945BE2D7CEC40A2B045EA846233EB8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification described</header><text>An identification described in this subsection is—</text> <subparagraph id="H0FE31233042042EBA9CEB661D006C0B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State-issued motor vehicle driver’s license that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1EECDA2D9A04448AAAED187A764DAD19"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification card issued by a State motor vehicle authority that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAC6B9A843E0D47D59F7C8F5B7892D463"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants to Tribes</header> <paragraph id="H352D4B6B5459453EA47E9D9D3A50BBD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall make grants to each Tribal government that provides identification described in paragraph (2) without charge to any individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H42A7153084E34097B28F1F5826D7BD2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is eligible for such identification; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE34DF56969F147D29AF5FF70607D4C2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides an attestation under penalty of perjury that the individual cannot afford to pay such fee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F3ACF91588144EAB96183DD09F5BB95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification described in this subsection is an identification document issued by a Tribal government that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FD88C7FCB584A1E9AFBE9D8A9529EB2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>Tribal government</term> means the governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or community that the Secretary of the Interior acknowledges to exist as an Indian tribe under the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/479a">25 U.S.C. 479a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FBF3EB0B3A54846ACEB91992C2C5879"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 296 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H44B2F8EBE0794E728C567E58865DECAA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="part">Part 7—Grant Program for Provision of Identification</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 298. Grant program for provision of identification.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

