<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HADEBD5F1301C469E94C529BEEF79CBD7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6420 IH: Affordable Care Economic Stability and Small Business Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6420</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to define short-term limited duration insurance.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC974B05EF86B47E190ACFFE8A1DC6C74" style="OLC"><section id="H8EB8D8607C954F749050CCAB0248AD51" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Care Economic Stability and Small Business Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ACCESS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H33B7FC47290F4E69BB76ABCD48DE97E7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H9472DE286BFE4D55BCDDA6F4520C2C94"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Americans, including small businesses in the Nation, could benefit from access to efficient, quality, and more affordable health care coverage options.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87F4A652E76145B1B2DBB965E4794437"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Health insurance coverage designed to fill temporary gaps in coverage when an individual is transitioning from one plan or coverage to another, such as transitions in employment, is valuable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AD601548A714E87BD083DDB0D37A3A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Small businesses are particularly challenged by escalating health care costs threatening their viability and ability to continue supporting their employees and contributing to their local economies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D84C69D91D4B3D9B57612FB0D11FFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With continuously rising health care costs, short-term limited duration affordable health plans may provide a critical means for small business owners to provide portable coverage for United States workers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78AD7109544F4AED9B1BDBB232A8F647"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Access to flexible health care choices for American consumers and the small business community is paramount, including insurance plans that provide affordable and flexible coverage, building a path toward stronger health care coverage in the Nation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H80AD78B573D94AD2B4E0B6B09DBAFDEE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Short-term limited duration insurance</header><subsection id="H90AA42A2E3BF4BEBBD47989343A11863"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2791(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E4CF8C026CD48FDBF0F18D9107D167A" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HDCD714B245114D639742BE0477A28E5B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Short-term limited duration insurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>short-term limited duration insurance</term> means health insurance coverage provided under a contract with a health insurance issuer that—</text><subparagraph id="H23FEE5D0D8DC45C7B3AC21DD2A4B0270"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has an expiration date specified in the contract that is less than 12 months after the original effective date of the contract; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC519DEE37B38437BAC77D7F81414CBBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a duration of not more than 3 years (taking into account renewals or extensions) after the original effective date of the contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HEF3D09FF45544217BA36DCD064CE12A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guaranteed renewability</header><text>Section 2703 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-2">42 U.S.C. 300gg–2</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H70C077A4ABA940ADBE7E509B5F5F751B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>or offers short-term limited duration insurance</quote> after <quote>group market</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39EBE5632A1A4CECB99229DF895841E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1892A31DA7114A419DF8E47DAB5C254F" style="OLC"><subsection id="HD658F53B4CBC4B52B93100113A23D8B9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application to short-Term limited duration insurance</header><paragraph id="HE9CDD2E2A0124A2799098B7F3EFE352B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In applying this section in the case of short-term limited duration insurance—</text><subparagraph id="H52E71FB7B08440F0AE10C878F3166337"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a reference to <term>health insurance coverage</term> with respect to such coverage offered in the individual market shall be deemed to include short-term limited duration insurance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8672F7C6B39241A1BC339BCB359A0426"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a reference to <term>health insurance issuer</term> with respect to health insurance coverage offered in the individual market shall be deemed to include an issuer of short-term limited duration insurance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H911B7C4E665941AF875EDF2E5891BD5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for short-term limited duration insurance</header><text>In the case of short-term limited duration insurance, at the time of application for enrollment in such insurance coverage, an individual may decline renewability of such coverage in accordance with this section, and the contract between such individual and the health insurance issuer shall specify whether the individual opted for renewability or no renewability.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8CE0EB8CE50F4C6E9BD7D5BE33BBD924"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to contracts for short-term limited duration insurance that take effect on or after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

