<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE51F4B337F684196BB217F137D43C0F8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8744 IH: Trade Responsibly for Environmental Emissions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8744</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the import of certain goods produced, sourced, made, or otherwise derived from deforestation and the sale of such items in interstate commerce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H95234E9611C340D09BBA22DD4C33747E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H16F73EFC9D024041AE09A845061BC1F1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trade Responsibly for Environmental Emissions Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TREE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HB1294410A0074BF7B23229467EC267E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on import and sale in interstate commerce of deforestation goods</header> 
<subsection id="H3E8616D2EA554946BDEBDCB9280CAD1F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on January 1, 2029, it shall be unlawful for any operator or trader—</text> <paragraph id="HD5AA201BDC7847AE92F49D9FB821498E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to import into the United States any deforestation good; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7E3EF39938849A28A514AA995E21152"><enum>(2)</enum><text>introduce into interstate commerce, manufacture for introduction into interstate commerce, or sell, trade, or advertise in interstate commerce in the United States any deforestation good.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB36710775F014AAD9B943ED09AEBED4B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>False labeling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any operator or trader to make or submit any false record, account, label, or other information, with respect to any deforestation good that has been, or is intended to be, imported into the United States.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H4030CD6F7C8D4C0AB3B0DD8980B48899"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="H60F8EB5BF0AE4F2C9050F603C47786B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Due diligence statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection shall require a due diligence statement that complies with subsection (b) to be provided by each operator or trader who imports into the United States a covered commodity.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H41B31E5F65184101BFF4514174AF2D02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The due diligence statement required under subsection (a) shall contain—</text> 
<paragraph id="H85F77F57C9924171A6F0A062EE9BC765"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of each covered commodity, that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC8B24E34C64415FB15FF89D6C7F37B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the trade name of each such commodity;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA00FCB1C7DB443C8BA8863ECD8273E11" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the quantity and required unit of measurement, as determined by the Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection, of each such commodity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7DF15D929F6431AAEB1BC12F369243E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each such commodity that is wood or is otherwise produced using wood, the common and scientific names of such wood; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8DAC5897C82B4FF0BC9F974162D657BF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each such commodity coming from countries categorized under section 3 as a Level I or Level II risk, the country of origin and geolocation coordinates, as determined practical by the Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95DE94C12A2C427E824B6B8A7453BEB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, postal address, and contact information of each person that supplied to such operator or trader each covered commodity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C82AE5B6ABB4F5B85EF2A6644F5A143"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adequately conclusive and verifiable information that the covered products are deforestation free; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85079CEE2A4240C69AC93615394D8541"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other information the Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection determines necessary to determine that each covered commodity is not a deforestation good and has been produced in accordance with the relevant law regarding deforestation of the country of origin.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF580932B20A345E092C117BD1E408F41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil Penalties</header> 
<paragraph id="H49D05B73E0694A8982FDEDD975E0E973"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any civil or criminal penalty that may be imposed under title 18, United States Code, or any other provision of law, any operator or trader who violates this Act, or any regulation issued under this Act, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H1719FDA123DA452786B8E7155030CEA8" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be assessed a civil penalty in an amount not more than 4 percent of the total United States revenue of such operator or trader for the fiscal year preceding the issuance of such fine;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9AC8DADA6D364830A9134145B51C1B5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have each deforestation good confiscated; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60B15323DB574EC79F1674D12984DDD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a period of not more than 12 months, be ineligible—</text> 
<clause id="HA95CC2E7FDF54A29BA42ED0F8241DCDD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to enter into any contract with any Federal agency for the procurement of goods, materials, and services; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8BAF489BB0AB43308A0FD3B9C7397EF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for any Federal funding, grants, and concessions.</text> </clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA62BD72B6E9B455ABCDF228AF6014AD8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determining fine</header><text>In calculating each fine required under paragraph (1), the United States Trade Representative may consider—</text> <subparagraph id="H838DA4F4546D440F910EA07194F6F14B" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the environmental damage caused by the deforestation good;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA58987330B51487EB7146E6910EB2754" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ability of the violator to pay;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H486E46BEA55A434DBB7FFAE48A441684" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure such fine effectively deprives the violator of the economic benefits derived from importing the deforestation good; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H428FA44305914BAF8DCD31D451B5731B" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>gradually increase such fine for each repeat violation until the fine is in an amount equal to 4 percent of the total United States revenue of the violator for the fiscal year preceding the issuance of such fine.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CDE94C1A6F740CD8C8826B98E38AE5D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Serious or repeat violations</header><text>In the case of a serious or repeat violation, an operator or trader shall be prohibited from importing into the United States any good for a period of not more than 12 months.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCA6526545AA4F709D240FF42EA4956A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Determining serious violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining what constitutes a serious violation under paragraph (3), the United States Trade Representative shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="H7BAFBFB6CAD741A883236DADD61880DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EB03043E3AF48338AC73B896FD32E28"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree of culpability; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86AF97BAD30B49C5AA741745C0F9988E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other matters as the United States Trade Representative, in consultation with the Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection, determines necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H519259A8FC5C4EE0AA07E6673A1843EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increased inspection rates</header> 
<paragraph id="HE2791EDCA1D8484788A48FE9021012C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on December 31, 2029, based on the country categorization list required under section 3(a)(1), the Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection shall implement the following increased inspection rates:</text> <subparagraph id="H2087D22D00ED405681B911CEB24BD87A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the goods originating from a country, or region thereof, categorized by the United States Trade Representative under section 3(a)(1) as a Level I risk, not less than 9 percent of such goods imported into the United States in a calendar year shall be inspected for deforestation goods.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BBF154204404B9D9C38DC8DBD6779AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the goods originating from a country, or region thereof, categorized by the United States Trade Representative under section 3(a)(1) as a Level II risk, not less than 3 percent of such goods imported into the United States in a calendar year shall be inspected for deforestation goods.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DE9D7E1C7044FC1B260726B75124883"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the goods originating from a country, or region thereof, categorized by the United States Trade Representative under section 3(a)(1) as a Level III risk, not less than 1 percent of such goods imported into the United States in a calendar year shall be inspected for deforestation goods.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADB40DAA337A4AC080523F07369707A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection may, in consultation with the Attorney General, Secretary of State, United States Trade Representative, Secretary of Commerce, and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, promulgate such rules and regulations as such Commissioner determines necessary to carry out paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6955AEF09E9F4DADB4BC0AFA57E8447A" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interstate commerce prohibition</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2029, the Secretary of the Interior shall by regulation establish a plan to enforce the prohibition under section 1(a)(2).</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H2CB41356BC2B4C8BA241742E736D0961"><enum>4.</enum><header>Country categorization based on risk posed of importing deforestation goods</header> 
<subsection id="HF68B595483E1424889BD6D4619C54944"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Country categorization</header> 
<paragraph id="H06F08E6E5D3640FF9C9ADAE9295B1DBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H052F868F48AC4E3AA0FE56B115DC481F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than December 1, 2029, and every other year thereafter, categorize every country under one of the three risk levels described under subsection (b), except as provided under paragraph (2), based on the risk that imports originating from such country are deforestation goods; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19402739AB4A48AFB91E4ED9833691DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than December 31, 2029, and every other year thereafter—</text> <clause id="HE6A20E5465F443DC8A56AADDC879D8B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publish such categorization on the internet website of the United States Trade Representative; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H441071B0CDEF4D48877C7BBFC9CF0334"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>formally notify each country, as described under subsection (c)(4), of the risk level of such country and of each regional categorization of such country under paragraph (2).</text> </clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCABC698D185F4EFEA6D2501A3FDFC23E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regional categorizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A region within a country may be categorized by the United States Trade Representative under a different risk level under subsection (b) than the risk level such country is categorized under if sufficient information is available for the United States Trade Representative to determine that such region warrants a different categorization than the country such region is in.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1AF97A223E7420591BFF7CA47B93788"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interim categorization</header><text>For the period beginning on January 1, 2029, and ending on the date on which the United States Trade Representative completes the risk level categorization required under paragraph (1), each country, and each region thereof, shall be categorized under subsection (b)(2) as a Level II risk.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC0C511DA461F4223A0F38A31EA588445"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Risk Levels</header> <paragraph id="H7F5BB03C76554E34A8A25E42037CD45D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Level I</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A country, or region thereof, shall be categorized as a <quote>Level I</quote> if the imports originating from such country, or region thereof, pose a high risk of being deforestation goods.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E6595D29B224CFC83B74EBB40FFE3E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Level II</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A country, or region thereof, shall be categorized as a <quote>Level II</quote> if the imports originating from such country, or region thereof, pose a moderate risk of being deforestation goods.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7667AF8D333F4E6C943DB4C12B124CF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Level III</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A country, or region thereof, shall be categorized as a <quote>Level III</quote> if the imports originating from such country, or region thereof, pose a low risk of being deforestation goods.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7C4768698EA4CF9B5D10E2C8731EA03" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determining risk level</header> 
<paragraph id="HBBFBC0004F75495681DA45B84E0953AB" commented="no">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Assessment</header>
 <text>The risk level categorization required under subsection (a)(1) shall be based on an objective and transparent assessment, determined by the United States Trade Representative, considering the latest scientific evidence and internationally recognized sources, and shall be primarily based on the following criteria:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HF8B197B8D0774687A63D3DA2DC44655E" commented="no">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The rate of deforestation and forest degradation since December 31, 2020, within the country, or region thereof, being categorized.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HFDF045653B3A4C05BE2D3CF76EC64F49" commented="no">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The rate at which the country, or region thereof, being categorized is expanding the use of agriculture land for covered products, covered commodities, and covered sources.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H3C0A630091864CEBAA7E4522AA0C2E6A" commented="no">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The production trends of the covered products, covered commodities, and covered sources within the country, or region thereof, being categorized.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74DAB5702F814C89891A67B67D95F055" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional considerations</header><text>The assessment required under paragraph (1) shall also consider the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H890F52C194E5421B86A3DA1AE22E7B91" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information related to the effective covering of emissions and removals from agriculture, forestry, and land use in the nationally determined contribution to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (adopted in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, in June 1992) that may be submitted by the country, or region thereof, being categorized, regional authorities and operators in such country, or region thereof, nongovernmental organizations, indigenous peoples, local communities, civil society organizations and any other interested party the United States Trade Representative determines appropriate.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9BE875639D840EE918F7DFE8D15EAE2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Agreements and other instruments between the country, or region thereof, being categorized and the United States that address deforestation, forest degradation, and compliance with section 1.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5AAEB2D858AD48EB8BF6A4B3B5C2DAD0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the country, or region thereof, being categorized has national, regional, or local laws in place to combat deforestation and forest degradation, including whether such country, or region thereof, has—</text> 
<clause id="H4B774719E4D9498E8795E54B1CD087ED">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>implemented Article 5 the decision by the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change’s 21st Conference of Parities in Paris, France, adopted on December 12, 2015 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paris Agreement</quote>);</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="HE9B788E59D2A4EFB9F3C4AF364B9162B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether such country effectively enforces such laws; and</text></clause> <clause id="H397DF0EB78754039807846E9A1DA44A7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether the penalties imposed under such laws are of sufficient severity to deprive the penalized operator or trader of the benefits gained from engaging in deforestation or forest degradation.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA20C532FE1B94105B5D689A6B8FECAA2" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether the country, or region thereof, being categorized has transparent data on deforestation and forest degradation and, where applicable, the existence of, compliance with, or effective enforcement of laws protecting human rights, the rights of indigenous peoples, and local communities.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5B8608B3CED4465A5AD9A2F97165717" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Sanctions imposed by the Security Council of the United Nations or the United States on the import or export of deforestation goods.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H680F0F0FE7414053821731CC4A7B2E55"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Risk classification determined by the European Union under the European Union Deforestation Regulation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03DAA40B120F49688E817E5683C891BB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative shall engage with each country, or region thereof, that is categorized, at risk of being categorized as a Level I risk, with the objective of reducing the level of risk of such country or region thereof.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H063D007191B5487DA6814D4601B0A1A0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon finalizing the second risk-level categorization required under subsection (a)(1), and each risk-level categorization thereafter, the United States Trade Representative shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2A3D97E973F4BE19935AD079748E0CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>formally notify each country of a change from the most recently published risk-level categorization under subsection (a)(2) in the risk-level of such country or region thereof;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7754A693B424264A703972ECE3E2828"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide not longer than 6 months for such country to respond; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE55D9FC35C84DA5B47419AE58FE1E37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include in such notification the following:</text> 
<clause id="H7F96807EB65145EABEBA05D294D95D7D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each reason for the intention to change the risk level of the country or region thereof.</text></clause> <clause id="HD4D3993907BE4869BF797339A14949BB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of an increase in risk level, an invitation to respond in writing to provide information on measures taken by such country to remedy the situation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H167D566F8DD9486593B48B005D7079C0" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The consequences such country will face because of a change in the risk level of such country or region thereof.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H8C2C069D11854D649F502669FD39FEFF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duty To update</header><text>The United States Trade Representative shall update the risk-level categorization required under subsection (a)(1) earlier than required under such subsection if any new evidence is received that the United States Trade Representative determines affects the risk-level categorization of a country or region thereof.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H12572488BE074500860EF879E532A532"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative may, in consultation with the Attorney General, Secretary of State, Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection, Secretary of Commerce, and Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, promulgate such rules and regulations as such representative determines necessary to carry out this paragraph.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H0AC2F7DC28774019A116600ED50F760A" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>International assistance</header> <subsection id="H965F7AB2996B40C18B2129EE90F7DF09" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assistance to Level I countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall provide preference to countries categorized under section 1(d)(2)(A) as a Level I risk when providing financial assistance related to deforestation and forest-related degradation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE23BE6873E5B4657BCE24E5B824980E7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revenue from penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to all amounts collected in the form of civil penalties pursuant to section 1, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall use an amount equal to half of the total amount of penalties collected in the preceding fiscal year to provide assistance to under developed countries with respect to deforestation and forest-degradation management.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H06911E81FFB944BB883BC40E983646D8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9266B4101A3D4048896CD50B120CC01A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agriculture use</header><text>The term <quote>agriculture use</quote> means the use of land for the purpose of—</text> <subparagraph id="H2512242098314ABB8ED809816AC0511B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agriculture, including agricultural plantations and set-aside agricultural areas; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF527D2754FA040288DA90E72D775C6A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rearing livestock.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5F88A6F275146EC87D104DAD2CEA9CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered commodity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered commodity</quote> means each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAE48E01CD95E4D29ADEAB9AA75C91D92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Cattle.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC033E52E33564460AD519CA81FACFFDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Cocoa.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88B43E565132454E90FDA0016E463C5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Palm oil.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC1A400A5C0F49A5BFF1AB062750F32C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Rubber.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H90B48E5938C546018B035DD1D21FCD2C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Soy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H893381D3E9C44F6CB2D44972334144EB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Wood.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF968DD1981E4A8B9C868B15F2B0ABDE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered product</header><text>The term <quote>covered product</quote> means any item that has been fed with, made with, contains, or was otherwise produced with a covered commodity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C2424B5C8864531A46D510C20C12125"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered source</header><text>The term <quote>covered source</quote> means any precursor to a covered commodity that is used to produce such commodity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB18FAB9F5DAB4D6CB8C785CC9E010B52"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deforestation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>deforestation</quote> means the loss of a forest resulting from the whole or partial conversion of such forest to—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD31D52C0D1E4731AAA16653DFD81281"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agricultural use or another non forest land use; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1CD08FAA697F4675B9B4AD3CAF6CBCEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a tree plantation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D17FFDE93F7447487249BB885BDC947"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Deforestation good</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>deforestation good</quote> means each of the following, only if produced, sourced, made, or otherwise derived from land, on or after December 31, 2020, that is subject to deforestation or forest degredation:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D360BBD46654F2BAA195AA689E3106D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered product.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C5896DBCABE4C45954E62794DCCDCDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A covered commodity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H209B7532BB8945DE8D373E8A9531622A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered source.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00534A87785849E1BD526F0654381890"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Forest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>forest</quote> means land spanning more than 0.5 hectares with trees higher than 5 meters and a canopy of more than 10 percent, or trees able to reach those thresholds in situ, excluding land that is predominately under agricultural or urban land use.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B551ACD4CF44620BD58114ABF482B52"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Forest degradation</header><text>The term <quote>forest degradation</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H90FB007B9AE8477D989119A105E76DA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means human-driven structural changes to forest cover that result in a change in species composition, structure, or function of the forest, which can be indicated by factors such as—</text> 
<clause id="HD1D5678491CB44AAA252E81899DF7F64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>impacts to carbon storage and other ecosystem services;</text></clause> <clause id="HC8D9675B5AA24B828B1541C382151BAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>native species abundance and composition; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE8624A5C139405EB02E0C1B9C17AD88"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>tree age class distribution; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCD26E44B4794CF28A8C1866C918E91E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the conversion of—</text> 
<clause id="H31B700BBAD5B47D090527B4B19446E86"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primary forests, naturally regenerating forests, or old growth forests into plantation forests or into other wooded land; and</text></clause> <clause id="H36A105317CE24700AEEDD3EEC82FE90F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primary forests or old growth forests into temporarily unstocked forests due to clearcutting or other harvesting.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37D848293A014BFA80CC57AFEB78E6DA"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Operator</header><text>The term <quote>operator</quote> means any person who, in the course of commercial activity—</text> <subparagraph id="H55CB633B93E44F009C1A8CDAE3971F44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>places relevant products into the interstate commerce of the United States; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7F94E40D15444ABB911C5F58BDEB699"><enum>(B)</enum><text>imports relevant products into the United States.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DB56736E5F649B5BEF745AAC7B6D10E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Trader</header><text>The term <quote>trader</quote> means any person in the supply chain other than the operator who, in the course of a commercial activity, makes a product available to be imported into the United States.</text> </paragraph> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

