<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25B76-KX0-FL-WFX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 515 ATS: Congratulating the Los Angeles Dodgers for winning the 2025 Major League Baseball World Series.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 515</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Los Angeles Dodgers for winning the 2025 Major League Baseball World Series.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 1, 2025, the Los Angeles Dodgers (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Dodgers</quote>) defeated the American League Champions, the Toronto Blue Jays, by a score of 5 to 4 to win the 2025 Major League Baseball World Series in seven games;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this marks the ninth World Series championship for the Dodgers franchise, cementing a dynasty by winning 3 titles in the last six years, and their eighth title since arriving in Los Angeles in 1958;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the 2025 playoffs, the Dodgers defeated the Cincinnati Reds, the Philadelphia Phillies, and the Milwaukee Brewers, before defeating the Toronto Blue Jays in the World Series;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Dodgers have won the National League West Division in 12 of the last 13 seasons;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Dodgers' opponents in the 2025 World Series, the Toronto Blue Jays, demonstrated true sportsmanship, teamwork, and respect for the game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every member of the 2025 Dodgers roster, one of the most diverse in Major League Baseball with players from 6 countries, played a key part in winning back-to-back World Series for the first time in 25 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dodgers pitcher Yoshinobu Yamamoto was named Most Valuable Player for the 2025 World Series after he went 3–0 with a 1.02 earned run average, threw a complete game in Game 2, and induced the series winning double play in extra innings in Game 7 while pitching in consecutive games with no days rest;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the reigning National League Most Valuable Player Shohei Ohtani played a starring role in the 2025 season for the Dodgers, and was named Most Valuable Player for the 2025 National League Championship Series following his two-way performance of throwing 10 strikeouts and hitting 3 home runs in Game 4;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dodgers catcher Will Smith recorded the most innings as a catcher in World Series history and hit the game and series winning homerun in Game 7;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Miguel Rojas hit a game-tying homerun with 1 out in the top of the ninth inning of Game 7 and made numerous significant defensive contributions throughout the series;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dodgers manager Dave Roberts recorded his third World Series Championship since joining the organization in 2016;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Dodgers overcame a three-run deficit to win 5 to 4 in extra innings in Game 7 of the World Series; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Dodgers are an immense source of pride for the city of Los Angeles and Dodgers Nation; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Dodgers secured a victory for the United States against Canada’s Toronto Blue Jays in America’s national pastime: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0234ef79bf4a4c96b356d696f3043fd9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Los Angeles Dodgers for winning the 2025 Major League Baseball World Series;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida809fe6d4a034416b329b41bd0e8fc9b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the dedication and teamwork of the players and staff who made this historic season possible; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0b4067573994380912f7219c2cb3acd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="idd9a62fc2c2144066939521d021b1c3ea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chairman and controlling owner of the Los Angeles Dodgers, Mark Walter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f1ae555e9894aa5a252f11043dd8833"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the president of the Los Angeles Dodgers, Stan Kasten; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36a3c7f58caa4de685cc10b4ed5387a5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the manager of the 2025 Los Angeles Dodgers, Dave Roberts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

