<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45E866E938B846A58F41B94ED426DD22" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6301 IH: Violence Impact and Vulnerabilities Assessment Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6301</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251125">November 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a comprehensive, culturally informed, and community-engaged study of gender-based violence in Puerto Rico, including its causes, prevalence, systemic drivers, and potential policy solutions, taking into account the island’s cultural, economic, educational, infrastructural, and post-disaster challenges.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDD527A6682AD495A82CD3DBB97E81E16" style="OLC"><section id="H5CC9EA95CB274F9FBF314937C55251B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Violence Impact and Vulnerabilities Assessment Study Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VIVAS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H48658316A06649A995D82779AC9AEFBE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H218C8DCD2EA241908F836CCFA30F522A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gender-based violence, including femicides, domestic abuse, and sexual violence constitutes a serious public health and human rights crisis in Puerto Rico, disproportionately affecting women, the LGBTQIA+ community, as well as other vulnerable and marginalized communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56630BC35EA04B298292ECF991A093C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This type of violence can take many forms, including physical, sexual, emotional, and psychological harm.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC93046F943640A4A0A5227AFE19C044"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Existing data on gender violence in Puerto Rico is fragmented and insufficient, impeding effective policy responses and resource allocation, in part due to the absence of a unified and transparent public data system capable of integrating information across governmental and non-governmental sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C7C5EE49521494AB1681B749136A925"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The role of local organizations and community advocates is critical in addressing the crisis, yet their contributions are not adequately documented or integrated into formal government strategies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE95169B037824E6C81CD3F43C658D92C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a pressing need for a comprehensive, culturally informed, and data-driven assessment of gender violence in Puerto Rico, including an evaluation of governmental policies, educational approaches, and community-based interventions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8D1BB35C6DE489491AF80C956956EA4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such an assessment should include an independent and thorough study on the causes, impact, and systemic responses to gender-based violence in Puerto Rico, with particular attention to cultural context, economic conditions, infrastructure challenges, and the role of local organizations, in order to effectively inform Federal and local policy and programming, as well as sustainable investments in reliable, publicly accessible data systems.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD80DC0A46FBA4CEEB7A4677AF7C6052E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comprehensive study on gender-based violence in Puerto Rico</header><subsection id="H7F456BF37DA140D18D02B6232CF9D162"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comptroller General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a comprehensive study on gender-based violence in Puerto Rico. The study shall assess each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H96F2354013E5453EAEDCE93D63B470F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prevalence, severity, and types of gender violence across Puerto Rico, disaggregated by demographic and geographic factors, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCE1EA0CC598C4942967DFC3294BE5E34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>detailed analysis of methods and patterns of violence (e.g., physical force, weapons, coercive control, economic dependence, digital abuse);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0039C77C80E14A34842DAD6A12023DC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the settings in which violence occurs (e.g., home, workplace, public space); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C39D2B6878D4855955811926FAC0BAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the relationship between victim and perpetrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BAE45F036244B349C5B6FB6664A90E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Historical and recent trends, including changes after—</text><subparagraph id="H635C73C03B814472BE53A98DC6B0D847"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">natural disasters (such as hurricanes Maria and Fiona);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF8CBEE9B4C94843BA85502D3861EC26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>economic crises and austerity measures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44778DEFB8BE402F9B7FC4628883E9E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86835BC36A59414BAD06D63913F5C038"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The manner and extent of the effects on the prevalence, severity, and types of gender violence of cultural norms, structural poverty and economic dependency, gender identity and sexual orientation, educational disparities and unemployment, inadequate transportation, housing, utility infrastructure, climate vulnerability and disaster risk, and other factors the Comptroller General may determine relevant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FBC3DF53D064F4C8D60159878D168E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Institutional response and capacity, including with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HCA262F4F4EBC49E2B4E1EB6487FE7E5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>law enforcement and judicial practices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEF618CD5664494697633C496656D5EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>health and social service systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBCE9C4C99FF4C4AAB62B39EA4573FFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shelter access and emergency housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FE33689725E49BF931845716CBDEC8B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>access to mental health and trauma care; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H629ED1C5EFC5465EBBAC874ABE74B135"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">and substance use disorder treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09C9E97A6B9D416091663F084D41D005"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Barriers to prevention, protection, and justice, such as under-reporting due to stigma and fear, inaccessibility of services in rural areas, police and prosecutorial shortcomings, or lack of culturally competent or trauma-informed services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC298FB425CE14A0CA28592584E60CA69"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The intersection of disaster events and gender violence, including the role of infrastructure collapse, displacement, and stressors in exacerbating violence and levels of access to shelters and services during and after disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FEF8A11369B4FBEB949DB0A43B4D62D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data infrastructure and reporting systems, including:</text><subparagraph id="H183074DE31AD43A1BA7CD5A0C2733141"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing Federal, Commonwealth, and local data systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE671AEE96B7D423098294DBC39FE50A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gaps in reporting, accuracy, and demographic disaggregation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE17418FB29498398E4E36821A8AD1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations to improve data collection and transparency, including evaluation of the creation and implementation of a publicly accessible data system with clear standards for integration of governmental and civil-society-generated information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F8DC99CB3C448E8C717893DF4EA518"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public access to femicide-related data and case updates, judicial outcomes and impunity rates, and Government accountability mechanisms and oversight, including current barriers to timely public disclosure and transparency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C38668287F74C429BE2743DBA8BB4F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional elements</header><paragraph id="H15ECC999AB3F4476B716CECC214A131D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Organizational impact analysis</header><text>The study required by subsection (a) shall also include—</text><subparagraph id="HFA0B17733C2B419DA8B78A9BCFBE8B68"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an examination of the reach of local interventions, the way local organizations and interventions work to fill systemic gaps to fill systemic gaps, and challenges in sustainability, infrastructure, and funding; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26DD950A5A26401182090B46355A2EA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for—</text><clause id="H97E5BB387C7741CBBC90060BDB3A509A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increasing support and additional funding to local Puerto Rican organizations;</text></clause><clause id="H78DD8EF97CB14A4AB3E1349FBC557A1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improving coordination between local, Commonwealth, and Federal entities;</text></clause><clause id="HF215A2B2F5C34941A012F621750B3940"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>protecting grassroots leadership and survivor-centered solutions; and</text></clause><clause id="HD7DCEC7AE27740518F1FE20DD8264905"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>ensuring disaster-resilient service delivery.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F76ABED81F843F2B3E9EF5B802D7E40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Analysis of governmental response to femicide</header><text>Upon concluding the study required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall evaluate—</text><subparagraph id="H40DFFF2DEF984D1AAB6D224675FF522D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Puerto Rican Government’s current policies and institutional strategies to prevent femicide and gender-based violence, with emphasis on analyzing—</text><clause id="HCEE42147AC1549BFA78261BD9AA90CF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>public education campaigns;</text></clause><clause id="H4ED80FAC06B8445E8A7E2D3F81D5665D"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>strategic plans and Executive orders; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5BDB0425C3B64957B9FD7B8E31B059CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>budget allocations and implementation status;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC35FAF7047F4DAF869D0EE2C34A784F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effectiveness of education-focused governmental initiatives compared to—</text><clause id="HBC233667248C45A19768B8EF549EBD2C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>law enforcement reform;</text></clause><clause id="HD6EC9BCAF6A840CFAE1C3CD31A7F9B9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>survivor services and safe housing;</text></clause><clause id="H28CDB4C7DA1F44749DAC19484CE7B5D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>judicial accountability; or</text></clause><clause id="HC6A97769E2C44013B538B59BF8B0C016"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>mental health and trauma support;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4214150EDE74FFF9B147E6981E3B6E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which education-centered approaches address—</text><clause id="H28E39E5739224A8DBC4FC96AB86C955B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>root causes versus symptoms;</text></clause><clause id="H85D23B9B448640FB8FD081E959AC8440"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>urgent protection versus long-term cultural change; or</text></clause><clause id="HDFFC3ADD29B340258AF760CEAF547A8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>urban versus rural disparities; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AD1F88C5C4747078BF38DF770602495"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of input from civil society, survivors, and impacted communities on effectiveness, gaps, delays or displacement of interventions, including cases where civil society data or monitoring efforts identify inconsistencies with official reporting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC526C04421144AC9ADAFD523741888A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of local organizations and community participants</header><text>In carrying out the study required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall—</text><paragraph id="H4AE540AB71F54CF68FC9CD68EE20FD27"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actively engage with Puerto Rican local organizations, such as—</text><subparagraph id="HDDEF064D51B943748C51EEDDDA08D117"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">women’s organizations and shelters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E288318B9E9430396B8AA58F102FBC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>LGBTQ+ advocacy groups;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC79B680FA074F37A157D7FBACCB839A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>survivor-led initiatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC738AE42D3A8486C8176A9BF70E06377"><enum>(D)</enum><text>youth and disability rights advocates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ED1BAC11C65485C85172FA9B6CB9A39"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">academic institutions and researchers including entities that maintain independent monitoring or data-collection initiatives in the absence of formalized governmental systems; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H084A152110B4433AAECC1F0A4E96A285"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include as a part of such engagement—</text><subparagraph id="H681974489BA9440883069526A93BFFF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community roundtables and listening sessions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB5273957FDF4F2682945611EF8D7190"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inclusion in research design and data interpretation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H897582CACCDD4AAB85873C48FFDDB248"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opportunities for written and oral testimony.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD557D0CA5F5C4E54877117C582B93050"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="HC56E366E87884325AFAB71E62E926869"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General shall publish an interim report not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, consisting of such findings as the Comptroller General may have reached, as of the date of the publication of the interim report, with respect to the study required by section 3(a) and the additional elements required by section 3(b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B78D0A5F53546CDB73864002C41A033"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress and concurrently publish in a publicly available form in both English and Spanish a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H01FB80E7E6CC4D888B8F79D25DDE35F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all findings from the study required by section 3(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD66E6989CC014FF793CF42354AC3A6CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all additional elements required by section 3(b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABABCB8A83D4413E88BF9EA9017179F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregation of the data and findings by municipality in Puerto Rico;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFB583380E6943358233D4336647B5F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the evidence-based recommendations of the Comptroller General with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H59F6A0ACFFC6474CA9E6705A368C70AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhancing or supplementing existing strategies to better balance prevention through education with structural reform and direct protections;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBECF702085324CFDA06B78F38275AEB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrating education within a comprehensive, multi-sectoral strategy that incorporates law enforcement, health systems, social services, and emergency management; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4596F24184134496B11C1E6084A7F15F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>building transparent, measurable, and participatory oversight systems, including through periodic reporting, public dashboards, independent evaluations, and survivor feedback mechanisms, with particular attention to ensuring sustained funding, public accessibility, and long-term maintenance of any recommended data systems;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A0F0202D8A84039B39EC4E8AD700469"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of mechanisms for ongoing Federal and local collaboration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H944A29685DB14833BD0047B736A089DE" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other policy, funding, data infrastructure or other recommendations the Comptroller General determines appropriate, whether addressed to Federal entities or to agencies of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, as a result of concluding the study and analysis required by section 3, including options for establishing or enhancing unified public data system on gender-based violence in Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

