<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00E715D0C1AB4299B9A01F128C25BA0A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9190 IH: Right to Try for Individualized Treatments Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9190</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize the use of investigational individualized medical treatments by patients diagnosed with a life-threatening disease or condition or severely debilitating illness, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC73CBDCF16FE4DD5835777DCDF249E8E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0A9EF54F343D4D1C8D017A00C5D8F815"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Right to Try for Individualized Treatments Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9E157F45D1074DB88FE29910D1091178"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of investigational individualized medical treatments by patients diagnosed with a life-threatening disease or condition or severely debilitating illness</header> <subsection id="H5C2CB2C8381147F19DCD328D8E499020"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 561B(a) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 360bbb–0a(a)) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDE15856E133E4B728B0217D2C63806A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D4D2D98DC344F8F9019A753888D9BF2"> <paragraph id="H9F3B1996848E409BB0A1F42090321103"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>eligible patient</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE304217A2D542C0B9FD0A80C17D05AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a patient requesting an eligible investigational drug, a patient who has—</text> <clause id="HBE9A9E44BF1B42878B2C7F3CBF879370"><enum>(i)</enum><text>been diagnosed with a life-threatening disease or condition (as defined in section 312.81 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations));</text></clause> 
<clause id="HADDD30299DF7488E92FB7FF15CFF412C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exhausted approved treatment options and is unable to participate in a clinical trial involving the eligible investigational drug, as certified by a physician, who—</text> <subclause id="H9EDB01C585FC4F72ABF6378C5A3E5FF1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is in good standing with the physician’s licensing organization or board; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H95F73622B3E04010926711B55314E6A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will not be compensated directly by the manufacturer of such drug for so certifying; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HDF8B18D767684200ABB838859DE06F6D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provided to the treating physician written informed consent regarding the eligible investigational drug, or, as applicable, on whose behalf a legally authorized representative of the patient has provided such consent; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1CAF98D9FA0413CBF6FB1830D53AC73"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a patient requesting an investigational individualized medical treatment, a patient who has—</text> <clause id="H16EE3690007C458B9E23313C7BA19703"><enum>(i)</enum><text>been diagnosed with a life-threatening disease or condition or severely debilitating illness (as such terms are defined in section 312.81 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations));</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0ADF0C9744814462BFF3B68B3032197E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>considered approved treatment options, as certified by a physician, who—</text> <subclause id="H5B81E528232E4628B5F903081F806D02"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is in good standing with the physician’s licensing organization or board;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0A1E4DC903534C85B38BA01D392DABDA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will not be compensated directly by the manufacturer of such treatment for so certifying; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2311F3F19FA64BAD943ADD2F22033C9D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>attests to the patient’s life-threatening disease or condition or severely debilitating illness; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H37249B9F4197480C920709D217DF3232"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provided to the treating physician—</text> <subclause id="H0C33A0D0E756415196398E498C4A1433"><enum>(I)</enum><text>written informed consent regarding the eligible investigational drug or, as applicable, on whose behalf a legally authorized representative of the patient has provided such consent; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9BE6D2E24B184A7F9FAE4793C7AFB3E4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as applicable, additional informed consent, regarding the investigational individualized medical treatment, or, as applicable, on whose behalf a legally authorized representative of the patient has provided such consent;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H625D4E95997E4AF18B22A81C960CF128"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(D), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H308596AE4F8D412E9F91112EA14222F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A8607C37B054CB5939D6BCCDC3F38FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H552C9905D66C47F3BF3922940AF255A0"> 
<paragraph id="HFFAE3350F7D44EBB9530B40525E50160"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible health care facility</term> means a health care facility that is operating under the Federal assurance for protection of human subjects pursuant to section 491(a) of the Public Health Service Act; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4F851087F8140DDAD70F8188D918653"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>investigational individualized medical treatment</term> means a drug or biological product for the patient based on an analysis of the patient’s unique genomic profile, including their genomic sequence, human chromosomes, deoxyribonucleic acid, genes, gene products (such as enzymes and other types of proteins), or metabolites; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EDA3BFDD88048D9BF3AE088DE6FBE34"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>additional informed consent</term> means consent attested to in writing by the patient’s physician and a witness for an investigational individualized medical treatment that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HB291BC92DFCF4EF6802EDD559AAE1283"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explanation of the currently approved treatments for the patient’s disease or condition;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H102501CDB8514F728D7C843C99F15DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the patient’s attestation that the patient concurs with the assessment of their physician that all currently approved and conventionally recognized treatments are unlikely to prolong or improve their life;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36B165489F7D432A9138769F7ED7402A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clear identification of the specific proposed investigational individualized medical treatment the patient’s physician recommends; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D605C30498741B0846E37969D594FDB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description, based on the physician’s knowledge of the proposed treatment and the patient’s disease, of the potential outcomes of the treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB25870C3B3BE48BAB70261064CBAB466"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility for investigational individualized medical treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 561B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-0a">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–0a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H962BE6E04A6B4B71B9DE20DAE11F937B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) through (d) as subsections (c) through (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADCCA08F5CCB4B4A8071049565A1AB80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD054D28532234DF1A7C4F80BAA0A13DB"> 
<subsection id="H673C86D20CED4864AF409C1AFFB59028"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility for investigational individualized medical treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer of an investigational individualized medical treatment that is in compliance with all applicable Federal assurance laws and regulations and is operating within an eligible health care facility may make available such investigational individualized medical treatment, and an eligible patient may request access to such treatment from the eligible health care facility or manufacturer of such treatment, consistent with the requirements of this section. A manufacturer of an investigational individualized medical treatment is not required to make available such treatment to any patient.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCD353AA7C21C41F3A9F52EBE3BD5946F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 561B(c) of such Act (21 U.S.C. 360bbb–0a(c)), as redesignated by subsection (b)(1) of this section, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE1BE0AB99E50493193A20A869625AF9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and investigational individualized medical treatments</quote> after <quote>Eligible investigational drugs</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H257DD0947A0B45288442C19A4F728F43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or investigational individualized medical treatment</quote> after <quote>such eligible investigational drug</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F809996B81F43E5983EAC144696131F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or investigational individualized medical treatment</quote> after <quote>an eligible investigational drug</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H871D4EEADC6A4A339E3CA2A6BD40C1FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or investigational individualized medical treatments</quote> after <quote>investigational drugs</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE1CA1593EEE45F4A30E55FD9BAB41B6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 561B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-0a">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–0a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2E68B247EEF340CFB147D241CF67341F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and investigational individualized medical treatments</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">drugs</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09F450AD985F4E9BB6940A35D6D8CBD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(2), as redesignated by subsection (b)(1) of this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A9263C77C6C4AB0AD6D8D1DDBE7377F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subsection (c)(1)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d)(1)(A)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2DC630E33F8E445E87F47E32C35D5A46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>subsection (c)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d)(1)(B)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

