<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H66B36C30FB7C40B7A5BA8178FFCEFA8C" resolution-type="house-resolution"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1247 IH: Major Richard Star Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1247</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2102) to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for concurrent receipt of veterans’ disability compensation and retired pay for disability retirees with combat-related disabilities, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0F78A76D5C5F4C078E9A48909DB3BE9F"> 
<section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H66B36C30FB7C40B7A5BA8178FFCEFA8D"><text> That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 2102) to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for concurrent receipt of veterans’ disability compensation and retired pay for disability retirees with combat-related disabilities, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute specified in section 4 of this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided among and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Armed Services or their respective designees and the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H66B36C30FB7C40B7A5BA8178FFCEFA8E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><text>Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 2102.</text></section> 
<section id="H66B36C30FB7C40B7A5BA8178FFCEFA8F"><enum>3.</enum><text>The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.R. 2102 no later than three calendar days after passage.</text></section> <section id="H66B36C30FB7C40B7A5BA8178FFCEFA8G"><enum>4.</enum><text>The amendment in the nature of a substitute referred to in the first section of this resolution is as follows:</text></section> 
<section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H66B36C30FB7C40B7A5BA8178FFCEFA8H"><text>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text></section> </resolution-body> <resolution-body display-resolving-clause="no-display-resolving-clause" style="OLC"> <section id="H4CC465039608404C90330D2148650ED2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Major Richard Star Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H03C0725EE6FB4B7BB9C77FE635334BA9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansions of eligibility to certain military retirees for concurrent receipt of veterans’ disability compensation and retired pay or combat-related special compensation</header> 
<subsection id="HC5AB069032E44A22AB73712DF89E9905"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of chapter 61 disability retirees with fewer than 20 years of service who are eligible for combat-Related special compensation</header><text>Section 1413a(b)(3) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBD545B2D9D9742BAB306915B7B484732"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>In</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraph (B), in</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADEC2FE010D74C35970ABCC0F217A96E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>In the case of</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>The retired pay of an eligible combat-related disabled uniformed services retiree, who is retired under chapter 61 of this title with fewer than 20 years of creditable service, is not subject to reduction under sections 5304 and 5305 of title 38.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA5F790C5E20A4AFBA98A6BB59482259A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HD5BD9A71B5A64769855A0668230647BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section heading</header><text>The heading of section 1414 of such title is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6FAF260B9F17498DB52C0154EEC1AA81" style="USC"> 
<section id="H921153D02CEB439996A31ED180615F5A"><enum>1414.</enum><header>Members eligible for retired pay who are also eligible for veterans’ disability compensation: concurrent receipt</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2717294C535444F280D76BDD92F823C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The item relating to such section 1414 in the table of sections at the beginning of chapter 71 of such title is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HDCA03699B8F54373A91E9340AE83127D" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">1414. Members eligible for retired pay who are also eligible for veterans’ disability compensation: concurrent receipt.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8677B4F57FAB40D880767C4E35D20BE1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments reflecting end of concurrent receipt phase-in period</header><text>Such section 1414 is further amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDDF996B22436455DA9E157B693DFC80A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <clause id="HC706FEC9A4E343E49D0958BF1744C6A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCEE4701F39804314AF2DB7E3B1F6F997"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (A) and (B);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8A5533FCD7648ACA5592DF86A40D1D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c) and redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D2F1E6FFB40431DA0E3FE07507C0BD2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as redesignated, by striking paragraphs (3) and (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2BD6C308805147E086185AF0D07FBA9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the first day of the first month beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to payments for months beginning on or after such date.</text></subsection></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


