<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9840DB8DA2D436CAECE6752D5A004BF" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1127 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of March 22, 2026, through March 28, 2026, as “National Cleaning Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of March 22, 2026, through March 28, 2026, as <quote>National Cleaning Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas cleaning and disinfection are an investment in protecting human health and safety;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention stresses the importance of routine cleaning and disinfecting to protect public health;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas ISSA, the Association for Cleaning and Facility Solutions, found that routine cleaning and disinfection reduce the number of surfaces contaminated by viruses by 62 percent and thereby significantly reduce the rate of transmission of infectious diseases;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas manufacturers and distributors produce and deliver critical cleaning and hygiene products; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas essential frontline cleaning professionals work tirelessly to keep our schools, hospitals, workplaces, and other spaces healthy and safe for us all: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8FF2E737FC9B4FD793AED33EC510EFD0"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HEE55C5855141425D998CC481107CE0B0"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAB0F7CC1EEEB49F0BD2CC85B7DA1D449"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the commitment and essential services provided by the cleaning industry in maintaining clean and sanitary conditions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8225AD7691647BB82456604809D0360"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Cleaning Week</quote> to continue to promote safe and clean environments at work, in schools, and at home.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

