<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25I95-SXJ-KL-TSD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S3202 IS: Advanced Artificial Intelligence Security Readiness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3202</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Director of the National Security Agency to develop guidance to secure artificial intelligence related technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5CD26EE6E643449AA4D2B2C49A2F982C"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB36868DDBAD6438182E351A5E0E49E15"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advanced Artificial Intelligence Security Readiness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H7B3B889060014D1BBD4733D93170772A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence security guidance</header><subsection id="HE58B615224F74A0E9A2A3CFCE84C1022" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Director of the National Security Agency, acting through the Artificial Intelligence Security Center (or successor office), shall develop and disseminate security guidance that identifies potential vulnerabilities in covered artificial intelligence technologies and artificial intelligence supply chains, with a focus on cybersecurity risks and security challenges that are unique to protecting artificial intelligence systems, associated computing environments, or the wider artificial intelligence supply chain from theft or sabotage by foreign threat actors.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3B831DCF4B1E4D58BB40B78EBFD5D1FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidance developed and disseminated under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H744C8CD549014D7FBACC34C973467FD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of potential vulnerabilities and cybersecurity challenges that are unique to protecting covered artificial intelligence technologies and the artificial intelligence supply chain, such as threat vectors that are less common or severe in conventional information technology systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3649b53532245a680f7847b0c8e3256"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identification of elements of the artificial intelligence supply chain that, if accessed by threat actors, would meaningfully contribute to the actor’s ability to develop covered artificial intelligence technologies or compromise the confidentiality, integrity, or availability of artificial intelligence systems or associated artificial intelligence supply chains.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0eeb99d30f649edafc33c0edaf4d157"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Strategies to identify, protect, detect, respond to, and recover from cyber threats posed by threat actors targeting covered artificial intelligence technologies, including—</text><subparagraph id="id78ef0b771cf441149f92b4a770b2b7db"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procedures to protect model weights or other competitively sensitive model artifacts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99d20aaa840a45219a77527bf2b8cc3f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ways to mitigate insider threats, including personnel vetting processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31ea489992314678baa65b365dd1d16e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>network access control procedures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7493730eff94b22b8c57b4f13b6b748"><enum>(D)</enum><text>counterintelligence and anti-espionage measures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id430a41e6c9f84153a9041292a1641a28"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other measures that can be used to reduce threats of technology theft or sabotage by foreign threat actors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id067cc931d1ed493688d68c8ba9d2280e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The guidance developed and disseminated under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="iddae41130752e4436b01e59fc55dbe552"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detailed best practices, principles, and guidelines in unclassified form, which may include a classified annex; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd60a022b97342cc8b4b834b2deee06d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>classified materials for conducting security briefings for service providers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H445E66CF25FA4B26BC1502C06AC28C61" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Engagement</header><text>In developing the guidance required by subsection (a), the Director shall—</text><paragraph id="H6C4DCF325B8242479E5AC993615D62B3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage with prominent artificial intelligence developers and researchers, as determined by the Director, to assess and anticipate the capabilities of highly advanced artificial intelligence systems relevant to national security, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H2BBAAF53A5B145E9A167511C06B1D631" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting a comprehensive review of publicly available industry documents pertaining to the security of artificial intelligence systems with respect to preparedness frameworks, scaling policies, risk management frameworks, and other matters;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H850385E0A5A042E885DDC1F81AACC7EC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting interviews with subject matter experts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EBC0D52455542C8BE3AD8EB120B2099" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hosting roundtable discussions and expert panels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06B1C805023D4390BFABE789B2ED3741" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>visiting facilities used to develop artificial intelligence;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB723095DA22A4E068009BA83998F70E5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leverage existing expertise and research, collaborate with relevant National Laboratories, university affiliated research centers, and any federally funded research and development center that has conducted research on strategies to secure artificial intelligence models from nation-state actors and other highly resourced actors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb389c032cb6b4a86ab8bcca9e457f476" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult, as appropriate, with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government as the Director determines relevant, including the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, the Center for Artificial Intelligence Standards and Innovation of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FDD53F27AFE409F8B38398482E52E34"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H26E0586030AE49D8967501CAE4ADF86C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on the guidance required by subsection (a), including a summary of progress on the development of the guidance, an outline of remaining sections, and any relevant insights about artificial intelligence security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5619A7B6A5CC46F7A9FEEFDA69D97CC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 365 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on the guidance required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE015788A06D044F2A20BDF27DD2920E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H37ED09D49FF7459C9F905976275BA825"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include—</text><clause id="HE9FBEDB4727642CF917B440EBC9E99B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an unclassified version suitable for dissemination to relevant individuals, including in the private sector; and</text></clause><clause id="H6D00372D896846B798A3FF19A6A6EBCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a publicly available version; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D9E6378B5804DBCAC5F1262E067CA4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52ADC870C90144788914D126ADED773A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA3D4924C0F9D47B1993B8F5BAD1F0E6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; 10 U.S.C. note prec. 4061).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c58ad588ea5417292f22c9810c90a48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence supply chain</term> means artificial intelligence models computing environments for performing model training or inference tasks, training or test data, frameworks, or other components or model artifacts necessary for the training, management, or maintenance of any artificial intelligence system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63050519E0AD45348F01EFA47DE682D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>congressional intelligence committees</term> means the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H075ABF1DDE7A4C90829D85F67E542778"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered artificial intelligence technologies</term> means advanced artificial intelligence (whether developed by the private sector, the United States Government, or a public-private partnership) with critical capabilities that the Director determines would pose a grave national security threat if acquired or stolen by threat actors, such as artificial intelligence systems that match or exceed human expert performance in chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear matters, cyber offense, model autonomy, persuasion, research and development, and self-improvement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C9E7EE5AD2E4213961F53BA291AD530"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>technology theft</term> means any unauthorized acquisition, replication, or appropriation of covered artificial intelligence technologies or components of such technologies, including models, model weights, architectures, or core algorithmic insights, through any means, such as cyber attacks, insider threats, and side-channel attacks, or exploitation of public interfaces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F6EF632B9294CE28AAC7AEDCF90ACA2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>threat actors</term> means nation-state actors and other highly resourced actors capable of technology theft or sabotage.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

