<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25C69-1MG-WW-9KM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 558 IS: Recognizing that climate change-driven extreme weather events are increasing at the same time that the government is dismantling weather monitoring and alert systems.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing that climate change-driven extreme weather events are increasing at the same time that the government is dismantling weather monitoring and alert systems.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas climate change drives and exacerbates extreme weather and disaster events;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas peer-reviewed science has established that climate change intensifies hurricanes and drives increased coastal flooding, erosion, and damage;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas climate change drives dangerously heavy rainfall, which can cause life-threatening flooding both in coastal and inland communities; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Weather Service has lost more than 550 employees since President Trump took office in January 2025, due primarily to layoffs and buyouts, and the administration has sought $2,200,000,000 in budget cuts to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, which houses the National Weather Service: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id77dcad74c7ea41ad8d41775adf84dcd4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acknowledges that climate change drives and exacerbates life-threatening extreme weather events;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcd27e6ee5bb47c981cf565b6a7a4af9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>mourns the loss of innocent lives to these events; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee514768284745e2af171166714cde2e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges the need to fund and maintain weather monitoring and alert systems, and ensure adequate staffing at the National Weather Service.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

