<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEA939BB3DAA04BC4B7C135009F4BEFEE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8259 IH: Federal Water Projects Consultation Improvement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure meaningful consultation and cooperation between Federal and local entities in the operation of Federal water projects in the Reclamation States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF7E75115EFFA4A2D8CBF92F6A4069D2A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9BA0C285F7014D339C4E201CB2AFAAB4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Water Projects Consultation Improvement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6B8BA7052EC546328A82902123D3A43E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consultation with affected contractors of Federal water projects</header> <subsection id="H356F0AFA977C4E2383C25ABB6AC61B3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Resolution of water resource issues</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In furtherance of the policy established by section 2(c)(2) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531(c)(2)</external-xref>), in a consultation or reconsultation under section 7 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>) with respect to the operation of a Federal water project, the head of each action agency, the Secretary, or the head of an action agency and the Secretary working in coordination, as applicable, shall ensure that each covered entity that so requests shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9E7CCADC229B41F0BC5DBE145FB46738"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have routine and continuing opportunities—</text> <subparagraph id="HAF46145F90C444F0A4566855A7825E2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to discuss and submit information to the action agency for consideration during the development of any biological assessment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H774251AEBD0B405BBEC2622F8DB58437"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage with the action agency with respect to the preparation of the biological assessment;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H873A37329363465D8850061C3AB88B8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the head of an action agency suggests or considers an agency action that would not result in full delivery of water pursuant to a contract for contractors of the Federal water project, be informed and engaged as to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H237E7BD676C94133AA2B309EB638758D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legal authority invoked by the action agency to support that such agency action would be within the scope of the authority of the action agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26751C5212B44C9E9106942135EC40E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how each component of the agency action would contribute to avoiding jeopardizing the continued existence of any threatened species or endangered species and destroying or adversely modifying critical habitat and the scientific data or information that supports each component of the agency action under consideration; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C33FDDCBEE6438F86BFB69F18AC82A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">why any other agency actions that would have fewer adverse water supply and economic impacts are inadequate to avoid jeopardizing the continued existence of any threatened species or endangered species and destroying or adversely modifying critical habitat;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H494C91652A5840A1B3B905B229F10A84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be informed by the head of the action agency of the schedule for preparation of a biological assessment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H920D68A9958C4FD4AF608782AD7FE6EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be informed by the Secretary of the schedule for preparation of the biological opinion at such time as the biological assessment is submitted to the Services by the action agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H797AC06388C041F480791AD3094F29D1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive a copy of draft biological opinion and have the opportunity to review each such draft biological opinion and provide comment to the Secretary through engagement with the action agency, which comments shall be afforded due consideration during the consultation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAED014828B94A49BB9CFF55D6C23865" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have the opportunity to confer and engage with the head of the action agency and applicant, if any, with respect to reasonable and prudent alternatives prior to the identification of any reasonable and prudent alternative for consideration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B31FCADD1EF4F7089CD7C66307AB035"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary suggests a reasonable and prudent alternative, be informed and engaged with respect to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD2B6052EA174451D98446799FB78C952"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how each component of the reasonable and prudent alternative will contribute to avoiding jeopardizing the continued existence of any threatened species or endangered species and destroying or adversely modifying critical habitat and the scientific data or information that supports each component of the reasonable and prudent alternative; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA56261CA99BF4A7F95F66834FD9CA044"><enum>(B)</enum><text>why any other proposed reasonable and prudent alternatives that would have fewer adverse water supply and economic impacts are inadequate to avoid jeopardizing the continued existence of any threatened species or endangered species and destroying or adversely modifying critical habitat; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9928ABB9C1F4AEFA6FA14D721491A97"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary proposes a reasonable and prudent measure to avoid or minimize take of threatened species or endangered species, or terms and conditions to implement such reasonable and prudent measure, be informed and engaged with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="H748D4566523445A09F844AB3E76929C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the reasonable and prudent measure or terms and conditions relate to avoiding or minimizing such take; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCEF98D3B79194F3198A88E384B58290D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the reasonable and prudent measure or terms and conditions conform to any applicable limitations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB130930ED7AB4003BFB43FB505C763F5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFE774095CBB64875A7820B7009988DAA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Action agency</header><text>The term <term>action agency</term> means the Federal agency responsible for authorizing, funding, or carrying out an action subject to consultation under section 7 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H780BB21E1516439A80006CDED456F4DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency action</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7(a)(2) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BB6A7E26531485EA14CA093DB44F1A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Biological assessment</header><text>The term <term>biological assessment</term> means a biological assessment conducted under section 7(c) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8C98597DD3D4F1D97A1E10EDAC53E24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Biological opinion</header><text>The term <term>biological opinion</term> means a written statement provided by the Secretary under section 7(b)(3) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(b)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7361CAFE5A194913BBC824372D3BC285"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Contractor</header><text>The term <term>contractor</term> means any public agency, quasi-municipal corporation, irrigation district, water users association, or similar entity that has entered into a water service, repayment, or other contract with the United States related to storage, diversion, or delivery of water from a Federal water project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C7AAEEA7BB84C67A9331565BEECD0F1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means a public or quasi-municipal agency or water users association that has a contract with the Bureau of Reclamation for municipal or agricultural water supply from a Federal water project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72EE1AB9CC164E97A2A249E3779792E8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Critical habitat</header><text>The term <term>critical habitat</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H156DEADCFEEC4A23BF67AC396795CC18"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Endangered species</header><text>The term <term>endangered species</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFA36E76C1A0449FA3122CA8CF296302"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Engage</header><text>The term <term>engage</term> means to conduct direct written and in-person communications recognizing the unique interest of the contractor and promoting maximum candor and cooperation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE534A4DFF9F847E384CF922BC140D422"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Federal water project</header><text>The term <term>Federal water project</term> means any project or facility—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H100861B9D7CB468BBF140977263CCE52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a Reclamation State described in subparagraphs (B) through (R) of section 128(a)(7) of the EXPLORE Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/8426">16 U.S.C. 8426(a)(7)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD309B38E82A344439674C3F3A15FFC85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operated or managed by a Federal agency for the authorized purpose of municipal or agricultural water supply.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B1833D6C38F48B09B716DB059D72EF7"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Reasonable and prudent alternative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reasonable and prudent alternative</term> means a reasonable and prudent alternative suggested by the Secretary under section 7(b)(3) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(b)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BF2C3472A0E4DFAAAE7AD98D435A51C"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Reasonable and prudent measure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reasonable and prudent measure</term> means a reasonable and prudent measure specified by the Secretary under section 7(b)(4) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(b)(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2C7D142C6A94AF58CC9D0BB658DB07D"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A2E68CCAC064F28AD27F0FA48189BE8"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Take</header><text>The term <term>take</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD347E5AE05C4D1D9304513BFE5F9CD2"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Threatened species</header><text>The term <term>threatened species</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

