<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT26336-CH0-KF-69C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4437 IS: Puppy Protection Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4437</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Animal Welfare Act to establish additional requirements for dealers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puppy Protection Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf3ee3999ce7e4d59aeab8457f5c29723"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional requirements for dealers</header><subsection id="id475842e4be864a1ab1a3dbfa605ae052"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Humane treatment of dogs by dealers</header><text>Section 13(a) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2143">7 U.S.C. 2143(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id617d395e7ae04e5b94d48ebdcd0811ea"><paragraph id="id3946df1718194e6298045fcec7235069" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In addition to the requirements under paragraph (2), the standards described in paragraph (1) shall, with respect to dealers, include requirements—</text><subparagraph id="ide5a0c7eba19b4894bdbfe60827d246ff"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the dealer provide adequate housing for dogs that includes—</text><clause id="idfcdc21a908d048a5b19ba71fe04bdcd3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>completely solid flooring;</text></clause><clause id="idecd21bbfc5a84299983be083bd08cc62"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>indoor space sufficient to allow the tallest dog in an enclosure to stand on his or her hind legs without touching the roof of the enclosure;</text></clause><clause id="idb7e6a9d542d3478fb1a754bcb6345e0d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to dogs over 8 weeks in age, primary enclosures that, with the length of the dog measured from the tip of the nose to the base of the tail, provide at least—</text><subclause id="idf21098622c97458ba9db2606994da318"><enum>(I)</enum><text>12 square feet of indoor floor space per each dog measuring not more than 25 inches long;</text></subclause><subclause id="id009864fce75640dfae582ae3f8fca8de"><enum>(II)</enum><text>20 square feet of indoor floor space per each dog measuring more than 25 but less than 35 inches long; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id66337b3bc80d4ff0a73ffa36f3c039d3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>30 square feet of indoor floor space per each dog measuring not less than 35 inches long;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id5f70d478838f4f849f2dc2d7dc159278"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>enclosures that are not stacked or otherwise placed on top of or below another enclosure; and</text></clause><clause id="idb68afe83f780471a842c518b227276c7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>temperature control that—</text><subclause id="id6a0b2ff2855b465492f2cee615423141"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is appropriate for the age, breed, and condition of each dog in the enclosure; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idd8cdbab2e96545d1a5342ae515678323"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is between 45 and 85 degrees Fahrenheit, when dogs are present in the enclosure;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1128391b71242c0ac71715697ec746f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that appropriate and nutritious food be provided to each dog at least twice per day, in an amount sufficient to maintain the good health and physical condition of each dog;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5c867da6195458eac7313b0e4156699"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that each dog has continuous access to potable water that is not frozen and is free of feces, algae, and other contaminants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58d6b79bdbde4b51b05170cfeff275e2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that each dog has adequate exercise, including, for each dog over the age of 12 weeks—</text><clause id="idC4B57B49B04F4F708E0E45B5CA55EFD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>except as provided in clause (ii), unrestricted access from the primary enclosure of the dog during daylight hours to an outdoor exercise area that—</text><subclause id="id704393aa8ab1411390f21adf561bd514"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is at ground-level;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf819b6ddd3b145fd81ecd638a7b70e2c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is a solid surface;</text></subclause><subclause id="id39faa78c2d924b7f8ceda26838e959a3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is enclosed by a fence or other structure;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide3c9ac06143d41229d3052b29a0a4f6e"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>is properly controlled for the safety of the dog; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id0f31d68686f44ee0a7fd534fc8f0b1e8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>allows the dog to extend to full stride, play, and engage in other types of mentally stimulating and social behaviors; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="iddd9075af5ce9427ebb805696071fb6b4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the dealer obtains a certification from the attending veterinarian stating that a dog should not have unrestricted access to an outdoor exercise area for a specific medical reason, an alternative exercise plan prescribed by the veterinarian for the dog that meets the applicable requirements under section 3.8 of title 9, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba26b4f6aaba4866a0fc9041ecb75f1c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>that each dog has meaningful socialization with humans and compatible dogs for at least 30 minutes each day that—</text><clause id="idb59beae8d5b34d6e87b87a6cbc693048"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes positive interaction with a human such as petting, stroking, grooming, feeding, playing with, exercising, or other touching of the dog that is beneficial to the well-being of the dog; and</text></clause><clause id="id7a074c606c444fa7a3f2831d2d7244c9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include time spent in veterinary care;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d9e916e945a48f4870d807ffdf8a52a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>that each dog receives adequate veterinary care, including—</text><clause id="idf742e453e6e748da854ea66dccadada7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prompt treatment of any disease, illness, or injury by a licensed veterinarian;</text></clause><clause id="id43ac00c716af4305865811e9b7ac8ac8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a thorough, hands-on examination by a licensed veterinarian at least once each year, which shall include a dental exam;</text></clause><clause id="ide27d36cf06e34316bcd64080eaa02463"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>core vaccinations recommended by the latest version of the American Animal Hospital Association Canine Vaccination Guidelines; and</text></clause><clause id="id309d14a14a9446a28b56fa32a06b1c30"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>medications to prevent intestinal parasites, heartworm disease, fleas, and ticks that are approved by a licensed veterinarian for canine use;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40899dddb78e45438ab8af2f83a3eb30"><enum>(G)</enum><text>with respect to safe breeding practices for dogs, including—</text><clause id="id04f3f6219ec8409ab3194f58cab50411"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a screening program for known prevalent inheritable diseases that may be disabling or likely to significantly affect the lifespan or quality of life of the mother or the offspring;</text></clause><clause id="id66fe54c576b64c80838ce9d57e57a272"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prohibiting breeding, unless each dog bred—</text><subclause id="id6D6CAA38CB98486793DED596419C0FB7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has been screened by a licensed veterinarian prior to each attempt to breed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idF20ECBB417814667AF7824DA37A4C580"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is found in the screening under subclause (I) to be free from health conditions that may be disabling to, or likely to significantly affect the lifespan or quality of life of, the mother or the offspring;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id689fcf5cb9f6472eafd53377cbdb230d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prohibiting the breeding of a female dog to produce—</text><subclause id="ide6e570881fd44ba0902bc08497017d7e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>more than 2 litters in any 18-month period; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id5f909631c62b409da0c13e1df2515444"><enum>(II)</enum><text>more than 6 litters during the lifetime of the dog;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id24f8cc4204ac4b39a20db9f4d2c16131"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that a female dog of any small breed (having a maximum weight range at maturity that is less than 40 pounds) not be bred—</text><subclause id="id9058101c788042d29064ac3291620bfb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>before reaching the age of 18 months; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id97ad6aff82314f5792d558b1188264dd"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after reaching the age of 9 years;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idc8b15bd1e9b14c19b390821fcc332bcf"><enum>(v)</enum><text>that a female dog of any large breed (having an expected weight range at maturity that includes 40 or more pounds) not be bred—</text><subclause id="id9ece3f2214b64215ae498c88e44de5ab"><enum>(I)</enum><text>before reaching the age of 2 years; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id42cd83f6bebb41a5873a146b0ba1324d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after reaching the age of 7 years; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id60c19720336b4082a6332cf220167620"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>that any canine caesarian section be performed by a licensed veterinarian;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0b57cc59ada84ce8898d98dea3bd2e03"><enum>(H)</enum><text>that dogs be housed with other dogs, unless health or behavioral issues make group housing unsafe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4418f543ee544565a71be9231a602aa0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to make all reasonable efforts to find humane placement for retired breeding dogs—</text><clause id="id44456FE356B24EF6A77C8578488159D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such as with an adoptive family, rescue organization, or other appropriate owner for that dog; and</text></clause><clause id="id14F5A15F46DD42B7B1801B7C591C81BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not including selling at auction or otherwise placing a retired breeding dog with another breeder for breeding purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id02f2fa019427407a946dbc740487db6b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 13(a)(2)(B) of the Animal Welfare Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2143">7 U.S.C. 2143(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>subject to paragraph (9),</quote> before <quote>for exercise of dogs</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7aa71cd5512e495da377721c1086a789"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue final regulations establishing the standards for the care of dogs by dealers, as required by this section and the amendments made by this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

