<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4036E50825DD422BAD15B038D832D1D2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7646 IH: Payback Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7646</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260223">February 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the United States Department of the Treasury to refund American consumers for increased costs resulting from tariffs imposed without congressional authorization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBE4A94745ED84FCC907AB5D3A03A9C1C" style="OLC">
<section id="H2B5E09D3359A4178B08C5AC9B0FE491F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Payback Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD489BAD2E9DD446A975E9C610B5FB76B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA132FD1324C848EDABEECF5B314726CD">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>In Learning Resources, Inc. v. Trump, the Supreme Court of the United States clarified that although the International Emergency Economic Powers Act authorizes the President to exercise certain economic authorities during a bona fide national emergency, that statute does not confer authority to impose tariffs absent clear and express congressional authorization; in so holding, the Court reaffirmed that article I, section 8 of the Constitution vests exclusively in Congress the power to lay and collect duties and tariffs, and that such legislative authority may not be exercised by the executive branch solely by virtue of an emergency declaration.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7EBBA65B0F4471EBB26283574059698">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The Constitution establishes a deliberate separation of powers, vesting in Congress alone the authority to lay and collect taxes, duties, imposts, and excises under article I, section 8; allowing the executive branch to unilaterally impose tariffs absent explicit congressional authorization would improperly transfer core legislative power to the Presidency, erode democratic accountability, and undermine the foundational principle that laws affecting the economic lives of Americans must originate with the people’s elected representatives.</text>
            </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H47FC399C8BA84C5BA23969482221AEF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These unlawful tariffs resulted in billions of dollars in collections by the Federal Government and materially increased the prices of goods for American consumers, functioning as a regressive tax that disproportionately burdened working families, seniors, and small businesses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5240B3C0EBCB4323AF12CE521A4D6F2E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>American consumers bore the direct financial consequences of these actions through higher costs on everyday necessities, without meaningful notice, representation, or recourse, and shall be made whole through a transparent and congressionally directed refund process administered by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HDA9A22823B8D43FAB784CCA685820BAC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HF884AA4D83E14120BB529878A6034467"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Covered tariffs</header> <text>The term <quote>covered tariffs</quote> means any duties or fees imposed pursuant to Presidential proclamations or Executive orders under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act that were subsequently determined to lack congressional authorization.</text>
            </paragraph></section>
<section id="H832DB8E28D4B4F4881149C3A9B8D1249"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of consumer refund formula</header>
<subsection id="H8780DB977C4742F2A8E0439E6F61C285"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Not later than 120 days after enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall develop and publish a formula to calculate refunds to American consumers for amounts paid that were attributable to covered tariffs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF1993E2F82264C63B7F5BDED17AE7CB0"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The refund formula shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HDC91BCBCB9454C098F8FAD7AC86F0405"><enum>(1)</enum><text>quantify total consumer cost increases tied to covered tariffs using data from U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and other relevant Federal datasets;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C3EF5BBFCA248298E553C06F1018C4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>estimate pass-through effects from importers, distributors, and retailers to end consumers; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4CD13DE54BD24C608BA0784E4C6B2433"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incorporate equitable adjustments based on household income and geographic disparities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC20AEC84B93D4F3CB3854ECB2DE643B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the formula, the Secretary shall consult with the Bureau of Economic Analysis, the Internal Revenue Service, the Federal Reserve Board, and independent economists with expertise in trade policy and consumer pricing.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HACA850C441E44333922992A675CC9539"><enum>5.</enum><header>Distribution of refunds</header>
<subsection id="H309F47FC0DC844A1A18ACE8CDA7440AD"><enum>(a)</enum><text>To the maximum extent practicable, refunds shall be issued automatically using existing Treasury and Internal Revenue Service payment systems, including direct deposit or refundable tax credits.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6C0FA7496520486F8F136B4FA8247EB7"><enum>(b)</enum><text>For individuals not captured through existing systems, the Secretary shall establish a streamlined application process requiring minimal documentation.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H1BEAEE1877E84A0CBC758A695F143DAE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to Congress and oversight</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after enactment, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress detailing the finalized refund formula, total anticipated refund obligations, and projected distribution timelines. The Government Accountability Office shall review the implementation of this Act and submit findings to Congress not later than one year after refunds commence.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

