<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H3D836A884B88412599DA669E57583F6E" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1414 IH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1589) to authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain aliens, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1414</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260702">July 2, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1589) to authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain aliens, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H764369AEEE384292BAB07CA9EEE7F612">
<section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3D836A884B88412599DA669E57583F6F"><text>That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 1589) to authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain aliens, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment specified in section 4 of this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section> <section id="H3D836A884B88412599DA669E57583F6G"><enum>2.</enum><text>Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 1589.</text></section>
<section id="H3D836A884B88412599DA669E57583F6H"><enum>3.</enum><text>The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.R. 1589 no later than three calendar days after passage.</text></section> <section id="H3D836A884B88412599DA669E57583F6I"><enum>4.</enum><text>The amendment referred to in the first section of this resolution is as follows:</text></section>
<section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H3D836A884B88412599DA669E57583F6J"><text><quote>In Sec. 202(b)(1)(A), strike <quote>January 1, 2017</quote> and insert <quote>July 1, 2024</quote></quote>.</text></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

