<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5465EF68A05E4270B4C82B5DA03DF5F1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7543 IH: Plastic Pellet Free Waters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7543</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate certain limitations with respect to pre-production plastic pellet pollution, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H81943CAAAA564AE998E8579F69100F4E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC9843A31F544428C82E9BE6856DB3412"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Plastic Pellet Free Waters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H75E133CBF2B048A99B3EF34C48927D2B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Effluent limitations for wastewater, spills, and runoff from plastic polymer production facilities, plastic molding and forming facilities, and other point sources associated with the transport and packaging of plastic pellets or other pre-production plastic materials</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall promulgate a final rule to ensure that—</text>
<paragraph id="HE8E6B935DFDE42DC8AC5147405062400"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the discharge of plastic pellets or other pre-production plastic materials (including discharge into wastewater and other runoff) from facilities regulated under part 414 or 463 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), is prohibited;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4033A04659464F099498573AE207D360"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the discharge of plastic pellets or other pre-production plastic materials (including discharge into wastewater and other runoff) from a point source (as defined in section 502 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>)) that makes, uses, packages, or transports those plastic pellets and other pre-production plastic materials is prohibited; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H242F97CED1AA44CABE971EA22D077F56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the requirements under paragraphs (1) and (2) are reflected in—</text> <subparagraph id="H0890D788B02345F6A40D911F37AFC548"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all wastewater, stormwater, and other permits issued by the Administrator and State-delegated programs under section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>) to facilities and other point sources (as defined in section 502 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>)) that make, use, package, or transport plastic pellets or other pre-production plastic materials, as determined by the Administrator, in addition to other applicable limits and standards; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEBC6CBFF0A424D8089FE1BAF5AD47364"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all standards of performance promulgated under section 312(p) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1322">33 U.S.C. 1322(p)</external-xref>) that are applicable to point sources (as defined in section 502 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>)) that make, use, package, or transport plastic pellets or other pre-production plastic materials, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

