<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFBA301526FCF46EBBD8AD22FDB7C63EE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6699 IH: Stop Communist Radio Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6699</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to establish a program to make grants to certain radio stations experiencing harmful interference, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F22651B50054DC58FA2CCF8C5D6486A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H733EDD95F7604F20BF310EE8016300C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Communist Radio Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B5E0F0C7338445F993533891549BA26"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to certain radio stations experiencing harmful interference</header> <subsection id="H7E64E40A23CF4244BB7099672EA0AF12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall establish a program to make grants on a competitive basis to enable covered radio stations experiencing harmful interference from radio transmissions originating in the Republic of Cuba to acquire and operate technology and equipment to mitigate such harmful interference.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE4326250AD3849C1A6E664645403AF21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The Commission may only award a grant under this section to the licensee of a covered radio station if—</text> <paragraph id="H90831C88173749C0B23729AA126AE078"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such station has experienced harmful interference from radio transmissions originating in Cuba; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13CB22660D9241ACA341DEFE3362EF90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such licensee submits to the Commission an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information and assurances as the Commission may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD44096C8C2034FBBB243B81C2615C793"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The licensee of a covered radio station that receives a grant under this section shall use grant funds to acquire and operate technology and equipment to mitigate harmful interference experienced by such station from radio transmissions originating in Cuba, in accordance with the terms and conditions specified by the Commission under subsection (d).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H287DFB1D452147CF9AFD47373F057895"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a grant to the licensee of a covered radio station under this section, the Commission shall specify such terms and conditions relating to the operation of the technology and equipment acquired with grant funds as the Commission considers appropriate in order to enable such licensee to reduce the effects of harmful interference to such station from radio transmissions originating in Cuba while avoiding harmful interference to other spectrum users.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEB6E180D22034EDAB09EBFE259CBADAA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment under Communications Act of 1934</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The operation by the licensee of a covered radio station that receives a grant under this section of technology and equipment acquired with grant funds, to the extent that such operation is in accordance with the terms and conditions specified by the Commission under subsection (d) in making such grant, shall be treated as being in compliance with the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>), the regulations promulgated under such Act, and the license of such station.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H86807E092DEB4629B60A86EF15E21CA3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6A8F86FB61AE4AA1B3E35EF4FD62F07F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7E392FFC3274401A39AD76562588287"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered radio station</header><text>The term <quote>covered radio station</quote> means a radio station that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF577AA2FF8A94FD6B790E0323A1E2FAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is licensed by the Commission to engage in AM or FM radio broadcasting;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5AD9784FDEC54DD9A4406F1CD26C293E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a small coverage area, as determined by the Commission; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7391E5E6F33D4353950C753E6A0F0CAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not affiliated with any radio network or government entity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

