<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB0188D4347D480F8E95E136F39FF86E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7495 IH: To authorize the establishment of memorials to the Wisconsin infantry officers and enlisted men who fought in the Battle of Antietam and the Second Battle of Bull Run, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7495</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the establishment of memorials to the Wisconsin infantry officers and enlisted men who fought in the Battle of Antietam and the Second Battle of Bull Run, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86A231A677714EE38AC63EBA0A711E47" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF88369A26CD5482284021479CD98D9A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of Wisconsin memorials at Antietam and Manassas</header> 
<subsection id="H32C0237C9D8C4E2F8457247A46F2A942"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Memorials authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall authorize the establishment of—</text> <paragraph id="H9A694E8A6D78465BA9D02DC9686BDC79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at a suitable location approved by the Secretary within the boundaries of Antietam National Battlefield, a memorial to the officers and enlisted men of the Second, Third, Fifth, Sixth, and Seventh Wisconsin Infantry Regiments who fought in the Battle of Antietam on September 17, 1862; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A7B349670964B87952AB102202E6536"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at a suitable location approved by the Secretary within the boundaries of Manassas National Battlefield Park, a memorial to the officers and enlisted men of the Second, Sixth, and Seventh Wisconsin Infantry Regiments who fought in the Second Battle of Bull Run on August 28–30, 1862.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H746D4D071F374C5A8BD9FE96853DF755"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select the persons who may establish each of the memorials authorized by subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C44C740B73246838F24148126F31C58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Design approvals</header><text>The size, design, and inscriptions of the memorials authorized by subsection (a) shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H305B706493DA44D8971558303C0CE149"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Prohibition on use of Federal funds for establishment</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be expended to design the memorials authorized by subsection (a), to acquire the memorials, to prepare the site selected for the memorials, or to install the memorials.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H437FE7154CD844B89373C9B1B8CD1F41"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Suspension for misrepresentation in fundraising</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may suspend the authority of the persons selected under subsection (b) to establish the memorials authorized by subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that fundraising efforts relating to the memorials have misrepresented an affiliation with the memorials or the Federal Government.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA590B2A1BC5F4F398F79EBA1B944A616"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Until each memorial authorized by subsection (a) is installed, the persons selected under subsection (b) to establish that memorial shall submit to the Secretary an annual report of operations related to fundraising efforts for the memorial and progress on the establishment of the memorial.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6DBBC99D64BF43958E4AC0A24F8967E7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Maintenance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon installation of each memorial authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall assume responsibility for the maintenance of that memorial. The Secretary may accept contributions for the maintenance of the memorials from the persons selected under subsection (b) to establish the memorials and from other persons. Amounts accepted under this subsection shall be merged with other funds available to the Secretary for the maintenance of the memorials and credited to a separate account with the National Park Foundation.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

