<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON26093-GW2-7P-G2X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3919 IS: Hurricane Forecast Improvement Program Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3919</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 with respect to the hurricane forecast improvement program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hurricane Forecast Improvement Program Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e7ac9ce4d7646f2862431833d9ee97e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Hurricane forecast improvement program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 104 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8514">15 U.S.C. 8514</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42c4036f601f4a8eac28dab4c032becf"><section id="id95eee2a170f1417cbb6e2ffd8f85920f"><enum>104.</enum><header>Hurricane forecast improvement program</header><subsection id="id23735c2a889846a7be09e4579074949d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary, in collaboration with the United States weather industry and academic partners, shall maintain a program to improve hurricane forecasting, predictions, and warnings.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc976d23d780242a68b82ec4ea82e074d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goal</header><text>The goal of the program under subsection (a) shall be to develop and extend accurate hurricane forecasts, predictions, and warnings in order to reduce the loss of life or property related to hurricanes, with a focus on the following:</text><paragraph id="id4f8fe6f8bbca42c7bc7aa6e89e42bea7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Improving the understanding, prediction, and communication of rapid intensity change and projected path of hurricanes, including probabilistic methods for hurricane hazard mapping.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3fa67a78ff44f34a975c44bbbb6a74b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Improving the forecast and impact-based communication of inland flooding, compound flooding, and storm surges from hurricanes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0b3f39e52b14401bb5b5e40c8239db2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Incorporating social, behavioral, risk, communication, and economic sciences to clearly inform response to prevent the loss of life or property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbb1db45624c4e7d983886baef0d8097"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Evaluating and incorporating, as appropriate, innovative observations, including acoustic or infrasonic measurements, novel sensor technologies, observation tools or networks, crewed or uncrewed systems, and hosted instruments on commercial aircrafts, vessels, and satellites.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id19a76cc21d8945eeaad584b7788046eb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall award grants for research, including relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="id0168840f6a5f4d19b0ad78ac2b15bdc7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Implementing key strategies and following priorities and objectives outlined by the 2019 report of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration entitled, <quote>Hurricane Forecast Improvement Program</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2131dd10dca0499db04b353101331a3b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In coordination with the Social and Behavioral Sciences Subcommittee of the National Science and Technology Council and other relevant interagency committees, improving the social, behavioral, and economic sciences related to risk communication, and delivery of information critical for reducing the loss of life or property related to hurricanes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03f0436f6eda4fb089d1ee7b821b5e28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improving the physical sciences, operational modeling, and tools related to hurricane formation, the impacts of wind and water-based hurricane hazards on the built and natural environment, and the interaction of hurricanes and tornadoes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd09a3072f5bc4aa6a5b25f873f5b0f9d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Warnings</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="idff56764b3e7e4dd7a497cdb281d70d5b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct and transition to operations the research necessary to develop and deploy probabilistic weather forecast guidance technology relating to hurricanes and related weather phenomena;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id373eb35e1f544874bddb87119be04967"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate into hurricane modeling and forecasting, as appropriate, social, behavioral, and economic sciences research; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id723cd5d3a28e4202b08a1fae64998369"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expand computational resources, including cloud computing, to support and improve higher resolution operational modeling of hurricanes and related weather phenomena.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4da79b8cfea44e1db33487ee9b733a85"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than June 1 of each year until 2029, the Under Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="idd0bcd7b17d364301ba183e191bfd55b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number and causes of missed mission requirements for the National Hurricane Operations Plan and the National Winter Season Operations Plan, including those related to equipment malfunction, aircraft availability, aircraft maintenance, flight hour limits, and availability of pilots or other air and maintenance crew members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaec54c5390e4fb1a6cd3da6d9829234"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Requirements related to the plans described in paragraph (1) that were requested by forecasters but not tasked, and the reasons why those were not tasked.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3703328d43a48c28504b1bd0ed39e30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A workforce management plan addressing any shortfalls in human capital resources that are necessary for hurricane observational data collection aboard aircraft or uncrewed systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18dcfd4c996f499cbfc2230cc058d5b0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A summary of—</text><subparagraph id="id2022eac7385f4239a955e934ac4a2df4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hurricane technology that is under research and development to improve confidence in hurricane track and intensity predictions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf9fc2effaaf4eff9e89f9e0181b148e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hurricane technology that is at the prototype demonstration stage or beyond; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc633f9d6f1e2467494ba6c8374154799"><enum>(C)</enum><text>plans for transitioning the hurricane technology described in subparagraph (B) into operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

