<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC16D54E9D6E04B4DB49F8F04EDFC6485" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8976 IH: Women in Criminal Justice Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8976</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for improvements in the treatment of women in the legal system.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H05AE5D8A506A44AEA7DF88A5F37D493F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H988192D2ED71469D80D52982E5AC919E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection id="HB32117077FAC4B86AE7959292E7B4B62"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women in Criminal Justice Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8245984A060E43628BDDCF3B5F5A560B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="H988192D2ED71469D80D52982E5AC919E" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="title" idref="H5A431BDFDE1D4AD29B7D305407511042">Title I—GENDER-INFORMED ARREST
            AND LAW ENFORCEMENT PRACTICES</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HC25E1802F976472BA0A99E862F658CE5" level="section">Sec. 101. Protection of children at arrest.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE322950E25AB4DA8A3A7300AE1991213" level="section">Sec. 102. Grant program for gender-informed training of local law enforcement officers.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 103. Representation in law enforcement grant program.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HC7F7334C15664F7F8792F5D944544AC5" level="title">Title II—FAMILY REUNIFICATION TO REDUCE RECIDIVISM AND PROTECT CHILDREN</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3F28E2CC98C74CBA945495A1B05472CA" level="section">Sec. 201. Parent-focused bail reform.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H9EECBC3B446A47439C092DF89A93DFB2" level="section">Sec. 202. Temporary release from imprisonment to maintain community ties.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 203. Updating custody requirements to preserve families.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="title" idref="HD8D7F78803D04961B915EF78F3678E29">Title III—GENDER-INFORMED
            ALTERNATIVES TO INCARCERATION</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HFE2842C64DBF4821B30779BB98B2E932" level="section">Sec. 301. Federal pretrial diversion.</toc-entry>
                    <toc-entry idref="H48258632C68F4FBF865976995A7E2466" level="title">Title
                        IV—CONSPIRACY REFORM ACT—FIXING THE <quote>GIRLFRIEND
                        PROBLEM</quote></toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3201192A0BDD4AF3B8E6CE0212785218" level="section">Sec. 401. Focusing penalties for drug conspiracy.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H385B057AE5074B4F94853A1B3E90596B" level="section">Sec. 402. Increasing judicial discretion to sentence less culpable justice-involved individuals.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H0615FBC1B25240F796AA1B9AD2E82320" level="section">Sec. 403. Clarifying culpability at sentencing.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="title" idref="H759E8D01C1ED458090090748B5A0F424">Title V—GENDER-RESPONSIVE AND
            TRAUMA-INFORMED IMPOSITION OF A SENTENCE</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H35C7BC7DA516497880B856FC5E770792" level="section">Sec. 501. Gender and trauma-informed sentencing.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="title" idref="H7B6CCC606C354B9BBAC12BB05CEA636E">Title VI—GENDER-RESPONSIVE PRISON
            REFORM</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HBB8E28D543274CE8A673682536115F46" level="section">Sec. 601. Health care needs of incarcerated women in the Bureau of Prisons.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H894B5BA8997644249700D5E559E8B5C4" level="section">Sec. 602. Trauma-informed care.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H8BA2565F26794D64B0F27F4D06C903E6" level="section">Sec. 603. Trauma-informed and gender-responsive training and staffing.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H1D31110A264447CB8410B5C62C296BF8" level="section">Sec. 604. Improving the Bureau of Prisons Resolve Trauma Therapy Program.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD3B17907D3654FA484CC670E5C3BAC9F" level="section">Sec. 605. Gender-responsive programs in the Bureau of Prisons.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H8A46DC114FB64E95B646AB624C3A1B3B" level="section">Sec. 606. Gender-responsive prison conditions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD6A390EA733046CF89573F3363FC6B59" level="section">Sec. 607. Gender-specific posts.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H07E5A01CCBEA4EE6AE281381E804AAF3" level="section">Sec. 608. Female incarcerated person nutritional standards.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H953E88D802F44BC08DA65AF04383779E" level="section">Sec. 609. Gender-responsive discipline policies.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE05F7A24FD664AF5B9B2F77DBBE419AC" level="section">Sec. 610. Expanding access to the Mothers and Infants Nurturing Together Program and the Residential Parenting Program.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H6F71D1D193AE4A9B9D3DF0E07417B827" level="section">Sec. 611. Report on failure to comply with the 500 mile rule.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 612. GAO study on representation in the Bureau of Prisons.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H89E22618CAD44E419DD1B6EDFE5DE2BB" level="section">Sec. 613. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="title" idref="HA53BE107CCF64FCF821902B09B1BDC17">Title VII—GENDER-INFORMED REENTRY
            REFORM</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE597915CD8834CE4AD5DF14AD99760EF" level="section">Sec. 701. Focus on women at residential reentry centers and in community confinement.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H28195C1300CC433E8A2D3734DC1FDB51" level="section">Sec. 702. Focusing supervision on the rehabilitation of women.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HA3DEFA9E5D1D45629A221DF038308642" level="section">Sec. 703. Gender-responsive modification of supervised release restrictions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H912C77D5EDE541859047DDC525A9A555" level="title">Title VIII—Definitions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H99BA6583B18C4F77838E8CEFF5F5D952" level="section">Sec. 801. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<title id="H5A431BDFDE1D4AD29B7D305407511042"><enum>I</enum><header>GENDER-INFORMED ARREST AND LAW ENFORCEMENT PRACTICES</header>
<section id="HC25E1802F976472BA0A99E862F658CE5"><enum>101.</enum><header>Protection of children at arrest</header>
<subsection id="H21218E9135B742A985D817BBF2ACF6FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">Chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding the following new section at the end:</text> <quoted-block id="HB89589D12D4E469D8B5A632CA31B7359" style="USC"> <section id="H383D8EDC72B742CEB859999A40103FAD"><enum>3065.</enum><header>Arrest by Federal law enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A law enforcement officer who is authorized to make arrests under any Federal law shall permit any person who is arrested and is the custodial parent or guardian of a minor or dependent child the opportunity to make arrangements for such child at the time of arrest, including by permitting access to a telephone and appropriate phone numbers for the purposes of securing care for the child, and shall not refer the child to a child welfare agency, unless the custodial parent or guardian of the minor cannot make arrangements for the child at the time of arrest or to secure care for the child, or unless the arresting officer has reasonable cause to suspect the child is experiencing abuse or neglect. A drug related charge on its own does not constitute sufficient cause to suspect abuse or neglect.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H808BF793AD8341BDB3074FC698E6C783"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of contents of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>3065. Arrest by Federal law enforcement</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE322950E25AB4DA8A3A7300AE1991213"><enum>102.</enum><header>Grant program for gender-informed training of local law enforcement officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H77CE7C4D15BE4B0084935BC6F5E65490" style="OLC">
<part id="H62095C15585A44B59DD7A2F27128CBF8">
            <enum>PP</enum>
            <header>GRANTS FOR GENDER-RESPONSIVE TRAINING</header>
            <section id="H4E17ED1F6D7E4CE1B230720218FABE27">
              <enum>3051.</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General may make a grant to a State each fiscal year for purposes of carrying out the requirements of section 3052. The term of such grant shall be 1 year.</text>
            </section>
            <section id="HD0452D03722142D0832245BAF3827AAA">
              <enum>3052.</enum>
              <header>Training on gender-informed law enforcement practices</header>
              <subsection id="H5488A2127DEF4E8BAED531339A2912F8">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Training curricula</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the effective date of this section, the Attorney General shall develop and identify training curricula under this paragraph in consultation with relevant law enforcement agencies of States and units of local government, associations that advocate on issues which disproportionately impact women, medical professionals, professional law enforcement organizations, mental health organizations, and family advocacy organizations.</text>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H27BC32CD441743B2B069C4B824A14D3D">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Training requirement</header>
 <text>The requirements of this subsection are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H6B0F5EB0699348B4A2DAFD15BECA808F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>A State shall require that all individuals enrolled in an academy of a law enforcement agency in the State and all chief law enforcement officers of the State fulfill a training session on gender-informed policing practices each fiscal year. In the case of individuals attending an academy, such training session shall be for at least 8 hours, and in the case of all other law enforcement officers, the training session shall be for at least 4 hours.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H301D487B799740EFB8809E51290BE703">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Gender-informed policing practices shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AA83A6021764FCFADE889E06DABB169"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence-based training on the circumstances most likely to disproportionately or differently impact women who have contact with law enforcement through traffic stops, street stops, searches, arrests, or any other contact, and may include training on trauma, sexual and physical abuse, family issues, physical and mental health issues, hygiene issues, racial disparities in the arrests of and law enforcement contacts with women, and issues related to the arrest of parents, including the identification and appropriate responses to a child, present or not present, whose parent is arrested in order to help minimize potential trauma and support a child’s physical safety and well-being following an arrest;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HBF0716DAB4424C4E9E2AB5CB690F93FF">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training on a proactive, victim-centered approach to be used when responding to domestic violence that utilizes best-practices aimed at reducing risk of imminent or future violence, and strongly discourages dual arrests;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H7F082DE2A0064F349DEF0D93D58E0694">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence-based training on proper interrogation techniques for individuals with a history of trauma such as intimate partner violence or sexual assault as well as information on false confessions;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HF92EAAD77F344F2AAA3D335BD549F0AC">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence-based training on how the interaction of race, class, disability, and gender may influence police response as well as behavior of an individual towards law enforcement officers; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H2C4339A22B09481F85F9ED49E240810F">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>evidence-based training on the specific needs and appropriate policies and protocols for pregnant persons who have contact with law enforcement through traffic stops, street stops, searches, arrests, or any other contact.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HC6F5E4027AA44A34A46599BAF8838EEE">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>No later than 2 years after receipt of a grant under this section, a State shall certify to the Attorney General of the United States that such training sessions have been completed.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="HE47CBB49E3624F7C9BC53FE099F6D409">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Compliance and ineligibility</header>
                <paragraph id="H11171C3201AB4957A59FD3BCD7234EE7">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Compliance date</header>
 <text>The period specified under this paragraph is the period beginning 120 days after the date of enactment of this part, to comply with subsection (a), except that—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H338FA924E3174EA8A61A00DF0932FC3E">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the Attorney General may grant an additional 120 days to a State that is making good faith efforts to comply with such subsection; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H81210D6BFC6B4E9CB6C2E2DF4C782648">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Attorney General shall waive the requirements of subsection (a) if compliance by a State would be unconstitutional under the constitution of such State.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H578E7AAC2E644F93915F61BFEB99D492">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Ineligibility</header>
 <text>A State that is not in compliance with the requirements of subsection (a) during a fiscal year is not eligible to apply for a grant under this part during the next fiscal year.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
            <section id="H8EB926BC29AE4D44A85C966FFED58E44">
              <enum>3053.</enum>
              <header>Use of funds</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">A grantee may use the grant to—</text> <paragraph id="HD98370AEF4DE4EAE9E59AD609C387E00"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pay for costs associated with carrying out section 3052(b), including attendance by law enforcement officers or professionals at an approved training course, including a course provided by a law enforcement training academy of a State or unit of local government;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H4D366AEBA9BE4EADB259C888994B50A9">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>procure training continuing education on 1 or more of the topics described in section 3052(b) from a certified entity;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HA27DB94B2868424BA810B6033A43DCAA">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a law enforcement agency of a unit of local government that employs fewer than 50 law enforcement officers (determined on a full-time equivalent basis), pay for the costs of overtime accrued as a result of the attendance of a law enforcement officer or covered professional at an approved training course for which the costs associated with conducting the approved training course are paid using amounts provided under this section; and</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H9042DEC13DA149FB81997F1D41CCF324">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>pay for the costs of developing mechanisms to comply with the certification requirement established under section 3052(b)(3), in an amount not to exceed 5 percent of the total amount of the grant award.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </section>
            <section id="H8AD87F219B5C4684A08F97B82957908D">
              <enum>3054.</enum>
              <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text>
            </section>
          </part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H74BBCB5C52F646298F49BF48E2C0A1EB"><enum>103.</enum><header>Representation in law enforcement grant program</header>
<subsection id="HC3E8B198B67F4BB6AE808B7BDF10B46C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a grant program to improve recruitment and retention of women law enforcement officers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB25667461A84407BBA8B3EA47DB41199"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice shall make a grant to a law enforcement agency or department eligible for a grant under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8D796024FA45467998AD4144A20974BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>Amounts from a grant made under this section may be used only for the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7DADF6494E6C4F7F9D08CAEA159FC82F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Establishing working groups, committees, or advisory boards to review current hiring practices to include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4C7B699AA4274249BA3B2FCC22A431DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recruitment procedures;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC73244CB7B04F9B945A29D5924E3F93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advertised job descriptions;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9BAD7A374272448FB8E05564828B31DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>images used on recruitment materials;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF63A9B97260B40C68F29261CE14DEB23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the process of reviewing applications;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDFFC17DC5793402CBA2C8E2AD812FD44"><enum>(E)</enum><text>required tests; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1468DECAF314C62B4840823C5F57B3F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the procedures and individuals or groups selected to interview candidates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC11E70332AEC48C0BA4423270C34AE5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Producing and distributing recruitment materials with inclusive racial and gender representation as well as language focused on a variety of important skills and/or qualifications for law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8876310704047F9AFF875773CCC8248"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Outreach to groups or locations with predominantly women in attendance.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B24FFA221164AB98861833282B0F033"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing on-site child care at law enforcement academies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC13778A83CB74B67874F5DC0BAF8C645"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Improving parental and family leave policies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4226EFA078654E54906FDDF7431DD504"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Establishing mentoring programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7C5E4C1C2464FE6AC9ACD6D0C8913F5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Training recruiters and academy staff on the importance of a diverse workforce, implicit bias, and equal employment opportunity matters.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H14D2AA95FF0B4463823041180DAD5B3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section></title> <title id="HC7F7334C15664F7F8792F5D944544AC5"><enum>II</enum><header>FAMILY REUNIFICATION TO REDUCE RECIDIVISM AND PROTECT CHILDREN</header> <section id="H3F28E2CC98C74CBA945495A1B05472CA"><enum>201.</enum><header>Parent-focused bail reform</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3142(g)(3)(A) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>minor or dependent children and whether detention would negatively impact a child, including through potential loss of custody,</quote> after <quote>family ties,</quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H9EECBC3B446A47439C092DF89A93DFB2"><enum>202.</enum><header>Temporary release from imprisonment to maintain community ties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking section 3622 and inserting:</text> <quoted-block id="HB0D1F77291064085B6FED847DA1FBF5B" style="USC"> <section id="H48B0F1263F0D400586C1F37AAE3DE793"><enum>3622.</enum><header>Temporary release</header> <subsection id="HE26A4EBD0A204A5CB78E9177C8FF4EA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Generally</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Prisons and the United States Marshals Service shall release an individual from imprisonment for a limited period if such release is authorized by the warden or a judicial officer under subsection (c) and in accordance with the facility or officer’s prescribed conditions, to—</text>
<paragraph id="HB8F1E54D19B940A6974CC4F3B2950BE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">visit a designated place for a period not to exceed thirty days without specific authorization, and then return to the same or another facility, for the purpose of—</text> <subparagraph id="H20258BBC2A2D408D91CB67F9D1EFE341"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtaining medical treatment not otherwise available, including access to sexual assault nurse examiners;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBF157D32952F448BB8767D5D043FF0F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing or reestablishing family or community ties; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E755E48688D44B49254F175A4A6CC07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>attending court proceedings concerning juvenile custody or dependency of a minor or dependent child; </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE8826D6E108542CEB805EEBD7E5A55CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">visit a designated place for a period not to exceed seven days without specific authorization, and then return to the same or another facility, for the purpose of—</text> <subparagraph id="HDDC70C1DB19643609B77A1A624F0C2D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>visiting a relative who is dying;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B61CEAFF0F4412CB9115DB3BC1BED4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>attending a funeral of a relative;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77A435C0F71546DE996156950E0E491D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contacting a prospective employer; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE3BB45B536C42F6908AE2F46AB2B790"><enum>(D)</enum><text>engaging in any other significant activity consistent with the public interest;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8114B7CE95E44453B528352581CAA8FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>participate in a training or educational program in the community while continuing in official detention at the prison facility; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H21C4D5197FD8409EBFC02C5ECCD59CEA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work at paid employment in the community while continuing in official detention at the penal or correctional facility if the rates of pay and other conditions of employment will not be less than those paid or provided for work of a similar nature in the community.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2C6D71F778A24C2694F9426A3656BA11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>As used in this section, the term <term>imprisonment</term> means custodial detention, juvenile official detention, or community supervision, both prior to a trial or a dispositional hearing, and after conviction or adjudication.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H55C9E07300B4434CAD6080C9664DC9FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon petition from a person who is under an order of imprisonment, a judicial officer is authorized to release such person under subsection (a) and may set the least restrictive conditions of release necessary to meet the requirements of safety and justice. Such authorization shall be provided for the purposes listed in subsection (a) if it is consistent with the purpose for which any sentence was imposed if applicable and any pertinent policy statement issued by the Sentencing Commission pursuant to section 994(a)(2) of title 28, United States Code, unless a factual showing is made to the court demonstrating that the release would create an imminent risk of flight or harm to the incarcerated person or others. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H6184E6D2FF2D430C9C7381CEBCF48C8F"><enum>203.</enum><header>Updating custody requirements to preserve families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 475(5)(E) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/675">42 U.S.C. 675(5)(E)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HBB6D087B6396489E9F8B9B4C0716AC60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>15 of the most recent 22 months</quote> and inserting <quote>24 consecutive months and who is not in the care of kin (including fictive kin), the State may consider filing or joining a petition for modification or termination of parental rights only after demonstrating by clear and convincing evidence that the State has provided to the family of the child such services, supports, and time needed to address the reasons for foster care and enable the family to safely reunify, and by demonstrating compelling reasons why the modification or termination is in the best interest of the child, and if the child is living with a kinship (including fictive kinship) caregiver, the State agency shall provide a meaningful opportunity for the kinship (including fictive kinship) caregiver to express whether modification or termination is or is not in the best interests of the child and shall document such in the case plan of the child</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64706F507E0E4DDD9ECBF1D9A5C567FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking clause (i) and redesignating clauses (ii) and (iii) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC5929983D49D428297FA97BDA79FC2AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii) (as so redesignated by paragraph (2) of this section), by striking the semicolon and inserting a comma; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37ABE9A5CC2746BB97998F4012B9A235"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after and below clause (ii) (as so redesignated) the following: <quote>except that, in the case of a child to whom this subparagraph applies solely because the child has been in foster care under the responsibility of the State for 24 consecutive months and is not in the care of kin (including fictive kin), the State may not file or join such a petition if a parent of the child is actively engaged in services to address the reasons the child entered care (including treatment for substance use disorder, mental health concerns, or parenting skills), if based principally on the incarceration of a parent, or if based principally on the detention of the parent by the Department of Homeland Security or the deportation of the parent;</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></title>
<title id="HD8D7F78803D04961B915EF78F3678E29"><enum>III</enum><header>GENDER-INFORMED ALTERNATIVES TO INCARCERATION</header>
<section id="HFE2842C64DBF4821B30779BB98B2E932"><enum>301.</enum><header>Federal pretrial diversion</header>
<subsection id="HBD4DE4E8DFAE4C5C80FF10E70549A1DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/201">Chapter 201</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding the following new section at the end:</text> <quoted-block id="HF4B15FA399A54668A5C6961E8A2DB007" style="USC"> <section id="H542CF88987464E25B65386AC921CBD6D"><enum>3015.</enum><header>Federal pretrial diversion</header> <subsection id="H5DA3C941A641440092EB3A3E947C78F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The following terms apply in this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H24F0BDF0D111406B8100B84DC00FE19E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criminal case</header><text>The term <term>criminal case</term> means a Federal criminal offense or Federal juvenile adjudication where a criminal complaint, information or indictment has been filed, or where a criminal complaint, information or indictment has not been filed and the Government has a reasonable belief that a prosecutable Federal offense may be filed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC22036A1AE4A472C8949BB6E5D67AABA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Divertee</header><text>The term <term>divertee</term> means an adult or juvenile who is accepted to participate in a pretrial diversion program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF8D73111C05F432A9667190CCC35EAEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pretrial diversion</header><text>The term <term>pretrial diversion</term> means an alternative to criminal prosecution that diverts a defendant or juvenile away from the traditional criminal justice process into a recidivism reduction plan, and which results in a diversionary disposition to a divertee who successfully completes such recidivism reduction plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE19C9FE2B954DDEB85B646AF4A1D6C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Diversionary disposition</header><text>The term <term>diversionary disposition</term> means the termination of a criminal case that results in—</text>
<subparagraph id="H322E8D8B8F58477F8BAC94EC6D66527A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Government not filing a criminal complaint, information, indictment or charge in a criminal case;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D93DA0F6AFB46859F66B8818AD70415"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dismissal of a criminal complaint, indictment, information or charge against a divertee; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFA368DA525014EA7B4DFC9771400EE0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a conviction and imposition of a sentence, or a juvenile adjudication and disposition, that does not include a term of incarceration, imprisonment or official detention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF522B1D32084EA0A26428DE2D80326D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recidivism reduction plan</header><text>The term <term>recidivism reduction plan</term> means a plan, ordered to be completed by the Court, and that the divertee agrees to complete in exchange for a diversionary disposition which—</text>
<subparagraph id="H22420D1547C443DF816142CBE99EF860"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include supervision, at a frequency and level to be determined by the Court; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C6A3DD7743F40EBBB9A263D612B85A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include classes, treatment, programs, assistance, requirements, restrictions, or other conditions that are gender-responsive, and are tailored specifically to the needs of the divertee, which shall include partnerships with nonprofit community-based organizations, and shall include—</text>
<clause id="H0CF67E16648242368C9EF4B201350420"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assistance with seeking, obtaining, and maintaining employment;</text></clause> <clause id="H53978D22EBC440A797502C20E9137AC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>placement in job placement programs that partner with private employers;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBC655254D91E40379D116F7FCB41D4C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>job skills classes, including computer skills, technical skills, vocational skills, and any other job-related skills;</text></clause> <clause id="H571C93521D9845BA8541297B5F55AB30"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assistance with locating and maintaining housing, including family-accessible housing, which may include counseling as to public housing opportunities, assistance with applications for public housing benefits, and locating and/or securing temporary or long-term housing;</text></clause>
<clause id="H939214510484457C8B1B42DF2A29CAA0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>obtaining an identification card or driver’s license;</text></clause> <clause id="H73682891A18B4E7F8A5BA3E267A9EEA7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>registering to vote, and applying for voting rights to be restored, where permitted by law;</text></clause>
<clause id="H92F25022E5B341B3B8FDB9291418640A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>assistance with, and requirements to apply for and remain in education programs, including assistance with applications for higher education loans and program admission;</text></clause> <clause id="HCD428495683549B6B2B9A8431D8E57EA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>financial counseling;</text></clause>
<clause id="H19DAD25DDC684266A2F953BA823F6370"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>referrals for legal assistance to pursue record expungement, family law and custody matters, legal aid services, and relevant civil matters including housing and other issues;</text></clause> <clause id="HC9CBCD33CFA24530903B9C3C94A3629F"><enum>(x)</enum><text>assistance with obtaining transportation, including through provision of transit fare;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4CF551F2E3B44DF28E63B7709A8A408C"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>familial counseling and parenting classes;</text></clause> <clause id="H7DDA159411734571A1139E8921B3A05B"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>problem-solving and life-skills assistance or classes;</text></clause>
<clause id="H708061393B2A4E17BF5F1F174AF45B0C"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>assistance with communication needs, including providing a mobile phone, mobile phone service or access, or internet access;</text></clause> <clause id="H264FAED5FEEB491AB4A9CF5C59089D24"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>assistance with applications for State or Federal Government benefits, where eligible;</text></clause>
<clause id="HDA3F45AF9EF148F1A8A60580B317883A"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>mentorship, including through programs that facilitate such services by formerly incarcerated or convicted individuals;</text></clause> <clause id="H0DD9DAB9554C49A5B2F5826F6D7F1A62"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>physical and emotional trauma-informed treatment, counseling, and therapy;</text></clause>
<clause id="H030E5237F72A46228A9C92D0B197CC38"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>medical and or mental health services, and cognitive-behavioral programming;</text></clause> <clause id="HC67263EB939D431CA2D33C4380A828C7"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>substance use treatment and testing, including family-based residential drug treatment;</text></clause>
<clause id="HE6495802A9F44DC7BB8502D660A976F2"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>reactivation, application for and maintaining professional or other licenses;</text></clause> <clause id="H5B51B416694443438626E240066FA543"><enum>(xx)</enum><text>payment of restitution, where appropriate;</text></clause>
<clause id="H8C59D355C16B42AB819DAE7C1A65397F"><enum>(xxi)</enum><text>restorative justice-based requirements; and</text></clause> <clause id="H740B341BEEB541419B3E787E023EA916"><enum>(xxii)</enum><text>any other needs-based assistance or requirement designed to reduce recidivism.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9BE4E8044C6041369CD9C87833E379F0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Restorative justice</header><text>The term <term>restorative justice</term> means a creative solution that focuses on repairing the harm caused by crime and reducing future harm through crime prevention, and which requires justice-involved individuals to take responsibility for their actions, seeks redress for victims, and the healing and reintegration of both within the community.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8AD1CCC61BF0409AA3C7C63EE2313317"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diversion authorized</header><text>Upon application by a defendant, the Government, United States Probation and Pretrial Services, or sua sponte by the Court, a United States Court with jurisdiction over a criminal case may divert such case into a pretrial diversion program under this section at any time prior to imposition of a sentence or disposition.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD0135F1C6B0143AC94D0D2FF86C0CD37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participation requirements</header><text>Participation in the program requires—</text> <paragraph id="H178ECE17625C497D86C99CC50FCD75B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">voluntary agreement to participate by the divertee, after being presented with the Court’s proposed pretrial diversion order as required under subsection (e);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F83E20D01AB499BAA111921DBB4062E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a signed waiver by the divertee that waives the right to a speedy trial for as much time as is needed for participation in the diversionary program as determined by the Court, and waiver of presentment of the case within the statute of limitations, if necessary, as determined by the Court; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H355B7F81A7E84589A7396EA13057B440"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that the divertee be afforded the advice of counsel, and if the divertee cannot afford counsel, that counsel be appointed at no cost to the divertee.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD8515E00BCDE489EA91D0F16E5EA940B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pretrial diversion determination application process</header><text>Upon the application for pretrial diversion of a criminal case, the applicant shall be referred to either the Chief Pretrial Services Officer or the Chief Probation Officer for a report, that shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HC43A9D7DD47946A58A78D488FF3935F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the applicant’s criminal history, background and characteristics, and the facts surrounding an applicant’s criminal case;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4B9763B65A02486393C729D3D828C3EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a recommendation to the Court whether a pretrial diversion program is appropriate for the applicant; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86ACD4B74FA14B6293D09C897788DD5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a needs-based assessment of the applicant, and a recommendation for a recidivism reduction plan tailored to the needs of the applicant, whether or not a pretrial diversion program is recommended.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC392138C38A042A58ADFEA096523DD0A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Pretrial diversion order</header><text>Upon review of the report described in subsection (e), and any argument, testimony and evidence presented by the Government and the applicant, the Court shall enter an order approving or denying the application of pretrial diversion, such an order shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HD9803003C5E440E9B2D475FDBCCB5638"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an order denying the application of pretrial diversion, a statement of reasons for such denial; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E17D6D2010F47E1AA658B9F09BBCA90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an order granting the application of pretrial diversion—</text> <subparagraph id="H8ACCC76F6AE94EEDBF0397F47F813D33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that the pretrial diversion period begins, and date, whereby, if successful completion is determined by the Court, a diversionary disposition may be entered;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H31E1AE33655840598DCB9BDEEE2E0E29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recidivism reduction plan which must be successfully completed by the divertee in order to receive a diversionary disposition;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F584714192946E3B62AEE336F4A16B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type of diversionary disposition that the divertee will receive if the divertee successfully completes the recidivism reduction plan, including opportunities for record expungement, which shall include the approval of the Government where required by law; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H734ECD375CE647B38F531E5E3D84D06F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the alternative disposition of the criminal case if the Court determines the divertee has not successfully completed the recidivism reduction plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1552FF1D97324850AEA0042410A3F2C5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Unsuccessful termination of pretrial diversion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A divertee is entitled to a hearing before the divertee’s pretrial diversion may be terminated. Upon breach of a condition of the recidivism reduction plan by the divertee, the U.S. Probation and Pretrial Services Office may so inform the Court, who shall determine whether such breach should warrant termination of diversion.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H09D77C1487F643ECBD8EA1C3D2914836"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Successful termination of pretrial diversion</header><text>If the Court determines that a divertee has successfully completed a recidivism reduction program as provided in the terms of the pretrial diversion order, the Court shall enter a diversionary disposition order, as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H9D84EBDC78A946F7A17C1E86CEA9398D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Upon approval of the Government, a criminal complaint, information, indictment or charge in a criminal case shall not be filed, and the Court shall order proceedings terminated.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3263721F05FA4FAFB4302C102DBF006E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon approval of the Government, dismissal of a criminal complaint, information, indictment or charge against a divertee shall be ordered and proceedings terminated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1383FA35C6A04504ACA7EDC402C871D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case of a divertee who has agreed to plead guilty to a criminal offense, a judgment of conviction and imposition of a sentence, or a juvenile adjudication shall be ordered, and notwithstanding any mandatory term of imprisonment provided for by law, the Court may order no term of incarceration.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The Court is authorized to permit withdrawal of a guilty plea under this subsection.</continuation-text></subsection>
<subsection id="H785ED4097A3F478598B51F08B406829D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>All information obtained in the course of making the decision to divert a justice-involved individual and all information obtained by treatment providers, class instructors, and other required program providers in the course of completing a recidivism reduction plan shall not be used against the divertee in criminal proceedings or at sentencing, except that in the case of a recommendation for termination of diversion, information regarding the divertee’s participation in such program may be used for purposes of termination proceedings.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4941D8D45A89495CB531D0F1966AD89E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Pretrial diversion program preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Where authorized by law, pretrial diversion program acceptance shall be prioritized in criminal cases where an applicant demonstrates a history of physical or emotional trauma, sexual or physical abuse, substance abuse, mental illness, or vulnerable circumstances such as pregnancy, disability, homelessness, physical health challenges, or the immediate familial economic needs of an applicant.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HEB27F004CF06409AAD5E9FF0C6938E73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of contents of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H2C93EB26040B4E3A98D8DF8BE5A7DAA5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">3015. Federal pretrial diversion.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title> <title id="H48258632C68F4FBF865976995A7E2466"><enum>IV</enum> <header>CONSPIRACY REFORM ACT—FIXING THE <quote>GIRLFRIEND PROBLEM</quote></header> <section id="H3201192A0BDD4AF3B8E6CE0212785218"><enum>401.</enum><header>Focusing penalties for drug conspiracy</header> <subsection id="H9B945A2A1D464264916EB2A81E856BFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Controlled substances act</header><text>Section 406 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/846">21 U.S.C. 846</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>subject to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense, the commission of which was the object of the attempt or conspiracy</quote> and inserting <quote>fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both, except that in no case may the penalty for an offense under this section exceed any penalty for the underlying substantive offense, the commission of which was the object of the attempt or conspiracy</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE5354830E18C4B1A9A285ED92393AD5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Controlled substances import and export act</header><text>Section 1013 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/963">21 U.S.C. 963</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>subject to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense, the commission of which was the object of the attempt or conspiracy</quote> and inserting <quote>fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both, except that in no case may the penalty for an offense under this section exceed the penalty for the underlying offense, the commission of which was the object of the attempt or conspiracy</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H385B057AE5074B4F94853A1B3E90596B"><enum>402.</enum><header>Increasing judicial discretion to sentence less culpable justice-involved individuals</header> <subsection id="H5F9085397E244B708DE9FB73C96CAEE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3553(e) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HA5BDBF6294824538B09EC46C151A4655"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Upon motion</quote> and inserting:</text> <quoted-block id="H45D6290712DD41D09C34DEDAD9AF8CC9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4DB9F5F35D4144C9BD1B6322A5C541A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Motion of the government</header><text>Upon motion</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F813983E36540D18EF7F28EAF85207D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBA674ACDA9A42799BE82C323D4ADC94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HBF28EB0737A047C291E8CCFE79C97D97" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H3895A5B181FD4096B11EDD9AC7C759D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Motion of a party or the court</header><text>The Court, sua sponte, or on the motion of a party, shall have the authority to impose a sentence below a level established by statute as a minimum sentence if the defendant shows that—</text> <subparagraph id="H1BD6EF180C3545208EAB27B8CE991CC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the defendant did not provide substantial assistance described in paragraph (1) based on a reasonable fear of serious bodily injury (as such term is defined in section 113) to the defendant, an intimate partner, child, or other family member of the defendant;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD33EA878ECCB416A8D9F4B678941F902"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the prosecution fails to demonstrate that the defendant has useful information that could be used by the Government in the investigation or prosecution of another person who has committed an offense; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0659AEBEB97E4681960F3C5F5040C60C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the defendant has provided substantial assistance described in paragraph (1), but the Government has not made a motion under such paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30542D8F97CA4612AFF7B26AA416E560"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sentencing guidelines</header><text>A sentence under paragraph (1) or (2) shall be imposed in accordance with the guidelines and policy statements issued by the Sentencing Commission pursuant to section 994 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAD75707BCD6F494AB5CC03DBDAC9419B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Counterfeit controlled substances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H8F31C2CB84E84111B88DB88BC2DCCE46" style="USC">
<subsection id="H95034838151C42D1A6CA90125B2193EC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of a person who conspires to commit an offense under this title, the type and quantity of the controlled or counterfeit substance for the offense that was the object of the conspiracy shall be the type and quantity involved in—</text> <paragraph id="HCCD768EB17D842E9A58624EE797B70D3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant’s own unlawful acts; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAEBD6C5EA01743199C58E224AB83F3C0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any unlawful act of a co-conspirator that—</text> <subparagraph id="H813EF23179AE4A83A1F82E412C526473" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the defendant agreed to jointly undertake;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6512F95148634CF18C42F396762E3C6C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was in furtherance of that unlawful act the defendant agreed to jointly undertake; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93970711FAE544A0ABFC7D38E5E6FACE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was known to and intended by the defendant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HBEA677655B664AFA861C272D45B6B6AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Counterfeit controlled substances import and export</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1010 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960">21 U.S.C. 960</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H501F964F93104D55BE343A695AAAF0F6" style="USC"> <subsection id="H3D3DAF2F7AE94663A4AEED2B3C53445A" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><text>In the case of a person who conspires to commit an offense under this title, the type and quantity of the controlled or counterfeit substance for the offense that was the object of the conspiracy shall be the type and quantity involved in—</text>
<paragraph id="H78D481004AA34DC28C7006FEDE7C534D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant’s own unlawful acts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95201B38190B4B4C85B705E0AC357890" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any unlawful act of a co-conspirator that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4CF6CED6473D4A958472AE98661AAD73" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the defendant agreed to jointly undertake;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76F5E3799874464FB72C54CA173B25D9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was in furtherance of that unlawful act the defendant agreed to jointly undertake; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H58019F9A6C69443284A8E89F5BF42753" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was known to and intended by the defendant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H0615FBC1B25240F796AA1B9AD2E82320"><enum>403.</enum><header>Clarifying culpability at sentencing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3661 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H382B6362C6AC402286BCD3BBB0727ED5" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>, except that such a court may not consider, except for purposes of mitigating a sentence—</text> <paragraph id="H807B2FBADA5645518972F38F3F1D3724"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any act with respect to which the person was criminally charged and adjudicated not guilty after trial in a Federal, State, or Tribal, court, or in the case of a juvenile an act that was charged and for which the juvenile was found not responsible after a juvenile adjudication hearing; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5A0D75D2056E4E3A9083BA5444B94D2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any act underlying a criminal charge or juvenile information that was dismissed in a Federal court upon a motion for acquittal under rule 29 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, or in a State or Tribal court upon a motion for acquittal or an analogous motion under the applicable State rule of criminal procedure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title> <title id="H759E8D01C1ED458090090748B5A0F424"><enum>V</enum><header>GENDER-RESPONSIVE AND TRAUMA-INFORMED IMPOSITION OF A SENTENCE</header> <section id="H35C7BC7DA516497880B856FC5E770792"><enum>501.</enum><header>Gender and trauma-informed sentencing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3553 of title 18, United States Code, is amended in subsection (a)(2)—</text>
<paragraph id="H2628547616314B7D89E511B2DFD53354"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1985E4F111E4EF2BE631E2EAE61263F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (D) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H2F4AACF50805466197C006A4E7B87299" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="HA1D9EB497CA942FE9393770E177E7F63"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to reflect any mitigation on behalf of the defendant, including any history of trauma, substance use, or medical and mental health disorders; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96B87FC8EEB14F3AB44A666BB64B7E44"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to provide the defendant with gender-responsive needed educational or vocational training, medical care, trauma-informed mental health care, or other correctional treatment in the most effective manner;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title>
<title id="H7B6CCC606C354B9BBAC12BB05CEA636E"><enum>VI</enum><header>GENDER-RESPONSIVE PRISON REFORM</header>
<section id="HBB8E28D543274CE8A673682536115F46"><enum>601.</enum><header>Health care needs of incarcerated women in the Bureau of Prisons</header>
<subsection id="HA909BAEB83354F3AB3265341B4FE30C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons, in consultation with the Administrator of the Women and Special Populations Branch, shall ensure that all incarcerated women have access to basic standards of health care specific to their needs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H568F63E49C0C4553913B176142D6F894"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Obstetrics and gynecology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that all incarcerated persons in need of obstetric or gynecological care have access to a licensed medical professional with specialized training in such care, which shall include, in addition to any medical treatment provided by law and Bureau of Prisons policy—</text>
<paragraph id="HCD2F83C54FB046759316BE85EA0798E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a screening upon intake into the Bureau of Prisons, and annual screening thereafter, that shall include screening for high-risk factors as provided under subsection (c);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE2037BE20A844BCB557145B98D45062"><enum>(2)</enum><text>testing for Hepatitis A, B, and C;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD1ED738716CB4271AAEB66DCD231A2F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>tuberculosis skin testing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBFCE40780E44194A8565CDCA7C90059"><enum>(4)</enum><text>testing for sexually transmitted infections, which shall include chlamydia, gonorrhea, syphilis, and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), and may include testing for other infections if symptoms present;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFE3C3DA6681943D9814F13AD182382F5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a breast examination screening no less frequently than recommended by medical professionals adhering to guidelines published by the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96F62754BF1142A19614DD824357B49B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a pelvic examination to include a Pap smear and testing for human papillomavirus (HPV) no less than every three years, but within 48 hours if medical history or symptoms require, with the option of being accompanied by a trained medical chaperone during this examination.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0F12151871D64FF6B34898EBF826C31C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Human papillomavirus vaccine for juveniles</header><text>The Director shall amend Bureau of Prisons policy for human papillomavirus screening and vaccination to include access for juvenile justice-involved individuals.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H436231E2B2D94B13B28D388467C6B959"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Dental care</header><text>The Director shall ensure that dental care for incarcerated persons complies with the standards developed by the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), Standards Administration Department, and not later than one year after enactment of this section, the Director, in consultation with the Chief of Dental Programs shall report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives and the Subcommittees on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, and such report shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H21FCD4EB34E7414A93CB550D6F37C719"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of incarcerated persons who have requested dental care, disaggregated by race and gender;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C386F8A9F064CEC9439C94E1DE2D45F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of incarcerated persons who have received dental care, disaggregated by race and gender;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5FACC6C246704AA58D3EBB90C185E10A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of incarcerated persons who are on waitlists for dental care disaggregated by race and gender; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53EE108703A34F3D804357A2E3049733"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of incarcerated persons who have been refused requested dental care, disaggregated by race and gender, and the reasons for such refusals.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1B068D28F0B24307B69C347FE29D6064"><enum>(e)</enum><header>High-Risk incarcerated person healthcare</header><text>Female incarcerated persons who present with any high-risk factors during any screening, shall be provided with care as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H99CEFFC91B104C5195AFBA40E66AAA37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Screening for bone density in postmenopausal persons younger than 65 years if any of the following risk factors are noted:</text>
<subparagraph id="H7672F0E5E9DC441A9A3A5C77B27EF6DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Medical history of a fragility fracture.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBD56CC9CF2547CF90672F250EDEBDD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Body weight less than 127 pounds.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H17F607636841461BBD1EDC6014CADF5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Medical causes of bone loss (medications or diseases).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H947188ECDDD34CC9A4A8A1E2907D8A88"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Parental medical history of hip fracture.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1B809D61AC8D46E785F5D81C0AA1ADCF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Current smoker.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FAE74E677DF49FCBA53786ED07F4482"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Alcoholism.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H07A7858FB82E489A95321A1EE1DC50B4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Rheumatoid arthritis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87F035D03841424C88A81F04526AD502"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For incarcerated persons with a medical history of preeclampsia who gave birth less than 37<fraction>0/7</fraction> weeks of gestation, or who have a medical history of recurrent preeclampsia, a yearly assessment of blood pressure, lipids, fasting blood glucose, and body mass index.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE75E43D71EAE44B8AB5862248947BF2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Screening for colorectal cancer for incarcerated persons who—</text> <subparagraph id="H524614635391449191D04CB7C18EF911"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are age 50 and above;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA5ED9C94CF254B2E80CA365E37207476"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a first-degree relative younger than age 60 or two or more first-degree relatives of any age who have had colorectal cancer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C45024FC2D44EC2A014886E8EBE7938"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have a family history of familial adenomatous polyposis or hereditary nonpolyposis colon cancer; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H411E5F9173EE459999F2D5F2BF6581F4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>have a history of colorectal cancer, adenomatous polyps, inflammatory bowel disease, chronic ulcerative colitis, or Crohn’s disease.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAB3218ECBDB49FE9705A495F6AD19C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Diabetes testing for incarcerated persons who—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFF858C1B211749B5A9B61B8627E559E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are overweight or obese;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4063D61B38D4162B6417C33AE8912CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">every three years for any incarcerated person who has delivered a baby weighing 9 pounds or more, or was diagnosed with gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) and normal postpartum screening test results;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H203A1F1BBB214C28BD46DC9C08E08B5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have been diagnosed with hypertension or are on therapy for hypertension;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H032DBB6587D84ACF8791CC102875E549"><enum>(D)</enum><text>have been diagnosed with a high cholesterol level or a high triglyceride level;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1DBAA81E6235457DBB0557EC3498CA3C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>have been diagnosed with polycystic ovary syndrome;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3A52875057840FFA27EDAD820D932B8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>have other clinical conditions associated with insulin resistance; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAC169544D5DD4CF6A23ABDE7F09309ED"><enum>(G)</enum><text>have a history of cardiovascular disease.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F7A7266E5334920AB4E3298E271EAE1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Hemoglobin level assessments for incarcerated persons who have a history of excessive menstrual flow.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6C93F01FFDC943EAB0BBE3F34A971E15"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Lipid profile assessments for incarcerated persons who—</text> <subparagraph id="H982783E7F5B440BFBFCED56A97AB5703"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a family history suggestive of familial hyperlipidemia;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H033A4F97BE1D433AB06D24EDDAE0CEDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a family history of premature cardiovascular disease;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB1F6D597DA2406FB156CEB5F024A08A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have a previous personal history of coronary heart disease or noncoronary atherosclerosis, or abdominal aortic aneurysm, peripheral artery disease, or carotid artery stenosis;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0CD7D99011464AAFA7EA11AF6230BA81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are obese;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DD2AE381D98446283C8721290A0A046"><enum>(E)</enum><text>have a personal or family history of peripheral vascular disease;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6A382C55A3F74E12A0F40B31998B8DAB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>have diabetes mellitus;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H855ED69851CB4C2E949118F293C84F4C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>have multiple coronary heart disease risk factors, such as tobacco use and hypertension; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H374542E80EFD4B9289FC5A8BFBB7802A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an annual lipid assessment for female incarcerated persons who have a medical history of preeclampsia who gave birth preterm, or who have a medical history of recurrent preeclampsia.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47650FE59C37439580E61A3E46A9BC1F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A mammography and triple negative breast cancer screening for incarcerated persons who—</text>
<subparagraph id="H889F3A9D715A4BDAAB28F159CC2ADCB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have had breast cancer or who have a first-degree relative or multiple other relatives who have a history of premenopausal breast or breast and ovarian cancers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA389748DEA7045BC87D41B3315A76976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have tested positive for BRCA1 or BRCA2 mutations;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H36A88386785F4311940BE4DD3AAF6A61"><enum>(C)</enum><text>received thoracic irradiation, a typically as a treatment for lymphoma, between the ages of 10 and 30; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE393A8C7CC6F489A8AE64A5D1349A00B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>have a personal history of high-risk breast biopsy results, including atypical hyperplasia and lobular carcinoma in situ.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2CC66D85B284EBC904409D4CAC1A519"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Thyroid-stimulating hormone testing for female incarcerated persons with a strong family history of thyroid disease or autoimmune disease.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F84B4142997476687E978F82BE717FC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Screening and appropriate treatment for incarcerated persons with diagnosis of sickle cell anemia.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H13CA8E4335C44FB2A6CF24272F2DCFC2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Contraceptive case</header><text>The Director shall ensure access to contraceptive care for an incarcerated person if determined to be medically recommended by a licensed obstetrician-gynecologist.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7B8CEE4CE3A94AD7BACCDB04F0E61EB0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>All medical reports and health records drafted or stored within the Bureau of Prisons may not be exchanged, transferred, or used for the purpose of any criminal investigation or prosecution federally, or under the laws of any State, local or Tribal government.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H894B5BA8997644249700D5E559E8B5C4"><enum>602.</enum><header>Trauma-informed care</header>
<subsection id="HB12743DA11A640C39337519E67DF9FB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons, in collaboration with the Bureau of Prisons Health Services Department, the Bureau of Prisons Women and Special Populations Branch, and the Department of Health &amp; Human Services, shall develop and implement training for Bureau of Prisons officers and employees that complies with national standards on trauma-informed care, and which shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HE691EF26E2784FB7A0E2144E41AFDB51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognition of the impact of trauma on multiple areas of life and different paths to recovery;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8A42F31A229D4576B1279F589367B750"><enum>(2)</enum><text>awareness of the signs and symptoms of trauma, and methods to respond to trauma;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7022E213D6644C01ABFC1A1F3EF62F8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>training on revised policies and practices that account for and are sensitive to potential trauma histories;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEFFA066E2D234BA9AED04E7578BDACAC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>methods to prevent retraumatization; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB664113DC68D4AA9A17714AB61D6705F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>awareness of the high rates of trauma among incarcerated persons and the higher rates of trauma among female incarcerated persons, and the causes of such trauma.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE3754C18B9DA4388B4F2E204923FC863"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trauma screening</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons, in collaboration with the Bureau of Prisons Health Services Department, the Bureau of Prisons Women and Special Populations Branch, and the Department of Health &amp; Human Services, shall develop and implement a trauma-screening program upon intake of all incarcerated persons into the Bureau of Prisons. Such screening shall also be incorporated into the periodic assessments of incarcerated persons under section 101 and section 102 of the First Step Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H50C7FDD2117B4FD6AA80DC71A8A535A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Trauma-Informed therapy and counseling</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons, in collaboration with the Bureau of Prisons Health Services Department, the Bureau of Prisons Women and Special Populations Branch, and the Department of Health &amp; Human Services, shall create trauma, and posttraumatic stress disorder, counseling and trauma-informed support programs for incarcerated persons who have experienced trauma, which programs shall be administered by a licensed mental health professional, and shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H6F0EF3FFAAF14E76BB4A777C9636A6A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assistance with methods to cope with trauma, including the development of safety plans and strategies for dealing with triggers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF5DE648CC4E441E815F6DE8A14091E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>programs and therapy modalities that directly address trauma within incarcerated populations, which may include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H83448533F25B49638E383D5CA87D0652"><enum>(A)</enum><text>programs designed for the treatment of individuals with co-occurring post-traumatic stress disorder and substance use symptoms;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4920A1B8585F47B9AC8CAE97913EA69E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>group intervention programs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H226925C94FBC4148AF332D35A4FE65E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individual counseling;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0022A0AA66664902B6A2A3A693F30074"><enum>(D)</enum><text>gender-responsive programs for female trauma survivors;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBB40CE6BA25F4325BEBB9BF214D9F9CE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>programs designed for trauma survivors who have severe mental health disorders;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D997403E4AF4EF680D497A6366700F6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Prolonged Exposure Therapy;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9FC7C0A97B7D4BC19DC578B7BCD2D289"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Eye Movement Desensitization and Reprocessing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB30C8F0EFEC4E3FA5E7C4F9A547018D"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">peer-to-peer support programming; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H79C1096DD8794DC4814734E3636AC4A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any other evidence-based trauma-informed and gender-responsive treatment or therapy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBCC09C6EA61240B0BE4F899856D28C92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this title, and annually thereafter, the Bureau of Justice Statistics shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives and the Subcommittees on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives that contains the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HF9DD8F7400FB4BA499EE5A401515B798"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of incarcerated persons screened for trauma exposure under this title, and the number of incarcerated persons presenting with a history of exposure to trauma at intake and upon reassessment, including demographic percentages by age, race, and gender.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41D1D1DECD7C438ABA1BFCD80FC72FED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The specific trauma-informed counseling and treatment programs developed under subsection (c).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5FA6D0B46F47427B90366E12877A1DA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of incarcerated persons who participate in each trauma-informed counseling and treatment program developed under subsection (c), including demographic percentages by age, race, and gender.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08570DFFFC304C54A035218F0EE38AEB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of incarcerated persons on a waitlist for such program developed under subsection (c), including demographic percentages by age, race, and gender.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall promptly respond to requests from the Bureau of Justice Statistics for access to Bureau of Prisons facilities, personnel, and information, in the completion of this report.</continuation-text></subsection></section>
<section id="H8BA2565F26794D64B0F27F4D06C903E6"><enum>603.</enum><header>Trauma-informed and gender-responsive training and staffing</header>
<subsection id="HA58F7335706842EAB3B5ED7A32F7DD1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gender-Responsive training</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons, in collaboration with the Bureau of Prisons Health Services Department, the Bureau of Prisons Women and Special Populations Branch, and the Department of Health &amp; Human Services, shall develop and implement gender-responsive training for Bureau of Prisons officers and employees which shall include incorporating gender-responsive components to all existing training for all correctional officers and employees, and shall include separate training on the unique needs of incarcerated women for all correctional officers and employees in facilities that house women and female juveniles, and all such trainings shall include training on—</text> <paragraph id="HD1CB343478D6434598BB6B3F936DCEE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">common characteristics of female incarcerated persons, including data on the numbers of women in Bureau of Prisons custody, and generally the race, charges, age, and common sentences of women in the legal system;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H16C46A9E03464A98BC831DEA22BCB38F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasons why women enter the legal system, and gender-responsive policy and practice that target women’s pathways to criminality by providing effective interventions that address the intersecting issues of substance abuse, trauma, mental health, and economic marginality;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BD13D444DD14190855EDB5356C18031"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the high rates of trauma that justice involved women are exposed to;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4DD2004A1DC940F3827213686A0116BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the high rates of mental health diagnosis among women justice-involved individuals;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC1AF27E4C964E0A8DA2D1BA37AA9675"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the menstrual needs, general health, and reproductive health care needs, of women;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9ECFE6CD8CD640A8A73A77A18D74AAC2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the high rates of motherhood amongst female incarcerated persons, and their ongoing roles as mothers and community members; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CF9D373689848DAB3137AF63C02956C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the low risk to public safety created by the typical offenses committed by justice-involved women.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEA72573E5F004E4AAD93D6DC5CEBF45C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staffing</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall ensure that correctional employees dedicated to the Women And Special Populations Branch be—</text> <paragraph id="H238D6111CAA445CB9465369DF3FB6479"><enum>(1)</enum><text>sufficient to ensure consistent, professional supervision of female incarcerated persons;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB497FEF29B9443849DECA422B67FA2C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sufficient to ensure proper gender-responsive implementation of Bureau of Prisons polices and legislative mandates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1353100F9BF4CA38A7B89879797DE7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sufficient to properly evaluate programming needs, develop, and administer programs for all eligible female incarcerated persons;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H50FE0302559E4965A1A666A87C07284E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>sufficient to ensure that incarcerated women in the Bureau of Prisons are healthy and safe from harm; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95EC6264822F486891D620CE0BBE6CB1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall not be less than twelve full time employees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H1D31110A264447CB8410B5C62C296BF8"><enum>604.</enum><header>Improving the Bureau of Prisons Resolve Trauma Therapy Program</header>
<subsection id="H6551A355ED0F47D5A6522D8F6B25EC0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Generally</header><text>The Director shall ensure that the Resolve Trauma Therapy Program is offered at all institutions that house female incarcerated persons, and that all female incarcerated persons who seek treatment through the Resolve Trauma Therapy Program have access to such program beginning during the first twelve months of the incarcerated person’s sentence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0F4A254E0DE34468B094BD4614DAC32F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Resolve program prerequisite notice and access</header><text>The Director shall ensure that all female incarcerated persons are provided notice of the Resolve Program and the prerequisites for admittance into the program. Any such prerequisites, which may include a Trauma in Life seminar and psychological screening test, shall be offered to all female incarcerated persons to begin within 60 days of intake into the Bureau of Prisons.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H48E3EFE8F8A34475A5618241DF87F7EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Resolve program staffing</header><text>The Director shall ensure that sufficient correctional employees are employed at each facility that houses female incarcerated persons, in order to comply with this section, which shall include, at minimum, one Resolve Coordinator at each location and one Treatment Specialist, but may include any number of correctional employees as needed.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H19D27A1FC6D84727BD62C2ACFE61AEF2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Spanish language resolve program</header><text>The Director shall ensure that the Resolve Program is offered in Spanish and accessible for all Spanish-speaking female incarcerated persons.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H62D878F4141B4B4E8BEBF39F36BC12AE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this title, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives and the Subcommittees on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives that contains the following:</text> <paragraph id="H41B26B01921F49A6AF46D9C3CA880382"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of female incarcerated persons who complete the Trauma in Life seminar and psychological screening test prerequisites for access to the Resolve Program, and whether each incarcerated person began such Resolve Program prerequisites within 60 days of intake into the Bureau of Prisons, and if not within 60 days of intake when they began program prerequisites.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H753301B245754ADDADE61E6E3DFF4F61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of female incarcerated persons who complete the Resolve Program, annually, and whether such program participation began within 1 year of intake into the Bureau of Prisons, and if not, how soon such program participation began and was completed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C2DA225B8B345CF879131A728CF5693"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of individuals on waitlists, if any, for Resolve Program access.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB1A90EEF1E75425C951D8A855D01F5AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of full-time correctional employees dedicated to work within the Resolve Program and vacancies during the previous calendar year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H456BDDD8ADBC43099C7B0CD84BA1F1B9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of female incarcerated persons who complete the Resolve Program in Spanish, and the number of Spanish-speaking female incarcerated persons who are on waitlists for program access.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F44BA4D3B2543C3A08FE41077E8EBB5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number of female incarcerated persons who qualify for Resolve Program access but were not afforded participation in the program before release.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD3B17907D3654FA484CC670E5C3BAC9F"><enum>605.</enum><header>Gender-responsive programs in the Bureau of Prisons</header> <subsection id="HB6FB44139A314FCF8B921F797C568E4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Generally</header><text>The Director, in consultation with the Director of the Women and Special Populations Branch, shall ensure that all incarcerated person programs and services are gender-responsive and all programs shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H028926F1B3FD4C9C820E6F6CEF9E7964"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the national profile of women who enter the legal system, which is most often disproportionately women of color, and women who are likely to have been convicted of a drug or drug-related offense, have fragmented family histories, with other family members also involved with the legal system, are survivors of physical and/or sexual abuse as children and adults, have significant substance abuse problems, have multiple physical and mental health problems, are mothers and legal guardians of minor children, and have limited vocational training and sporadic work histories;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8330C4F097EF445295743A5CDA901934"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be evidence-based, and responsive to data concerning the distinguishing aspects of different genders of justice-involved individuals;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36F31EC4AD22463B89E3D65B03F2A52C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>address substance misuse, trauma, and mental health issues through comprehensive, integrated, services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09D78EE42817479FAE465AA048DCE65D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide opportunities through education and training to provide women with opportunities to improve socioeconomic conditions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE0E2209E8CA84B5ABF01F2A0975A3266"><enum>(5)</enum><text>have a relational component wherever possible, and goals to promote healthy connections to children, family, significant others, and the community;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H626ABB4744AE4A57A3F5971EAA25C610"><enum>(6)</enum><text>consider the pattern of emotional, physical, and sexual abuse that many female justice-involved individuals have experienced, and mitigate against an abusive environment and traumatization; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE31EF702EDCF49D7B0FAC83B6D9AEB10"><enum>(7)</enum><text>be otherwise gender-responsive based on empirical evidence and research.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2F7135FD45EE42E08ECEAB115C50F7C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ensuring first step act early release programs are gender-Responsive</header><text>Section 3635(3) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HD7E8EA3D100C484294C78CDFEC0F6372"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6084ADC038EC49D5995A60258B775EC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1C1AB3D7FEE0467392BDA7887B21A613"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting the following after subparagraph (B):</text> <quoted-block id="H1200C5658493476F9A5B0AC1E66D9C6F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD01D3BD79271418AAC807894927EA409"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are gender-responsive, in compliance with section 5 of title VI of the Gender-Informed Justice Act; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H8A46DC114FB64E95B646AB624C3A1B3B"><enum>606.</enum><header>Gender-responsive prison conditions</header>
<subsection id="HD2738C82525E4C038A132D079346E681"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Generally</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall ensure all institutions that house female incarcerated persons maintain the same minimum standard of care and conditions as institutions that house male incarcerated persons. Lack of resources shall not be sufficient reason for failing to meet minimum standards of treatment or conditions where such failure constitutes a violation of incarcerated persons’ constitutional or statutory rights.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB51CC9CE106441B96D1E86D963EB18C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum standard of conditions</header><text>The term <term>standard of conditions</term> means the provision of adequate care and treatment in compliance with the United States Constitution and laws of the United States, and shall at minimum include—</text>
<paragraph id="H98F78BDE1D2F484999C862736919DA2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>safe and orderly conditions in all correctional institutions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC87448F9110C4CF6A0B8C17665FC8BE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a goal to prepare prisoners to live law-abiding lives upon release, and to facilitate prisoners’ reintegration into free society by implementing appropriate conditions of confinement and by sustained planning for such reintegration;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H99BE76C9C35844DB85125D6212BD252B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protection of incarcerated persons from harm, with restrictions placed on incarcerated persons only that are necessary and proportionate to the legitimate objectives for which those restrictions are imposed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53BCF21F0EBD41BE82A5D08D1DBFEAA3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a respect of the human rights and dignity of incarcerated persons, with no incarcerated person being subjected to cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or conditions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD4AC4EF3E4584564A645B32785D69326"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for a convicted individual, loss of liberty and separation from society should be the sole punishments imposed by imprisonment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DFFC095F6D04046A330076E2B1555D8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>appropriate levels of correctional officers and employees;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0C3444B943BE4595A808AC5212243D1C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>implementation of internal processes for continually assessing and improving each correctional facility;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDC1FA75AD28411992C6F13AD7A2AEF2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>humane and healthful living conditions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB4482D15F932480F8C2F704118B36CF3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>necessary health care;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE67EE31D9D444C15835581C84A1DC2A8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>freedom from staff harassment and invidious discrimination;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE5C57B7D4B8C4A0A806D8049D5E66471"><enum>(11)</enum><text>freedom of religion and substantial freedom of expression;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD66C79D464FD4893A974A94B79D392A9"><enum>(12)</enum><text>equal conditions conducive to maintaining healthy relationships with families;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE3584AED812140E18D80B520F1A1E0D3"><enum>(13)</enum><text>equal opportunities to participate in constructive activity and rehabilitative programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19E726F6C235417CB456ED8CC23F4E68"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to gender-responsive and comprehensive community-based reentry programs and planning, including family reunification legal clinics within correctional facilities where present;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C0172F4E2224C668594C60E173EC75D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>all Bureau of Prisons physical facilities shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9935B07670FE4ED691B3107665DF68D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be adequate to protect and promote the health and safety of incarcerated persons and staff;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6A8F1A0108E84944A7C0BF0DA8653C3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be clean and well-maintained;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A9D522B6E46471FBB84D387F18BF4F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include appropriate housing, laundry, health care, food service, visitation, recreation, education, and program space;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H96A3F39E5FAB4F47BF1A6F1F24A5F10B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>have appropriate heating and ventilation systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB22DBB79172E47ADAC28D8B4F587622E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not deprive incarcerated people or staff of natural light, of light sufficient to permit reading throughout prisoners’ housing areas, and of reasonable darkness during the sleeping hours;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2E61E4E55E3F4D1A90C237142E786A29"><enum>(F)</enum><text>be free from tobacco smoke and excessive noise;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E3BAEEB918C4FCEA06989A53BAC1B50"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow unrestricted access for incarcerated people to potable drinking water and to adequate, clean, reasonably private, and functioning toilets and washbasins; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H58582C9098D24AEF84BFBF388084CAD4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>comply with health, safety, and building codes, subject to regular inspection;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC93F440D483D42A9A022CA165A9ED7CF"><enum>(16)</enum><text>all Bureau of Prisons facility housing conditions shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7EAE6B927556491193568EDFEBC6D526"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include living quarters of adequate size, with single-occupancy cells as the preferred form of housing, but facilities that must use multiple-person living quarters should provide sufficient staffing, supervision, and personal space to ensure safety for persons and security for their belongings, and to ensure that all living quarters and personal hygiene areas are designed to facilitate adequate and appropriate supervision of incarcerated persons and to allow such persons privacy consistent with their security classification;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3395969E760D44768CF2CFB0C96CBC0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at a minimum, include a bed and mattress off the floor for each incarcerated person, a writing area and seating, an individual secure storage compartment sufficient in size to hold personal belongings and legal papers, a source of natural light, and light sufficient to permit reading; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2A02A022A4834B27B75BFB887024F936"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sufficient access to showers at an appropriate temperature to enable each incarcerated person to shower as frequently as necessary, and allowing for gender appropriate separation, to maintain general hygiene;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H664C1C8F2C364E2EBF6368328F82EFFB"><enum>(17)</enum><text>living quarters and associated common areas shall be maintained in a sanitary condition;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA8F0E5C327F6419D9EFA65479F51FE0F"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">correctional authorities should provide incarcerated people with clean, appropriately sized clothing suited to the season and facility temperature and to the incarcerated person’s work assignment and gender identity, in quantities sufficient to allow for a daily change of clothing and permitting incarcerated persons opportunities to mend and machine launder their clothing if the facility does not provide these services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B16CFE5A2D44B9D924ADB0938D3F8EE"><enum>(19)</enum><text>to the extent practicable and consistent with safety concerns, correctional authorities should minimize the periods during the day in which prisoners are required to remain in their cells;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H645C7E00DE914350835A1A06FC10CA4E"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incarcerated persons shall be provided daily opportunities for significant out-of-cell time and for recreation at appropriate hours that allows them to maintain physical health and, for incarcerated persons not otherwise prohibited by specific health or safety concerns, to socialize with other incarcerated persons, and at minimum all incarcerated persons shall be offered the opportunity for at least one hour per day of exercise, in the open air if the weather permits; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CB45261BED645A6922E15447E1DEFE3"><enum>(21)</enum><text>incarcerated persons should be permitted, whenever practicable, to eat in a congregate setting, whether that is a specialized room or a housing area dayroom, absent an individualized decision that a congregate setting is inappropriate for a particular individual, and incarcerated persons shall be allowed an adequate time to eat each meal.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H27B0EFBDC7124A86AD27C6C53BA7AF4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>incarcerated person conditions during menstruation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in consultation with the Director of the Women and Special Populations Branch, shall ensure that incarcerated persons during the time of menstruation are treated with dignity and respect, and that such incarcerated persons are given appropriate medical and hygienic care, including as necessary for pain relief. This shall include free and adequate supply of menstrual materials as well as sufficient access to toilet paper.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD6A390EA733046CF89573F3363FC6B59"><enum>607.</enum><header>Gender-specific posts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that the assignment of female staff at locations in female institutions where incarcerated person searches are common, such that Bureau of Prisons is in compliance with the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 without requiring female Correctional Officers to leave other assigned posts.</text></section>
<section id="H07E5A01CCBEA4EE6AE281381E804AAF3"><enum>608.</enum><header>Female incarcerated person nutritional standards</header>
<subsection id="H6A3A04D400D640F38E2AB616103A9A93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nutritional standards for female incarcerated persons</header><text>The Director shall revise the Bureau of Prisons standards for nutrition to ensure they are gender-specific, and that women receive a healthy diet consistent with national dietary guidelines for women.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6121506943C847838C5ACBD39201F086"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nutraloaf prohibited</header><text>The Director shall ensure that food quantity, type, or the prohibition of food, shall never be used as a means of discipline, and the Bureau of Prisons shall never provide as meals to incarcerated persons <quote>Nutraloaf</quote>, ground up leftovers, or any similar meal.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE7EF8CFB78024C759CBF8CB4FB27FE4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pregnant and lactating incarcerated persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For pregnant and lactating incarcerated persons nutrition standards shall reflect the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEFB8C9CA880B47319FEE43409B80F88C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Access to at least 64–96 ounces of fluid per day.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H76093B8248FE476FA8F4CB7719E2EDD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Access to appropriate dietary supplements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D687404D74A40D8987686007E50D46C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Caloric supplementation as medically appropriate not from processed meats associated with listeriosis.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H953E88D802F44BC08DA65AF04383779E"><enum>609.</enum><header>Gender-responsive discipline policies</header>
<subsection id="HCE6774E8A5FE4C5D9FB1E6F2886F196F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Generally</header><text>The Director, in consultation with the Director of the Women and Special Populations Branch, the Director of the Health Services Division, and in consultation with experts in correctional standards for gender-responsive sanctions, shall develop gender-responsive policies for discipline, which shall—</text> <paragraph id="H1BE2FD8BB355439B95462A3A177E5897"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include a review of the existing Bureau of Prisons’ discipline and sanctions policies to evaluate where policies are not gender-responsive, and to include gender-responsive mission statements and goals and revise all policies and standards to be gender-responsive;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9E73C0B80E07461BBF05350ADFAEADA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that revised policies focus on safety, motivation of incarcerated person behavior, and incarcerated person self-management, including through methods to teach incarcerated persons alternatives to rule violating behaviors before such behaviors are displayed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A66B0E2AFD14C7A9364E7A0853466FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include an understanding of gender-based peer dynamics and relationships;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE86C6C26F0CD45E9BE65C968570368CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledge trauma, and how many rule violating behaviors have roots in traumatic experiences;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C783C5B25A14EC2A5FCD48047FDB089"><enum>(5)</enum><text>address gender-responsive and trauma-informed approaches with female incarcerated persons;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63571494A58142038C82BBD5E1751079"><enum>(6)</enum><text>review common incarcerated person violation behavior based on gender, and determine what sanctions and supports are available to respond to the range of common behaviors, based on gender;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DFE03AF66D24ADDA1CC23DD8C410496"><enum>(7)</enum><text>determine which sanctions can be reduced or eliminated based on research and best practices, and which sanctions can be added to achieve better outcomes with female incarcerated persons, with a focus on sanctions that reinforce motivation and rehabilitation rather than a punitive response; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H214B010677A74D61A2790F131FE1A232"><enum>(8)</enum><text>eliminate the use of extremely punitive sanctions, including shackling and segregated housing, except in circumstances when an incarcerated person presents a severe danger to other staff or incarcerated persons, and create gender-responsive policies for the use of such sanctions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H29FADC78EFD44AF197A1ADD8E2754B82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Visitation as a disciplinary tool</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that loss of visitation privileges, including in-person, video, electronic, phone, and physical mail opportunities, is reserved as a sanction in only high and greatest severity level offenses by incarcerated persons.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD0CF7294935D48E9BE3EFE6FFF3700D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Discipline report</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this title, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives that contains the following information for the previous calendar year:</text> <paragraph id="H3479846937C34E8D91F52825BF49EDC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of incarcerated persons who are sanctioned for prohibited acts, disaggregated by race, gender, and age.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD9FE4A546D6B4147A1FE37B3A0A61FA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of incarcerated persons who are sanctioned for greatest severity level offenses, high severity level offenses, moderate severity level offenses, low severity level offenses, disaggregated by race, gender, and age.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E91333F63F64ED0919754F11A33BAB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of incarcerated persons who lose good conduct time as a sanction, the reason for loss of good conduct time, and the amount of good conduct time lost, disaggregated by race, gender, and age.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H15AA958C89C946659763E026CE51C4A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The type of sanctions imposed for all greatest level severity offenses, disaggregated by race, gender, and age of the incarcerated person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB867A8474914778B758F78C949B3B49"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The type of sanctions imposed for all high level severity offenses, disaggregated by race, gender, and age of the incarcerated person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1E3B1FD1C4C04D7CB034DE8D662D574C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The type of sanctions imposed for all moderate level severity offenses, disaggregated by race, gender, and age of the incarcerated person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H521BA151CCB64DD598BA2666FDBA6611"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The type of sanctions imposed for all low level severity offenses, disaggregated by race, gender, and age of the incarcerated person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0A5373959FCA4A23BA81CD6D19C50B99"><enum>(8)</enum><text>All sanctions imposed on mentally ill incarcerated persons, disaggregated by race, gender, and age of the incarcerated person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE05F7A24FD664AF5B9B2F77DBBE419AC"><enum>610.</enum><header>Expanding access to the Mothers and Infants Nurturing Together Program and the Residential Parenting Program</header> <subsection id="HFEB40B6BD123494C8BBAFDC1143EE21F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Director shall ensure that every correctional officer and employee, and every female incarcerated person admitted into the Bureau of Prisons, is given notice of the Washington State Department of Corrections’ Residential Parenting Program and the Mothers and Infants Nurturing Together Program, and of the eligibility requirements for each program.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0CE2CEFE48A74D51B645BDB5016CABC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall revise eligibility requirements for the Residential Parenting Program and the Mothers and Infants Nurturing Together Program to ensure that all incarcerated persons who have given birth while in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons have access to both programs, except in limited circumstances where the female incarcerated person presents a risk of danger to herself or others, and without regard to citizenship status or criminal charge.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2A8EEC19B6C04C27852E4DD64C9A0921"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of exclusions</header><text>In the case of a female incarcerated person who has been pregnant or given birth while in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons, and has been excluded from participation in the Washington State Department of Corrections’ Residential Parenting Program and the Mothers and Infants Nurturing Together Program eligibility, such exclusion shall be reviewed by the Director of the Women and Special Populations Branch, or the Director’s designee who must be a licensed psychologist.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H93965BDB66B942B4B6E07D6CA27C0234"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this title, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives and the Subcommittees on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives that contains the following information about the Washington State Department of Corrections’ Residential Parenting Program and the Mothers and Infants Nurturing Together Program:</text> <paragraph id="H71786195DAF447E1AD40067D618018D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of women who have been pregnant or given birth while in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4BD995ADA39049EA9DF5BCE4D63996D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of women who participate in the Washington State Department of Corrections’ Residential Parenting Program and the Mothers and Infants Nurturing Together Program, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HC92F12B6B01B46809BC4DDD457781E75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of participants who start each program; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8BE6CCDA45EA46599B3232AE4BF62A21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of participants who complete each program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2762810CA6BF43B3B911C1B492B3D0D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For all incarcerated persons who enter each program and do not complete each program, the reasons for failure to complete the program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H45E18FEA8C234561A5114BB54D0578AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of available, unused program participation incarcerated person spaces.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D13DC21666F4409B32468ADB33DD724"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of female incarcerated persons who have been pregnant or given birth while in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons who have been excluded from participation in the programs by the Bureau of Prisons or personal preference, and the reasons for such exclusion.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H6F71D1D193AE4A9B9D3DF0E07417B827"><enum>611.</enum><header>Report on failure to comply with the 500 mile rule</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this title, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall submit a report on compliance with the requirements under section 3621(b) of title 18, United States Code, to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives and the Subcommittees on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives that contains—</text> <paragraph id="HFA4F454312CE4C16AD3BCAEF8B3029CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of incarcerated persons who are not placed in a facility that is within 500 miles of their primary residence;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H19B0678116AB4099B26C7FC277E3E53D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each incarcerated person who is not placed in a facility that is within 500 miles of his or her primary residence, the reason for such placement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C40917888B642659F736A194CD6D5F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each incarcerated person who is not placed in a facility that is within 500 miles of his or her primary residence, the number of miles from the primary residence to the facility where such is placed; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC743C397ACE64E53806CB82D94AA9273"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each incarcerated person who is not placed at a facility within 500 miles of his or her primary residence, whether such incarcerated person has received any visits in the previous calendar year, and if so, how many.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H80354498B8F0466E98D427A1ACF51BF9"><enum>612.</enum><header>GAO study on representation in the Bureau of Prisons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of the best practices as of the date of enactment of this Act in recruiting and retaining women as correctional officers within the Bureau of Prisons. This report shall also include practices which have been counterproductive to any such effort. Additionally the report shall detail the demographics of the Bureau workforce as of the date of the study, disaggregated by age, racial, ethnic, and gender composition.</text></section>
<section id="H89E22618CAD44E419DD1B6EDFE5DE2BB"><enum>613.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. Not less than 30 percent of such funding shall be used for salaries and benefits and increased employment mandates as provided under this title.</text></section></title> <title id="HA53BE107CCF64FCF821902B09B1BDC17"><enum>VII</enum><header>GENDER-INFORMED REENTRY REFORM</header> <section id="HE597915CD8834CE4AD5DF14AD99760EF"><enum>701.</enum><header>Focus on women at residential reentry centers and in community confinement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that placement of incarcerated persons into prerelease custody through community confinement, which shall include residential reentry centers, community treatment centers, halfway houses, restitution centers, mental health facilities, alcohol or drug rehabilitation centers, or other community correctional facilities, shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H027079B6DE394DBE89D7312F42560188"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an incarcerated person who is a custodial parent of a minor child, permit the visitation with such child or residence with such child;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DEF71FCC226425A9B3713A17210711F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall ensure that such placement provides adequate gender-appropriate hygiene, healthcare, and nutrition needs; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2CD0A4816CD84F0389C4A1C058125073"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of an incarcerated person who is a victim of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, that such incarcerated person be permitted the ability to reside in a safe, and if necessary confidential, community confinement dwelling.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H28195C1300CC433E8A2D3734DC1FDB51"><enum>702.</enum><header>Focusing supervision on the rehabilitation of women</header> <subsection id="H4FA1192A3AF247A69C4F471E37F411E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training requirement</header><text>The Chief United States Probation Officer shall ensure that all training for probation officers shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H7ECED618BB2D4B40B0A8B801C9411AD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that all individuals enrolled in the academy fulfill a training session on gender-informed supervision practices; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E4398A93CA94D719D2B796733D81BBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>gender-informed supervision practices shall include evidence-based training on the specific needs of women who enter the justice system and have been incarcerated, and shall include training on trauma, sexual and physical abuse, family issues, physical and mental health issues, hygiene issues, racial disparities in the arrests of and law enforcement contacts with women, and issues related to the supervision and arrest of parents, including the identification and appropriate responses to a child, present or not present, whose parent is supervised, arrested, searched, or otherwise, in order to help minimize potential trauma and support a child’s physical safety and well-being.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H611245F980CE4C66AAB0582A0591CCA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Successful rehabiliation</header><text>Section 3603(3) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>to aid a probationer or a person on supervised release who is under his supervision, and to bring about improvements in his conduct and condition</quote> and inserting <quote>to effect the successful rehabilitation and reintegration of a probationer or a person on supervised release into society, using trauma-informed and restorative techniques with an understanding of the collateral consequences of conviction</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA3DEFA9E5D1D45629A221DF038308642"><enum>703.</enum><header>Gender-responsive modification of supervised release restrictions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3583 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H057AD6F594C140118A616687C38AE4CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by inserting <quote>and after consideration of any basis for difficulty in compliance by the defendant, including parental obligations, poverty, substance use disorders, mental health disorders, or otherwise</quote> after <quote>(a)(7)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BE21F4E6DE64E73AC3C2674FA086370"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB158072CF09D4F14B79593BD3AB6BD2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC60FA3BEF9C544DF8B4756240A405528"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7DD37CC83D1A4753A55477048A7F1985"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></title> <title id="H912C77D5EDE541859047DDC525A9A555"><enum>VIII</enum><header>Definitions</header> <section id="H99BA6583B18C4F77838E8CEFF5F5D952"><enum>801.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the terms <term>gender-responsive</term>, <term>trauma-informed</term>, and <term>victim-centered</term> as used within this Act shall have the meanings given such terms in rules made by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</text></section></title> 
</legis-body></bill>

